<rss version="2.0"><channel xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Have I Been Pwned latest breaches</title><description>The latest publicly leaked data breaches to hit Have I Been Pwned</description><atom:link href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/</link><item><guid isPermaLink="false">TehetsegKapu</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#TehetsegKapu</link><title>TehetségKapu - 54,357 breached accounts</title><description>In March 2025, &lt;a href="https://444.hu/2025/03/27/55-ezer-szemelyes-adat-magyar-diakok-tanarok-es-az-oktatasi-hivatal-dolgozoinak-informacioi-szivaroghattak-ki" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;almost 55k records were breached from the Hungarian education office website TehetségKapu&lt;/a&gt;. The data was subsequently published to a popular hacking forum and included email addresses, names and usernames.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 06:55:54 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">SamsungGermany</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#SamsungGermany</link><title>Samsung Germany Customer Tickets - 216,333 breached accounts</title><description>In March 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.infostealers.com/article/samsung-tickets-data-leak-infostealers-strike-again-in-massive-free-dump/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;data from Samsung Germany was compromised in a data breach of their logistics provider, Spectos&lt;/a&gt;. Allegedly due to credentials being obtained by malware running on a Spectos employee's machine, the breach included 216k unique email addresses along with names, physical addresses, items purchased from Samsung Germany and related support tickets and shipping tracking numbers.</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:24:36 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Qraved</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Qraved</link><title>Qraved - 984,519 breached accounts</title><description>In July 2021, the Indonesian restaurant website Qraved suffered a data breach &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/billions-passwords-credentials-leaked-mother-of-all-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;that was later redistributed as part of a larger corpus of data&lt;/a&gt;. The breach exposed almost 1M unique email addresses along with names, phone numbers, dates of birth and passwords stored as MD5 hashes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 15:43:51 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Boulanger</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Boulanger</link><title>Boulanger - 2,077,078 breached accounts</title><description>In September 2024, &lt;a href="https://therecord.media/france-retailers-hacked-confirm-cyberattack" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;French electronics retailer Boulanger suffered a data breach that exposed over 27M rows of data&lt;/a&gt;. The data included 2M unique email addresses along with names, physical addresses, phone numbers and latitude and longitude. The data was later publicly published to a popular hacking forum. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;leidhall&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 16:55:02 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">GermanDonerKebab</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#GermanDonerKebab</link><title>German Doner Kebab - 162,373 breached accounts</title><description>In March 2025, &lt;a href="https://x.com/darkwebinformer/status/1905275857159008341" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;data allegedly sourced from German Doner Kebab was published on a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. The data included 162k unique email addresses alongside names, phone numbers and physical addresses. &lt;a href="https://x.com/troyhunt/status/1906398239026196582" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;German Doner Kebab subsequently sent a disclosure notice to impacted individuals&lt;/a&gt;.</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 17:33:35 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">TroyHuntMailchimpList</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#TroyHuntMailchimpList</link><title>Troy Hunt's Mailchimp List - 16,627 breached accounts</title><description>In March 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/a-sneaky-phish-just-grabbed-my-mailchimp-mailing-list/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;a phishing attack successfully gained access to Troy Hunt's Mailchimp account and automatically exported a list of people who had subscribed to the newsletter for his personal blog&lt;/a&gt;. The exported list contained 16k email addresses and other data automatically collected by Mailchimp including IP address and a derived latitude, longitude and time zone.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:45:48 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">SpyX</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#SpyX</link><title>SpyX - 1,977,011 breached accounts</title><description>In June 2024, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/data-breach-at-stalkerware-spyx-affects-close-to-2-million-including-thousands-of-apple-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;spyware maker SpyX suffered a data breach that exposed almost 2M unique email addresses&lt;/a&gt;. The breach also exposed IP addresses, countries of residence, device information and 6-digit PINs in the password field. Further, a collection of iCloud credentials likely used to monitor targets directly via the cloud were also in the breach and contained the target's email address and plain text Apple password.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 22:34:18 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Lexipol</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Lexipol</link><title>Lexipol - 672,546 breached accounts</title><description>In February 2025, the public safety policy management systems company &lt;a href="https://www.them.us/story/puppygirl-hacker-polycule-leak" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Lexipol suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt;. Attributed to the self-proclaimed &amp;quot;Puppygirl Hacker Polycule&amp;quot;, the breach exposed an extensive number of documents and user records which were subsequently published publicly. The breach included over 670k unique email addresses in the user records, along with names, phone numbers, system-generated usernames and passwords stored as either MD5 or SHA-256 hashes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 01:07:39 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">ColorDating</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#ColorDating</link><title>Color Dating - 220,503 breached accounts</title><description>In September 2018, the dating app to match people with different ethnicities Color Dating suffered a data breach &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/billions-passwords-credentials-leaked-mother-of-all-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;that was later redistributed as part of a larger corpus of data&lt;/a&gt;. The breach exposed 220k unique email addresses along with bios, names, profile photos and bcrypt password hashes. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;ANK (Veles)&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 05:03:18 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">FlatEarthDave</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#FlatEarthDave</link><title>Flat Earth Sun, Moon and Zodiac App - 33,294 breached accounts</title><description>In October 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=71FRE9cZczw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the flat earth sun, moon and zodiac app created by Flat Earth Dave was found to be leaking extensive personal information of its users&lt;/a&gt;. The data included 33k unique email addresses along with usernames, latitudes and longitudes (their position on the globe) and passwords stored in plain text. A small number of profiles also contained names, dates of birth and genders.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 05:12:30 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Spyzie</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Spyzie</link><title>Spyzie - 518,643 breached accounts</title><description>In February 2025, the spyware service &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/27/spyzie-stalkerware-spying-on-thousands-of-android-and-iphone-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Spyzie suffered a data breach along with sibling spyware services, Spyic and Cocospy&lt;/a&gt;. The Spyzie breach alone exposed almost 519k customer email addresses which were provided to HIBP, and reportedly also enabled unauthorised access to captured messages, photos, call logs, and more. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;zathienaephi@proton.me&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 22:57:21 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">OrangeRomania</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#OrangeRomania</link><title>Orange Romania - 556,557 breached accounts</title><description>In February 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/orange-group-confirms-breach-after-hacker-leaks-company-documents/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the Romanian arm of telecommunications company Orange suffered a data breach which was subsequently published to a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. The data included 556k email addresses (of which hundreds of thousands were in the form of [phone number]@as1.romtelecom.net), phone numbers, subscription details, partial credit card data (type, last 4 digits, expiration date and issuing bank). The breach also exposed an extensive number of internal documents.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 05:39:42 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">AlienStealerLogs</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#AlienStealerLogs</link><title>ALIEN TXTBASE Stealer Logs - 284,132,969 breached accounts</title><description>In February 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/processing-23-billion-rows-of-alien-txtbase-stealer-logs" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;23 billion rows of stealer logs were obtained from a Telegram channel known as ALIEN TXTBASE&lt;/a&gt;. The data contained 284M unique email addresses alongside the websites they were entered into and the passwords used. This data is now searchable in HIBP by both email domain and the domain of the target website.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 19:25:18 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Spyic</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Spyic</link><title>Spyic - 875,999 breached accounts</title><description>In February 2025, the spyware service &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/20/stalkerware-apps-cocospy-spyic-exposing-phone-data-of-millions-of-people/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Spyic suffered a data breach along with sibling spyware service, Cocospy&lt;/a&gt;. The Spyic breach alone exposed almost 876k customer email addresses which were provided to HIBP, and reportedly also enabled unauthorised access to captured messages, photos, call logs, and more. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;zathienaephi@proton.me&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 23:12:38 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Cocospy</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Cocospy</link><title>Cocospy - 1,798,059 breached accounts</title><description>In February 2025, the spyware service &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/20/stalkerware-apps-cocospy-spyic-exposing-phone-data-of-millions-of-people/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Cocospy suffered a data breach along with sibling spyware service, Spyic&lt;/a&gt;. The Cocospy breach alone exposed almost 1.8M customer email addresses which were provided to HIBP, and reportedly also enabled unauthorised access to captured messages, photos, call logs, and more. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;zathienaephi@proton.me&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 22:36:16 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Storenvy</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Storenvy</link><title>Storenvy - 11,052,071 breached accounts</title><description>In mid-2019, &lt;a href="https://hackread.com/e-commerce-firm-storenvy-hacked-accounts-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the e-commerce website Storenvy suffered a data breach that exposed millions of customer records&lt;/a&gt;. A portion of the breached records were subsequently posted to a hacking forum with cracked password hashes, whilst the entire corpus of 23M rows was put up for sale. The data contained 11M unique email addresses alongside usernames, IP addresses, the user's city, gender date of birth and original salted SHA-1 password hash.</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 08:31:34 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">DoxbinTOoDA</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#DoxbinTOoDA</link><title>Doxbin (TOoDA) - 136,461 breached accounts</title><description>In February 2025, &lt;a href="https://x.com/vxunderground/status/1889487191283474872" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the &amp;quot;doxing&amp;quot; website Doxbin was compromised by a group calling themselves &amp;quot;TOoDA&amp;quot; and the data dumped publicly&lt;/a&gt;. Included in the breach were 336k unique email addresses alongside usernames. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;emo.rip&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 07:18:47 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Zacks2024</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Zacks2024</link><title>Zacks (2024) - 11,994,223 breached accounts</title><description>In June 2024, &lt;a href="https://darkwebinformer.com/a-threat-actor-claims-to-have-leaked-the-data-of-zacks-investment-research/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the investment research company Zacks was allegedly breached, and data was later published to a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. This comes after &lt;a href="https://www.zacks.com/breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;a separate Zacks data breach confirmed by the organisation in 2023&lt;/a&gt; with the subsequent breach disclosing millions of additional records representing a superset of data from the first incident. The 2024 breach included 12M unique email addresses along with IP and physical addresses, names, usernames, phone numbers and unsalted SHA-256 password hashes. Zacks did not respond to multiple attempts to contact them about the incident.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 23:19:43 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">LandAirSea</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#LandAirSea</link><title>LandAirSea - 337,373 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, the GPS tracking service LandAirSea suffered a data breach that exposed 337k unique customer email addresses alongside names, usernames and password hashes. The breach also exposed partial credit card data (card type, last 4 digits and expiration), and GPS device identifiers and locations. LandAirSea is aware of the breach and has remediated the underlying vulnerability. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;zathienaephi@proton.me&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 02:35:40 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">AdoptMeTradingValues</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#AdoptMeTradingValues</link><title>Adopt Me Trading Values - 86,136 breached accounts</title><description>In July 2022, the Adopt Me Trading Values website for assessing the value of pet trades within the &amp;quot;Adopt Me!&amp;quot; Roblox game suffered a data breach &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/billions-passwords-credentials-leaked-mother-of-all-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;that was later redistributed as part of a larger corpus of data&lt;/a&gt;. The breach exposed 86k unique email addresses along with usernames (and Roblox usernames), IP addresses and bcrypt password hashes. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;Leidhall&amp;quot;. </description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 02:58:18 Z</pubDate></item></channel></rss>