<rss version="2.0"><channel xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Have I Been Pwned latest breaches</title><description>The latest publicly leaked data breaches to hit Have I Been Pwned</description><atom:link href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/</link><item><guid isPermaLink="false">AdoptMeTradingValues</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#AdoptMeTradingValues</link><title>Adopt Me Trading Values - 86,136 breached accounts</title><description>In July 2022, the Adopt Me Trading Values website for assessing the value of pet trades within the &amp;quot;Adopt Me!&amp;quot; Roblox game suffered a data breach &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/billions-passwords-credentials-leaked-mother-of-all-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;that was later redistributed as part of a larger corpus of data&lt;/a&gt;. The breach exposed 86k unique email addresses along with usernames (and Roblox usernames), IP addresses and bcrypt password hashes. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;Leidhall&amp;quot;. </description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 02:58:18 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Youthmanual</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Youthmanual</link><title>Youthmanual - 937,912 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2019, the Indonesian college and career platform &lt;a href="https://thehackernews.com/2019/03/data-breach-security.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Youthmanual suffered a data breach that exposed 1.1M records of data&lt;/a&gt;. The breached included 938k unique email addresses along with extensive personal information including names, genders, dates and places of birth, phone numbers, physical addresses and salted SHA-1 password hashes.</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 06:28:46 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Thermomix</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Thermomix</link><title>Thermomix Recipe World Forum - 3,123,439 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.presseportal.de/pm/52621/5965724" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the Rezeptwelt (German for &amp;quot;recipe world&amp;quot;) forum for Thermomix owners suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt;. The incident exposed 3.1M registered users' details including names, email and physical addresses, phone numbers, dates of birth and bios (usually cooking related). The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;ayame@xmpp.jp&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 20:20:40 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Hakko</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Hakko</link><title>Hakko Corporation - 9,665 breached accounts</title><description>In March 2019, &lt;a href="https://upfsecurity.co.jp/pmark/8395/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the Japanese solder-related business Hakko Corporation suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt;. The incident exposed almost 10k customer records including email and physical addresses, phone numbers, names, usernames, genders, dates of birth and plain text passwords.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 01:58:47 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">PoinCampus</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#PoinCampus</link><title>PoinCampus - 89,116 breached accounts</title><description>In November 2024, &lt;a href="https://darkwebinformer.com/888-has-allegedly-leaked-the-data-of-poincampus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the South Korean education platform PoinCampus suffered a data breach which was later published to a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. The data included 89k unique email addresses, names and a small number of phone numbers and dates of birth. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;Threat Actor 888&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:29:41 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">1win</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#1win</link><title>1win - 96,166,543 breached accounts</title><description>In November 2024, &lt;a href="https://cryptoadventure.com/1win-hack-leaks-data-of-100-million-users-can-gamblefi-save-the-day/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the online betting platform 1win suffered a data breach that exposed 96M users&lt;/a&gt;. The exposed data included email and IP addresses, phone numbers, dates of birth, country and SHA-256 password hashes. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;Leidhall&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:37:55 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">DragonNest</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#DragonNest</link><title>DragonNest - 511,290 breached accounts</title><description>In August 2013, the massively multiplayer online role-playing game (MMORGP) DragonNest suffered a data breach &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/billions-passwords-credentials-leaked-mother-of-all-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;that was later redistributed as part of a larger corpus of data&lt;/a&gt;. The breach exposed over 500k unique email addresses along with usernames, IP addresses and plain text passwords. &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MMORPG/comments/4508tc/dragonnest_eu_experiences_massive_data_loss_and/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The service later suffered a massive data loss.&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 04:29:37 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">9Lives</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#9Lives</link><title>9Lives - 109,515 breached accounts</title><description>In October 2014, the (now defunct) Belgian gaming news forum 9Lives suffered a data breach &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/billions-passwords-credentials-leaked-mother-of-all-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;that was later redistributed as part of a larger corpus of data&lt;/a&gt;. The breach exposed 109k unique email addresses along with usernames and salted MD5 password hashes. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;Leidhall&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 02:04:44 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Speedio</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Speedio</link><title>Speedio (unverified) - 27,501,041 breached accounts</title><description>In December 2024, &lt;a href="https://darkwebinformer.com/a-threat-actor-is-allegedly-selling-the-data-of-speedio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;data alleged to have been taken from the Brazilian lead generation platform Speedio was posted for sale to a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. The data was allegedly obtained from an unsecured Elasticsearch instance and contained over 62M records of largely public business information including company names, phone numbers and physical addresses, along with 27M unique email addresses, predominantly from public services such as Gmail and Outlook. Speedio did not respond to multiple attempts to disclose the incident, and the origin of the data could not be independently verified. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;ayame@xmpp.jp&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 07:14:40 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">HeatGames</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#HeatGames</link><title>HeatGames - 647,896 breached accounts</title><description>In June 2021, the (now defunct) gaming website HeatGames suffered a data breach &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/billions-passwords-credentials-leaked-mother-of-all-breaches/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;that was later redistributed as part of a larger corpus of data&lt;/a&gt;. The breach exposed almost 650k unique email addresses along with IP addresses, country and salted MD5 password hashes.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 07:40:43 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">DoxbinScrape</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#DoxbinScrape</link><title>Doxbin Scrape - 435,784 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@zuajes/public-statement-on-the-extraction-of-emails-from-doxbin-cfd036c07a24" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;435k email addresses were scraped from the &amp;quot;doxing&amp;quot; service Doxbin&lt;/a&gt;. Posts to the service are usually intended to disclose the personal information of non-consensually third parties. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;oathnet.ru&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 02:09:58 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">FrameAndOptic</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#FrameAndOptic</link><title>Frame &amp; Optic - 15,678 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, &lt;a href="https://dailydarkweb.net/eyewear-wholesaler-data-breach-sparks-privacy-concerns/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the eyewear seller Frame &amp; Optic suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt;. The incident exposed almost 16k unique email addresses along with names, phone numbers and geolocation data including country, state and postcode. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;oathnet.ru&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 08:46:16 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Welhof</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Welhof</link><title>Welhof - 107,292 breached accounts</title><description>In late 2023, &lt;a href="https://www.welhof.com/nl_nl/klantenservice/welhof-cyberbeveiligingsincident" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the Dutch appliance store Welhof suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt;. The incident exposed over 100k unique email addresses along with names, physical addresses and the value of purchases made. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;oathnet.ru&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 08:28:11 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Otelier</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Otelier</link><title>Otelier - 436,855 breached accounts</title><description>In July 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/otelier-data-breach-exposes-info-hotel-reservations-of-millions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;a threat actor gained access to the hotel management platform Otelier and retrieved customer data from well-known hotel brands including Marriott, Hilton, and Hyatt&lt;/a&gt;. The data included 437k customer email addresses (a further 868k generated email addresses from the booking.com and Expedia platforms were not loaded into HIBP), names, physical addresses, phone numbers, booking information related to travel plans, purchases recorded by the platform and in a small number of cases, partial credit card data. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;ayame@xmpp.jp&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 06:47:39 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">MSI</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#MSI</link><title>MSI - 249,990 breached accounts</title><description>In July 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DeE_gLl3j94" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;MSI inadvertently exposed hundreds of thousands of customer records related to RMA claims that were subsequently found to be publicly accessible&lt;/a&gt;. The data included 250k unique email addresses alongside names, phone numbers, physical addresses and warranty claims. When contacted about the incident, MSI advised that &amp;quot;there is no evidence the information was ever accessed&amp;quot; and that &amp;quot;the security incident we had did not trigger state data breach notification obligations&amp;quot; due to the absence of &amp;quot;(social security number, driver's license number….etc)&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:14:17 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">LeCoqSportif</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#LeCoqSportif</link><title>Le Coq Sportif Columbia - 79,712 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, &lt;a href="https://dailydarkweb.net/colombia-data-breach-reported-at-lecoqsportif-com-co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;a data breach from the Columbian website for Le Coq Sportif was posted to a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. The data included almost 80k unique email addresses with the breach dating back to May 2023. Impacted data included physical and IP addresses, names, purchases, genders, dates of birth and bcrypt password hashes. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;oathnet.ru&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:40:33 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">StealerLogsJan2025</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#StealerLogsJan2025</link><title>Stealer Logs, Jan 2025 - 71,039,833 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, &lt;a href="https://troyhunt.com/experimenting-with-stealer-logs-in-have-i-been-pwned/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;stealer logs with 71M email addresses were added to HIBP&lt;/a&gt;. Consisting of email address, password and the website the credentials were entered against, this breach marks the launch of a new HIBP feature enabling the retrieval of the specific websites the logs were collected against. The incident also resulted in 106M more passwords being added to the &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords" rel="noopener"&gt;Pwned Passwords service&lt;/a&gt;.</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:41:58 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Scholastic</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Scholastic</link><title>Scholastic - 4,247,768 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.dailydot.com/debug/furry-hacks-scholastic-8-million-records-stolen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;a data breach of the publishing company Scholastic surfaced&lt;/a&gt;. The breach contained 4.2M unique email addresses with many of the records also including name, phone number and physical address.</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:55:39 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">SuperDraft</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#SuperDraft</link><title>SuperDraft - 300,187 breached accounts</title><description>In October 2024, the fantasy sports platform &lt;a href="https://x.com/troyhunt/status/1878316383303250120" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;SuperDraft suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt; that exposed over 300k customer records. The breach contained 24GB of data including email addresses, usernames, purchases, latitudes and longitudes, dates of birth and bcrypt password hashes.</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:43:05 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">GLAMIRA</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#GLAMIRA</link><title>GLAMIRA - 874,594 breached accounts</title><description>In late 2023, the online jewellery store &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/EngagementRings/comments/1adqinl/comment/koqzq4g/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;GLAMIRA suffered a data breach they attributed to &amp;quot;an unauthorised individual [who] briefly accessed one of our servers&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;. The data was subsequently published on a popular hacking forum and included 875k email addresses, names, phone numbers and purchases. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;oathnet.ru&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:55:22 Z</pubDate></item></channel></rss>