<rss version="2.0"><channel xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Have I Been Pwned latest breaches</title><description>The latest publicly leaked data breaches to hit Have I Been Pwned</description><atom:link href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/</link><item><guid isPermaLink="false">StealerLogsJan2025</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#StealerLogsJan2025</link><title>Stealer Logs, Jan 2025 - 71,039,833 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, &lt;a href="https://troyhunt.com/experimenting-with-stealer-logs-in-have-i-been-pwned/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;stealer logs with 71M email addresses were added to HIBP&lt;/a&gt;. Consisting of email address, password and the website the credentials were entered against, this breach marks the launch of a new HIBP feature enabling the retrieval of the specific websites the logs were collected against. The incident also resulted in 106M more passwords being added to the &lt;a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords" rel="noopener"&gt;Pwned Passwords service&lt;/a&gt;.</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:41:58 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Scholastic</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Scholastic</link><title>Scholastic - 4,247,768 breached accounts</title><description>In January 2025, &lt;a href="https://www.dailydot.com/debug/furry-hacks-scholastic-8-million-records-stolen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;a data breach of the publishing company Scholastic surfaced&lt;/a&gt;. The breach contained 4.2M unique email addresses with many of the records also including name, phone number and physical address.</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:55:39 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">SuperDraft</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#SuperDraft</link><title>SuperDraft - 300,187 breached accounts</title><description>In October 2024, the fantasy sports platform &lt;a href="https://x.com/troyhunt/status/1878316383303250120" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;SuperDraft suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt; that exposed over 300k customer records. The breach contained 24GB of data including email addresses, usernames, purchases, latitudes and longitudes, dates of birth and bcrypt password hashes.</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:43:05 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">GLAMIRA</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#GLAMIRA</link><title>GLAMIRA - 874,594 breached accounts</title><description>In late 2023, the online jewellery store &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/EngagementRings/comments/1adqinl/comment/koqzq4g/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;GLAMIRA suffered a data breach they attributed to &amp;quot;an unauthorised individual [who] briefly accessed one of our servers&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;. The data was subsequently published on a popular hacking forum and included 875k email addresses, names, phone numbers and purchases. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;oathnet.ru&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:55:22 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">FrenchCitizens</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#FrenchCitizens</link><title>French Citizens - 28,445,106 breached accounts</title><description>In September 2024, &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/french-records-exposed-by-mysterious-data-hoarder/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;over 90M rows of data on French Citizens was found left exposed in a publicly facing database&lt;/a&gt;. Compiled from various data breaches, the corpus contained 28M unique email addresses with the various source breaches each exposing different fields including name, physical and IP address, phone number and partial credit card data including payment type and last 4 digits.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:54:50 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">YoungLivingEssentialOils</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#YoungLivingEssentialOils</link><title>Young Living Essential Oils - 1,128,951 breached accounts</title><description>In December 2024, &lt;a href="https://x.com/H4ckManac/status/1866937778057122203" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;data claimed to be breached from the multi-level marketing company Young Living Essential Oils was posted to a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. The data contained 1.1M unique email addresses alongside names, the country of the account and in many cases, their date of birth. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;Threat Actor 888&amp;quot;. Young Living Essential Oils did not respond to multiple attempts to contact them about the data.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:37:40 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">schenkYOU</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#schenkYOU</link><title>schenkYOU - 237,349 breached accounts</title><description>In September 2024, &lt;a href="https://dailydarkweb.net/alleged-data-breach-at-schenkyou-a-threat-actor-claims-to-sell-6-million-records-on-dark-web/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;data from the online German gift store schenkYOU was put up for sale on a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. Obtained the month before, the data included 237k unique email addresses alongside names, dates of birth and salted SHA-256 password hashes. The standalone store was subsequently shut down with all traffic redirected to their Amazon store.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:26:26 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">BitView</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#BitView</link><title>BitView - 63,127 breached accounts</title><description>In December 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.bitview.net/blog#157" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the video sharing Community BitView suffered a data breach that exposed 63k customer records&lt;/a&gt;. Attributed to a backup taken by a previous administrator earlier in the year, the breach exposed email and IP addresses, bcrypt password hashes, usernames, bios, private messages, video comments and for some records, gender, date of birth and country of location.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:46:30 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Hopamedia</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Hopamedia</link><title>Hopamedia - 23,835,870 breached accounts</title><description>In 2024, &lt;a href="https://x.com/troyhunt/status/1868213788530630948" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;data relating to an unknown service referred to as &amp;quot;Hopamedia&amp;quot; and dating back to 2020 appeared in a publicly exposed database&lt;/a&gt;. The data included almost 24M records of email address, name, phone number, the country of the individual and their telecommunications carrier.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:23:36 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">MC2Data</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#MC2Data</link><title>MC2 Data - 2,122,280 breached accounts</title><description>In August 2024, &lt;a href="https://cybernews.com/security/us-mc2-background-check-data-leak/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;data aggregator MC2 Data left a database publicly accessible without a password which was subsequently discovered by a security researcher&lt;/a&gt;. The breach exposed the personal information of 2.1M subscribers to the service &lt;a href="https://infosec.exchange/@JayeLTee/113081021941257552" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;which was marketed under a series of different brand names&lt;/a&gt;. The data included email addresses, names and salted SHA-256 password hashes.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:47:05 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Yonema</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Yonema</link><title>Yonéma - 35,962 breached accounts</title><description>In November 2024, &lt;a href="https://x.com/cyberfeeddigest/status/1859676458588713010" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;data from the Senegalese payment platform Yonéma was posted to a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. The data included 36k unique email addresses alongside phone numbers, names and what appears to be encrypted passwords and dates of birth.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:28:27 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Tibber</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Tibber</link><title>Tibber - 50,002 breached accounts</title><description>In November 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.heise.de/en/news/Electricity-provider-Tibber-hacked-50-000-German-customers-affected-10031690.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the German electricity provider Tibber suffered a data breach that exposed the personal information of 50k customers&lt;/a&gt;. The data included names, email addresses, geographic locations (city and postcode) and total spend on purchases. The data was provided to HIBP by a source who requested it be attributed to &amp;quot;Threat Actor 888&amp;quot;.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:49:41 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">SeniorDating</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#SeniorDating</link><title>Senior Dating - 765,517 breached accounts</title><description>In 2024, &lt;a href="https://x.com/RhinozzCode/status/1863745736245928351" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the 40+ dating website Senior Dating suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt;. Attributed to an exposed Firebase database, the breach included extensive personal information on 766k users of the service including email addresses, photos, genders, links to Facebook accounts, dates of birth and precise latitude and longitude, among other personal attributes. The website was shut down after the breach was acknowledged by the site operator in December, along with a breach of the &amp;quot;ladies.com&amp;quot; website run by the same organisation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 12:38:50 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Ladies</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Ladies</link><title>Ladies.com - 118,809 breached accounts</title><description>In 2024, &lt;a href="https://x.com/RhinozzCode/status/1863745736245928351" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the lesbian dating website ladies.com suffered a data breach&lt;/a&gt;. Attributed to an exposed Firebase database, the breach included extensive personal information on 119k users of the service including email addresses, photos, sexual orientation, genders, dates of birth and precise latitude and longitude, among other personal attributes. The website was shut down in mid-2024 and the breach later acknowledged by the site operator in December, along with a breach of the &amp;quot;Senior Dating&amp;quot; website run by the same organisation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 11:45:16 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">TheRealWorld</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#TheRealWorld</link><title>The Real World - 324,382 breached accounts</title><description>In November 2024, the online course founded by Andrew Tate known as &amp;quot;The Real World&amp;quot; (previously &amp;quot;Hustler's University&amp;quot; &lt;a href="https://www.dailydot.com/debug/andrew-tate-the-real-world-hack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;suffered a data breach that exposed almost 325k users of the platform&lt;/a&gt;. The impacted data was limited to usernames, email addresses and chat logs.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:55:44 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">FlipaClip</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#FlipaClip</link><title>FlipaClip - 892,854 breached accounts</title><description>In November 2024, the animation app &lt;a href="https://x.com/RhinozzCode/status/1859291987360321631" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;FlipaClip suffered a data breach that exposed almost 900k records due to an exposed Firebase server&lt;/a&gt;. The impacted data included name, email address, country and date of birth. FlipaClip advised the issue has since been rectified.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 22:37:58 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Finsure</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Finsure</link><title>Finsure - 296,124 breached accounts</title><description>In October 2024, almost 300k unique email addresses from Australian mortgage broking group Finsure were obtained from the ActivePipe real estate marketing platform. The impacted data also included names, phone numbers and physical addresses. The incident did not directly affect any of Finsure's systems or expose any passwords or financial data.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 04:25:18 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">DemandScience</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#DemandScience</link><title>DemandScience by Pure Incubation - 121,796,165 breached accounts</title><description>In early 2024, &lt;a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/inside-the-demandscience-by-pure-incubation-data-breach" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;a large corpus of data from DemandScience (a company owned by Pure Incubation), appeared for sale on a popular hacking forum&lt;/a&gt;. Later attributed to a leak from a decommissioned legacy system, the breach contained extensive data that was largely business contact information aggregated from public sources. Specifically, the data included 122M unique corporate email addresses, physical addresses, phone numbers, employers and job titles. It also included names and for many individuals, a link to their LinkedIn profile.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:53:35 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">HotTopic</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#HotTopic</link><title>Hot Topic - 56,904,909 breached accounts</title><description>In October 2024, &lt;a href="https://au.pcmag.com/security/107921/hacker-may-have-breached-hot-topic-stolen-data-on-millions" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;retailer Hot Topic suffered a data breach that exposed 57 million unique email addresses&lt;/a&gt;. The impacted data also included physical addresses, phone numbers, purchases, genders, dates of birth and partial credit data containing card type, expiry and last 4 digits.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 07:50:58 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">Earth2</guid><link>https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Earth2</link><title>Earth 2 - 420,961 breached accounts</title><description>In October 2024, 421k unique email addresses from the virtual earth game Earth 2 were derived from embedded Gravatar images. Appearing alongside player usernames, the root cause was related to how Gravatar presents links to avatars as MD5 hashes within consuming services, a feature Earth 2 advised has now been disabled on their platform. This incident did not expose any further personal information, passwords or financial data.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 04:49:02 Z</pubDate></item></channel></rss>