<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/?" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 03:09:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Patch Tuesday, April 2025 Edition</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/patch-tuesday-april-2025-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/patch-tuesday-april-2025-edition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 03:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security Tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Goettl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CLFS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Common Log File System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-26671]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-27480]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-27482]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-29824]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ivanti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satnam Narang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Remote Desktop Services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today released updates to plug at least 121 security holes in its Windows operating systems and software, including one vulnerability that is already being exploited in the wild. Eleven of those flaws earned Microsoft's most-dire "critical" rating, meaning malware or malcontents could exploit them with little to no interaction from Windows users.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today released updates to plug at least 121 security holes in its <strong>Windows</strong> operating systems and software, including one vulnerability that is already being exploited in the wild. Eleven of those flaws earned Microsoft&#8217;s most-dire &#8220;critical&#8221; rating, meaning malware or malcontents could exploit them with little to no interaction from Windows users.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter  wp-image-56287" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png" alt="" width="750" height="528" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png 841w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-768x541.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-782x550.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>The zero-day flaw already seeing exploitation is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-29824" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-29824</a>, a local elevation of privilege bug in the Windows <strong>Common Log File System</strong> (CLFS) driver.  Microsoft rates it as &#8220;important,&#8221; but as <strong>Chris Goettl</strong> from <strong>Ivanti</strong> points out, risk-based prioritization warrants treating it as critical.</p>
<p>This CLFS component of Windows is no stranger to Patch Tuesday: According to Tenable&#8217;s <strong>Satnam Narang</strong>, since 2022 Microsoft has patched 32 CLFS vulnerabilities &#8212; averaging 10 per year &#8212; with six of them exploited in the wild. The <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-49138" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last CLFS zero-day</a> was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/patch-tuesday-december-2024-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">patched in December 2024</a>.</p>
<p>Narang notes that while flaws allowing attackers to install arbitrary code are consistently top overall Patch Tuesday features, the data is reversed for zero-day exploitation.</p>
<p>&#8220;For the past two years, elevation of privilege flaws have led the pack and, so far in 2025, account for over half of all zero-days exploited,&#8221; Narang wrote.<span id="more-70933"></span></p>
<p>Rapid7&#8217;s <strong>Adam Barnett</strong> warns that any Windows defenders responsible for an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightweight_Directory_Access_Protocol" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LDAP server</a> — which means almost any organization with a non-trivial Microsoft footprint — should add <span class="il">patching</span> for the critical flaw <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-26663" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-26663&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1744231709116000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3moAqrbzoHqolAikc6dYLo">CVE-2025-26663</a> to their to-do list.</p>
<p>&#8220;With no privileges required, no need for user interaction, and code execution presumably in the context of the LDAP server itself, successful exploitation would be an attractive shortcut to any attacker,&#8221; Barnett said. &#8220;Anyone wondering if today is a re-run of December 2024 <span class="il">Patch</span> <span class="il">Tuesday</span> can take some small solace in the fact that the worst of the <a href="https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/2024/12/10/patch-tuesday-december-2024/#ldap-critical-rce" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/2024/12/10/patch-tuesday-december-2024/%23ldap-critical-rce&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1744231709116000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2C4e66FL53_LrZBhrndLUw">trio of LDAP critical RCEs published at the end of last year</a> was likely easier to exploit than today’s example, since today’s CVE-2025-26663 requires that an attacker win a race condition. Despite that, Microsoft still expects that exploitation is more likely.&#8221;</p>
<p>Among the critical updates Microsoft patched this month are remote code execution flaws in <strong>Windows Remote Desktop </strong>services (RDP), including <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-26671" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-26671</a>, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-27480" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-27480</a> and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-27482" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-27482</a>; only the latter two are rated &#8220;critical,&#8221; and Microsoft marked both of them as “Exploitation More Likely.&#8221;</p>
<p>Perhaps the most widespread vulnerabilities fixed this month were in web browsers. <strong>Google Chrome</strong> <a href="https://chromereleases.googleblog.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">updated</a> to fix 13 flaws this week, and <strong>Mozilla Firefox </strong>fixed <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/security/advisories/mfsa2025-20/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">eight bugs</a>, with possibly more updates coming later this week for <strong>Microsoft</strong> <strong>Edge</strong>.</p>
<p>As it tends to do on Patch Tuesdays, <strong>Adobe</strong> has <a href="https://helpx.adobe.com/security/security-bulletin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released 12 updates</a> resolving 54 security holes across a range of products, including <strong>ColdFusion</strong>, <strong>Adobe Commerce</strong>, <strong>Experience Manager Forms</strong>, <strong>After Effects</strong>, <strong>Media Encoder</strong>, <strong>Bridge</strong>, <strong>Premiere Pro</strong>, <strong>Photoshop</strong>, <strong>Animate</strong>, <strong>AEM Screens</strong>, and <strong>FrameMaker</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Apple</strong> users may need to patch as well. On March 31, Apple released a huge security update (more than three gigabytes in size) to fix issues in a range of their products, including <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/apple-backports-zero-day-patches-to-older-iphones-and-macs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">at least one zero-day flaw</a>.</p>
<p>And in case you missed it, on March 31, 2025 <strong>Apple</strong> released <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/100100?is=1ef7934f6635b02395adcab09a0c1b24bf0ea745b648bfe87189de8aadc7300b" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a rather large batch of security updates</a> for a wide range of their products, from <strong>macOS</strong> to the<strong> iOS</strong> operating systems on <strong>iPhones</strong> and <strong>iPads</strong>.</p>
<p>Earlier today, Microsoft included a note saying <strong>Windows 10</strong> security updates weren&#8217;t available but would be released as soon as possible. It appears from browsing <a href="https://www.askwoody.com/2025/april-2025-updates-out/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">askwoody.com</a> that this snafu has since been rectified. Either way, if you run into complications applying any of these updates please leave a note about it in the comments below, because the chances are good that someone else had the same problem.</p>
<p>As ever, please consider backing up your data and or devices prior to updating, which makes it far less complicated to undo a software update gone awry. For more granular details on today&#8217;s Patch Tuesday, check out the <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/forums/diary/Microsoft%20April%202025%20Patch%20Tuesday/31838/">SANS Internet Storm Center&#8217;s roundup</a>. Microsoft&#8217;s update guide for April 2025 <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/releaseNote/2025-Apr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is here</a>.</p>
<p>For more details on Patch Tuesday, check out the write-ups from <a href="https://www.action1.com/patch-tuesday/patch-tuesday-april-2025/?vyj" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Action1</a> and <a href="https://www.automox.com/blog/patch-tuesday-april-2025" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Automox</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/patch-tuesday-april-2025-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cyber Forensic Expert in 2,000+ Cases Faces FBI Probe</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/cyber-forensic-expert-in-2000-cases-faces-fbi-probe/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/cyber-forensic-expert-in-2000-cases-faces-fbi-probe/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 16:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Forensic Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felician University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HarvardX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kimberly Hanlon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Lanterman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark rasch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perkins Coie LLP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean Harrington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen Allwine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Secret Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 221B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Upsala College]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A Minnesota cybersecurity and computer forensics expert whose testimony has featured in thousands of courtroom trials over the past 30 years is facing questions about his credentials and an inquiry from the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI). Legal experts say the inquiry could be grounds to reopen a number of adjudicated cases in which the expert's testimony may have been pivotal.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Minnesota cybersecurity and computer forensics expert whose testimony has featured in thousands of courtroom trials over the past 30 years is facing questions about his credentials and an inquiry from the <strong>Federal Bureau of Investigation</strong> (FBI). Legal experts say the inquiry could be grounds to reopen a number of adjudicated cases in which the expert&#8217;s testimony may have been pivotal.</p>
<div id="attachment_70889" style="width: 827px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70889" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70889" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/marklanterman-linkedin.png" alt="" width="817" height="597" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/marklanterman-linkedin.png 817w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/marklanterman-linkedin-768x561.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/marklanterman-linkedin-782x571.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 817px) 100vw, 817px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70889" class="wp-caption-text">One might conclude from reading Mr. Lanterman&#8217;s LinkedIn profile that has a degree from Harvard University.</p></div>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/marklanterman" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Lanterman</a></strong> is a former investigator for the U.S. Secret Service Electronics Crimes Task Force who founded the Minneapolis consulting firm <strong>Computer Forensic Services</strong> (CFS). The CFS website says Lanterman&#8217;s 30-year career has seen him testify as an expert in more than 2,000 cases, with experience in cases involving sexual harassment and workplace claims, theft of intellectual property and trade secrets, white-collar crime, and class action lawsuits.</p>
<p>Or at least it did until last month, when Lanterman&#8217;s profile and work history were quietly removed from the CFS website. The removal came after <strong>Hennepin County Attorney&#8217;s Office</strong> <a href="https://www.hennepinattorney.org/news/news/2025/March/lanterman-disclosure" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> it was notifying parties to ten pending cases that they were unable to verify Lanterman&#8217;s educational and employment background. The county attorney also said the FBI is now investigating the allegations.</p>
<p>Those allegations were raised by <strong>Sean Harrington</strong>, an attorney and forensics examiner based in Prescott, Wisconsin. Harrington alleged that Lanterman lied under oath in court on multiple occasions when he testified that he has a Bachelor of Science and a Master&#8217;s degree in computer science from the now-defunct <strong>Upsala College</strong>, and that he completed his postgraduate work in cybersecurity at <strong>Harvard University</strong>.</p>
<p>Harrington&#8217;s claims gained steam thanks to digging by the law firm <strong>Perkins Coie LLP</strong>, which is defending a case wherein a client&#8217;s laptop was forensically reviewed by Lanterman. On March 14, Perkins Coie attorneys <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/155-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">asked the judge</a> (PDF) to strike Lanterman&#8217;s testimony because neither he nor they could substantiate claims about his educational background.</p>
<p>Upsala College, located in East Orange, N.J., operated for 102 years until it closed in 1995 after a period of declining enrollment and financial difficulties. Perkins Coie told the court that they&#8217;d visited <strong>Felician University</strong>, which holds the transcripts for Upsala College during the years Lanterman claimed to have earned undergraduate and graduate degrees. The law firm said Felician <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/155-21.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">had no record of transcripts for Lanterman</a> (PDF), and that his name was absent from all of the Upsala College student yearbooks and commencement programs during that period.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, Lanterman acknowledged he had no way to prove he attended Upsala College, and that his &#8220;postgraduate work&#8221; at Harvard was in fact an eight-week online cybersecurity class called <strong>HarvardX</strong>, which cautions that its certificates should not be considered equivalent to a Harvard degree or a certificate earned through traditional, in-person programs at Harvard University.</p>
<p>Lanterman has testified that his first job after college was serving as a police officer in Springfield Township, Pennsylvania, although the Perkins Coie attorneys noted that this role was omitted from his resume. The attorneys said when they tried to verify Lanterman&#8217;s work history, &#8220;the police department responded with a story that would be almost impossible to believe if it was not corroborated by Lanterman&#8217;s own email communications.&#8221;</p>
<p>As recounted in the March 14 filing, Lanterman was deposed on Feb. 11, and the following day <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/155-21.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">he emailed the Springfield Township Police Department</a> to see if he could have a peek at his old personnel file. On Feb. 14, Lanterman visited the Springfield Township PD and asked to borrow his employment record. He told the officer he spoke with on the phone that he&#8217;d recently been instructed to &#8220;get his affairs in order&#8221; after being diagnosed with a grave heart condition, and that he wanted his old file to show his family about his early career.</p>
<p>According to Perkins Coie, Lanterman left the Springfield Township PD with his personnel file, and has not returned it as promised.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is shocking that an expert from Minnesota would travel to suburban Philadelphia and abscond with his decades-old personnel file to obscure his background,&#8221; the law firm wrote. &#8220;That appears to be the worst and most egregious form of spoliation, and the deception alone is reason enough to exclude Lanterman and consider sanctions.&#8221;</p>
<p>Harrington initially contacted KrebsOnSecurity about his concerns in late 2023, fuming after sitting through <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/srxrxkwyf03inudrw9ymn/2023-Seminar-Recording-copy-copy-1.MP4?rlkey=th0yqylm5uvmq84skfg8qvfh3&amp;e=1&amp;dl=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a conference speech</a> in which Lanterman shared documents from a ransomware victim and told attendees it was because they&#8217;d refused to hire his company to perform a forensic investigation on a recent breach.</p>
<p>&#8220;He claims he was involved in the Martha Stewart investigation, the Bernie Madoff trial, Paul McCartney’s divorce, the Tom Petters investigation, the Denny Hecker investigation, and many others,&#8221; Harrington said. &#8220;He claims to have been invited to speak to the Supreme Court, claims to train the &#8216;entire federal judiciary&#8217; on cybersecurity annually, and is a faculty member of the United States Judicial Conference and the Judicial College — positions which he obtained, in part, on a house of fraudulent cards.&#8221;</p>
<p>In an interview this week, Harrington said court documents reveal that at least two of Lanterman&#8217;s previous clients complained CFS had held their data for ransom over billing disputes. In <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2022-10-26_Declaration-ofKimberlyHanlon.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a declaration</a> (PDF) dated August 2022, the co-founder of the law firm <strong>MoreLaw Minneapolis LLC</strong> said she hired Lanterman in 2014 to examine several electronic devices after learning that one of their paralegals had a criminal fraud history.</p>
<p>But the law firm said when it pushed back on a consulting bill that was far higher than expected, Lanterman told them CFS would &#8220;escalate&#8221; its collection efforts if they didn&#8217;t pay, including &#8220;a claim and lien against the data which will result in a public auction of your data.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;All of us were flabbergasted by Mr. Lanterman’s email,&#8221; wrote MoreLaw co-founder <strong>Kimberly Hanlon</strong>. &#8220;I had never heard of any legitimate forensic company threatening to &#8216;auction&#8217; off an attorney’s data, particularly knowing that the data is comprised of confidential client data, much of which is sensitive in nature.&#8221;<span id="more-70780"></span></p>
<p>In 2009, a Wisconsin-based manufacturing company that had hired Lanterman for computer forensics balked at paying an $86,000 invoice from CFS, calling it &#8220;excessive and unsubstantiated.&#8221; The company told a Hennepin County court that on April 15, 2009, CFS conducted an auction of its trade secret information in violation of their confidentiality agreement.</p>
<p>&#8220;CFS noticed and conducted a Public Sale of electronic information that was entrusted to them pursuant to the terms of the engagement agreement,&#8221; the company wrote. &#8220;CFS submitted the highest bid at the Public Sale in the amount of $10,000.&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-70891" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/27-cv-12-22089-ExtrusionDiesIndustries.png" alt="" width="1039" height="439" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/27-cv-12-22089-ExtrusionDiesIndustries.png 1039w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/27-cv-12-22089-ExtrusionDiesIndustries-768x324.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/27-cv-12-22089-ExtrusionDiesIndustries-782x330.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 1039px) 100vw, 1039px" /></p>
<p>Lanterman briefly responded to a list of questions about his background (and recent heart diagnosis) on March 24, saying he would send detailed replies the following day. Those replies never materialized. Instead, Lanterman forwarded a recent memo he wrote to the court that attacked Harrington and said his accuser was only trying to take out a competitor. He has not responded to further requests for comment.</p>
<p>&#8220;When I attended Upsala, I was a commuter student who lived with my grandparents in Morristown, New Jersey approximately 30 minutes away from Upsala College,&#8221; Lanterman <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/ACU-Plasmold-Lanterman-Repsonse-Letter.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">explained to the judge</a> (PDF) overseeing <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2025-03-12_memo-toCourt-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a separate ongoing case</a> (PDF) in which he has testified. &#8220;With limited resources, I did not participate in campus social events, nor did I attend graduation ceremonies. In 2023, I confirmed with Felician University — which maintains Upsala College’s records — that they could not locate my transcripts or diploma, a situation that they indicated was possibly due to unresolved money-related issues.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lanterman was ordered to appear in court on April 3 in the case defended by Perkins Coie, but he did not show up. Instead, he sent a message to the judge withdrawing from the case.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am 60 years old,&#8221; Lanterman <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/lanterman-retire.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told the judge</a>. &#8220;I created my business from nothing. I am done dealing with the likes of individuals like Sean Harrington. And quite frankly, I have been planning at turning over my business to my children for years. That time has arrived.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lanterman&#8217;s letter leaves the impression that it was his decision to retire. But according to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/affidavit-seanlanterman.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an affidavit</a> (PDF) filed in a Florida case on March 28, Mark Lanterman&#8217;s son Sean said he&#8217;d made the difficult decision to ask his dad to step down given all the negative media attention.</p>
<p><strong>Mark Rasch</strong>, a former federal cybercrime prosecutor who now serves as counsel to the New York cybersecurity intelligence firm <a href="https://www.unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a>, said that if an expert witness is discredited, any defendants who lost cases that were strongly influenced by that expert&#8217;s conclusions at trial could have grounds for appeal.</p>
<p>Rasch said law firms who propose an expert witness have a duty in good faith to vet that expert&#8217;s qualifications, knowing that those credentials will be subject to cross-examination.</p>
<p>&#8220;Federal rules of civil procedure and evidence both require experts to list every case they have testified in as an expert for the past few years,&#8221; Rasch said. &#8220;Part of that due diligence is pulling up the results of those cases and seeing what the nature of their testimony has been.&#8221;</p>
<p>Perhaps the most well-publicized case involving significant forensic findings from Lanterman was the 2018 conviction of <strong>Stephen Allwine</strong>, who was <a href="https://www.fox9.com/news/convicted-dark-net-killer-claims-innocence-i-couldnt-have-done-it" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found guilty of killing his wife</a> two years earlier after attempts at hiring a hitman on the dark net fell through. Allwine is serving a sentence of life in prison, and continues to maintain that he was framed, casting doubt on computer forensic evidence found on 64 electronic devices taken from his home.</p>
<p>On March 24, Allwine <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/78.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">petitioned a Minnesota court</a> (PDF) to revisit his case, citing the accusations against Lanterman and his role as a key witness for the prosecution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/cyber-forensic-expert-in-2000-cases-faces-fbi-probe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/srxrxkwyf03inudrw9ymn/2023-Seminar-Recording-copy-copy-1.MP4?rlkey=th0yqylm5uvmq84skfg8qvfh3&#038;e=1&#038;dl=0" length="0" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Each Pillar of the 1st Amendment is Under Attack</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/how-each-pillar-of-the-1st-amendment-is-under-attack/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/how-each-pillar-of-the-1st-amendment-is-under-attack/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 01:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1st Amendment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[60 Minutes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ABC News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Americans United for Separation of Church and State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[András Pethő]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brendan Carr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Center for Democracy & Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CNN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electronic Frontier Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Communications Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Amendment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Information Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gannett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George Stephanopoulos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House Speaker Mike Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interfaith Alliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeffrey Goldberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jenner & Block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judge Richard Leon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kate Ruane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marc Elias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Michael Waltz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NPR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paramount]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PBS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pulitzer Prize board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Free Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio Free Europe / Radio Liberty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rev. Paul Brandeis Raushenbush]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Secretary of State Marco Rubio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Des Moines Register]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tony Bradley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Agency for Global Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Agency for International Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. District Court Judge Royce Lamberth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. District Judge James Boasberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Supreme Court Justice John Roberts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vice President JD Vance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WilmerHale]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an address to Congress this month, President Trump claimed he had "brought free speech back to America." But barely two months into his second term, the president has waged an unprecedented attack on the First Amendment rights of journalists, students, universities, government workers, lawyers and judges.

This story explores a slew of recent actions by the Trump administration that threaten to undermine all five pillars of the First Amendment to the U.S. Constitution, which guarantees freedoms concerning speech, religion, the media, the right to assembly, and the right to petition the government and seek redress for wrongs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><em>&#8220;Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances.&#8221; -U.S. Constitution, First Amendment.</em></p>
<div id="attachment_70858" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70858" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70858" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/1stamendment.png" alt="" width="747" height="508" /><p id="caption-attachment-70858" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, zimmytws.</p></div>
<p>In an address to Congress this month, <strong>President Trump</strong> claimed he had &#8220;brought free speech back to America.&#8221; But barely two months into his second term, the president has waged an unprecedented attack on the First Amendment rights of journalists, students, universities, government workers, lawyers and judges.</p>
<p>This story explores a slew of recent actions by the Trump administration that threaten to undermine all five pillars of the First Amendment to the U.S. Constitution, which guarantees freedoms concerning speech, religion, the media, the right to assembly, and the right to petition the government and seek redress for wrongs.</p>
<h2>THE RIGHT TO PETITION</h2>
<p>The right to petition allows citizens to communicate with the government, whether to complain, request action, or share viewpoints &#8212; without fear of reprisal. But that right is being assaulted by this administration on multiple levels. For starters, many GOP lawmakers are now heeding their leadership&#8217;s advice to stay away from local town hall meetings and avoid the wrath of constituents affected by the administration&#8217;s many federal budget and workforce cuts.</p>
<p>Another example: President Trump recently <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/18/politics/opm-privacy-team-fired/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fired most of the people</a> involved in processing <strong>Freedom of Information Act</strong> (FOIA) requests for government agencies. FOIA is an indispensable tool used by journalists and the public to request government records, and to hold leaders accountable.</p>
<p>The biggest story by far this week was the bombshell from The Atlantic editor <strong>Jeffrey Goldberg</strong>, who recounted how he was <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/trump-administration-accidentally-texted-me-its-war-plans/682151/?gift=DjgA9DZGvABas7wFCM-ptk0vpPuikYUZT9Ej3cJbK1s&amp;utm_source=copy-link&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=share" target="_blank" rel="noopener">inadvertently added to a Signal group chat</a> with <strong>National Security Advisor Michael Waltz</strong> and 16 other Trump administration officials discussing plans for an upcoming attack on Yemen.</p>
<p>One overlooked aspect of Goldberg&#8217;s incredible account is that by planning and coordinating the attack on Signal &#8212; which features messages that can auto-delete after a short time &#8212; administration officials were evidently seeking a way to avoid creating a lasting (and potentially FOIA-able) record of their deliberations.</p>
<p>&#8220;Intentional or not, use of Signal in this context was an act of erasure—because without Jeffrey Goldberg being accidentally added to the list, the general public would never have any record of these communications or any way to know they even occurred,&#8221; <strong>Tony Bradley</strong> <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tonybradley/2025/03/26/what-everyone-has-missed-about-the-trump-administration-signal-scandal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote this week at Forbes</a>.</p>
<p>Petitioning the government, particularly when it ignores your requests, often requires challenging federal agencies in court. But that becomes far more difficult if the most competent law firms start to shy away from cases that may involve crossing the president and his administration.</p>
<p>On March 22, the president issued <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/preventing-abuses-of-the-legal-system-and-the-federal-court/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a memorandum</a> that directs heads of the Justice and Homeland Security Departments to &#8220;seek sanctions against attorneys and law firms who engage in frivolous, unreasonable and vexatious litigation against the United States,&#8221; or in matters that come before federal agencies.</p>
<p>The POTUS recently issued several executive orders railing against specific law firms with attorneys who worked legal cases against him. On Friday, the <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-03-28/trump-says-he-s-reached-100-million-pro-bono-deal-with-skadden" target="_blank" rel="noopener">president announced</a> that the law firm of <strong>Skadden, Arps, Slate, Meager &amp; Flom</strong> had agreed to provide $100 million in pro bono work on issues that he supports.</p>
<p>Trump issued <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/addressing-remedial-action-by-paul-weiss/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">another order</a> naming the firm <strong>Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton &amp; Garrison</strong>, which ultimately agreed to pledge $40 million in pro bono legal services to the president&#8217;s causes.</p>
<p>Other Trump executive orders targeted law firms <strong>Jenner &amp; Block</strong> and <strong>WilmerHale</strong>, both of which have attorneys that worked with special counsel Robert Mueller on the investigation into Russian interference in the 2016 election. But this week, two federal judges in separate rulings <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/03/28/politics/law-firms-fighting-trump-executive-order/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">froze parts of those orders</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is no doubt this retaliatory action chills speech and legal advocacy, and that is qualified as a constitutional harm,&#8221; wrote <strong>Judge Richard Leon</strong>, who ruled against the executive order targeting WilmerHale.</p>
<p>President Trump recently took the extraordinary step of calling for the impeachment of federal judges who rule against the administration. Trump called <strong>U.S. District Judge James Boasberg</strong> <a class=" js-tealium-tracking " href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/03/18/trump-impeachment-judge-deportations-00235173" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-tracking="mpos=&amp;mid=&amp;lindex=&amp;lcol=" aria-label=" (Opens in a new window)">a “Radical Left Lunatic”</a> and urged he be removed from office for blocking deportation of Venezuelan alleged gang members under a rarely invoked wartime legal authority.</p>
<p>In a rare public rebuke to a sitting president, <strong>U.S. Supreme Court Justice John Roberts</strong> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/us-chief-justice-roberts-calls-judges-impeachment-are-inappropriate-after-trump-2025-03-18/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">issued a statement on March 18</a> pointing out that &#8220;For more than two centuries, it has been established that impeachment is not an appropriate response to disagreement concerning a judicial decision.&#8221;</p>
<p>The U.S. Constitution provides that judges can be removed from office only through impeachment by the House of Representatives and conviction by the Senate. The Constitution also states that judges&#8217; salaries cannot be reduced while they are in office.</p>
<p>Undeterred, <strong>House Speaker Mike Johnson </strong>this week suggested the administration could still use the power of its purse to keep courts in line, and even <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/now/video/speaker-mike-johnson-floats-possibility-of-congress-eliminating-federal-courts-235397189724" target="_blank" rel="noopener">floated the idea of wholesale eliminating federal courts</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;We do have authority over the federal courts as you know,&#8221; Johnson said. &#8220;We can eliminate an entire district court. We have power of funding over the courts, and all these other things. But desperate times call for desperate measures, and Congress is going to act, so stay tuned for that.&#8221;</p>
<h2>FREEDOM OF ASSEMBLY</h2>
<p>President Trump has taken a number of actions to discourage lawful demonstrations at universities and colleges across the country, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-says-federal-funding-will-stop-colleges-schools-allowing-illegal-protests-2025-03-04/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">threatening to cut federal funding</a> for any college that supports protests he deems &#8220;illegal.&#8221;</p>
<p>A Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/additional-measures-to-combat-anti-semitism/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">executive order in January</a> outlined a broad federal crackdown on what he called &#8220;the explosion of antisemitism&#8221; on U.S. college campuses. This administration has asserted that foreign students who are lawfully in the United States on visas do not enjoy the same free speech or due process rights as citizens.</p>
<p><strong>Reuters</strong> reports that the acting civil rights director at the <strong>Department of Education</strong> <a href="https://www.ed.gov/about/news/press-release/us-department-of-educations-office-civil-rights-sends-letters-60-universities-under-investigation-antisemitic-discrimination-and-harassment" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on March 10 sent letters to 60 educational institutions</a> warning they could lose federal funding if they don&#8217;t do more to combat anti-semitism. On March 20, Trump issued an order calling for <a href="https://www.ed.gov/about/news/press-release/statement-president-trumps-executive-order-return-power-over-education-states-and-local-communities" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the closure of the Education Department</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, <strong>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement</strong> (ICE) agents have been <a href="https://apnews.com/article/immigration-detainees-students-ozturk-khalil-78f544fb2c8b593c88a0c1f0e0ad9c5f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">detaining and trying to deport</a> pro-Palestinian students who are legally in the United States. The administration is targeting students and academics who spoke out against Israel&#8217;s attacks on Gaza, or who were active in campus protests against U.S. support for the attacks. <strong>Secretary of State Marco Rubio</strong> <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/education/5218410-ice-arrests-tufts-alabama-students-trump-immigration-crackdown-rumeysa-ozturk-khalil/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told reporters Thursday</a> that at least 300 foreign students have seen their visas revoked under President Trump, a far higher number than was previously known.</p>
<p>In his first term, Trump threatened to use the national guard or the U.S. military to deal with protesters, and in campaigning for re-election he promised to revisit the idea.</p>
<p>“I think the bigger problem is the enemy from within,” Trump told <strong>Fox News</strong> in October 2024. “We have some very bad people. We have some sick people, radical left lunatics. And I think they’re the big — and it should be very easily handled by, if necessary, by National Guard, or if really necessary, by the military, because they can’t let that happen.”</p>
<p>This term, Trump acted swiftly to remove the top judicial advocates in the armed forces who would almost certainly push back on any request by the president to use U.S. soldiers in an effort to quell public protests, or to arrest and detain immigrants. In late February, the president and <strong>Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth</strong> fired the top legal officers for the military services &#8212; those responsible for ensuring the Uniform Code of Military Justice is followed by commanders.</p>
<p>Military.com <a href="https://www.military.com/daily-news/2025/02/24/people-are-very-scared-trump-administration-purge-of-jag-officers-raises-legal-ethical-fears.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warns</a> that the purge &#8220;sets an alarming precedent for a crucial job in the military, as President Donald Trump has mused about using the military in unorthodox and potentially illegal ways.&#8221; Hegseth told reporters the removals were necessary because he didn&#8217;t want them to pose any &#8220;roadblocks to orders that are given by a commander in chief.&#8221;<span id="more-70660"></span></p>
<h2>FREEDOM OF THE PRESS</h2>
<p>President Trump has sued a number of U.S. news outlets, including <strong>60 Minutes</strong>, <strong>CNN</strong>, <strong>The Washington Post</strong>, <strong>The New York Times</strong> and other smaller media organizations for unflattering coverage.</p>
<p>In a $10 billion lawsuit against 60 Minutes and its parent <strong>Paramount</strong>, Trump claims they selectively edited an interview with former <strong>Vice President Kamala Harris</strong> prior to the 2024 election. The TV news show last month published transcripts of the interview at the heart of the dispute, but Paramount is <a href="https://apnews.com/article/cbs-60-minutes-lawsuit-trump-pelley-58339cc1a1eb52739bb365e2e8c6d8bc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reportedly considering a settlement</a> to avoid potentially damaging its chances of winning the administration&#8217;s approval for a pending multibillion-dollar merger.</p>
<p>The president <a href="https://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/crime-and-courts/2025/02/25/dismissal-sought-donald-trump-lawsuit-pollster-ann-selzer-des-moines-register-iowa-poll/79442387007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sued The Des Moines Register</a> and its parent company, <strong>Gannett</strong>, for publishing a poll showing Trump trailing Harris in the 2024 presidential election in Iowa (a state that went for Trump). The POTUS also is <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/07/21/trump-libel-suit-pulitzer-prize-00169975" target="_blank" rel="noopener">suing the Pulitzer Prize board</a> over 2018 awards given to The New York Times and The Washington Post for their coverage of purported Russian interference in the 2016 election.</p>
<p>Whether or not any of the president&#8217;s lawsuits against news organizations have merit or succeed is almost beside the point. The strategy behind suing the media is to make reporters and newsrooms think twice about criticizing or challenging the president and his administration. The president also knows some media outlets will find it more expedient to settle.</p>
<p>Trump also sued <strong>ABC News</strong> and <strong>George Stephanopoulos</strong> for stating that the president had been found liable for &#8220;rape&#8221; in a civil case [Trump was found liable of sexually abusing and defaming E. Jean Carroll]. ABC parent <strong>Disney</strong> settled that claim by agreeing to donate $15 million to the Trump Presidential Library.</p>
<p>Following the attack on the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021, <strong>Facebook</strong> blocked President Trump&#8217;s account. Trump sued <strong>Meta</strong>, and after the president&#8217;s victory in 2024 Meta <a class="sc-19cc8fd2-0 kspHIT" href="https://www.wsj.com/us-news/law/trump-signs-agreement-calling-for-meta-to-pay-25-million-to-settle-suit-6f734c8c?mod=article_inline" target="_blank" rel="noopener" aria-label="Go to https://www.wsj.com/us-news/law/trump-signs-agreement-calling-for-meta-to-pay-25-million-to-settle-suit-6f734c8c?mod=article_inline">settled</a> and agreed to pay Trump $25 million: $22 million would go to his presidential library, and the rest to legal fees. <strong>Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg</strong> also announced Facebook and Instagram would <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/07/tech/meta-censorship-moderation/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">get rid of fact-checkers</a> and rely instead on reader-submitted &#8220;community notes&#8221; to debunk disinformation on the social media platform.</p>
<p><strong>Brendan Carr</strong>, the president&#8217;s pick to run the <strong>Federal Communications Commission</strong> (FCC), has pledged to &#8220;dismantle the censorship cartel and restore free speech rights for everyday Americans.&#8221; But on January 22, 2025, the FCC reopened complaints against ABC, <strong>CBS</strong> and <strong>NBC</strong> over their coverage of the 2024 election. The previous FCC chair had dismissed the complaints as attacks on the First Amendment and an attempt to weaponize the agency for political purposes.</p>
<p>According to Reuters, the complaints call for an investigation into how ABC News moderated the pre-election TV debate between Trump and Biden, and appearances of then-Vice President Harris on 60 Minutes and on NBC&#8217;s &#8220;Saturday Night Live.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since then, the FCC has opened investigations into <strong>NPR</strong> and <strong>PBS</strong>, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/01/30/nx-s1-5281162/fcc-npr-pbs-investigation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">alleging</a> that they are breaking sponsorship rules. The <strong>Center for Democracy &amp; Technology </strong>(CDT), a think tank based in Washington, D.C., <a href="https://cdt.org/insights/when-it-comes-to-free-speech-the-trump-administration-should-follow-its-own-order/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">noted</a> that the FCC is also investigating <strong>KCBS</strong> in San Francisco for reporting on the location of federal immigration authorities.</p>
<p>&#8220;Even if these investigations are ultimately closed without action, the mere fact of opening them – and the implicit threat to the news stations’ license to operate – can have the effect of deterring the press from news coverage that the Administration dislikes,&#8221; the CDT&#8217;s <strong>Kate Ruane</strong> observed.</p>
<p>Trump has repeatedly threatened to &#8220;open up&#8221; libel laws, with the goal of making it easier to sue media organizations for unfavorable coverage. But this week, the U.S. Supreme Court <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/supreme-court-thwarts-trump-dream-of-opening-up-libel-laws.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">declined to hear a challenge</a> brought by Trump donor and Las Vegas casino magnate Steve Wynn to overturn the landmark 1964 decision in <em>New York Times v. Sullivan</em>, which insulates the press from libel suits over good-faith criticism of public figures.</p>
<p>The president also has insisted on picking which reporters and news outlets should be allowed to cover White House events and participate in the press pool that trails the president. He barred the <strong>Associated Press</strong> from the White House and Air Force One over their refusal to call the Gulf of Mexico by another name.</p>
<p>And the Defense Department has ordered a number of top media outlets <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/pentagon-doubles-number-news-outlets-rotate-out-office-spaces-2025-02-08/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to vacate their spots at the Pentagon</a>, including CNN, The Hill, The Washington Post, The New York Times, NBC News, Politico and National Public Radio.</p>
<p>&#8220;Incoming media outlets include the New York Post, Breitbart, the Washington Examiner, the Free Press, the Daily Caller, Newsmax, the Huffington Post and One America News Network, most of whom are seen as conservative or favoring Republican President Donald Trump,&#8221; Reuters reported.</p>
<h2>FREEDOM OF SPEECH</h2>
<p>Shortly after Trump took office again in January 2025, the administration began circulating <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/03/07/us/trump-federal-agencies-websites-words-dei.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lists of hundreds of words</a> that government staff and agencies shall not use in their reports and communications.</p>
<p>The Brookings Institution <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/the-us-government-data-purge-is-a-loss-for-policymaking-and-research/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notes</a> that in moving to comply with this anti-speech directive, federal agencies have purged countless taxpayer-funded data sets from a swathe of government websites, including data on crime, sexual orientation, gender, education, climate, and global development.</p>
<p><strong>The New York Times</strong> reports that in the past two months, hundreds of terabytes of digital resources analyzing data have been taken off government websites.</p>
<p>&#8220;While in many cases the underlying data still exists, the tools that make it possible for the public and researchers to use that data have been removed,&#8221; The Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/21/climate/government-websites-climate-environment-data.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>.</p>
<p>On Jan. 27, Trump issued <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/documents/deb7af80-48b6-4b8a-8bfa-3d84fd7c3ec8.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a memo</a> (PDF) that paused all federally funded programs pending a review of those programs for alignment with the administration&#8217;s priorities. Among those was ensuring that no funding goes toward advancing &#8220;Marxist equity, transgenderism, and green new deal social engineering policies.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to the CDT, this order is a blatant attempt to force government grantees to cease engaging in speech that the current administration dislikes, including speech about the benefits of diversity, climate change, and LGBTQ issues.</p>
<p>&#8220;The First Amendment does not permit the government to discriminate against grantees because it does not like some of the viewpoints they espouse,&#8221; the CDT&#8217;s Ruane wrote. &#8220;Indeed, those groups that are challenging the constitutionality of the order argued as much in their complaint, and have won an injunction blocking its implementation.&#8221;</p>
<p>On January 20, the same day Trump issued an executive order on free speech, the president also issued an executive order titled “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/reevaluating-and-realigning-united-states-foreign-aid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reevaluating and Realigning United States Foreign Aid</a>,” which froze funding for programs run by the <strong>U.S. Agency for International Development</strong> (USAID). Among those were programs designed to empower civil society and human rights groups, journalists and others responding to digital repression and Internet shutdowns.</p>
<p>According to the <strong>Electronic Frontier Foundation</strong> (EFF), this includes many freedom technologies that use cryptography, fight censorship, protect freedom of speech, privacy and anonymity for millions of people around the world.</p>
<p>&#8220;While the State Department has issued some limited waivers, so far those waivers do not seem to cover the open source internet freedom technologies,&#8221; the EFF <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/01/executive-order-state-department-sideswipes-freedom-tools-threatens-censorship" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> about the USAID disruptions. &#8220;As a result, many of these projects have to stop or severely curtail their work, lay off talented workers, and stop or slow further development.&#8221;</p>
<p>On March 14, the president signed <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/continuing-the-reduction-of-the-federal-bureaucracy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">another executive order</a> that effectively gutted the <strong>U.S. Agency for Global Media</strong> (USAGM), which oversees or funds media outlets including <strong>Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty</strong> and <strong>Voice of America</strong> (VOA). The USAGM also oversees <strong>Radio Free Asia</strong>, which supporters say has been one of the most reliable tools used by the government to combat Chinese propaganda.</p>
<p>But this week, <strong>U.S. District Court Judge Royce Lamberth</strong>, a Reagan appointee, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/03/26/nx-s1-5341321/trump-radio-free-europe-radio-liberty-restraining-order" target="_blank" rel="noopener">temporarily blocked USAGM&#8217;s closure</a> by the administration.</p>
<p>“RFE/RL has, for decades, operated as one of the organizations that Congress has statutorily designated to carry out this policy,” Lamberth <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.278524/gov.uscourts.dcd.278524.14.0.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote in a 10-page opinion</a>. “The leadership of USAGM cannot, with one sentence of reasoning offering virtually no explanation, force RFE/RL to shut down — even if the President has told them to do so.”</p>
<h2>FREEDOM OF RELIGION</h2>
<p>The Trump administration <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2025/01/21/statement-dhs-spokesperson-directives-expanding-law-enforcement-and-ending-abuse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rescinded a decades-old policy</a> that instructed officers not to take immigration enforcement actions in or near &#8220;sensitive&#8221; or &#8220;protected&#8221; places, such as churches, schools, and hospitals.</p>
<p>That directive was immediately challenged in a case brought by a group of Quakers, Baptists and Sikhs, who argued the policy reversal was keeping people from attending services for fear of being arrested on civil immigration violations. On Feb. 24, a federal judge agreed and <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2025/02/24/judge-blocks-immigration-enforcement-churches/80043880007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blocked</a> ICE agents from entering churches or targeting migrants nearby.</p>
<p>The president&#8217;s executive order allegedly addressing antisemitism came with <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/01/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-takes-forceful-and-unprecedented-steps-to-combat-anti-semitism/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a fact sheet</a> that described college campuses as &#8220;infested&#8221; with &#8220;terrorists&#8221; and &#8220;jihadists.&#8221; Multiple faith groups expressed alarm over the order, saying it attempts to <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/03/20/nx-s1-5326047/kenneth-stern-antimsietim-executive-order-free-speech" target="_blank" rel="noopener">weaponize antisemitism</a> and promote &#8220;<a href="https://www.ucc.org/faith-that-calls-for-welcome-confronts-the-harshest-anti-immigrant-policies-in-modern-u-s-history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dehumanizing anti-immigrant policies.</a>&#8221;</p>
<p>The president also <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-national-prayer-breakfast-30ff6f55a2e3c7b8643a15e7b158537d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the creation of a &#8220;Task Force to Eradicate Anti-Christian Bias,&#8221; to be led by Attorney General Pam Bondi. Never mind that Christianity is easily the largest faith in America and that Christians are well-represented in Congress.</p>
<p>The <strong>Rev. Paul Brandeis Raushenbush</strong>, a Baptist minister and head of the progressive <strong>Interfaith Alliance</strong>, issued a statement accusing Trump of hypocrisy in claiming to champion religion by creating the task force.</p>
<p>“From allowing immigration raids in churches, to targeting faith-based charities, to suppressing religious diversity, the Trump Administration’s aggressive government overreach is infringing on religious freedom in a way we haven’t seen for generations,” Raushenbush said.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.au.org/the-latest/press/task-force-anti-christian-bias-trump/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> from <strong>Americans United for Separation of Church and State</strong> said the task force could lead to religious persecution of those with other faiths.</p>
<p>&#8220;Rather than protecting religious beliefs, this task force will misuse religious freedom to justify bigotry, discrimination, and the subversion of our civil rights laws,&#8221; said Rachel Laser, the group&#8217;s president and CEO.</p>
<p>Where is President Trump going with all these blatant attacks on the First Amendment? The president has made no secret of his affection for autocratic leaders and &#8220;strongmen&#8221; around the world, and he is particularly enamored with Hungary&#8217;s far-right <strong>Prime Minister Viktor Orbán</strong>, who has visited Trump&#8217;s Mar-a-Lago resort twice in the past year.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/trumps-press-freedom-hungary-orban/682060/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">March 15 essay</a> in The Atlantic by Hungarian investigative journalist <strong>András Pethő</strong> recounts how Orbán rose to power by consolidating control over the courts, and by building his own media universe while simultaneously placing a stranglehold on the independent press.</p>
<p>&#8220;As I watch from afar what’s happening to the free press in the United States during the first weeks of Trump’s second presidency — the verbal bullying, the legal harassment, the buckling by media owners in the face of threats — it all looks very familiar,&#8221; Pethő wrote. &#8220;The MAGA authorities have learned Orbán’s lessons well.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/how-each-pillar-of-the-1st-amendment-is-under-attack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>220</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When Getting Phished Puts You in Mortal Danger</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/when-getting-phished-puts-you-in-mortal-danger/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/when-getting-phished-puts-you-in-mortal-danger/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 16:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia's War on Ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artem Tamoian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DuckDuckGo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Russia legion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Volunteer Corps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stark Industries Solutions Ltd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yandex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many successful phishing attacks result in a financial loss or malware infection. But falling for some phishing scams, like those currently targeting Russians searching online for organizations that are fighting the Kremlin war machine, can cost you your freedom or your life.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many successful phishing attacks result in a financial loss or malware infection. But falling for some phishing scams, like those currently targeting Russians searching online for organizations that are fighting the Kremlin war machine, can cost you your freedom or your life.</p>
<div id="attachment_70811" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70811" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70811" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/legionlibertyarmy.png" alt="" width="750" height="420" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/legionlibertyarmy.png 1430w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/legionlibertyarmy-768x430.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/legionlibertyarmy-782x437.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70811" class="wp-caption-text">The real website of the Ukrainian paramilitary group &#8220;Freedom of Russia&#8221; legion. The text has been machine-translated from Russian.</p></div>
<p>Researchers at the security firm <strong>Silent Push</strong> mapped a network of several dozen phishing domains that spoof the recruitment websites of Ukrainian paramilitary groups, as well as Ukrainian government intelligence sites.</p>
<p>The website <strong>legiohliberty[.]army</strong> features a carbon copy of the homepage for the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_Russia_Legion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Freedom of Russia Legion</a> (a.k.a. &#8220;Free Russia Legion&#8221;), a three-year-old Ukraine-based paramilitary unit made up of Russian citizens who oppose Vladimir Putin and his invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>The phony version of that website copies the legitimate site &#8212; <strong>legionliberty[.]army &#8212; </strong>providing an interactive <strong>Google Form</strong> where interested applicants can share their contact and personal details. The form asks visitors to provide their name, gender, age, email address and/or Telegram handle, country, citizenship, experience in the armed forces; political views; motivations for joining; and any bad habits.</p>
<p>&#8220;Participation in such anti-war actions is considered illegal in the Russian Federation, and participating citizens are regularly charged and arrested,&#8221; Silent Push wrote in a report released today. &#8220;All observed campaigns had similar traits and shared a common objective: collecting personal information from site-visiting victims. Our team believes it is likely that this campaign is the work of either Russian Intelligence Services or a threat actor with similarly aligned motives.&#8221;</p>
<p>Silent Push&#8217;s <strong>Zach Edwards</strong> said the fake Legion Liberty site shared multiple connections with <strong>rusvolcorps[.]net</strong>. That domain mimics the recruitment page for a Ukrainian far-right paramilitary group called the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_Volunteer_Corps" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Russian Volunteer Corps</a> (rusvolcorps[.]com), and uses a similar Google Forms page to collect information from would-be members.</p>
<p>Other domains Silent Push connected to the phishing scheme include: <strong>ciagov[.]icu</strong>, which mirrors the content on the official website of the <strong>U.S. Central Intelligence Agency</strong>; and <strong>hochuzhitlife[.]com</strong>, which spoofs the <strong>Ministry of Defense of Ukraine &amp; General Directorate of Intelligence</strong> (whose actual domain is <strong>hochuzhit[.]com</strong>).</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-70814" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/recruit-form.png" alt="" width="749" height="775" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/recruit-form.png 790w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/recruit-form-768x794.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/recruit-form-782x809.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>According to Edwards, there are no signs that these phishing sites are being advertised via email. Rather, it appears those responsible are promoting them by manipulating the search engine results shown when someone searches for one of these anti-Putin organizations.</p>
<p>In August 2024, security researcher <strong>Artem Tamoian</strong> posted <a href="https://x.com/artemtam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on Twitter/X</a> about how he received startlingly different results when he searched for &#8220;Freedom of Russia legion&#8221; in Russia&#8217;s largest domestic search engine <strong>Yandex</strong> versus Google.com. The top result returned by Google was the legion&#8217;s actual website, while the first result on Yandex was a phishing page targeting the group.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think at least some of them are surely promoted via search,&#8221; Tamoian said of the phishing domains. &#8220;My first thread on that accuses Yandex, but apart from Yandex those websites are consistently ranked above legitimate in DuckDuckGo and Bing. Initially, I didn&#8217;t realize the scale of it. They keep appearing to this day.&#8221;<span id="more-70785"></span></p>
<p>Tamoian, a native Russian who left the country in 2019, is the founder of the cyber investigation platform <a href="https://malfors.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">malfors.com</a>. He recently discovered two other sites impersonating the Ukrainian paramilitary groups &#8212; <strong>legionliberty[.]world</strong> and <strong>rusvolcorps[.]ru</strong> &#8212; and reported both to Cloudflare. When Cloudflare responded by blocking the sites with a phishing warning, the real Internet address of these sites <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/rusvolcorps-stark.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was exposed</a> as belonging to a known &#8220;bulletproof hosting&#8221; network called <strong>Stark Industries Solutions Ltd</strong>.</p>
<p>Stark Industries Solutions appeared two weeks before Russia invaded Ukraine in February 2022, materializing out of nowhere with hundreds of thousands of Internet addresses in its stable &#8212; many of them originally assigned to Russian government organizations. In May 2024, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-an-iron-hammer-in-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published a deep dive on Stark</a>, which has repeatedly been used to host infrastructure for distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks, phishing, malware and disinformation campaigns from Russian intelligence agencies and pro-Kremlin hacker groups.</p>
<p>In March 2023, Russia’s Supreme Court designated the Freedom of Russia legion as a terrorist organization, meaning that Russians caught communicating with the group could face between 10 and 20 years in prison.</p>
<p>Tamoian said those searching online for information about these paramilitary groups have become easy prey for Russian security services.</p>
<p>&#8220;I started looking into those phishing websites, because I kept stumbling upon news that someone gets arrested for trying to join [the] Ukrainian Army or for trying to help them,&#8221; Tamoian told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;I have also seen reports [of] FSB contacting people impersonating Ukrainian officers, as well as using fake Telegram bots, so I thought fake websites might be an option as well.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70810" style="width: 622px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70810" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70810" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/legion-arrests.png" alt="" width="612" height="802" /><p id="caption-attachment-70810" class="wp-caption-text">Search results showing news articles about people in Russia being sentenced to lengthy prison terms for attempting to aid Ukrainian paramilitary groups.</p></div>
<p>Tamoian said <a href="https://en.zona.media/article/2024/10/15/phish-trl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports surface regularly in Russia</a> about people being arrested for trying carry out an action requested by a &#8220;Ukrainian recruiter,&#8221; with the courts unfailingly imposing harsh sentences regardless of the defendant’s age.</p>
<p>&#8220;This keeps happening regularly, but usually there are no details about how exactly the person gets caught,&#8221; he said. &#8220;All cases related to state treason [and] terrorism are classified, so there are barely any details.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tamoian said while he has no direct evidence linking any of the reported arrests and convictions to these phishing sites, he is certain the sites are part of a larger campaign by the Russian government.</p>
<p>&#8220;Considering that they keep them alive and keep spawning more, I assume it might be an efficient thing,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They are on top of DuckDuckGo and Yandex, so it unfortunately works.&#8221;</p>
<p>Further reading: Silent Push report, <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/russian-intelligence-phishing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Russian Intelligence Targeting its Citizens and Informants</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/when-getting-phished-puts-you-in-mortal-danger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arrests in Tap-to-Pay Scheme Powered by Phishing</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/arrests-in-tap-to-pay-scheme-powered-by-phishing/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/arrests-in-tap-to-pay-scheme-powered-by-phishing/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 19:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple Pay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bernie Lyon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSIS Security Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Merrill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SecAlliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tap-to-pay fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Z-NFC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Authorities in at least two U.S. states last week independently announced arrests of Chinese nationals accused of perpetrating a novel form of tap-to-pay fraud using mobile devices. Details released by authorities so far indicate the mobile wallets being used by the scammers were created through online phishing scams, and that the accused were relying on a custom Android app to relay tap-to-pay transactions from mobile devices located in China.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in at least two U.S. states last week independently announced arrests of Chinese nationals accused of perpetrating a novel form of tap-to-pay fraud using mobile devices. Details released by authorities so far indicate the mobile wallets being used by the scammers were created through online phishing scams, and that the accused were relying on a custom Android app to relay tap-to-pay transactions from mobile devices located in China.</p>
<div id="attachment_70773" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70773" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70773" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/kcso-taptopay.png" alt="" width="748" height="413" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/kcso-taptopay.png 903w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/kcso-taptopay-768x424.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/kcso-taptopay-782x431.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70773" class="wp-caption-text">Image: WLVT-8.</p></div>
<p>Authorities in Knoxville, Tennessee last week <a href="https://knoxsheriff.org/tap-2-pay-fraud-scheme-bust/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> they arrested 11 Chinese nationals accused of buying tens of thousands of dollars worth of gift cards at local retailers with mobile wallets created through online phishing scams. The Knox County Sheriff&#8217;s office said the arrests are considered the first in the nation for a new type of tap-to-pay fraud.</p>
<p>Responding to questions about what makes this scheme so remarkable, Knox County said that while it appears the fraudsters are simply buying gift cards, in fact they are using multiple transactions to purchase various gift cards and are plying their scam from state to state.</p>
<p>&#8220;These offenders have been traveling nationwide, using stolen credit card information to purchase gift cards and launder funds,&#8221; Knox County Chief Deputy <strong>Bernie Lyon</strong> wrote. &#8220;During Monday’s operation, we recovered gift cards valued at over $23,000, all bought with unsuspecting victims’ information.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked for specifics about the mobile devices seized from the suspects, Lyon said &#8220;tap-to-pay fraud involves a group <em>utilizing Android phones to conduct Apple Pay transactions</em> utilizing stolen or compromised credit/debit card information,&#8221; [emphasis added].</p>
<p>Lyon declined to offer additional specifics about the mechanics of the scam, citing an ongoing investigation.</p>
<p><strong>Ford Merrill</strong> works in security research at <a href="https://www.secalliance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SecAlliance</a>, a <a href="https://www.csis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSIS Security Group</a> company. Merrill said there aren&#8217;t many valid use cases for Android phones to transmit Apple Pay transactions. That is, he said, unless they are running a custom Android app that KrebsOnSecurity wrote about last month as part of <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a deep dive into the operations of China-based phishing cartels</a> that are breathing new life into the payment card fraud industry (a.k.a. &#8220;carding&#8221;).</p>
<p>How are these China-based phishing groups obtaining stolen payment card data and then loading it onto Google and Apple phones? It all starts with phishing.</p>
<p>If you own a mobile phone, the chances are excellent that at some point in the past two years it has received at least one phishing message that spoofs the <strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong> to supposedly collect some outstanding delivery fee, or an SMS that pretends to be a local toll road operator warning of a delinquent toll fee.</p>
<p>These messages are being sent through sophisticated phishing kits sold by several cybercriminals based in mainland China. And they are not traditional SMS phishing or “<strong>smishing</strong>” messages, as they bypass the mobile networks entirely. Rather, the missives are sent through the <strong>Apple iMessage</strong> service and through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rich_Communication_Services" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RCS</a>, the functionally equivalent technology on <strong>Google</strong> phones.</p>
<p>People who enter their payment card data at one of these sites will be told their financial institution needs to verify the small transaction by sending a one-time passcode to the customer’s mobile device. In reality, that code will be sent by the victim’s financial institution in response to a request by the fraudsters to link the phished card data to a mobile wallet.</p>
<p>If the victim then provides that one-time code, the phishers will link the card data to a new mobile wallet from Apple or Google, loading the wallet onto a mobile phone that the scammers control. These phones are then loaded with multiple stolen wallets (often between 5-10 per device) and sold in bulk to scammers on Telegram.</p>
<div id="attachment_70436" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70436" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70436" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png" alt="" width="750" height="567" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png 1160w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-768x581.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-782x591.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70436" class="wp-caption-text">An image from the Telegram channel for a popular Chinese smishing kit vendor shows 10 mobile phones for sale, each loaded with 5-7 digital wallets from different financial institutions.</p></div>
<p>Merrill found that at least one of the Chinese phishing groups sells an Android app called “<strong>Z-NFC</strong>” that can relay a valid NFC transaction to anywhere in the world. The user simply waves their phone at a local payment terminal that accepts Apple or Google pay, and the app relays an NFC transaction over the Internet from a phone in China.</p>
<p>&#8220;I would be shocked if this wasn&#8217;t the NFC relay app,&#8221; Merrill said, concerning the arrested suspects in Tennessee.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ekqZjPAxB4c?si=hYLqGPIBrNthAg9_" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>Merrill said the Z-NFC software can work from anywhere in the world, and that one phishing gang offers the software for $500 a month.</p>
<p>&#8220;It can relay both NFC enabled tap-to-pay as well as any digital wallet,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;They even have 24-hour support.&#8221;<span id="more-70697"></span></p>
<p>On March 16, the ABC affiliate in Sacramento (<strong>ABC10</strong>), Calif. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dUjaj0d1T6A" target="_blank" rel="noopener">aired a segment</a> about two Chinese nationals who were arrested after using an app to run stolen credit cards at a local Target store. The news story quoted investigators saying the men were trying to buy gift cards using a mobile app that cycled through more than 80 stolen payment cards.</p>
<p>ABC10 reported that while most of those transactions were declined, the suspects still made off with $1,400 worth of gift cards. After their arrests, both men reportedly admitted that they were being paid $250 a day to conduct the fraudulent transactions.</p>
<p>Merrill said it&#8217;s not unusual for fraud groups to advertise this kind of work on social media networks, including TikTok.</p>
<p>A <strong>CBS News</strong> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/sacramento/news/sacramento-county-credit-card-scheme-arrest-chinese-nationals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">story</a> on the Sacramento arrests said one of the suspects tried to use 42 separate bank cards, but that 32 were declined. Even so, the man still was reportedly able to spend $855 in the transactions.</p>
<p>Likewise, the suspect&#8217;s alleged accomplice tried 48 transactions on separate cards, finding success 11 times and spending $633, CBS reported.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s interesting that so many of the cards were declined,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;One reason this might be is that banks are getting better at detecting this type of fraud. The other could be that the cards were already used and so they were already flagged for fraud even before these guys had a chance to use them. So there could be some element of just sending these guys out to stores to see if it works, and if not they&#8217;re on their own.&#8221;</p>
<p>Merrill&#8217;s investigation into the Telegram sales channels for these China-based phishing gangs shows their phishing sites are actively manned by fraudsters who sit in front of giant racks of Apple and Google phones that are used to send the spam and respond to replies in real time.</p>
<p>In other words, the phishing websites are powered by real human operators as long as new messages are being sent. Merrill said the criminals appear to send only a few dozen messages at a time, likely because completing the scam takes manual work by the human operators in China. After all, most one-time codes used for mobile wallet provisioning are generally only good for a few minutes before they expire.</p>
<p>For more on how these China-based mobile phishing groups operate, check out <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How Phished Data Turns Into Apple and Google Wallets</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_70435" style="width: 528px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70435" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70435" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phonesashtray.png" alt="" width="518" height="688" /><p id="caption-attachment-70435" class="wp-caption-text">The ashtray says: You&#8217;ve been phishing all night.</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/arrests-in-tap-to-pay-scheme-powered-by-phishing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DOGE to Fired CISA Staff: Email Us Your Personal Data</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/doge-to-fired-cisa-staff-email-us-your-personal-data/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/doge-to-fired-cisa-staff-email-us-your-personal-data/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 01:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christopher Stanley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fannie Mae]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hunter Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jake Williams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kash Patel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Masnick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national security agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBC News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Joyce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shane Harris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starlink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Techdirt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Cybersecurity & Infrastructure Security Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A message posted on Monday to the homepage of the U.S. Cybersecurity &#038; Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) is the latest exhibit in the Trump administration's continued disregard for basic cybersecurity protections. The message instructed recently-fired CISA employees to get in touch so they can be rehired and then immediately placed on leave, asking employees to send their Social Security number or date of birth in a password-protected email attachment -- presumably with the password needed to view the file included in the body of the email.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A message posted on Monday to the homepage of the <strong>U.S. Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA) is the latest exhibit in the Trump administration&#8217;s continued disregard for basic cybersecurity protections. The message instructed recently-fired CISA employees to get in touch so they can be rehired and then immediately placed on leave, asking employees to send their Social Security number or date of birth in a password-protected email attachment &#8212; presumably with the password needed to view the file included in the body of the email.</p>
<div id="attachment_70732" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70732" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70732" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cisa-resinstatement.png" alt="" width="747" height="371" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cisa-resinstatement.png 1370w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cisa-resinstatement-768x381.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cisa-resinstatement-782x388.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70732" class="wp-caption-text">The homepage of cisa.gov as it appeared on Monday and Tuesday afternoon.</p></div>
<p>On March 13, a Maryland district court judge <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/fired-cisa-probationary-employees-reinstated/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ordered</a> the Trump administration to reinstate more than 130 probationary CISA employees who were fired last month. On Monday, the administration announced that those dismissed employees would be reinstated but placed on paid administrative leave. They are among nearly 25,000 fired federal workers who are in the process of being rehired.</p>
<p>A notice covering the CISA homepage said the administration is making every effort to contact those who were unlawfully fired in mid-February.</p>
<p>&#8220;Please provide a password protected attachment that provides your full name, your dates of employment (including date of termination), and one other identifying factor such as date of birth or social security number,&#8221; the message reads. &#8220;Please, to the extent that it is available, attach any termination notice.&#8221;</p>
<p>The message didn&#8217;t specify how affected CISA employees should share the password for any attached files, so the implicit expectation is that employees should just include the plaintext password in their message.</p>
<p>Email is about as secure as a postcard sent through the mail, because anyone who manages to intercept the missive anywhere along its path of delivery can likely read it. In security terms, that&#8217;s the equivalent of encrypting sensitive data while also attaching the secret key needed to view the information.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, a great many antivirus and security scanners have trouble inspecting password-protected files, meaning the administration&#8217;s instructions are likely to increase the risk that malware submitted by cybercriminals could be accepted and opened by U.S. government employees.</p>
<p>The message in the screenshot above was removed from the CISA homepage Tuesday evening and replaced with a much shorter notice directing former CISA employees to contact a specific email address. But a slightly different version of the same message originally posted to CISA&#8217;s website <a href="https://www.uscis.gov/newsroom/alerts/uscis-probationary-reinstatements" target="_blank" rel="noopener">still exists</a> at the website for the <strong>U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</strong>, which likewise instructs those fired employees who wish to be rehired and put on leave to send a password-protected email attachment with sensitive personal data.</p>
<div id="attachment_70736" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70736" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70736" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/uscis-probation.png" alt="" width="750" height="490" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/uscis-probation.png 1094w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/uscis-probation-768x502.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/uscis-probation-782x511.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70736" class="wp-caption-text">A message from the White House to fired federal employees at the U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services instructs recipients to email personal information in a password-protected attachment.</p></div>
<p>This is hardly the first example of the administration discarding Security 101 practices in the name of expediency. Last month, the <strong>Central Intelligence Agency</strong> (CIA) sent an unencrypted email to the White House with the first names and first letter of the last names of recently hired CIA officers who might be easy to fire.</p>
<p>As cybersecurity journalist <strong>Shane Harris</strong> <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/02/doge-intelligence-agencies-harm/681667/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">noted</a> in <em>The Atlantic</em>, even those fragments of information could be useful to foreign spies.</p>
<p>&#8220;Over the weekend, a former senior CIA official showed me the steps by which a foreign adversary who knew only his first name and last initial could have managed to identify him from the single line of the congressional record where his full name was published more than 20 years ago, when he became a member of the Foreign Service,&#8221; Harris wrote. &#8220;The former official was undercover at the time as a State Department employee. If a foreign government had known even part of his name from a list of confirmed CIA officers, his cover would have been blown.&#8221;</p>
<p>The White House has also fired at least 100 intelligence staffers from the <strong>National Security Agency </strong>(NSA), reportedly for using an internal NSA chat tool <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/25/us/politics/gabbard-nsa-firing-explicit-chat.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to discuss their personal lives and politics</a>. Testifying before the House Select Committee on the Communist Party earlier this month, the NSA&#8217;s former top cybersecurity official said the Trump administration&#8217;s attempts to mass fire probationary federal employees will be &#8220;devastating&#8221; to U.S. cybersecurity operations.</p>
<p><strong>Rob Joyce</strong>, who spent 34 years at the NSA, told Congress how important those employees are in sustaining an aggressive stance against China in cyberspace.</p>
<p>&#8220;At my former agency, remarkable technical talent was recruited into developmental programs that provided intensive unique training and hands-on experience to cultivate vital skills,” Joyce <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/joyce-china-probationary-firings-devastating-congress/?utm_campaign=CyberScoop%20-%20Editorial&amp;utm_content=326616240&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=linkedin&amp;hss_channel=lcp-11061843" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told the panel</a>. &#8220;Eliminating probationary employees will destroy a pipeline of top talent responsible for hunting and eradicating [Chinese] threats.&#8221;</p>
<p>Both the message to fired CISA workers and DOGE&#8217;s ongoing efforts to bypass vetted government networks for a faster Wi-Fi signal are emblematic of this administration&#8217;s overall approach to even basic security measures: To go around them, or just pretend they don&#8217;t exist <a href="https://fs.blog/chestertons-fence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for a good reason</a>.</p>
<p>On Monday, <em>The New York Times</em> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/17/us/politics/elon-musk-starlink-white-house.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that U.S. Secret Service agents at the White House were briefly on alert last month when a trusted captain of Elon Musk&#8217;s &#8220;Department of Government Efficiency&#8221; (DOGE) visited the roof of the Eisenhower building inside the White House compound &#8212; to see about setting up a dish to receive satellite Internet access directly from Musk&#8217;s <strong>Starlink</strong> service.</p>
<p>The White House press secretary told The Times that Starlink had &#8220;donated&#8221; the service and that the gift had been vetted by the lawyer overseeing ethics issues in the White House Counsel’s Office. The White House claims the service is necessary because its wireless network is too slow.</p>
<p><strong>Jake Williams</strong>, vice president for research and development at the cybersecurity consulting firm <strong>Hunter Strategy</strong>, told The Times &#8220;it&#8217;s super rare” to install Starlink or another internet provider as a replacement for existing government infrastructure that has been vetted and secured.</p>
<p>&#8220;I can’t think of a time that I have heard of that,&#8221; Williams said. &#8220;It introduces another attack point,” Williams said. &#8220;But why introduce that risk?&#8221;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, <strong>NBC News</strong> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/elon-musk/elon-musk-starlink-growing-footprint-federal-government-rcna195400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported on March 7</a> that Starlink is expanding its footprint across the federal government.</p>
<p>&#8220;Multiple federal agencies are exploring the idea of adopting SpaceX’s Starlink for internet access — and at least one agency, the General Services Administration (GSA), has done so at the request of Musk’s staff, according to someone who worked at the GSA last month and is familiar with its network operations — despite a vow by Musk and Trump to slash the overall federal budget,&#8221; NBC wrote.<span id="more-70729"></span></p>
<p>The longtime Musk employee who encountered the Secret Service on the roof in the White House complex was <strong>Christopher Stanley</strong>, the 33-year-old senior director for security engineering at <strong>X</strong> and principal security engineer at SpaceX.</p>
<p>On Monday, Bloomberg broke the news that Stanley had been tapped for a seat on the board of directors at the mortgage giant <strong>Fannie Mae</strong>. Stanley was added to the board alongside newly confirmed Federal Housing Finance Agency director <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Pulte" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bill Pulte</a>, the grandson of the late housing businessman and founder of PulteGroup &#8212; William J. Pulte.</p>
<p>In a nod to his new board role atop an agency that helps drive the nation&#8217;s $12 trillion mortgage market, Stanley retweeted a Bloomberg story about the hire with a smiley emoji and the comment &#8220;Tech Support.&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-70750" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/stanley-fannie.png" alt="" width="750" height="676" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/stanley-fannie.png 905w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/stanley-fannie-768x692.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/stanley-fannie-782x705.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>But earlier today, Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-03-19/musk-ally-stanley-abruptly-resigns-from-fannie-mae-board" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that Stanley had abruptly resigned from the Fannie board, and that details about the reason for his quick departure weren&#8217;t immediately clear. As <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/trump-2-0-brings-cuts-to-cyber-consumer-protections/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first reported here</a> last month, Stanley had a brush with celebrity on Twitter in 2015 when he leaked the user database for the DDoS-for-hire service <strong>LizardStresser</strong>, and soon faced threats of physical violence against his family.</p>
<p>My <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/01/another-lizard-arrested-lizard-lair-hacked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2015 story on that leak</a> did not name Stanley, but he exposed himself as the source by posting a video about it on his Youtube channel. A review of domain names registered by Stanley shows he went by the nickname “enKrypt,” and was the former owner of a pirated software and hacking forum called <strong>error33[.]net</strong>, as well as <strong>theC0re</strong>, a video game cheating community.</p>
<p>Stanley is one of more than 50 DOGE workers, mostly young men and women who have worked with one or more of Musk&#8217;s companies. The Trump administration remains <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/teen-on-musks-doge-team-graduated-from-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dogged by questions</a> about how many &#8212; if any &#8212; of the DOGE workers were put through the gauntlet of a thorough security background investigation before being given access to such sensitive government databases.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s largely because in one of his first executive actions after being sworn in for a second term on Jan. 20, President Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/memorandum-to-resolve-the-backlog-of-security-clearances-for-executive-office-of-the-president-personnel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">declared</a> that the security clearance process was simply too onerous and time-consuming, and that anyone so designated by the White House counsel would have full top secret/sensitive compartmented information (TS/SCI) clearances for up to six months. Translation: We <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9IG3zqvUqJY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">accepted the risk</a>, so TAH-DAH! No risk!</p>
<p>Presumably, this is the same counsel who saw no ethical concerns with Musk &#8220;donating&#8221; Starlink to the White House, or with President Trump summoning the media to film him hawking Cybertrucks and Teslas (a.k.a. &#8220;Teslers&#8221;) on the White House lawn last week.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uUntzU4Toy4?si=76K-2CkYWGNN0kYh" width="660" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>Mr. Musk&#8217;s unelected role as head of an ad hoc executive entity that is gleefully firing federal workers and feeding federal agencies into &#8220;the wood chipper&#8221; has seen his Tesla stock price plunge in recent weeks, while firebombings and other vandalism attacks on property carrying the Tesla logo are cropping up across the U.S. and overseas and driving down Tesla sales.</p>
<p>President Trump and his attorney general Pam Bondi have dubiously asserted that those responsible for attacks on Tesla dealerships are committing &#8220;domestic terrorism,&#8221; and that vandals will be prosecuted accordingly. But it&#8217;s not clear this administration would recognize a real domestic security threat if it was ensconced squarely behind the Resolute Desk.</p>
<p>Or at the pinnacle of the <strong>Federal Bureau of Investigation</strong> (FBI). <em>The Washington Post</em> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2025/02/07/patel-fbi-russia-lopatonok/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> last month that Trump&#8217;s new FBI director <strong>Kash Patel</strong> was paid $25,000 last year by a film company owned by a dual U.S. Russian citizen that has made programs promoting &#8220;deep state&#8221; conspiracy theories pushed by the Kremlin.</p>
<p>&#8220;The resulting six-part documentary appeared on Tucker Carlson’s online network, itself a reliable conduit for Kremlin propaganda,&#8221; The Post reported. &#8220;In the film, Patel made his now infamous pledge to shut down the FBI’s headquarters in Washington and &#8216;open it up as a museum to the deep state.'&#8221;</p>
<p>When the head of the FBI is promising to turn his own agency headquarters into a mocking public exhibit on the U.S. National Mall, it may seem silly to fuss over the White House&#8217;s clumsy and insulting instructions to former employees they unlawfully fired.</p>
<p>Indeed, one consistent feedback I&#8217;ve heard from a subset of readers here is something to this effect: &#8220;I used to like reading your stuff more when you weren&#8217;t writing about politics all the time.&#8221;</p>
<p>My response to that is: &#8220;Yeah, me too.&#8221; It&#8217;s not that I&#8217;m suddenly interested in writing about political matters; it&#8217;s that various actions by this administration keep intruding on my areas of coverage.</p>
<p>A less charitable interpretation of that reader comment is that anyone still giving such feedback is either dangerously uninformed, being disingenuous, or just doesn’t want to keep being reminded that they’re on the side of the villains, despite all the evidence showing it.</p>
<p>Article II of the U.S. Constitution unambiguously states that the president shall take care that the laws be faithfully executed. But almost from Day One of his second term, Mr. Trump has been acting in violation of his sworn duty as president by choosing not to enforce laws passed by Congress (TikTok ban, anyone?), by freezing funds already allocated by Congress, and most recently by flouting a federal court order while simultaneously <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/19/us/politics/trump-deportations-constitutional-crisis-impeachment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">calling for the impeachment of the judge who issued it</a>. Sworn to uphold, protect and defend The Constitution, President Trump appears to be creating new constitutional challenges with almost each passing day.</p>
<p>When Mr. Trump was voted out of office in November 2020, he turned to baseless claims of widespread &#8220;election fraud&#8221; to explain his loss &#8212; with deadly and long-lasting consequences. This time around, the rallying cry of DOGE and White House is &#8220;government fraud,&#8221; which gives the administration a certain amount of cover for its actions among a base of voters that has long sought to shrink the size and cost of government.</p>
<p>In reality, &#8220;government fraud&#8221; has become a term of derision and public scorn applied to anything or anyone the current administration doesn&#8217;t like. If DOGE and the White House were truly interested in trimming government waste, fraud and abuse, they could scarcely do better than consult the inspectors general fighting it at various federal agencies.</p>
<p>After all, the inspectors general likely know exactly where a great deal of the federal government&#8217;s fiscal skeletons are buried. Instead, Mr. Trump <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-firings-watchdogs-inspectors-general-60-minutes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">fired at least 17 inspectors general</a>, leaving the government without critical oversight of agency activities. That action is unlikely to stem government fraud; if anything, it will only encourage such activity.</p>
<p>As <em>Techdirt</em> founder <strong>Mike Masnick</strong> noted in a recent column &#8220;<a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2025/03/04/why-techdirt-is-now-a-democracy-blog-whether-we-like-it-or-not/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Why Techdirt is Now a Democracy Blog (Whether We Like it or Not)</a>,&#8221; when the very institutions that made American innovation possible are being systematically dismantled, it’s not a &#8220;political&#8221; story anymore: It’s a story about whether the environment that enabled all the other stories we cover will continue to exist.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is why tech journalism’s perspective is so crucial right now,&#8221; Masnick wrote. &#8220;We’ve spent decades documenting how technology and entrepreneurship can either strengthen or undermine democratic institutions. We understand the dangers of concentrated power in the digital age. And we’ve watched in real-time as tech leaders who once championed innovation and openness now actively work to consolidate control and dismantle the very systems that enabled their success.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But right now, the story that matters most is how the dismantling of American institutions threatens everything else we cover,&#8221; Masnick continued. &#8220;When the fundamental structures that enable innovation, protect civil liberties, and foster open dialogue are under attack, every other tech policy story becomes secondary.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/doge-to-fired-cisa-staff-email-us-your-personal-data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>89</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ClickFix: How to Infect Your PC in Three Easy Steps</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/clickfix-how-to-infect-your-pc-in-three-easy-steps/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/clickfix-how-to-infect-your-pc-in-three-easy-steps/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 22:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arctic Wolf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[booking.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ClickFix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mshta.exe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proofpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Health and Human Services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A clever malware deployment scheme first spotted in targeted attacks last year has now gone mainstream. In this scam, dubbed "ClickFix," the visitor to a hacked or malicious website is asked to distinguish themselves from bots by pressing a combination of keyboard keys that causes Microsoft Windows to download password-stealing malware.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A clever malware deployment scheme <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/this-windows-powershell-phish-has-scary-potential/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first spotted in targeted attacks last year</a> has now gone mainstream. In this scam, dubbed &#8220;<strong>ClickFix</strong>,&#8221; the visitor to a hacked or malicious website is asked to distinguish themselves from bots by pressing a combination of keyboard keys that causes <strong>Microsoft Windows</strong> to download password-stealing malware.</p>
<p>ClickFix attacks mimic the &#8220;Verify You are a Human&#8221; tests that many websites use to separate real visitors from content-scraping bots. This particular scam usually starts with a website popup that looks something like this:</p>
<div id="attachment_68856" style="width: 793px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68856" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-68856" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/verifyhuman.png" alt="" width="783" height="397" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/verifyhuman.png 783w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/verifyhuman-768x389.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 783px) 100vw, 783px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68856" class="wp-caption-text">This malware attack pretends to be a CAPTCHA intended to separate humans from bots.</p></div>
<p>Clicking the &#8220;I&#8217;m not a robot&#8221; button generates a pop-up message asking the user to take three sequential steps to prove their humanity.</p>
<div id="attachment_70703" style="width: 634px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70703" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70703 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/verifsteps.png" alt="" width="624" height="339" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/verifsteps.png 624w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/verifsteps-370x200.png 370w" sizes="(max-width: 624px) 100vw, 624px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70703" class="wp-caption-text">Executing this series of keypresses prompts Windows to download password-stealing malware.</p></div>
<p>Step 1 involves simultaneously pressing the keyboard key with the Windows icon and the letter &#8220;R,&#8221; which opens a Windows &#8220;Run&#8221; prompt that will execute any specified program that is already installed on the system.</p>
<p>Step 2 asks the user to press the &#8220;CTRL&#8221; key and the letter &#8220;V&#8221; at the same time, which pastes malicious code from the site&#8217;s virtual clipboard.</p>
<p>Step 3 — pressing the “Enter” key — causes Windows to download and launch malicious code through &#8220;<strong>mshta.exe</strong>,&#8221; a Windows program designed to run Microsoft HTML application files.</p>
<p>&#8220;This campaign delivers multiple families of commodity malware, including XWorm, Lumma stealer, VenomRAT, AsyncRAT, Danabot, and NetSupport RAT,&#8221; <strong>Microsoft</strong> wrote in <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/03/13/phishing-campaign-impersonates-booking-com-delivers-a-suite-of-credential-stealing-malware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a blog post</a> on Thursday. &#8220;Depending on the specific payload, the specific code launched through mshta.exe varies. Some samples have downloaded PowerShell, JavaScript, and portable executable (PE) content.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to Microsoft, hospitality workers are being tricked into downloading credential-stealing malware by cybercriminals impersonating <strong>Booking.com</strong>. The company said attackers have been sending malicious emails impersonating Booking.com, often referencing negative guest reviews, requests from prospective guests, or online promotion opportunities &#8212; all in a bid to convince people to step through one of these ClickFix attacks.<span id="more-70700"></span></p>
<p>In November 2024, KrebsOnSecurity reported that hundreds of hotels that use booking.com had been subject to targeted phishing attacks. Some of those lures worked, and allowed thieves to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/booking-com-phishers-may-leave-you-with-reservations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">gain control over booking.com accounts</a>. From there, they sent out phishing messages asking for financial information from people who&#8217;d just booked travel through the company&#8217;s app.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the security firm <strong>Arctic Wolf</strong> <a href="https://arcticwolf.com/resources/blog/healthcare-sector-targeted-by-fake-captcha-attack-on-hep2go-to-deliver-infostealer-malware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warned</a> about ClickFix attacks targeting people working in the healthcare sector. The company said those attacks leveraged malicious code stitched into the widely used physical therapy video site HEP2go that redirected visitors to a ClickFix prompt.</p>
<p>An <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/clickfix-attacks-sector-alert-tlpclear.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">alert</a> (PDF) released in October 2024 by the <strong>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</strong> warned that the ClickFix attack can take many forms, including fake <strong>Google Chrome</strong> error pages and popups that spoof <strong>Facebook</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_70706" style="width: 1182px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70706" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70706" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/hhs-clickfix.png" alt="" width="1172" height="745" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/hhs-clickfix.png 1172w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/hhs-clickfix-768x488.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/hhs-clickfix-782x497.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 1172px) 100vw, 1172px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70706" class="wp-caption-text">ClickFix tactic used by malicious websites impersonating Google Chrome, Facebook, PDFSimpli, and reCAPTCHA. Source: Sekoia.</p></div>
<p>The ClickFix attack &#8212; and its reliance on mshta.exe &#8212; is reminiscent of phishing techniques employed for years that hid exploits inside <strong>Microsoft Office</strong> <strong>macros</strong>. Malicious macros became such a common malware threat that Microsoft was forced to start blocking macros by default in Office documents that try to download content from the web.</p>
<p>Alas, the email security vendor <strong>Proofpoint</strong> has <a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/us/blog/threat-insight/security-brief-clickfix-social-engineering-technique-floods-threat-landscape" target="_blank" rel="noopener">documented</a> plenty of ClickFix attacks via phishing emails that include HTML attachments spoofing Microsoft Office files. When opened, the attachment displays an image of Microsoft Word document with a pop-up error message directing users to click the &#8220;Solution&#8221; or &#8220;How to Fix&#8221; button.</p>
<div id="attachment_70707" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/proofpoint-clickfix.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70707" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70707" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/proofpoint-clickfix.png" alt="" width="749" height="278" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/proofpoint-clickfix.png 1294w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/proofpoint-clickfix-768x285.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/proofpoint-clickfix-782x290.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-70707" class="wp-caption-text">HTML files containing ClickFix instructions. Examples for attachments named “Report_” (on the left) and “scan_doc_” (on the right). Image: Proofpoint.</p></div>
<p>Organizations that wish to do so can take advantage of <a href="https://m.majorgeeks.com/content/page/disable_run_command.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Group Policy restrictions</a> to prevent Windows from executing the &#8220;run&#8221; command when users hit the Windows key and the &#8220;R&#8221; key simultaneously.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/clickfix-how-to-infect-your-pc-in-three-easy-steps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>57</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft: 6 Zero-Days in March 2025 Patch Tuesday</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/microsoft-6-zero-days-in-march-2025-patch-tuesday/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/microsoft-6-zero-days-in-march-2025-patch-tuesday/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 23:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security Tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-24983]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-24984]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-24985]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-24991]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-24993]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-26633]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Filip Jurčacko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today issued more than 50 security updates for its various Windows operating systems, including fixes for a whopping six zero-day vulnerabilities that are already seeing active exploitation.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today issued more than 50 security updates for its various <strong>Windows</strong> operating systems, including fixes for a whopping <em>six zero-day vulnerabilities</em> that are already seeing active exploitation.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-60331" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png" alt="" width="749" height="496" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png 923w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-768x508.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-782x518.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>Two of the zero-day flaws include <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-24991" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-24991</a> and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-24993" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-24993&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1741811978241000&amp;usg=AOvVaw08YeX5TKKSxWlXHXx6FFHl">CVE-2025-24993</a>, both vulnerabilities in <strong>NTFS</strong>, the default file system for Windows and Windows Server. Both require the attacker to trick a target into mounting a malicious virtual hard disk. CVE-2025-24993 would lead to the possibility of local code execution, while CVE-2025-24991 could cause NTFS to disclose portions of memory.</p>
<p>Microsoft credits researchers at <strong>ESET</strong> with reporting the zero-day bug labeled <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-24983" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-24983</a>, an elevation of privilege vulnerability in older versions of Windows. ESET said the exploit was deployed via the <a href="https://www.kaspersky.com/about/press-releases/kaspersky-uncovers-pipemagic-backdoor-attacks-businesses-through-fake-chatgpt-application" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PipeMagic backdoor</a>, capable of exfiltrating data and enabling remote access to the machine.</p>
<p>ESET&#8217;s <strong>Filip</strong> <b>Jurčacko </b>said the exploit in the wild targets only older versions of Windows OS: Windows 8.1 and Server 2012 R2. Although still used by millions, security support for these products ended more than a year ago, and mainstream support ended years ago. However, ESET notes the vulnerability itself also is present in newer Windows OS versions, including <strong>Windows 10 build 1809</strong> and the still-supported <strong>Windows Server 2016</strong>.</p>
<p>Rapid7&#8217;s lead software engineer <strong>Adam Barnett</strong> said <strong>Windows 11</strong> and <strong>Server 2019</strong> onwards are not listed as receiving patches, so are presumably not vulnerable.</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s not clear why newer Windows products dodged this particular bullet,&#8221; Barnett wrote. &#8220;The Windows 32 subsystem is still presumably alive and well, since there is no apparent mention of its demise on the Windows client OS deprecated features list.&#8221;<span id="more-70681"></span></p>
<p>The zero-day flaw <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-24984" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-24984</a> is another NTFS weakness that can be exploited by inserting a malicious USB drive into a Windows computer. Barnett said Microsoft&#8217;s advisory for this bug doesn&#8217;t quite join the dots, but successful exploitation appears to mean that portions of heap memory could be improperly dumped into a log file, which could then be combed through by an attacker hungry for privileged information.</p>
<p>&#8220;A relatively low CVSSv3 base score of 4.6 reflects the practical difficulties of real-world exploitation, but a motivated attacker can sometimes achieve extraordinary results starting from the smallest of toeholds, and Microsoft does rate this vulnerability as important on its own proprietary severity ranking scale,&#8221; Barnett said.</p>
<p>Another zero-day fixed this month &#8212; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-24985" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-24985</a> &#8212; could allow attackers to install malicious code. As with the NTFS bugs, this one requires that the user mount a malicious virtual hard drive.</p>
<p>The final zero-day this month is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-26633" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-26633</a>, a weakness in the <strong>Microsoft Management Console</strong>, a component of Windows that gives system administrators a way to configure and monitor the system. Exploiting this flaw requires the target to open a malicious file.</p>
<p>This month&#8217;s bundle of patch love from Redmond also addresses six other vulnerabilities Microsoft has rated &#8220;critical,&#8221; meaning that malware or malcontents could exploit them to seize control over vulnerable PCs with no help from users.</p>
<p>Barnett observed that this is now the sixth consecutive month where Microsoft has published zero-day vulnerabilities on Patch Tuesday without evaluating any of them as critical severity at time of publication.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/forums/diary/Microsoft%20Patch%20Tuesday%3A%20March%202025/31756/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SANS Internet Storm Center</a> has a useful list of all the Microsoft patches released today, indexed by severity. Windows enterprise administrators would do well to keep an eye on <a href="http://www.askwoody.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">askwoody.com</a>, which often has the scoop on any patches causing problems. Please consider backing up your data before updating, and leave a comment below if you experience any issues applying this month&#8217;s updates.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/microsoft-6-zero-days-in-march-2025-patch-tuesday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alleged Co-Founder of Garantex Arrested in India</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/alleged-co-founder-of-garantex-arrested-in-india/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/alleged-co-founder-of-garantex-arrested-in-india/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aleksandr Mira Serda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aleksej Besciokov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elliptic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garantex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Secret Service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70662</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Authorities in India today arrested the alleged co-founder of Garantex, a cryptocurrency exchange sanctioned by the U.S. government in 2022 for facilitating tens of billions of dollars in money laundering by transnational criminal and cybercriminal organizations. Sources close to the investigation told KrebsOnSecurity the Lithuanian national Aleksej Besciokov, 46, was apprehended while vacationing on the coast of India with his family.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in India today arrested the alleged co-founder of <strong>Garantex</strong>, a cryptocurrency exchange sanctioned by the U.S. government in 2022 for facilitating tens of billions of dollars in money laundering by transnational criminal and cybercriminal organizations. Sources close to the investigation told KrebsOnSecurity the Lithuanian national <strong>Aleksej Besciokov</strong>, 46, was apprehended while vacationing on the coast of India with his family.</p>
<div id="attachment_70665" style="width: 472px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70665" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70665" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Besciokov_Photo.png" alt="" width="462" height="552" /><p id="caption-attachment-70665" class="wp-caption-text">Aleksej Bešciokov, &#8220;proforg,&#8221; &#8220;iram&#8221;. Image: U.S. Secret Service.</p></div>
<p>On March 7, the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> (DOJ) unsealed <a href="https://www.justice.gov/media/1392316/dl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an indictment</a> against Besciokov and the other alleged co-founder of Garantex, <strong>Aleksandr Mira Serda</strong>, 40, a Russian national living in the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>Launched in 2019, Garantex was <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0701" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first sanctioned</a> by the U.S. Treasury Office of Foreign Assets Control in April 2022 for receiving hundreds of millions in criminal proceeds, including funds used to facilitate hacking, ransomware, terrorism and drug trafficking. Since those penalties were levied, Garantex has processed more than $60 billion, according to the blockchain analysis company <strong>Elliptic.</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;Garantex has been used in sanctions evasion by Russian elites, as well as to launder proceeds of crime including ransomware, darknet market trade and thefts attributed to North Korea’s Lazarus Group,&#8221; Elliptic wrote in <a href="https://www.elliptic.co/blog/elliptic-in-action-garantex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a blog post</a>. &#8220;Garantex has also been implicated in enabling Russian oligarchs to move their wealth out of the country, following the invasion of Ukraine.&#8221;</p>
<p>The DOJ alleges Besciokov was Garantex&#8217;s primary technical administrator and responsible for obtaining and maintaining critical Garantex infrastructure, as well as reviewing and approving transactions. Mira Serda is allegedly Garantex’s co-founder and chief commercial officer.</p>
<div id="attachment_70666" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70666" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70666" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/garantex-elliptic.png" alt="" width="747" height="492" /><p id="caption-attachment-70666" class="wp-caption-text">Image: elliptic.co</p></div>
<p>In conjunction with the release of the indictments, German and Finnish law enforcement seized servers hosting Garantex’s operations. A <a href="https://www.secretservice.gov/investigations/mostwanted/besciokov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&#8220;most wanted&#8221; notice</a> published by the <strong>U.S. Secret Service</strong> states that U.S. authorities separately obtained earlier copies of Garantex’s servers, including customer and accounting databases. Federal investigators say they also froze over $26 million in funds used to facilitate Garantex’s money laundering activities.</p>
<p>Besciokov was arrested within the past 24 hours while vacationing with his family in Varkala, a major coastal city in the southwest Indian state of Kerala. An officer with the local police department in Varkala confirmed Besciokov&#8217;s arrest, and said the suspect will appear in a Delhi court on March 14 to face charges.</p>
<div id="attachment_70667" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70667" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70667" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/kerala-shutterstock.png" alt="" width="749" height="495" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/kerala-shutterstock.png 988w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/kerala-shutterstock-768x507.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/kerala-shutterstock-782x516.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70667" class="wp-caption-text">Varkala Beach in Kerala, India. Image: Shutterstock, Dmitry Rukhlenko.</p></div>
<p><span id="more-70662"></span>The DOJ&#8217;s indictment says Besciokov went by the hacker handle &#8220;<strong>proforg</strong>.&#8221; This nickname corresponds to the administrator of a 20-year-old Russian language forum dedicated to nudity and crudity called &#8220;<strong>udaff</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Besciokov and Mira Serda are each charged with one count of conspiracy to commit money laundering, which carries a maximum sentence of 20 years in prison. Besciokov is also charged with one count of conspiracy to violate the International Economic Emergency Powers Act—which also carries a maximum sentence of 20 years in person—and with conspiracy to operate an unlicensed money transmitting business, which carries a maximum sentence of five years in prison.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/alleged-co-founder-of-garantex-arrested-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feds Link $150M Cyberheist to 2022 LastPass Hacks</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/feds-link-150m-cyberheist-to-2022-lastpass-hacks/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/feds-link-150m-cyberheist-to-2022-lastpass-hacks/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 01:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Larsen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karim Toubba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lastpass breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nick Bax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taylor Monahan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Secret Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZachXBT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70634</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In September 2023, KrebsOnSecurity published findings from security researchers who concluded that a series of six-figure cyberheists across dozens of victims resulted from thieves cracking master passwords stolen from the password manager service LastPass in 2022. In a court filing this week, U.S. federal agents investigating a spectacular $150 million cryptocurrency heist said they had reached the same conclusion.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In September 2023, KrebsOnSecurity published findings from security researchers who concluded that a series of six-figure cyberheists across dozens of victims resulted from thieves cracking master passwords stolen from the password manager service <strong>LastPass</strong> in 2022. In a court filing this week, U.S. federal agents investigating a spectacular $150 million cryptocurrency heist said they had reached the same conclusion.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-31264" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lastpass-580x132.png" alt="" width="580" height="132" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lastpass-580x132.png 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lastpass.png 808w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /></p>
<p>On March 6, federal prosecutors in northern California said they seized approximately $24 million worth of cryptocurrencies that were clawed back following a $150 million cyberheist on Jan. 30, 2024. The complaint refers to the person robbed only as &#8220;Victim-1,&#8221; but according to blockchain security researcher <strong>ZachXBT</strong> the theft was perpetrated against <strong>Chris Larsen</strong>, the co-founder of the cryptocurrency platform <strong>Ripple</strong>. ZachXBT was the <a href="https://x.com/zachxbt/status/1752694489905528943" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first to report on the heist</a>.</p>
<p>This week&#8217;s action by the government merely allows investigators to officially seize the frozen funds. But there is an important conclusion in this seizure document: It basically says the <strong>U.S. Secret Service</strong> and the <strong>FBI</strong> agree with the findings of <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/09/experts-fear-crooks-are-cracking-keys-stolen-in-lastpass-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the LastPass breach story published here in September 2023</a>.</p>
<p>That piece quoted security researchers who said they were witnessing six-figure crypto heists several times each month that all appeared to be the result of crooks cracking master passwords for the password vaults stolen from LastPass in 2022.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Federal Bureau of Investigation has been investigating these data breaches, and law enforcement agents investigating the instant case have spoken with FBI agents about their investigation,&#8221; reads the seizure complaint, which was written by a U.S. Secret Service agent. &#8220;From those conversations, law enforcement agents in this case learned that the stolen data and passwords that were stored in several victims’ online password manager accounts were used to illegally, and without authorization, access the victims’ electronic accounts and steal information, cryptocurrency, and other data.&#8221;</p>
<p>The document continues:</p>
<p>&#8220;Based on this investigation, law enforcement had probable cause to believe the same attackers behind the above-described commercial online password manager attack used a stolen password held in Victim 1’s online password manager account and, without authorization, accessed his cryptocurrency wallet/account.&#8221;</p>
<p>Working with dozens of victims, security researchers <strong>Nick Bax</strong> and <strong>Taylor Monahan</strong> found that none of the six-figure cyberheist victims appeared to have suffered the sorts of attacks that typically preface a high-dollar crypto theft, such as the compromise of one’s email and/or mobile phone accounts, or SIM-swapping attacks.</p>
<p>They discovered the victims all had something else in common: Each had at one point stored their cryptocurrency seed phrase &#8212; the secret code that lets anyone gain access to your cryptocurrency holdings &#8212; in the &#8220;Secure Notes&#8221; area of their LastPass account prior to the 2022 breaches at the company.</p>
<p>Bax and Monahan found another common theme with these robberies: They all followed a similar pattern of cashing out, rapidly moving stolen funds to a dizzying number of drop accounts scattered across various cryptocurrency exchanges.</p>
<p>According to the government, a similar level of complexity was present in the $150 million heist against the Ripple co-founder last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;The scale of a theft and rapid dissipation of funds would have required the efforts of multiple malicious actors, and was consistent with the online password manager breaches and attack on other victims whose cryptocurrency was stolen,&#8221; the government wrote. &#8220;For these reasons, law enforcement agents believe the cryptocurrency stolen from Victim 1 was committed by the same attackers who conducted the attack on the online password manager, and cryptocurrency thefts from other similarly situated victims.&#8221;</p>
<p>Reached for comment, LastPass said it has seen no definitive proof &#8212; from federal investigators or others &#8212; that the cyberheists in question were linked to the LastPass breaches.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since we initially disclosed this incident back in 2022, LastPass has worked in close cooperation with multiple representatives from law enforcement,&#8221; LastPass said in a written statement. &#8220;To date, our law enforcement partners have not made us aware of any conclusive evidence that connects any crypto thefts to our incident. In the meantime, we have been investing heavily in enhancing our security measures and will continue to do so.&#8221;<span id="more-70634"></span></p>
<p>On August 25, 2022, <strong>LastPass CEO Karim Toubba</strong> told users the company had detected unusual activity in its software development environment, and that the intruders stole some source code and proprietary LastPass technical information. On Sept. 15, 2022, LastPass said an investigation into the August breach determined the attacker did not access any customer data or password vaults.</p>
<p>But on Nov. 30, 2022, LastPass notified customers about another, far more serious security incident that the company said leveraged data stolen in the August breach. LastPass disclosed that criminal hackers had compromised encrypted copies of some password vaults, as well as other personal information.</p>
<p>Experts say the breach would have given thieves &#8220;offline&#8221; access to encrypted password vaults, theoretically allowing them all the time in the world to try to crack some of the weaker master passwords using powerful systems that can attempt millions of password guesses per second.</p>
<p>Researchers found that many of the cyberheist victims had chosen master passwords with relatively low complexity, and were among LastPass&#8217;s oldest customers. That&#8217;s because legacy LastPass users were more likely to have master passwords that were protected with far fewer &#8220;iterations,&#8221; which refers to the number of times your password is run through the company&#8217;s encryption routines. In general, the more iterations, the longer it takes an offline attacker to crack your master password.</p>
<p>Over the years, LastPass forced new users to pick longer and more complex master passwords, and they increased the number of iterations on multiple occasions by several orders of magnitude. But researchers found strong indications that LastPass never succeeded in upgrading many of its older customers to the newer password requirements and protections.</p>
<p>Asked about LastPass&#8217;s continuing denials, Bax said that after the initial warning in our 2023 story, he naively hoped people would migrate their funds to new cryptocurrency wallets.</p>
<p>&#8220;While some did, the continued thefts underscore how much more needs to be done,&#8221; Bax told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;It&#8217;s validating to see the Secret Service and FBI corroborate our findings, but I’d much rather see fewer of these hacks in the first place. ZachXBT and <a href="https://x.com/_SEAL_Org/status/1868805837311074576" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAL 911 reported yet another wave of thefts</a> as recently as December, showing the threat is still very real.&#8221;</p>
<p>Monahan said LastPass still hasn’t alerted their customers that their secrets—especially those stored in “Secure Notes”—may be at risk.</p>
<p>&#8220;Its been two and a half years since LastPass was first breached [and] hundreds of millions of dollars has been stolen from individuals and companies around the globe,&#8221; Monahan said. &#8220;They could have encouraged users to rotate their credentials. They could’ve prevented millions and millions of dollars from being stolen by these threat actors. But  instead they chose to deny that their customers were are risk and blame the victims instead.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/feds-link-150m-cyberheist-to-2022-lastpass-hacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 252/252 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2025-04-08 23:12:13 by W3 Total Cache
-->