<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 18:37:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How Phished Data Turns into Apple &#038; Google Wallets</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 18:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[All About Skimmers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andy Chandler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSIS Security Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Merrill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghost tap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grant Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iMessage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M3AAWG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RCS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SecAlliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ThreatFabric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZNFC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carding -- the underground business of stealing, selling and swiping stolen payment card data -- has long been the dominion of Russia-based hackers. Happily, the broad deployment of more secure chip-based payment cards in the United States has weakened the carding market. But a flurry of innovation from cybercrime groups in China is breathing new life into the carding industry, by turning phished card data into mobile wallets that can be used online and at main street stores.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Carding &#8212; the underground business of stealing, selling and swiping stolen payment card data &#8212; has long been the dominion of Russia-based hackers. Happily, the broad deployment of more secure chip-based payment cards in the United States has weakened the carding market. But a flurry of innovation from cybercrime groups in China is breathing new life into the carding industry, by turning phished card data into mobile wallets that can be used online and at main street stores.</p>
<div id="attachment_70443" style="width: 490px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70443" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-70443" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/tollpassphishing.png" alt="" width="480" height="630" /><p id="caption-attachment-70443" class="wp-caption-text">An image from one Chinese phishing group&#8217;s Telegram channel shows various toll road phish kits available.</p></div>
<p>If you own a mobile phone, the chances are excellent that at some point in the past two years it has received at least one phishing message that spoofs the <strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong> to supposedly collect some outstanding delivery fee, or an SMS that pretends to be a local toll road operator warning of a delinquent toll fee.</p>
<p>These messages are being sent through sophisticated phishing kits sold by several cybercriminals based in mainland China. And they are not traditional SMS phishing or &#8220;<strong>smishing</strong>&#8221; messages, as they bypass the mobile networks entirely. Rather, the missives are sent through the <strong>Apple iMessage</strong> service and through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rich_Communication_Services" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RCS</a>, the functionally equivalent technology on <strong>Google</strong> phones.</p>
<p>People who enter their payment card data at one of these sites will be told their financial institution needs to verify the small transaction by sending a one-time passcode to the customer&#8217;s mobile device. In reality, that code will be sent by the victim&#8217;s financial institution to verify that the user indeed wishes to link their card information to a mobile wallet.</p>
<p>If the victim then provides that one-time code, the phishers will link the card data to a new mobile wallet from Apple or Google, loading the wallet onto a mobile phone that the scammers control.</p>
<h2>CARDING REINVENTED</h2>
<p><strong>Ford Merrill</strong> works in security research at <a href="https://www.secalliance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SecAlliance</a>, a <a href="https://www.csis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSIS Security Group</a> company. Merrill has been studying the evolution of several China-based smishing gangs, and found that most of them feature helpful and informative video tutorials in their sales accounts on Telegram. Those videos show the thieves are loading multiple stolen digital wallets on a single mobile device, and then selling those phones in bulk for hundreds of dollars apiece.</p>
<p>&#8220;Who says carding is dead?,&#8221; said Merrill, who presented about his findings at the <a href="https://www.m3aawg.org/upcoming-meetings" target="_blank" rel="noopener">M3AAWG</a> security conference in Lisbon earlier today. &#8220;This is the best mag stripe cloning device ever. This threat actor is saying you need to buy at least 10 phones, and they&#8217;ll air ship them to you.&#8221;</p>
<p>One promotional video shows stacks of milk crates stuffed full of phones for sale. A closer inspection reveals that each phone is affixed with a handwritten notation that typically references the date its mobile wallets were added, the number of wallets on the device, and the initials of the seller.</p>
<div id="attachment_70436" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70436" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70436" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png" alt="" width="749" height="567" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png 1160w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-768x581.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-782x591.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70436" class="wp-caption-text">An image from the Telegram channel for a popular Chinese smishing kit vendor shows 10 mobile phones for sale, each loaded with 4-6 digital wallets from different UK financial institutions.</p></div>
<p>Merrill said one common way criminal groups in China are cashing out with these stolen mobile wallets involves setting up fake e-commerce businesses on <strong>Stripe</strong> or <strong>Zelle</strong> and running transactions through those entities &#8212; often for amounts totaling between $100 and $500.</p>
<p>Merrill said that when these phishing groups first began operating in earnest two years ago, they would wait between 60 to 90 days before selling the phones or using them for fraud. But these days that waiting period is more like just seven to ten days, he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;When they first installed this, the actors were very patient,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Nowadays, they only wait like 10 days before [the wallets] are hit hard and fast.&#8221;<span id="more-70276"></span></p>
<h2>GHOST TAP</h2>
<p>Criminals also can cash out mobile wallets by obtaining real point-of-sale terminals and using tap-to-pay on phone after phone. But they also offer a more cutting-edge mobile fraud technology: Merrill found that at least one of the Chinese phishing groups sells an Android app called &#8220;<strong>ZNFC</strong>&#8221; that can relay a valid NFC transaction to anywhere in the world. The user simply waves their phone at a local payment terminal that accepts Apple or Google pay, and the app relays an NFC transaction over the Internet from a phone in China.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ekqZjPAxB4c?si=hYLqGPIBrNthAg9_" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;The software can work from anywhere in the world,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;These guys provide the software for $500 a month, and it can relay both NFC enabled tap-to-pay as well as any digital wallet. The even have 24-hour support.&#8221;</p>
<p>The rise of so-called &#8220;ghost tap&#8221; mobile software was <a href="https://www.threatfabric.com/blogs/ghost-tap-new-cash-out-tactic-with-nfc-relay" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first documented in November 2024</a> by security experts at <strong>ThreatFabric</strong>. <strong>Andy Chandler</strong>, the company&#8217;s chief commercial officer, said their researchers have since identified a number of criminal groups from different regions of the world latching on to this scheme.</p>
<p>Chandler said those include organized crime gangs in Europe that are using similar mobile wallet and NFC attacks to take money out of ATMs made to work with smartphones.</p>
<p>&#8220;No one is talking about it, but we&#8217;re now seeing ten different methodologies using the same modus operandi, and none of them are doing it the same,&#8221; Chandler said. &#8220;This is much bigger than the banks are prepared to say.&#8221;</p>
<p>A November 2024 story in the Singapore daily <em>The Straits Times</em> <a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/scam-syndicates-sending-foreigners-into-singapore-to-cheat-retailers-like-apple-store-and-best-denki" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> authorities there arrested three foreign men who were recruited in their home countries via social messaging platforms, and given ghost tap apps with which to purchase expensive items from retailers, including mobile phones, jewelry, and gold bars.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since Nov 4, at least 10 victims who had fallen for e-commerce scams have reported unauthorised transactions totaling more than $100,000 on their credit cards for purchases such as electronic products, like iPhones and chargers, and jewelry in Singapore,&#8221; <em>The Straits Times</em> wrote, noting that in another case with a similar modus operandi, the police arrested a Malaysian man and woman on Nov 8.</p>
<div id="attachment_70459" style="width: 863px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70459" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70459" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thestraitstimes.png" alt="" width="853" height="567" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thestraitstimes.png 853w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thestraitstimes-768x510.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thestraitstimes-782x520.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 853px) 100vw, 853px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70459" class="wp-caption-text">Three individuals charged with using ghost tap software at an electronics store in Singapore. Image: The Straits Times.</p></div>
<h2>ADVANCED PHISHING TECHNIQUES</h2>
<p>According to Merrill, the phishing pages that spoof the USPS and various toll road operators are powered by several innovations designed to maximize the extraction of victim data.</p>
<p>For example, a would-be smishing victim might enter their personal and financial information, but then decide the whole thing is scam before actually submitting the data. In this case, anything typed into the data fields of the phishing page will be captured in real time, regardless of whether the visitor actually clicks the &#8220;submit&#8221; button.</p>
<p>Merrill said people who submit payment card data to these phishing sites often are then told their card can&#8217;t be processed, and urged to use a different card. This technique, he said, sometimes allows the phishers to steal more than one mobile wallet per victim.</p>
<p>Many phishing websites expose victim data by storing the stolen information directly on the phishing domain. But Merrill said these Chinese phishing kits will forward all victim data to a back-end database operated by the phishing kit vendors. That way, even when the smishing sites get taken down for fraud, the stolen data is still safe and secure.</p>
<p>Another important innovation is the use of mass-created Apple and Google user accounts through which these phishers send their spam messages. One of the Chinese phishing groups posted images on their Telegram sales channels showing how these robot Apple and Google accounts are loaded onto Apple and Google phones, and arranged snugly next to each other in an expansive, multi-tiered rack that sits directly in front of the phishing service operator.</p>
<div id="attachment_70435" style="width: 528px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70435" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70435" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phonesashtray.png" alt="" width="518" height="688" /><p id="caption-attachment-70435" class="wp-caption-text">The ashtray says: You&#8217;ve been phishing all night.</p></div>
<p>In other words, the smishing websites are powered by real human operators as long as new messages are being sent. Merrill said the criminals appear to send only a few dozen messages at a time, likely because completing the scam takes manual work by the human operators in China. After all, most one-time codes used for mobile wallet provisioning are generally only good for a few minutes before they expire.</p>
<p>Notably, none of the phishing sites spoofing the toll operators or postal services will load in a regular Web browser; they will only render if they detect that a visitor is coming from a mobile device.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the reasons they want you to be on a mobile device is they want you to be on the same device that is going to receive the one-time code,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;They also want to minimize the chances you will leave. And if they want to get that mobile tokenization and grab your one-time code, they need a live operator.&#8221;</p>
<p>Merrill found the Chinese phishing kits feature another innovation that makes it simple for customers to turn stolen card details into a mobile wallet: They programmatically take the card data supplied by the phishing victim and convert it into a digital image of a real payment card that matches that victim&#8217;s financial institution. That way, attempting to enroll a stolen card into Apple Pay, for example, becomes as easy as scanning the fabricated card image with an iPhone.</p>
<div id="attachment_70439" style="width: 407px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70439" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70439" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phish-cabelas.png" alt="" width="397" height="488" /><p id="caption-attachment-70439" class="wp-caption-text">An ad from a Chinese SMS phishing group&#8217;s Telegram channel showing how the service converts stolen card data into an image of the stolen card.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;The phone isn&#8217;t smart enough to know whether it&#8217;s a real card or just an image,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;So it scans the card into Apple Pay, which says okay we need to verify that you&#8217;re the owner of the card by sending a one-time code.&#8221;</p>
<h2>PROFITS</h2>
<p>How profitable are these mobile phishing kits? The best guess so far comes from data gathered by other security researchers who&#8217;ve been tracking these advanced Chinese phishing vendors.</p>
<p>In August 2023, the security firm Resecurity <a href="https://www.resecurity.com/blog/article/smishing-triad-targeted-usps-and-us-citizens-for-data-theft" target="_blank" rel="noopener">discovered a vulnerability</a> in one popular Chinese phish kit vendor&#8217;s platform that exposed the personal and financial data of phishing victims. Resecurity dubbed the group the <strong>Smishing Triad</strong>, and found the gang had harvested 108,044 payment cards across 31 phishing domains (3,485 cards per domain).</p>
<p>In August 2024, security researcher <strong>Grant Smith</strong> gave <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gLOv67LlIQs&amp;list=PL9fPq3eQfaaB2scbXRczwvjVH0ckX4bwt&amp;index=14" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a presentation</a> at the DEFCON security conference about tracking down the Smishing Triad after scammers spoofing the U.S. Postal Service <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/usps-scam-text-smishing-triad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">duped his wife</a>. By identifying a different vulnerability in the gang&#8217;s phishing kit, Smith said he was able to see that people entered 438,669 unique credit cards in 1,133 phishing domains (387 cards per domain).</p>
<p>Based on his research, Merrill said it&#8217;s reasonable to expect between $100 and $500 in losses on each card that is turned into a mobile wallet. Merrill said they observed nearly 33,000 unique domains tied to these Chinese smishing groups during the year between the publication of Resecurity&#8217;s research and Smith&#8217;s DEFCON talk.</p>
<p>Using a median number of 1,935 cards per domain and a conservative loss of $250 per card, that comes out to about $15 billion in fraudulent charges over a year.</p>
<p>Merrill was reluctant to say whether he&#8217;d identified additional security vulnerabilities in any of the phishing kits sold by the Chinese groups, noting that the phishers quickly fixed the vulnerabilities that were detailed publicly by Resecurity and Smith.</p>
<h2>FIGHTING BACK</h2>
<p>Adoption of touchless payments took off in the United States after the Coronavirus pandemic emerged, and many financial institutions in the United States were eager to make it simple for customers to link payment cards to mobile wallets. Thus, the authentication requirement for doing so defaulted to sending the customer a one-time code via SMS.</p>
<p>Experts say the continued reliance on one-time codes for onboarding mobile wallets has fostered this new wave of carding. KrebsOnSecurity interviewed a security executive from a large European financial institution who spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak to the press.</p>
<p>That expert said the lag between the phishing of victim card data and its eventual use for fraud has left many financial institutions struggling to correlate the causes of their losses.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s part of why the industry as a whole has been caught by surprise,&#8221; the expert said. &#8220;A lot of people are asking, how this is possible now that we&#8217;ve tokenized a plaintext process. We&#8217;ve never seen the volume of sending and people responding that we&#8217;re seeing with these phishers.&#8221;</p>
<p>To improve the security of digital wallet provisioning, some banks in Europe and Asia require customers to log in to the bank&#8217;s mobile app before they can link a digital wallet to their device.</p>
<p>Addressing the ghost tap threat may require updates to contactless payment terminals, to better identify NFC transactions that are being relayed from another device. But experts say it&#8217;s unrealistic to expect retailers will be eager to replace existing payment terminals before their expected lifespans expire.</p>
<p>And of course Apple and Google have an increased role to play as well, given that their accounts are being created en masse and used to blast out these smishing messages. Both companies could easily tell which of their devices suddenly have 7-10 different mobile wallets added from 7-10 different people around the world. They could also recommend that financial institutions use more secure authentication methods for mobile wallet provisioning.</p>
<p>Neither Apple nor Google responded to requests for comment on this story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nearly a Year Later, Mozilla is Still Promoting OneRep</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/nearly-a-year-later-mozilla-is-still-promoting-onerep/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/nearly-a-year-later-mozilla-is-still-promoting-onerep/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dimitiri Shelest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozilla Monitor Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuwber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OneRep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radaris]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In mid-March 2024, KrebsOnSecurity revealed that the founder of the personal data removal service Onerep also founded dozens of people-search companies. Shortly after that investigation was published, Mozilla said it would stop bundling Onerep with the Firefox browser and wind down its partnership. But nearly a year later, Mozilla is still promoting it to Firefox users.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In mid-March 2024, KrebsOnSecurity revealed that the founder of the personal data removal service <strong>Onerep</strong> also founded dozens of people-search companies. Shortly after that investigation was published, <strong>Mozilla</strong> said it would stop bundling Onerep with the <strong>Firefox</strong> browser and wind down its partnership with the company. But nearly a year later, Mozilla is still promoting it to Firefox users.</p>
<p>Mozilla offers Onerep to Firefox users on a subscription basis as part of <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/about/legal/terms/subscription-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mozilla Monitor Plus</a>. Launched in 2018 under the name <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firefox_Monitor" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Firefox Monitor</a>, Mozilla Monitor also checks data from the website <a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Have I Been Pwned?</a> to let users know when their email addresses or password are leaked in data breaches.</p>
<p>The ink on that partnership agreement had barely dried before KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/ceo-of-data-privacy-company-onerep-com-founded-dozens-of-people-search-firms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published a story</a> showing that Onerep’s Belarusian CEO and founder <strong>Dimitiri Shelest</strong> launched dozens of people-search services since 2010, including a still-active data broker called <strong>Nuwber</strong> that sells background reports on people. This seemed to contradict Onerep&#8217;s stated motto, &#8220;We believe that no one should compromise personal online security and get a profit from it.”</p>
<p>Shelest released <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Dimitri-Shelest-Letter-_-Comment-on-Krebs-article-3.20.24-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a lengthy statement</a> (PDF) wherein he acknowledged maintaining an ownership stake in <strong>Nuwber</strong>, a consumer data broker he founded in 2015 — around the same time he started Onerep.</p>
<div id="attachment_66783" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-66783" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-66783" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/onerep-shellest.png" alt="" width="750" height="439" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/onerep-shellest.png 1275w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/onerep-shellest-768x450.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/onerep-shellest-782x458.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-66783" class="wp-caption-text">Onerep.com CEO and founder Dimitri Shelest, as pictured on the &#8220;about&#8221; page of onerep.com.</p></div>
<p>Shelest maintained that Nuwber has “zero cross-over or information-sharing with Onerep,” and said any other old domains that may be found and associated with his name are no longer being operated by him.</p>
<p>“I get it,” Shelest wrote. “My affiliation with a people search business may look odd from the outside. In truth, if I hadn’t taken that initial path with a deep dive into how people search sites work, Onerep wouldn’t have the best tech and team in the space. Still, I now appreciate that we did not make this more clear in the past and I’m aiming to do better in the future.”</p>
<p>When asked to comment on the findings, Mozilla said then that although customer data was never at risk, the outside financial interests and activities of Onerep&#8217;s CEO did not align with their values.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re working now to solidify a transition plan that will provide customers with a seamless experience and will continue to put their interests first,&#8221; Mozilla <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/mozilla-drops-onerep-after-ceo-admits-to-running-people-search-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a>.</p>
<p>In October 2024, Mozilla published a statement saying the search for a different provider was taking longer than anticipated.</p>
<p>&#8220;While we continue to evaluate vendors, finding a technically excellent and values-aligned partner takes time,&#8221; Mozilla <a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/securing-new-partner-monitor-plus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>. &#8220;While we continue this search, Onerep will remain the backend provider, ensuring that we can maintain uninterrupted services while we continue evaluating new potential partners that align more closely with Mozilla’s values and user expectations. We are conducting thorough diligence to find the right vendor.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked for an update, Mozilla said the search for a replacement partner continues.</p>
<p>&#8220;The work’s ongoing but we haven’t found the right alternative yet,&#8221; Mozilla said in an emailed statement. &#8220;Our customers’ data remains safe, and since the product provides a lot of value to our subscribers, we’ll continue to offer it during this process.”</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a win-win for Mozilla that they&#8217;ve received accolades for their principled response while continuing to partner with Onerep almost a year later. But if it takes so long to find a suitable replacement, what does that say about the personal data removal industry itself?<span id="more-70392"></span></p>
<p>Onerep appears to be working in partnership with another problematic people-search service: <strong>Radaris</strong>, which has a history of ignoring opt-out requests or failing to honor them. A week before breaking the story about Onerep, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/a-close-up-look-at-the-consumer-data-broker-radaris/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published research</a> showing the co-founders of Radaris were two native Russian brothers who&#8217;d built a vast network of affiliate marketing programs and consumer data broker services.</p>
<p>Lawyers for the Radaris co-founders threatened to sue KrebsOnSecurity unless that story was retracted in full, claiming the founders were in fact Ukrainian and that our reporting had defamed the brothers by associating them with the actions of Radaris. Instead, we published <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/06/krebsonsecurity-threatened-with-defamation-lawsuit-over-fake-radaris-ceo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a follow-up investigation</a> which showed that not only did the brothers from Russia create Radaris, for many years they issued press releases quoting a fictitious CEO seeking money from investors.</p>
<p>Several readers have shared emails they received from Radaris after attempting to remove their personal data, and those messages show Radaris has been promoting Onerep.</p>
<div id="attachment_70413" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70413" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70413" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email.png" alt="" width="750" height="316" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email.png 1402w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email-768x324.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email-782x330.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-70413" class="wp-caption-text">An email from Radaris promoting Onerep.</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/nearly-a-year-later-mozilla-is-still-promoting-onerep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Patch Tuesday, February 2025 Edition</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/microsoft-patch-tuesday-february-2025-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/microsoft-patch-tuesday-february-2025-edition/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 04:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38193]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21377]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21391]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21418]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft 365 Copilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Patch Tuesday February 2025]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sans internet storm center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satnam Narang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tenable]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today issued security updates to fix at least 56 vulnerabilities in its Windows operating systems and supported software, including two zero-day flaws that are being actively exploited.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today issued security updates to fix at least 56 vulnerabilities in its Windows operating systems and supported software, including two zero-day flaws that are being actively exploited.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter  wp-image-56287" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png" alt="" width="749" height="527" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png 841w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-768x541.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-782x550.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>All supported Windows operating systems will receive an update this month for a buffer overflow vulnerability that carries the catchy name <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-21418" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21418</a>. This patch should be a priority for enterprises, as Microsoft says it is being exploited, has low attack complexity, and no requirements for user interaction.</p>
<p><strong>Tenable</strong> senior staff research engineer <strong>Satnam Narang</strong> noted that since 2022, there have been nine elevation of privilege vulnerabilities in this same Windows component &#8212; three each year &#8212; including one in 2024 that was exploited in the wild as a zero day (CVE-2024-38193).</p>
<p>&#8220;CVE-2024-38193 was exploited by the North Korean APT group known as Lazarus Group to implant a new version of the FudModule rootkit in order to maintain persistence and stealth on compromised systems,&#8221; Narang said. &#8220;At this time, it is unclear if CVE-2025-21418 was also exploited by Lazarus Group.&#8221;</p>
<p>The other zero-day, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-21391" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21391</a>, is an elevation of privilege vulnerability in Windows Storage that could be used to delete files on a targeted system. Microsoft&#8217;s advisory on this bug references something called “CWE-59: Improper Link Resolution Before File Access,&#8221; says no user interaction is required, and that the attack complexity is low.</p>
<p><strong>Adam Barnett</strong>, lead software engineer at <strong>Rapid7</strong>, said although the advisory provides scant detail, and even offers some vague reassurance that &#8216;an attacker would only be able to delete targeted files on a system,&#8217; it would be a mistake to assume that the impact of deleting arbitrary files would be limited to data loss or denial of service.</p>
<p>&#8220;As long ago as 2022, ZDI researchers set out how a motivated attacker could parlay arbitrary file deletion into full SYSTEM access using techniques which also involve creative misuse of symbolic links,&#8221;Barnett wrote.<span id="more-70396"></span></p>
<p>One vulnerability patched today that was publicly disclosed earlier is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-21377" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21377</a>, another weakness that could allow an attacker to elevate their privileges on a vulnerable Windows system. Specifically, this is yet another Windows flaw that can be used to steal NTLMv2 hashes &#8212; essentially allowing an attacker to authenticate as the targeted user without having to log in.</p>
<p>According to Microsoft, minimal user interaction with a malicious file is needed to exploit CVE-2025-21377, including selecting, inspecting or &#8220;performing an action other than opening or executing the file.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This trademark linguistic ducking and weaving may be Microsoft’s way of saying &#8216;if we told you any more, we’d give the game away,'&#8221; Barnett said. &#8220;Accordingly, Microsoft assesses exploitation as more likely.&#8221;</p>
<p>The <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/diary/Microsoft%20February%202025%20Patch%20Tuesday/31674" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SANS Internet Storm Center</a> has a handy list of all the Microsoft patches released today, indexed by severity. Windows enterprise administrators would do well to keep an eye on <a href="http://www.askwoody.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">askwoody.com</a>, which often has the scoop on any patches causing problems.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s getting harder to buy Windows software that isn&#8217;t also bundled with Microsoft&#8217;s flagship Copilot artificial intelligence (AI) feature. Last month Microsoft started bundling Copilot with <strong>Microsoft Office 365</strong>, which Redmond has since rebranded as &#8220;<strong>Microsoft 365 Copilot</strong>.&#8221; Ostensibly to offset the costs of its substantial AI investments, Microsoft also jacked up prices from 22 percent to 30 percent for upcoming license renewals and new subscribers.</p>
<p>Office-watch.com <a href="https://office-watch.com/2025/microsoft-365-classic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that existing Office 365 users who are paying an annual cloud license do have the option of &#8220;Microsoft 365 Classic,&#8221; an AI-free subscription at a lower price, but that many customers are not offered the option until they attempt to cancel their existing Office subscription.</p>
<p>In other security patch news, <strong>Apple</strong> has shipped iOS 18.3.1, which fixes a <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/122174">zero day</a> vulnerability (CVE-2025-24200) that is showing up in attacks.</p>
<p><strong>Adobe</strong> has issued security updates that fix a total of 45 vulnerabilities across <strong>InDesign</strong>, <strong>Commerce</strong>, <strong>Substance 3D</strong> <strong>Stager</strong>, <strong>InCopy</strong>, <strong>Illustrator</strong>, <strong>Substance 3D Designer</strong> and <strong>Photoshop Elements</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Chris Goettl</strong> at <strong>Ivanti</strong> notes that <strong>Google Chrome</strong> is shipping an update today which will trigger updates for Chromium based browsers including <strong>Microsoft Edge</strong>, so be on the lookout for Chrome and Edge updates as we proceed through the week.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/microsoft-patch-tuesday-february-2025-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teen on Musk&#8217;s DOGE Team Graduated from &#8216;The Com&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/teen-on-musks-doge-team-graduated-from-the-com/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/teen-on-musks-doge-team-graduated-from-the-com/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AS400495]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BackConnect Security LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Curtis Gervais]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DiamondCDN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director of National Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dstat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edward Coristine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marshal Webb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuralink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Packetware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Path Networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla Sexy LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tucker Preston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wired reported this week that a 19-year-old working for Elon Musk's so-called Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) was given access to sensitive US government systems even though his past association with cybercrime communities should have precluded him from gaining the necessary security clearances to do so. As today's story explores, the DOGE teen is a former denizen of 'The Com,' an archipelago of Discord and Telegram chat channels that function as a kind of distributed cybercriminal social network for facilitating instant collaboration.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Wired</em> reported this week that a 19-year-old working for <strong>Elon Musk</strong>&#8216;s so-called <strong>Department of Government Efficiency</strong> (DOGE) was given access to sensitive US government systems even though his past association with cybercrime communities should have precluded him from gaining the necessary security clearances to do so. As today&#8217;s story explores, the DOGE teen is a former denizen of &#8216;<strong>The Com</strong>,&#8217; an archipelago of Discord and Telegram chat channels that function as a kind of distributed cybercriminal social network for facilitating instant collaboration.</p>
<p>Since President Trump&#8217;s second inauguration, Musk&#8217;s DOGE team has gained access to a truly staggering amount of personal and sensitive data on American citizens, moving quickly to seize control over databases at the <strong>U.S. Treasury</strong>, the <strong>Office of Personnel Management</strong>, the <strong>Department of Education</strong>, and the <strong>Department of Health and Human Resources</strong>, among others.</p>
<p><em>Wired</em> first <a href="https://archive.ph/HCCA4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported on Feb. 2</a> that one of the technologists on Musk&#8217;s crew is a 19-year-old high school graduate named <strong>Edward Coristine</strong>, who reportedly goes by the nickname &#8220;Big Balls&#8221; online. One of the companies Coristine founded, <strong>Tesla.Sexy LLC</strong>, was set up in 2021, when he would have been around 16 years old.</p>
<p>&#8220;Tesla.Sexy LLC controls dozens of web domains, including at least two Russian-registered domains,&#8221; <em>Wired</em> reported. &#8220;One of those domains, which is still active, offers a service called Helfie, which is an AI bot for Discord servers targeting the Russian market. While the operation of a Russian website would not violate US sanctions preventing Americans doing business with Russian companies, it could potentially be a factor in a security clearance review.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mr. Coristine has not responded to requests for comment. In <a href="https://archive.ph/VAD48" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a follow-up story</a> this week, <em>Wired</em> found that someone using a Telegram handle tied to Coristine solicited a DDoS-for-hire service in 2022, and that he worked for a short time at a company that specializes in protecting customers from DDoS attacks.</p>
<div id="attachment_70369" style="width: 647px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70369" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70369" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/coristine.png" alt="" width="637" height="636" /><p id="caption-attachment-70369" class="wp-caption-text">A profile photo from Coristine&#8217;s WhatsApp account.</p></div>
<p>Internet routing records <a href="https://bgp.he.net/net/23.133.104.0/24#_whois" target="_blank" rel="noopener">show</a> that Coristine runs an Internet service provider called <strong>Packetware</strong> (AS400495). Also known as &#8220;<strong>DiamondCDN</strong>,&#8221; Packetware <a href="https://bgp.he.net/net/23.133.104.0/24#_dnsrecords" target="_blank" rel="noopener">currently hosts</a> tesla[.]sexy and diamondcdn[.]com, among other domains.</p>
<p>DiamondCDN was advertised and claimed by someone who used the nickname &#8220;<strong>Rivage</strong>&#8221; on several Com-based Discord channels over the years. A review of chat logs from some of those channels show other members frequently referred to Rivage as &#8220;Edward.&#8221;</p>
<p>From late 2020 to late 2024, Rivage&#8217;s conversations would show up in multiple Com chat servers that are closely monitored by security companies. In November 2022, Rivage could be seen requesting recommendations for a reliable and powerful DDoS-for-hire service.</p>
<p>Rivage made that request in the cybercrime channel &#8220;<strong>Dstat</strong>,&#8221; a core Com hub where users could buy and sell attack services. <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ddos-site-dstatcc-seized-and-two-suspects-arrested-in-germany/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dstat’s website dstat[.]cc was seized</a> in 2024 as part of “Operation PowerOFF,” an international law enforcement action against DDoS services.</p>
<p>Coristine&#8217;s LinkedIn profile said that in 2022 he worked at an anti-DDoS company called <strong>Path Networks</strong>, which <em>Wired</em> generously described as a &#8220;network monitoring firm known for hiring reformed blackhat hackers.&#8221; <em>Wired</em> wrote:</p>
<p>&#8220;At Path Network, Coristine worked as a systems engineer from April to June of 2022, according to his now-deleted LinkedIn résumé. Path has at times listed as employees <strong>Eric Taylor</strong>, also known as Cosmo the God, a well-known former cybercriminal and member of the hacker group UGNazis, as well as Matthew Flannery, an Australian convicted hacker whom police allege was a member of the hacker group LulzSec. It’s unclear whether Coristine worked at Path concurrently with those hackers, and WIRED found no evidence that either Coristine or other Path employees engaged in illegal activity while at the company.&#8221;</p>
<p>The founder of Path is a young man named <strong>Marshal Webb</strong>. I wrote about Webb back in 2016, in a story about a DDoS defense company he co-founded called <strong>BackConnect Security LLC</strong>. On September 20, 2016, KrebsOnSecurity published data showing that the company <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/ddos-mitigation-firm-has-history-of-hijacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">had a history of hijacking Internet address space that belonged to others</a>.</p>
<p>Less than 24 hours after that story ran, KrebsOnSecurity.com was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/krebsonsecurity-hit-with-record-ddos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hit with the biggest DDoS attack the Internet had ever seen at the time</a>. That sustained attack <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/the-democratization-of-censorship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kept this site offline for nearly 4 days</a>.</p>
<p>The other founder of BackConnect Security LLC was <strong>Tucker Preston</strong>, a Georgia man who <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/01/ddos-mitigation-firm-founder-admits-to-ddos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pleaded guilty in 2020</a> to paying a DDoS-for-hire service to launch attacks against others.</p>
<p>The aforementioned Path employee Eric Taylor <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/02/men-who-sent-swat-team-heroin-to-my-home-sentenced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pleaded guilty in 2017</a> to charges including <a href="http://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/03/the-world-has-no-room-for-cowards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an attack on our home in 2013</a>. Taylor was among several men involved in making a false report to my local police department about a supposed hostage situation at our residence in Virginia. In response, a heavily-armed police force surrounded my home and put me in handcuffs at gunpoint before the police realized it was all a dangerous hoax known as &#8220;swatting.&#8221;</p>
<p>CosmoTheGod rocketed to Internet infamy in 2013 when he and a number of other hackers <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/03/credit-reports-sold-for-cheap-in-the-underweb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">set up the Web site exposed[dot]su</a>, which “doxed” dozens of public officials and celebrities by publishing the address, Social Security numbers and other personal information on the former First Lady Michelle Obama, the then-director of the FBI and the U.S. attorney general, among others. The group also swatted many of the people they doxed.</p>
<p><em>Wired</em> noted that Coristine only worked at Path for a few months in 2022, but the story didn&#8217;t mention why his tenure was so short. A screenshot shared on the website <a href="https://www.pathtruths.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pathtruths.com</a> includes a snippet of conversations in June 2022 between Path employees discussing Coristine&#8217;s firing.</p>
<p>According to that record, Path founder Marshal Webb dismissed Coristine for leaking internal documents to a competitor. Not long after Coristine&#8217;s termination, someone leaked an abundance of internal Path documents and conversations. Among other things, those chats revealed that one of Path&#8217;s technicians was a Canadian man named <strong>Curtis Gervais</strong> who was convicted in 2017 of <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/09/canadian-man-gets-9-months-detention-for-serial-swattings-bomb-threats/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">perpetrating dozens of swatting attacks and fake bomb threats</a> &#8212; including at least two attempts against our home in 2014.</p>
<div id="attachment_70370" style="width: 595px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70370" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70370" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/pathchat.png" alt="" width="585" height="808" /><p id="caption-attachment-70370" class="wp-caption-text">A snippet of text from an internal Path chat room, wherein members discuss the reason for Coristine&#8217;s termination: Allegedly, leaking internal company information. Source: Pathtruths.com.</p></div>
<p><span id="more-70358"></span></p>
<p>On May 11, 2024, Rivage posted on a Discord channel for a DDoS protection service that is chiefly marketed to members of The Com. Rivage expressed frustration with his time spent on Com-based communities, suggesting that its profitability had been oversold.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a lot of money to be made in the com,&#8221; Rivage lamented. &#8220;I&#8217;m not buying Heztner [servers] to set up some com VPN.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rivage largely stopped posting messages on Com channels after that. <em>Wired</em> reports that Coristine subsequently spent three months last summer working at <strong>Neuralink</strong>, Elon Musk&#8217;s brain implant startup.</p>
<p>The trouble with all this is that even if someone sincerely intends to exit The Com after years of consorting with cybercriminals, they are often still subject to personal attacks, harassment and hacking long after they have left the scene.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s because a huge part of Com culture involves harassing, swatting and hacking other members of the community. These internecine attacks are often for financial gain, but just as frequently they are perpetrated by cybercrime groups to exact retribution from or assert dominance over rival gangs.</p>
<p>Experts say it is extremely difficult for former members of violent street gangs to gain a security clearance needed to view sensitive or classified information held by the U.S. government. That&#8217;s because ex-gang members are highly susceptible to extortion and coercion from current members of the same gang, and that alone presents an unacceptable security risk for intelligence agencies.</p>
<p>And make no mistake: The Com is the English-language cybercriminal hacking equivalent of a violent street gang. KrebsOnSecurity has published numerous stories detailing how feuds within the community <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/09/violence-as-a-service-brickings-firebombings-shootings-for-hire/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">periodically spill over into real-world violence</a>.</p>
<p>When Coristine&#8217;s name surfaced in <em>Wired</em>&#8216;s report this week, members of The Com immediately took notice. In the following segment from a February 5, 2025 chat in a Com-affiliated hosting provider, members criticized Rivage&#8217;s skills, and discussed harassing his family and notifying authorities about incriminating accusations that may or may not be true.</p>
<blockquote><p>2025-02-05 16:29:44 UTC vperked#0 they got this nigga on indiatimes man<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:46 UTC alexaloo#0 Their cropping is worse than AI could have done<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:48 UTC hebeatsme#0 bro who is that<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:53 UTC hebeatsme#0 yalla re talking about<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:56 UTC xewdy#0 edward<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:56 UTC .yarrb#0 rivagew<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:57 UTC vperked#0 Rivarge<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:57 UTC xewdy#0 diamondcdm<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:59 UTC vperked#0 i cant spell it<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:00 UTC hebeatsme#0 rivage<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:08 UTC .yarrb#0 yes<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:14 UTC hebeatsme#0 i have him added<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:20 UTC hebeatsme#0 hes on discord still<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:47 UTC .yarrb#0 hes focused on stroking zaddy elon<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:47 UTC vperked#0 https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Coristine<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:50 UTC vperked#0 no fucking way<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:53 UTC vperked#0 they even made a wiki for him<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:55 UTC vperked#0 LOOOL<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:05 UTC hebeatsme#0 no way<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:08 UTC hebeatsme#0 hes not a good dev either<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:14 UTC hebeatsme#0 like????<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:22 UTC hebeatsme#0 has to be fake<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:24 UTC xewdy#0 and theyre saying ts<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:29 UTC xewdy#0 like ok bro<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:51 UTC .yarrb#0 now i wanna know what all the other devs are like&#8230;<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:00 UTC vperked#0 &#8220;`Coristine used the moniker &#8220;bigballs&#8221; on LinkedIn and @Edwardbigballer on Twitter, according to The Daily Dot.[&#8220;`<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:05 UTC vperked#0 LOL<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:06 UTC hebeatsme#0 lmfaooo<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:07 UTC vperked#0 bro<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:10 UTC hebeatsme#0 bro<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:17 UTC hebeatsme#0 has to be fake right<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:22 UTC .yarrb#0 does it mention Rivage?<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:23 UTC xewdy#0 He previously worked for NeuraLink, a brain computer interface company led by Elon Musk<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:26 UTC xewdy#0 bro what<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:27 UTC alexaloo#0 I think your current occupation gives you a good insight of what probably goes on<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:29 UTC hebeatsme#0 bullshit man<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:33 UTC xewdy#0 this nigga got hella secrets<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:37 UTC hebeatsme#0 rivage couldnt print hello world<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:42 UTC hebeatsme#0 if his life was on the line<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:50 UTC xewdy#0 nigga worked for neuralink<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:54 UTC hebeatsme#0 bullshit<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:06 UTC Nashville Dispatch ##0000 ||@PD Ping||<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:07 UTC hebeatsme#0 must have killed all those test pigs with some bugs<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:24 UTC hebeatsme#0 ur telling me the rivage who failed to start a company<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:28 UTC hebeatsme#0 https://cdn.camp<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:32 UTC hebeatsme#0 who didnt pay for servers<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:34 UTC hebeatsme#0 ?<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:42 UTC hebeatsme#0 was too cheap<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:44 UTC vperked#0 yes<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:50 UTC hebeatsme#0 like??<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:53 UTC hebeatsme#0 it aint adding up<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:56 UTC alexaloo#0 He just needed to find his calling idiot.<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:58 UTC alexaloo#0 He found it.<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:59 UTC hebeatsme#0 bro<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:01 UTC alexaloo#0 Cope in a river dude<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:04 UTC hebeatsme#0 he cant make good money right<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:08 UTC hebeatsme#0 doge is about efficiency<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:11 UTC hebeatsme#0 he should make $1/he<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:15 UTC hebeatsme#0 $1/hr<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:25 UTC hebeatsme#0 and be whipped for better code<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:26 UTC vperked#0 prolly makes more than us<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:35 UTC vperked#0 with his dad too<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:52 UTC hebeatsme#0 time to report him for fraud<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:54 UTC hebeatsme#0 to donald trump<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:04 UTC hebeatsme#0 rivage participated in sim swap hacks in 2018<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:08 UTC hebeatsme#0 put that on his wiki<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:10 UTC hebeatsme#0 thanks<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:15 UTC hebeatsme#0 and in 2021<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:17 UTC hebeatsme#0 thanks<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:19 UTC chainofcommand#0 i dont think they&#8217;ll care tbh</p></blockquote>
<p>Given the speed with which Musk&#8217;s DOGE team was allowed access to such critical government databases, it strains credulity that Coristine could have been properly cleared beforehand. After all, he&#8217;d recently been dismissed from a job <em>for allegedly leaking internal company information to outsiders</em>.</p>
<p>According to the national security adjudication <a href="https://www.dni.gov/files/NCSC/documents/Regulations/SEAD-4-Adjudicative-Guidelines-U.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">guidelines</a> (PDF) released by the <strong>Director of National Intelligence</strong> (DNI), eligibility determinations take into account a person&#8217;s stability, trustworthiness, reliability, discretion, character, honesty, judgment, and ability to protect classified information.</p>
<p>The DNI policy further states that &#8220;eligibility for covered individuals shall be granted only when facts and circumstances indicate that eligibility is clearly consistent with the national security interests of the United States, and any doubt shall be resolved in favor of national security.&#8221;</p>
<p>On Thursday, 25-year-old DOGE staff member <strong>Marko Elez</strong> resigned after being linked to a deleted social media account that advocated racism and eugenics. Elez resigned after <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/doge-staffer-resigns-over-racist-posts-d9f11a93" target="_blank" rel="noopener">asked</a> the White House about his connection to the account.</p>
<p>&#8220;Just for the record, I was racist before it was cool,” the account posted in July. &#8220;You could not pay me to marry outside of my ethnicity,” the account wrote on X in September. &#8220;Normalize Indian hate,&#8221; the account wrote the same month, in reference to a post noting the prevalence of people from India in Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>Elez&#8217;s resignation came a day after the Department of Justice agreed to limit the number of DOGE employees who have access to federal payment systems. The DOJ said access would be limited to two people, Elez and <strong>Tom Krause</strong>, the CEO of a company called Cloud Software Group.</p>
<p>Earlier today, Musk <a href="https://thehill.com/business/5133430-elon-musk-doge-staffer-racist-posts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said he planned to rehire Elez</a> after <strong>President Trump</strong> and <strong>Vice President JD Vance</strong> reportedly endorsed the idea. Speaking at The White House today, Trump said he wasn&#8217;t concerned about the security of personal information and other data accessed by DOGE, adding that he was &#8220;very proud of the job that this group of young people&#8221; are doing.</p>
<p>A White House official <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/staffer-with-elon-musks-doge-amplified-white-supremacists-online-2025-02-07/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told</a> <em>Reuters</em> on Wednesday that Musk and his engineers have appropriate security clearances and are operating in &#8220;full compliance with federal law, appropriate security clearances, and as employees of the relevant agencies, not as outside advisors or entities.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>NPR</em> <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/02/07/nx-s1-5288988/doge-elon-musk-staff-trump" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> Trump added that his administration&#8217;s cost-cutting efforts would soon turn to the Education Department and the Pentagon, &#8220;where he suggested without evidence that there could be &#8216;trillions&#8217; of dollars in wasted spending within the $6.75 trillion the federal government spent in fiscal year 2024.&#8221;</p>
<p>GOP leaders in the Republican-controlled House and Senate have largely shrugged about Musk&#8217;s ongoing efforts to seize control over federal databases, dismantle agencies mandated by Congress, freeze federal spending on a range of already-appropriated government programs, and threaten workers with layoffs.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, multiple parties have sued to stop DOGE&#8217;s activities. ABC News <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/judge-decide-block-doge-accessing-sensitive-labor-department/story?id=118575362" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> a federal judge was to rule today on whether DOGE should be blocked from accessing Department of Labor records, following a lawsuit alleging Musk&#8217;s team sought to illegally access highly sensitive data, including medical information, from the federal government.</p>
<p>At least 13 state attorneys general say they plan to file a lawsuit to stop DOGE from accessing federal payment systems containing Americans&#8217; sensitive personal information, <a href="https://www.mychamplainvalley.com/news/local-news/vermont-joins-lawsuit-over-doge-access-to-government-payment-system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> <em>The Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-treasury-temporarily-agrees-limit-doge-access-amid-privacy-lawsuit-2025-02-06/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported Thursday</a> that the U.S. Treasury Department had agreed not to give Musk&#8217;s team access to its payment systems while a judge is hearing arguments in a lawsuit by employee unions and retirees alleging Musk illegally searched those records.</p>
<p><em>Ars Technica</em> <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/02/lawsuit-tries-to-block-doges-access-to-student-loan-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that The Department of Education (DoE) was sued Friday by a California student association demanding an &#8220;immediate stop&#8221; to DOGE&#8217;s &#8220;unlawfully&#8221; digging through student loan data to potentially dismantle the DoE.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/teen-on-musks-doge-team-graduated-from-the-com/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>163</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experts Flag Security, Privacy Risks in DeepSeek AI App</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/experts-flag-security-privacy-risks-in-deepseek-ai-app/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/experts-flag-security-privacy-risks-in-deepseek-ai-app/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 21:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Hoog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app transport security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ByteDance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepseek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepseek AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NowSecure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volcengine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New mobile apps from the Chinese artificial intelligence (AI) company DeepSeek have remained among the top three "free" downloads for Apple and Google devices since their debut on Jan. 25, 2025. But experts caution that many of DeepSeek's design choices -- such as using hard-coded encryption keys, and sending unencrypted user and device data to Chinese companies -- introduce a number of glaring security and privacy risks.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New mobile apps from the Chinese artificial intelligence (AI) company <strong>DeepSeek</strong> have remained among the top three &#8220;free&#8221; downloads for Apple and Google devices since their debut on Jan. 25, 2025. But experts caution that many of DeepSeek&#8217;s design choices &#8212; such as using hard-coded encryption keys, and sending unencrypted user and device data to Chinese companies &#8212; introduce a number of glaring security and privacy risks.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-70327" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek.png" alt="" width="747" height="417" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek.png 854w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-768x428.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-782x436.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /></p>
<p>Public interest in the DeepSeek AI chat apps swelled following widespread <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/27/business/us-stock-market-deepseek-ai-sp500-nvidia.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">media</a> reports that the upstart Chinese AI firm had managed to match the abilities of cutting-edge chatbots while using a fraction of the specialized computer chips that leading AI companies rely on. As of this writing, DeepSeek is the third most-downloaded &#8220;free&#8221; app on the Apple store, and #1 on Google Play.</p>
<p>DeepSeek&#8217;s rapid rise caught the attention of the mobile security firm <strong>NowSecure</strong>, a Chicago-based company that helps clients screen mobile apps for security and privacy threats. In <a href="https://www.nowsecure.com/blog/2025/02/06/nowsecure-uncovers-multiple-security-and-privacy-flaws-in-deepseek-ios-mobile-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a teardown</a> of the DeepSeek app published today, NowSecure urged organizations to remove the DeepSeek iOS mobile app from their environments, citing security concerns.</p>
<p>NowSecure founder <strong>Andrew Hoog</strong> said they haven&#8217;t yet concluded an in-depth analysis of the DeepSeek app for <strong>Android</strong> devices, but that there is little reason to believe its basic design would be functionally much different.</p>
<p>Hoog told KrebsOnSecurity there were a number of qualities about the DeepSeek iOS app that suggest the presence of deep-seated security and privacy risks. For starters, he said, the app collects an awful lot of data about the user&#8217;s device.</p>
<p>&#8220;They are doing some very interesting things that are on the edge of advanced device fingerprinting,&#8221; Hoog said, noting that one property of the app tracks the device&#8217;s name &#8212; which for many iOS devices defaults to the customer&#8217;s name followed by the type of iOS device.</p>
<p>The device information shared, combined with the user&#8217;s Internet address and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/10/the-global-surveillance-free-for-all-in-mobile-ad-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">data gathered from mobile advertising companies</a>, could be used to deanonymize users of the DeepSeek iOS app, NowSecure warned. The report notes that DeepSeek communicates with <strong>Volcengine</strong>, a cloud platform developed by <strong>ByteDance</strong> (the makers of <strong>TikTok</strong>), although NowSecure said it wasn&#8217;t clear if the data is just leveraging ByteDance&#8217;s digital transformation cloud service or if the declared information share extends further between the two companies.</p>
<div id="attachment_70342" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70342" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70342" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic.png" alt="" width="750" height="327" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic.png 1634w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic-768x335.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic-1536x669.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic-782x341.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-70342" class="wp-caption-text">Image: NowSecure.</p></div>
<p>Perhaps more concerning, NowSecure said the iOS app transmits device information &#8220;in the clear,&#8221; without any encryption to encapsulate the data. This means the data being handled by the app could be intercepted, read, and even modified by anyone who has access to any of the networks that carry the app&#8217;s traffic.</p>
<p>&#8220;The DeepSeek iOS app globally disables App Transport Security (ATS) which is an iOS platform level protection that prevents sensitive data from being sent over unencrypted channels,&#8221; the report observed. &#8220;Since this protection is disabled, the app can (and does) send unencrypted data over the internet.&#8221;<span id="more-70323"></span></p>
<p>Hoog said the app does selectively encrypt portions of the responses coming from DeepSeek servers. But they also found it uses an insecure and now deprecated encryption algorithm called 3DES (aka <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triple_DES" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Triple DES</a>), and that the developers had hard-coded the encryption key. That means the cryptographic key needed to decipher those data fields can be extracted from the app itself.</p>
<p>There were other, less alarming security and privacy issues highlighted in the report, but Hoog said he&#8217;s confident there are additional, unseen security concerns lurking within the app&#8217;s code.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we see people exhibit really simplistic coding errors, as you dig deeper there are usually a lot more issues,&#8221; Hoog said. &#8220;There is virtually no priority around security or privacy. Whether cultural, or mandated by China, or a witting choice, taken together they point to significant lapse in security and privacy controls, and that puts companies at risk.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apparently, plenty of others share this view. <em>Axios</em> <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/01/30/house-congress-bans-deepseek-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> on January 30 that U.S. congressional offices are being warned not to use the app.</p>
<p>&#8220;[T]hreat actors are already exploiting DeepSeek to deliver malicious software and infect devices,&#8221; read the notice from the chief administrative officer for the House of Representatives. &#8220;To mitigate these risks, the House has taken security measures to restrict DeepSeek’s functionality on all House-issued devices.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>TechCrunch</em> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/03/deepseek-the-countries-and-agencies-that-have-banned-the-ai-companys-tech/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that Italy and Taiwan have already moved to ban DeepSeek over security concerns. <em>Bloomberg</em> <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-30/pentagon-workers-used-deepseek-s-chatbot-for-days-before-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that <strong>The Pentagon</strong> has blocked access to DeepSeek. <em>CNBC</em> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/01/31/nasa-becomes-latest-federal-agency-to-block-chinas-deepseek.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> <strong>NASA</strong> also banned employees from using the service, as did the <strong>U.S. Navy</strong>.</p>
<p>Beyond security concerns tied to the DeepSeek iOS app, there are indications the Chinese AI company may be playing fast and loose with the data that it collects from and about users. On January 29, researchers at <strong>Wiz</strong> <a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/wiz-research-uncovers-exposed-deepseek-database-leak" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> they discovered a publicly accessible database linked to DeepSeek that exposed &#8220;a significant volume of chat history, backend data and sensitive information, including log streams, API secrets, and operational details.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;More critically, the exposure allowed for full database control and potential privilege escalation within the DeepSeek environment, without any authentication or defense mechanism to the outside world,&#8221; Wiz wrote. [Full disclosure: Wiz is currently an advertiser on this website.]</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity sought comment on the report from DeepSeek and from Apple. This story will be updated with any substantive replies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/experts-flag-security-privacy-risks-in-deepseek-ai-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who&#8217;s Behind the Seized Forums &#8216;Cracked&#8217; &#038; &#8216;Nulled&#8217;?</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/whos-behind-the-seized-forums-cracked-nulled/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/whos-behind-the-seized-forums-cracked-nulled/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 17:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1337 Services Gmbh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AS210558]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Constella Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cracked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DreamDrive GmbH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finn Alexander Grimpe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finn@shoppy.gg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finndev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[floriaN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florian Marzahl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HRB 164175]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel 471]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucas Sohn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northdata.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nulled]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olivia.messla@outlook.de]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operation Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sellix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shoppy Ecommerce Ltd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[StarkRDP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The FBI joined authorities across Europe last week in seizing domain names for Cracked and Nulled, English-language cybercrime forums with millions of users that trafficked in stolen data, hacking tools and malware. An investigation into the history of these communities shows their apparent co-founders quite openly operate an Internet service provider and a pair of e-commerce platforms catering to buyers and sellers on both forums.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>FBI</strong> joined authorities across Europe last week in seizing domain names for <strong>Cracked</strong> and <strong>Nulled</strong>, English-language cybercrime forums with millions of users that trafficked in stolen data, hacking tools and malware. An investigation into the history of these communities shows their apparent co-founders quite openly operate an Internet service provider and a pair of e-commerce platforms catering to buyers and sellers on both forums.</p>
<div id="attachment_70283" style="width: 755px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70283" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70283" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/cracked-to.png" alt="" width="745" height="774" /><p id="caption-attachment-70283" class="wp-caption-text">In this 2019 post from Cracked, a forum moderator told the author of the post (Buddie) that the owner of the RDP service was the founder of Nulled, a.k.a. &#8220;Finndev.&#8221; Image: Ke-la.com.</p></div>
<p>On Jan. 30, the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/cracked-and-nulled-marketplaces-disrupted-international-cyber-operation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> it seized eight domain names that were used to operate Cracked, a cybercrime forum that sprang up in 2018 and attracted more than four million users. The DOJ said the law enforcement action, dubbed <a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-takes-down-two-largest-cybercrime-forums-in-world" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Operation Talent</a>, also seized domains tied to <strong>Sellix</strong>, Cracked&#8217;s payment processor.</p>
<p>In addition, the government seized the domain names for two popular anonymity services that were heavily advertised on Cracked and Nulled and allowed customers to rent virtual servers: <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210924052821/https://starkrdp.io/imprint.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StarkRDP[.]io</a>, and <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210306133432/https://rdp.sh/imprint" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rdp[.]sh</a>.</p>
<p>Those archived webpages show both RDP services were owned by an entity called <strong>1337 Services Gmbh</strong>. According to <a href="https://www.northdata.com/1337%20Services%20GmbH,%20Hamburg/HRB%20164175" target="_blank" rel="noopener">corporate records</a> compiled by <strong>Northdata.com</strong>, 1337 Services GmbH is also known as <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211215172634/https://as210558.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>AS210558</strong></a> and is incorporated in Hamburg, Germany.</p>
<p>The Cracked forum administrator went by the nicknames &#8220;<strong>FlorainN</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>StarkRDP</strong>&#8221; on multiple cybercrime forums. Meanwhile, a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/florian-m-095a0183/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LinkedIn profile</a> for a <strong>Florian M</strong>. from Germany refers to this person as the co-founder of Sellix and founder of 1337 Services GmbH.</p>
<p>Northdata&#8217;s business profile for 1337 Services GmbH shows the company is controlled by two individuals: 32-year-old <strong>Florian Marzahl</strong> and <strong>Finn Alexander Grimpe</strong>, 28.</p>
<div id="attachment_70281" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/1337servicesGmbH.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70281" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70281" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/1337servicesGmbH.png" alt="" width="749" height="312" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/1337servicesGmbH.png 2234w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/1337servicesGmbH-768x320.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/1337servicesGmbH-1536x639.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/1337servicesGmbH-2048x853.png 2048w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/1337servicesGmbH-782x326.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-70281" class="wp-caption-text">An organization chart showing the owners of 1337 Services GmbH as Florian Marzahl and Finn Grimpe. Image: Northdata.com.</p></div>
<p>Neither Marzahl nor Grimpe responded to requests for comment. But Grimpe&#8217;s first name is interesting because it corresponds to the nickname chosen by the founder of Nulled, who goes by the monikers &#8220;<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150224213016/http://www.finn.lu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Finn</a>&#8221; and &#8220;<a href="https://github.com/finndev" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Finndev</a>.&#8221; NorthData reveals that Grimpe was the founder of a German entity called <strong>DreamDrive GmbH</strong>, which rented out <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210627121102/https://dreamdrive-rent.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">high-end sports cars and motorcycles</a>.</p>
<p>According to the cyber intelligence firm <a href="https://www.intel471.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel 471</a>, a user named Finndev registered on multiple cybercrime forums, including <strong>Raidforums</strong> [<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/raidforums-get-raided-alleged-admin-arrested/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seized by the FBI in 2022</a>], <strong>Void[.]to</strong>, and <strong>vDOS</strong>, a DDoS-for-hire service that was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/alleged-vdos-proprietors-arrested-in-israel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shut down in 2016 after its founders were arrested</a>.</p>
<p>The email address used for those accounts was <strong>f.grimpe@gmail.com</strong>. <a href="https://www.domaintools.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DomainTools.com</a> reports f.grimpe@gmail.com was used to register at least nine domain names, including <strong>nulled[.]lol</strong> and <strong>nulled[.]it</strong>. Neither of these domains were among those seized in Operation Talent.</p>
<p>Intel471 finds the user FlorainN registered across multiple cybercrime forums using the email address <strong>olivia.messla@outlook.de</strong>. The breach tracking service <a href="https://www.constella.ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Constella Intelligence</a> says this email address used the same password (and slight variations of it) across many accounts online &#8212; including at hacker forums &#8212; and that the same password was used in connection with dozens of other email addresses, such as <strong>florianmarzahl@hotmail.de, </strong>and <strong>fmarzahl137@gmail.com</strong>.<span id="more-70279"></span></p>
<p>The Justice Department said the Nulled marketplace had more than five million members, and has been selling stolen login credentials, stolen identification documents and hacking services, as well as tools for carrying out cybercrime and fraud, since 2016.</p>
<p>Perhaps fittingly, both Cracked and Nulled have been hacked over the years, exposing countless private messages between forum users. A review of those messages archived by Intel 471 showed that dozens of early forum members referred privately to Finndev as the owner of <strong>shoppy[.]gg</strong>, an e-commerce platform that caters to the same clientele as Sellix.</p>
<p>Shoppy was not targeted as part of Operation Talent, and its website remains online. Northdata <a href="https://www.northdata.com/Shoppy%20Ecommerce%20Ltd%C2%B7,%20Gan-Ner/ICA-515912517" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that Shoppy&#8217;s business name &#8212; <strong>Shoppy Ecommerce Ltd.</strong> &#8212; is registered at an address in Gan-Ner, Israel, but there is no ownership information about this entity. Shoppy did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<p>Constella found that a user named Shoppy registered on Cracked in 2019 using the email address <strong>finn@shoppy[.]gg</strong>. Constella says that email address is tied to <a href="https://x.com/shoppyecommerce" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a Twitter/X account</a> for Shoppy Ecommerce in Israel.</p>
<p>The DOJ said one of the alleged administrators of Nulled, a 29-year-old Argentinian national named <strong>Lucas Sohn</strong>, was arrested in Spain. The government has not announced any other arrests or charges associated with Operation Talent.</p>
<p>Indeed, both StarkRDP and FloraiN have posted to their accounts on <strong>Telegram</strong> that there were no charges levied against the proprietors of 1337 Services GmbH. FlorainN told former customers they were in the process of moving to a new name and domain for StarkRDP, where existing accounts and balances would be transferred.</p>
<p>&#8220;StarkRDP has always been operating by the law and is not involved in any of these alleged crimes and the legal process will confirm this,&#8221; the StarkRDP Telegram account wrote on January 30. &#8220;All of your servers are safe and they have not been collected in this operation. The only things that were seized is the website server and our domain. Unfortunately, no one can tell who took it and with whom we can talk about it. Therefore, we will restart operation soon, under a different name, to close the chapter [of] &#8216;StarkRDP.'&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/whos-behind-the-seized-forums-cracked-nulled/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FBI, Dutch Police Disrupt &#8216;Manipulaters&#8217; Phishing Gang</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/fbi-dutch-police-disrupt-manipulaters-phishing-gang/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/fbi-dutch-police-disrupt-manipulaters-phishing-gang/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 18:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BEC fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business email compromise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cracked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch National Police]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FudCo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fudpage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fudtools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HeartSender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operation Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saim Raza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sellix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Manipulaters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeCodeSolutions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The FBI and authorities in The Netherlands this week seized a number of servers and domains for a hugely popular spam and malware dissemination service operating out of Pakistan. The proprietors of the service, who use the collective nickname "The Manipulaters," have been the subject of three stories published here since 2015. The FBI said the main clientele are organized crime groups that try to trick victim companies into making payments to a third party.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The FBI and authorities in The Netherlands this week seized dozens of servers and domains for a hugely popular spam and malware dissemination service operating out of Pakistan. The proprietors of the service, who use the collective nickname &#8220;<strong>The Manipulaters</strong>,&#8221; have been the subject of three stories published here since 2015. The FBI said the main clientele are organized crime groups that try to trick victim companies into making payments to a third party.</p>
<div id="attachment_56857" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-56857" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-56857" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit.png" alt="" width="749" height="530" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit.png 1208w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit-768x544.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit-782x553.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-56857" class="wp-caption-text">One of several current Fudtools sites run by the principals of The Manipulators.</p></div>
<p>On January 29, the FBI and the Dutch national police seized the technical infrastructure for a cybercrime service marketed under the brands <strong>Heartsender</strong>, <strong>Fudpage</strong> and <strong>Fudtools</strong> (and many other &#8220;fud&#8221; variations). The &#8220;fud&#8221; bit stands for &#8220;Fully Un-Detectable,&#8221; and it refers to cybercrime resources that will evade detection by security tools like antivirus software or anti-spam appliances.</p>
<p>The Dutch authorities <a href="https://www.politie.nl/nieuws/2025/januari/27/09-verstoringsactie-deelt-klap-uit-aan-crimineel-cybernetwerk-heartsender.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> 39 servers and domains abroad were seized, and that the servers contained millions of records from victims worldwide &#8212; including at least 100,000 records pertaining to Dutch citizens.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdtx/pr/cybercrime-websites-selling-hacking-tools-transnational-organized-crime-groups-seized" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> from the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> refers to the cybercrime group as <strong>Saim Raza</strong>, after a pseudonym The Manipulaters communally used to promote their spam, malware and phishing services on social media.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Saim Raza-run websites operated as marketplaces that advertised and facilitated the sale of tools such as phishing kits, scam pages and email extractors often used to build and maintain fraud operations,&#8221; the DOJ explained.</p>
<p>The core Manipulaters product is <strong>Heartsender</strong>, a spam delivery service whose homepage openly advertised phishing kits targeting users of various Internet companies, including <strong>Microsoft 365</strong>, <strong>Yahoo</strong>, <strong>AOL</strong>, <strong>Intuit</strong>, <strong>iCloud</strong> and <strong>ID.me</strong>, to name a few.</p>
<p>The government says transnational organized crime groups that purchased these services primarily used them to run <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/business-email-compromise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">business email compromise</a> (BEC) schemes, wherein the cybercrime actors tricked victim companies into making payments to a third party.</p>
<p>&#8220;Those payments would instead be redirected to a financial account the perpetrators controlled, resulting in significant losses to victims,&#8221; the DOJ wrote. &#8220;These tools were also used to acquire victim user credentials and utilize those credentials to further these fraudulent schemes. The seizure of these domains is intended to disrupt the ongoing activity of these groups and stop the proliferation of these tools within the cybercriminal community.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_67010" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-67010" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-67010" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/manipulaters-o365.png" alt="" width="748" height="291" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/manipulaters-o365.png 1097w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/manipulaters-o365-768x299.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/manipulaters-o365-782x304.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-67010" class="wp-caption-text">Manipulaters advertisement for “Office 365 Private Page with Antibot” phishing kit sold via Heartsender. “Antibot” refers to functionality that attempts to evade automated detection techniques, keeping a phish deployed and accessible as long as possible. Image: DomainTools.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity first wrote about The Manipulaters <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/05/phishing-gang-is-audacious-manipulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in May 2015</a>, mainly because their ads at the time were blanketing a number of popular cybercrime forums, and because they were fairly open and brazen about what they were doing &#8212; even who they were in real life.</p>
<p>We caught up with The Manipulaters again in 2021, with <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/09/fudco-spam-empire-tied-to-pakistani-software-firm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a story</a> that found the core employees had started a web coding company in Lahore called <strong>WeCodeSolutions</strong> &#8212; presumably as a way to account for their considerable Heartsender income. That piece examined how WeCodeSolutions employees had all doxed themselves on Facebook by posting pictures from company parties each year featuring a large cake with the words <strong>FudCo</strong> written in icing.<span id="more-70250"></span></p>
<p>A <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/04/the-manipulaters-improve-phishing-still-fail-at-opsec/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">follow-up story last year</a> about The Manipulaters prompted messages from various WeCodeSolutions employees who pleaded with this publication to remove stories about them. The Saim Raza identity told KrebsOnSecurity they were recently released from jail after being arrested and charged by local police, although they declined to elaborate on the charges.</p>
<p>The Manipulaters never seemed to care much about protecting their own identities, so it&#8217;s not surprising that they were unable or unwilling to protect their own customers. In <a href="https://www.domaintools.com/resources/blog/the-resurgence-of-the-manipulaters-team-breaking-heartsenders?utm_source=Krebs-on-Security" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an analysis</a> released last year, <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> found the web-hosted version of Heartsender leaked an extraordinary amount of user information to unauthenticated users, including customer credentials and email records from Heartsender employees.</p>
<div id="attachment_56860" style="width: 761px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-56860" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-56860" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcocake.png" alt="" width="751" height="773" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcocake.png 834w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcocake-768x790.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcocake-782x805.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 751px) 100vw, 751px" /><p id="caption-attachment-56860" class="wp-caption-text">Almost every year since their founding, The Manipulaters have posted a picture of a FudCo cake from a company party celebrating its anniversary.</p></div>
<p>DomainTools also uncovered evidence that the computers used by The Manipulaters were all infected with the same password-stealing malware, and that vast numbers of credentials were stolen from the group and sold online.</p>
<p>&#8220;Ironically, the Manipulaters may create more short-term risk to their own customers than law enforcement,&#8221; DomainTools wrote. &#8220;The data table &#8216;User Feedbacks&#8217; (sic) exposes what appear to be customer authentication tokens, user identifiers, and even a customer support request that exposes root-level SMTP credentials–all visible by an unauthenticated user on a Manipulaters-controlled domain.&#8221;</p>
<p>Police in The Netherlands said the investigation into the owners and customers of the service is ongoing.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Cybercrime Team is on the trail of a number of buyers of the tools,&#8221; the Dutch national police said. &#8220;Presumably, these buyers also include Dutch nationals. The investigation into the makers and buyers of this phishing software has not yet been completed with the seizure of the servers and domains.&#8221;</p>
<p>U.S. authorities this week also joined law enforcement in Australia, France, Greece, Italy, Romania and Spain in seizing a number of domains for several long-running cybercrime forums and services, including <strong>Cracked</strong> and <strong>Nulled</strong>. According to <a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-takes-down-two-largest-cybercrime-forums-in-world" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a statement</a> from the European police agency <strong>Europol</strong>, the two communities attracted more than 10 million users in total.</p>
<p>Other domains seized as part of &#8220;<strong>Operation Talent</strong>&#8221; included <strong>Sellix</strong>, an e-commerce platform that was frequently used by cybercrime forum members to buy and sell illicit goods and services.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/fbi-dutch-police-disrupt-manipulaters-phishing-gang/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Infrastructure Laundering: Blending in with the Cloud</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/infrastructure-laundering-blending-in-with-the-cloud/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/infrastructure-laundering-blending-in-with-the-cloud/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ACB Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anjie CDN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crowell & Moring LLP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fangneng CDN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funnull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infrastructure laundering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NETSCOUT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NoName057(16)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polyfill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richard Hummel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suncity Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70065</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an effort to blend in and make their malicious traffic tougher to block, hosting firms catering to cybercriminals in China and Russia increasingly are funneling their operations through major U.S. cloud providers. Research published this week on one such outfit -- a sprawling network tied to Chinese organized crime gangs and aptly named "Funnull" -- highlights a persistent whac-a-mole problem facing cloud services.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_70230" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70230" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70230" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss.png" alt="" width="749" height="452" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss.png 1319w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss-768x463.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss-782x472.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70230" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, ArtHead.</p></div>
<p>In an effort to blend in and make their malicious traffic tougher to block, hosting firms catering to cybercriminals in China and Russia increasingly are funneling their operations through major U.S. cloud providers. Research published this week on one such outfit &#8212; a sprawling network tied to Chinese organized crime gangs and aptly named &#8220;<strong>Funnull</strong>&#8221; &#8212; highlights a persistent whac-a-mole problem facing cloud services.</p>
<p>In October 2024, the security firm <strong>Silent Push</strong> published a <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/triad-nexus-funnull/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lengthy analysis</a> of how <strong>Amazon AWS</strong> and <strong>Microsoft Azure</strong> were providing services to Funnull, a two-year-old Chinese content delivery network that hosts a wide variety of fake trading apps, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/07/massive-losses-define-epidemic-of-pig-butchering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pig butchering scams</a>, gambling websites, and retail phishing pages.</p>
<p>Funnull made headlines last summer after it acquired the domain name <strong>polyfill[.]io</strong>, previously the home of a widely-used open source code library that allowed older browsers to handle advanced functions that weren&#8217;t natively supported. There were still tens of thousands of legitimate domains linking to the Polyfill domain at the time of its acquisition, and Funnull soon after <a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/07/384000-sites-link-to-code-library-caught-performing-supply-chain-attack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conducted a supply-chain attack that redirected visitors to malicious sites</a>.</p>
<p>Silent Push&#8217;s October 2024 report found a vast number of domains hosted via Funnull promoting gambling sites that bear the logo of the <strong>Suncity Group</strong>, a Chinese entity named in <a href="https://www.unodc.org/roseap/uploads/documents/Publications/2024/Casino_Underground_Banking_Report_2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2024 UN report</a> (PDF) for laundering millions of dollars for the North Korean <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lazarus_Group" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lazarus Group</a>.</p>
<p>In 2023, Suncity’s CEO was <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/business/companies/ex-suncity-boss-alvin-chau-jailed-for-18-years-in-macau-20230118-p5cdmj.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sentenced to 18 years in prison</a> on charges of fraud, illegal gambling, and “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triad_(organized_crime)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">triad</a> offenses,” i.e. working with Chinese transnational organized crime syndicates. Suncity is alleged to have built an underground banking system that <a href="https://macaonews.org/news/city/former-suncity-boss-alvin-chau-sentenced-to-18-years-in-prison/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">laundered billions of dollars for criminals</a>.</p>
<p>It is likely the gambling sites coming through Funnull are abusing top casino brands as part of their money laundering schemes. In reporting on Silent Push&#8217;s October report, <em>TechCrunch</em> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/10/22/researchers-link-polyfill-supply-chain-attack-to-huge-network-of-copycat-gambling-sites/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">obtained</a> a comment from Bwin, one of the casinos being advertised en masse through Funnull, and Bwin said those websites did not belong to them.</p>
<p>Gambling is illegal in China except in Macau, a special administrative region of China. Silent Push researchers say Funnull may be helping online gamblers in China evade the Communist party&#8217;s &#8220;Great Firewall,&#8221; which blocks access to gambling destinations.</p>
<p>Silent Push&#8217;s <strong>Zach Edwards</strong> said that upon <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/infrastructure-laundering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revisiting Funnull&#8217;s infrastructure again this month</a>, they found dozens of the same Amazon and Microsoft cloud Internet addresses still forwarding Funnull traffic through a dizzying chain of auto-generated domain names before redirecting malicious or phishous websites.</p>
<p>Edwards said Funnull is a textbook example of an increasing trend Silent Push calls &#8220;infrastructure laundering,&#8221; wherein crooks selling cybercrime services will relay some or all of their malicious traffic through U.S. cloud providers.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s crucial for global hosting companies based in the West to wake up to the fact that extremely low quality and suspicious web hosts based out of China are deliberately renting IP space from multiple companies and then mapping those IPs to their criminal client websites,&#8221; Edwards told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;We need these major hosts to create internal policies so that if they are renting IP space to one entity, who further rents it to host numerous criminal websites, all of those IPs should be reclaimed and the CDN who purchased them should be banned from future IP rentals or purchases.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70232" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70232" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70232" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/suncity-funnull.png" alt="" width="750" height="370" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/suncity-funnull.png 958w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/suncity-funnull-768x379.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/suncity-funnull-782x386.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70232" class="wp-caption-text">A Suncity gambling site promoted via Funnull. The sites feature a prompt for a Tether/USDT deposit program.</p></div>
<p>Reached for comment, Amazon referred this reporter to a statement Silent Push included in <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/infrastructure-laundering" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a report released today</a>. Amazon said AWS was already aware of the Funnull addresses tracked by Silent Push, and that it had suspended all known accounts linked to the activity.</p>
<p>Amazon said that contrary to implications in the Silent Push report, it has every reason to aggressively police its network against this activity, noting the accounts tied to Funnull used &#8220;fraudulent methods to temporarily acquire infrastructure, for which it never pays. Thus, AWS incurs damages as a result of the abusive activity.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;When AWS&#8217;s automated or manual systems detect potential abuse, or when we receive reports of potential abuse, we act quickly to investigate and take action to stop any prohibited activity,&#8221; Amazon&#8217;s statement continues. &#8220;In the event anyone suspects that AWS resources are being used for abusive activity, we encourage them to report it to AWS Trust &amp; Safety using the <a href="https://support.aws.amazon.com/#/contacts/report-abuse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">report abuse form</a>. In this case, the authors of the report never notified AWS of the findings of their research via our easy-to-find security and abuse reporting channels. Instead, AWS first learned of their research from a journalist to whom the researchers had provided a draft.&#8221;</p>
<p>Microsoft likewise said it takes such abuse seriously, and encouraged others to report suspicious activity found on its network.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are committed to protecting our customers against this kind of activity and actively enforce acceptable use policies when violations are detected,&#8221; Microsoft said in a written statement. &#8220;We encourage <a href="https://protect.checkpoint.com/v2/r01/___https://msrc.microsoft.com/report/___.YzJ1OndlY29tbXVuaWNhdGlvbnM6YzpvOjQwMWQyNWE1OWIxMDNiNWUyZGQ5ZmY2MmZiYTMxMTNiOjc6NDRlNzoyZDg4NzY5MmI4MGVmYWY2M2NmZWVjOGMxMjhkNTRhYjhmODc4Mzk3MjJkYjdkMTEzMjk0MDdmMzA4NDUxNDczOmg6VDpG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reporting</a> suspicious activity to Microsoft so we can investigate and take appropriate actions.&#8221;<span id="more-70065"></span></p>
<p><strong>Richard Hummel</strong> is threat intelligence lead at <strong>NETSCOUT</strong>. Hummel said it used to be that &#8220;noisy&#8221; and frequently disruptive malicious traffic &#8212; such as automated application layer attacks, and &#8220;brute force&#8221; efforts to crack passwords or find vulnerabilities in websites &#8212; came mostly from botnets, or large collections of hacked devices.</p>
<p>But he said the vast majority of the infrastructure used to funnel this type of traffic is now proxied through major cloud providers, which can make it difficult for organizations to block at the network level.</p>
<p>&#8220;From a defenders point of view, you can&#8217;t wholesale block cloud providers, because a single IP can host thousands or tens of thousands of domains,&#8221; Hummel said.</p>
<p>In May 2024, KrebsOnSecurity published <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-an-iron-hammer-in-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a deep dive on Stark Industries Solutions</a>, an ISP that materialized at the start of Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine and has been used as a global proxy network that conceals the true source of cyberattacks and disinformation campaigns against enemies of Russia. Experts said much of the malicious traffic  traversing Stark&#8217;s network (e.g. vulnerability scanning and password brute force attacks) was being bounced through U.S.-based cloud providers.</p>
<p>Stark&#8217;s network has been a favorite of the Russian hacktivist group called <strong>NoName057(16)</strong>, which frequently launches huge distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks against a variety of targets seen as opposed to Moscow. Hummel said NoName&#8217;s history suggests they are adept at cycling through new cloud provider accounts, making anti-abuse efforts into a game of whac-a-mole.</p>
<p>&#8220;It almost doesn&#8217;t matter if the cloud provider is on point and takes it down because the bad guys will just spin up a new one,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Even if they&#8217;re only able to use it for an hour, they&#8217;ve already done their damage. It&#8217;s a really difficult problem.&#8221;</p>
<p>Edwards said Amazon declined to specify whether the banned Funnull users were operating using compromised accounts or stolen payment card data, or something else.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m surprised they wanted to lean into &#8216;We&#8217;ve caught this 1,200+ times and have taken these down!&#8217; and yet didn&#8217;t connect that each of those IPs was mapped to [the same] Chinese CDN,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We&#8217;re just thankful Amazon confirmed that account mules are being used for this and it isn&#8217;t some front-door relationship. We haven&#8217;t heard the same thing from Microsoft but it&#8217;s very likely that the same thing is happening.&#8221;</p>
<p>Funnull wasn&#8217;t always a bulletproof hosting network for scam sites. Prior to 2022, the network was known as <strong>Anjie CDN</strong>, based in the Philippines. One of Anjie&#8217;s properties was a website called <strong>funnull[.]app</strong>. Loading that domain reveals a pop-up message by the original Anjie CDN owner, who said their operations had been seized by an entity known as <strong>Fangneng CDN</strong> and <strong>ACB Group</strong>, the parent company of Funnull.</p>
<div id="attachment_70228" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70228" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70228" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app.png" alt="" width="749" height="533" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app.png 1079w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app-768x546.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app-782x556.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70228" class="wp-caption-text">A machine-translated message from the former owner of Anjie CDN, a Chinese content delivery network that is now Funnull.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;After I got into trouble, the company was managed by my family,&#8221; the message explains. &#8220;Because my family was isolated and helpless, they were persuaded by villains to sell the company. Recently, many companies have contacted my family and threatened them, believing that Fangneng CDN used penetration and mirroring technology through customer domain names to steal member information and financial transactions, and stole customer programs by renting and selling servers. This matter has nothing to do with me and my family. Please contact Fangneng CDN to resolve it.&#8221;</p>
<p>In January 2024, the <strong>U.S. Department of Commerce</strong> issued <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2024/01/29/2024-01580/taking-additional-steps-to-address-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-significant-malicious" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a proposed rule</a> that would require cloud providers to create a &#8220;Customer Identification Program&#8221; that includes procedures to collect data sufficient to determine whether each potential customer is a foreign or U.S. person.</p>
<p>According to the law firm <strong>Crowell &amp; Moring LLP</strong>, the Commerce rule also would require &#8220;infrastructure as a service&#8221; (IaaS) providers to report knowledge of any transactions with foreign persons that might allow the foreign entity to train a large AI model with potential capabilities that could be used in malicious cyber-enabled activity.</p>
<p>&#8220;The proposed rulemaking has garnered global attention, as its cross-border data collection requirements are unprecedented in the cloud computing space,&#8221; Crowell <a href="https://www.crowell.com/en/insights/client-alerts/who-iaas-your-foreign-customer-department-of-commerce-proposes-foreign-customer-identification-requirements-for-us-iaas-providers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>. &#8220;To the extent the U.S. alone imposes these requirements, there is concern that U.S. IaaS providers could face a competitive disadvantage, as U.S. allies have not yet announced similar foreign customer identification requirements.&#8221;</p>
<p>It remains unclear if the new White House administration will push forward with the requirements. The Commerce action was mandated as part of an executive order President Trump issued a day before leaving office in January 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/infrastructure-laundering-blending-in-with-the-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Tumultuous Week for Federal Cybersecurity Efforts</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-tumultuous-week-for-federal-cybersecurity-efforts/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-tumultuous-week-for-federal-cybersecurity-efforts/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 02:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alfa Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Sacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House Judiciary Committee's Select Subcommittee on the Weaponization of the Federal Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jack Goldsmith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Hall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Durham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Melania Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Sussman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quinta Jurecic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rep. Jim Jordan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Council on Transnational Organized Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Liberty Financial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Trump last week issued a flurry of executive orders that upended a number of government initiatives focused on improving the nation's cybersecurity posture. The president fired all advisors from the Department of Homeland Security's Cyber Safety Review Board, called for the creation of a strategic cryptocurrency reserve, and voided a Biden administration action that sought to reduce the risks that artificial intelligence poses to consumers, workers and national security.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_70185" style="width: 761px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70185" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70185" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/whitehousenight.png" alt="" width="751" height="495" /><p id="caption-attachment-70185" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock. Greg Meland.</p></div>
<p><strong>President Trump</strong> last week issued a flurry of executive orders that upended a number of government initiatives focused on improving the nation&#8217;s cybersecurity posture. The president fired all advisors from the Department of Homeland Security&#8217;s Cyber Safety Review Board, called for the creation of a strategic cryptocurrency reserve, and voided a Biden administration action that sought to reduce the risks that artificial intelligence poses to consumers, workers and national security.</p>
<p>On his first full day back in the White House, Trump dismissed all 15 advisory committee members of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyber_Safety_Review_Board" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cyber Safety Review Board</a> (CSRB), a nonpartisan government entity established in February 2022 with a mandate to investigate the causes of major cybersecurity events. The CSRB has so far produced three detailed reports, including an analysis of the <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/log4j-log4shell/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Log4Shell vulnerability</a> crisis, attacks from <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/lapsus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the cybercrime group LAPSUS$</a>, and the 2023 <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/resources-tools/resources/CSRB-Review-Summer-2023-MEO-Intrusion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Exchange Online breach</a>.</p>
<p>The CSRB was in the midst of an inquiry into cyber intrusions uncovered recently across a broad spectrum of U.S. telecommunications providers at the hands of Chinese state-sponsored hackers. One of the CSRB&#8217;s most recognizable names is <strong>Chris Krebs </strong>(no relation), the former director of the <strong>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA). Krebs was fired by President Trump in November 2020 for declaring the presidential contest was the most secure in American history, and for refuting Trump&#8217;s false claims of election fraud.</p>
<p>South Dakota Governor <strong>Kristi Noem</strong>, confirmed by the U.S. Senate last week as the new director of the DHS, criticized CISA at her confirmation hearing, <em>TheRecord</em> <a href="https://therecord.media/kristi-noem-cisa-smaller-nimble?utm_medium=email&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-80A9JU5jFUojRnewo-h4MRW17b74bMAW6oR5rGLelMqQ7jRJp3Ors1qYeq5RFK2jrpXM9V5J2o-RGJSorsePm_8KCvoZ8nFsrOw8h_pdBDQggry0c&amp;_hsmi=343361648&amp;utm_content=343361495&amp;utm_source=hs_email" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a>.</p>
<p>Noem told lawmakers CISA needs to be &#8220;much more effective, smaller, more nimble, to really fulfill their mission,&#8221; which she said should be focused on hardening federal IT systems and hunting for digital intruders. Noem said the agency&#8217;s work on fighting misinformation shows it has &#8220;gotten far off mission&#8221; and involved &#8220;using their resources in ways that was never intended.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The misinformation and disinformation that they have stuck their toe into and meddled with, should be refocused back onto what their job is,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p><strong>Moses Frost</strong>, a cybersecurity instructor with the SANS Institute, compared the sacking of the CSRB members to firing all of the experts at the <strong>National Transportation Safety Board</strong> (NTSB) while they&#8217;re in the middle of an investigation into a string of airline disasters.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don’t recall seeing an &#8216;NTSB Board&#8217; being fired during the middle of a plane crash investigation,&#8221; Frost said in a recent SANS newsletter. &#8220;I can say that the attackers in the phone companies will not stop because the review board has gone away. We do need to figure out how these attacks occurred, and CISA did appear to be doing some good for the vast majority of the federal systems.&#8221;</p>
<p>Speaking of transportation, <em>The Record</em> notes that Transportation Security Administration chief <strong>David Pekoske</strong> <a href="https://therecord.media/tsa-chief-behind-cyber-directives-ousted-trump-administration?utm_medium=email&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-_a5PHD4Ff2FlOiHIlYbcfVNbftiTItDbxlH5TxzCLZicEcan3et6L6nmVmhC57_5AXp-a1k45WwHO6jbVxejLlMjPtTTdVzGtbreDzSl6fzHhGdkg&amp;_hsmi=343497657&amp;utm_content=343496082&amp;utm_source=hs_email" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was fired</a> despite overseeing critical cybersecurity improvements across pipeline, rail and aviation sectors. Pekoske was appointed by Trump in 2017 and had his 5-year tenure renewed in 2022 by former President Joe Biden.</p>
<h2>AI &amp; CRYPTOCURRENCY</h2>
<p>Shortly after being sworn in for a second time, Trump voided a Biden executive order that focused on supporting research and development in artificial intelligence. The previous administration&#8217;s order on AI was crafted with an eye toward managing <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/PSA/2024/PSA241203" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the safety and security risks introduced by the technology</a>. But a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/01/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-takes-action-to-enhance-americas-ai-leadership/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> released by the White House said Biden&#8217;s approach to AI had hindered development, and that the United States would support AI systems that are &#8220;free from ideological bias or engineered social agendas,&#8221; to maintain leadership.</p>
<p>The Trump administration issued <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/01/fact-sheet-executive-order-to-establish-united-states-leadership-in-digital-financial-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its own executive order on AI</a>, which calls for an &#8220;AI Action Plan&#8221; to be led by the assistant to the president for science and technology, the White House &#8220;AI &amp; crypto czar,&#8221; and the national security advisor. It also directs the White House to revise and reissue policies to federal agencies on the government&#8217;s acquisition and governance of AI &#8220;to ensure that harmful barriers to America&#8217;s AI leadership are eliminated.&#8221;</p>
<p>Trump&#8217;s AI &amp; crypto czar is <strong>David Sacks</strong>, an entrepreneur and Silicon Valley venture capitalist who argues that the Biden administration&#8217;s approach to AI and cryptocurrency has driven innovation overseas. Sacks recently asserted that non-fungible cryptocurrency tokens and memecoins are neither securities nor commodities, but rather should be treated as &#8220;collectibles&#8221; like baseball cards and stamps.</p>
<p><span class="s1">There is already a legal definition of collectibles under the U.S. tax code that applies to things like art or antiques, which can be subject to high capital gains taxes. But <strong>Joe Hall</strong>, a capital markets attorney and partner at Davis Polk, <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/crypto-czar-david-sacks-says-224508277.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAL0Zay1PbdGAe14O3Q6FoNdB1zkg6wbzSRDfb7oPUC6Wd6zrQ6vU2RRSCVbDRAzdKV-8hUw3m5wdMKoCzprArK-YuIyoeEjJwTP3ZNk1AoW8dVIhp4KFD3-c9i7NrrUPaY3u2e2yLSFfzlqeJDnJ55BTbyBLHx9pM_KywC0pCxWf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told <em>Fortune</em></a> there are</span> no market regulations that apply to collectibles under U.S. securities law. Hall said Sacks’ comments “suggest a viewpoint that it would not be appropriate to regulate these things the way we regulate securities.”</p>
<p>The new administration&#8217;s position makes sense considering that the Trump family is deeply and personally invested in a number of recent memecoin ventures that have attracted billions from investors. President Trump and First Lady Melania Trump each launched their own vanity memecoins this month, dubbed <strong>$TRUMP</strong> and <strong>$MELANIA</strong>.</p>
<p><em>The Wall Street Journal</em> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/finance/trump-meme-coin-crypto-explained-c881afff" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported Thursday</a> the market capitalization of $TRUMP stood at about $7 billion, down from a peak of near $15 billion, while $MELANIA is hovering somewhere in the $460 million mark. Just two months before the 2024 election, Trump&#8217;s three sons debuted a cryptocurrency token called <strong>World Liberty Financial</strong>.</p>
<p>Despite maintaining a considerable personal stake in how cryptocurrency is regulated, Trump issued <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/01/fact-sheet-executive-order-to-establish-united-states-leadership-in-digital-financial-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an executive order on January 23</a> calling for a working group to be chaired by Sacks that would develop &#8220;a federal regulatory framework governing digital assets, including stablecoins,&#8221; and evaluate the creation of a &#8220;strategic national digital assets stockpile.&#8221;</p>
<p>Translation: Using taxpayer dollars to prop up the speculative, volatile, and highly risky cryptocurrency industry, which has been marked by endless scams, rug-pulls, 8-figure cyber heists, rampant fraud, and unrestrained innovations in money laundering.<span id="more-70172"></span></p>
<h2>WEAPONIZATION &amp; DISINFORMATION</h2>
<p>Prior to the election, President Trump frequently vowed to use a second term to exact retribution against his perceived enemies. Part of that promise materialized in an executive order Trump issued last week titled &#8220;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/ending-the-weaponization-of-the-federal-government/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ending the Weaponization of the Federal Government</a>,&#8221; which decried &#8220;an unprecedented, third-world weaponization of prosecutorial power to upend the democratic process,&#8221; in the prosecution of more than 1,500 people who invaded the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021.</p>
<p>On Jan. 21, Trump <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/justice-department/trump-set-pardon-defendants-stormed-capitol-jan-6-2021-rcna187735" target="_blank" rel="noopener">commuted the sentences</a> of several leaders of the Proud Boys and Oath Keepers who were convicted of seditious conspiracy. He also issued &#8220;a full, complete and unconditional pardon to all other individuals convicted of offenses related to events that occurred at or near the United States Capitol on January 6, 2021,&#8221; which include those who assaulted law enforcement officers.</p>
<p>The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/20/us/politics/weaponization-government-executive-order-trump.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> &#8220;the language of the document suggests — but does not explicitly state — that the Trump administration review will examine the actions of local district attorneys or state officials, such as the district attorneys in Manhattan or Fulton County, Ga., or the New York attorney general, all of whom filed cases against President Trump.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another Trump order called &#8220;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/restoring-freedom-of-speech-and-ending-federal-censorship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Restoring Freedom of Speech and Ending Federal Censorship</a>&#8221; asserts:</p>
<p>&#8220;Over the last 4 years, the previous administration trampled free speech rights by censoring Americans’ speech on online platforms, often by exerting substantial coercive pressure on third parties, such as social media companies, to moderate, deplatform, or otherwise suppress speech that the Federal Government did not approve,&#8221; the Trump administration alleged. &#8220;Under the guise of combatting &#8216;misinformation,&#8217; &#8216;disinformation,&#8217; and &#8216;malinformation,&#8217; the Federal Government infringed on the constitutionally protected speech rights of American citizens across the United States in a manner that advanced the Government’s preferred narrative about significant matters of public debate.&#8221;</p>
<p>Both of these executive orders have <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/katestarbird.bsky.social/post/3kdu7ucy3jd2f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">potential implications</a> for security, privacy and civil liberties activists who have sought to track conspiracy theories and raise awareness about disinformation efforts on social media coming from U.S. adversaries.</p>
<p>In the wake of the 2020 election, Republicans created the <strong>House Judiciary Committee&#8217;s Select Subcommittee on the Weaponization of the Federal Government</strong>. Led by GOP <strong>Rep. Jim Jordan</strong> of Ohio, the committee&#8217;s stated purpose was to investigate alleged collusion between the Biden administration and tech companies to unconstitutionally shut down political speech.</p>
<p>The GOP committee focused much of its ire at members of the short-lived <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disinformation_Governance_Board" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disinformation Governance Board</a>, an advisory board to DHS created in 2022 (the &#8220;combating misinformation, disinformation, and malinformation&#8221; quote from Trump&#8217;s executive order is a reference to the board&#8217;s stated mission). Conservative groups seized on social media posts made by the director of the board, who <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/05/21/1100438703/dhs-disinformation-board-nina-jankowicz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resigned</a> after facing death threats. The board was dissolved by DHS soon after.</p>
<p>In his first administration, President Trump created a special prosecutor to probe the origins of the FBI&#8217;s investigation into possible collusion between the Trump campaign and Russian operatives seeking to influence the 2016 election. Part of that inquiry examined evidence gathered by some of the world’s most renowned cybersecurity experts who identified <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/09/lawsuits-indictments-revive-trump-alfa-bank-story/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">frequent and unexplained communications</a> between an email server used by the <strong>Trump Organization</strong> and <strong>Alfa Bank</strong>, one of Russia’s largest financial institutions.</p>
<p>Trump&#8217;s Special Prosecutor <strong>John Durham</strong> later subpoenaed and/or deposed dozens of security experts who&#8217;d collected, viewed or merely commented on the data. Similar harassment and deposition demands would come from lawyers for Alfa Bank. Durham ultimately indicted <strong>Michael Sussman</strong>, the former federal cybercrime prosecutor who reported the oddity to the FBI. Sussman was acquitted in May 2022. Last week, Trump appointed Durham to lead the U.S. attorney&#8217;s office in Brooklyn, NY.</p>
<p><strong>Quinta Jurecic</strong> at <em>Lawfare</em> <a href="https://www.lawfaremedia.org/article/what-do-trump-s-weaponization-and-censorship-executive-orders-actually-do" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notes</a> that while the executive actions are ominous, they are also vague, and could conceivably generate either a campaign of retaliation, or nothing at all.</p>
<p>&#8220;The two orders establish that there will be investigations but leave open the questions of what kind of investigations, what will be investigated, how long this will take, and what the consequences might be,&#8221; Jurecic wrote. &#8220;It is difficult to draw firm conclusions as to what to expect. Whether this ambiguity is intentional or the result of sloppiness or disagreement within Trump’s team, it has at least one immediate advantage as far as the president is concerned: generating fear among the broad universe of potential subjects of those investigations.&#8221;</p>
<p>On Friday, Trump moved <a href="https://www.lawfaremedia.org/article/trump-fired-17-inspectors-general-was-it-legal" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to fire at least 17 inspectors general</a>, the government watchdogs who conduct audits and investigations of executive branch actions, and who often uncover instances of government waste, fraud and abuse. Lawfare&#8217;s <strong>Jack Goldsmith</strong> argues that the removals are probably legal even though Trump defied a 2022 law that required congressional notice of the terminations, which Trump did not give.</p>
<p>&#8220;Trump probably acted lawfully, I think, because the notice requirement is probably unconstitutional,&#8221; Goldsmith wrote. &#8220;The real bite in the 2022 law, however, comes in the limitations it places on Trump’s power <em>to replace</em> the terminated IGs—limitations that I believe are constitutional. This aspect of the law will make it hard, but not impossible, for Trump to put loyalists atop the dozens of vacant IG offices around the executive branch. The ultimate fate of IG independence during Trump 2.0, however, depends less on legal protections than on whether Congress, which traditionally protects IGs, stands up for them now. Don’t hold your breath.&#8221;</p>
<p>Among the many Biden administration executive orders revoked by President Trump last week was an action from December 2021 establishing the <strong>United States Council on Transnational Organized Crime</strong>, which is charged with advising the White House on a range of criminal activities, including drug and weapons trafficking, migrant smuggling, human trafficking, cybercrime, intellectual property theft, money laundering, wildlife and timber trafficking, illegal fishing, and illegal mining.</p>
<p>So far, the White House doesn&#8217;t appear to have revoked <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250117143627/https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2025/01/16/executive-order-on-strengthening-and-promoting-innovation-in-the-nations-cybersecurity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an executive order</a> that former President Biden issued less than a week before President Trump took office. On Jan. 16, 2025, Biden released a directive that focused on improving the security of federal agencies and contractors, and giving the government more power to sanction the hackers who target critical infrastructure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-tumultuous-week-for-federal-cybersecurity-efforts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>114</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MasterCard DNS Error Went Unnoticed for Years</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to Break Into Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akam.ne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akam.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Akamai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awsdns-06.ne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[az.mastercard.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bugcrowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CloudFlare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippe Caturegli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seralys]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The payment card giant MasterCard just fixed a glaring error in its domain name server settings that could have allowed anyone to intercept or divert Internet traffic for the company by registering an unused domain name. The misconfiguration persisted for nearly five years until a security researcher spent $300 to register the domain and prevent it from being grabbed by cybercriminals.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The payment card giant <strong>MasterCard</strong> just fixed a glaring error in its domain name server settings that could have allowed anyone to intercept or divert Internet traffic for the company by registering an unused domain name. The misconfiguration persisted for nearly five years until a security researcher spent $300 to register the domain and prevent it from being grabbed by cybercriminals.</p>
<div id="attachment_70128" style="width: 677px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70128" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70128" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/akamne.png" alt="" width="667" height="478" /><p id="caption-attachment-70128" class="wp-caption-text">A DNS lookup on the domain az.mastercard.com on Jan. 14, 2025 shows the mistyped domain name a22-65.akam.ne.</p></div>
<p>From June 30, 2020 until January 14, 2025, one of the core Internet servers that MasterCard uses to direct traffic for portions of the mastercard.com network was misnamed. MasterCard.com relies on five shared Domain Name System (DNS) servers at the Internet infrastructure provider <strong>Akamai </strong>[DNS acts as a kind of Internet phone book, by translating website names to numeric Internet addresses that are easier for computers to manage].</p>
<p>All of the Akamai DNS server names that MasterCard uses are supposed to end in &#8220;akam.net&#8221; but one of them was misconfigured to rely on the domain &#8220;<strong>akam.ne</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>This tiny but potentially critical typo was discovered recently by <strong>Philippe Caturegli</strong>, founder of the security consultancy <a href="https://www.seralys.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Seralys</a>. Caturegli said he guessed that nobody had yet registered the domain akam.ne, which is under the purview of the top-level domain authority for the West Africa nation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Niger</a>.</p>
<p>Caturegli said it took $300 and nearly three months of waiting to secure the domain with the registry in Niger. After enabling a DNS server on akam.ne, he noticed hundreds of thousands of DNS requests hitting his server each day from locations around the globe. Apparently, MasterCard wasn&#8217;t the only organization that had fat-fingered a DNS entry to include &#8220;akam.ne,&#8221; but they were by far the largest.</p>
<p>Had he enabled an email server on his new domain akam.ne, Caturegli likely would have received wayward emails directed toward mastercard.com or other affected domains. If he&#8217;d abused his access, he probably could have <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/local-networks-go-global-when-domain-names-collide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">obtained website encryption certificates (SSL/TLS certs)</a> that were authorized to accept and relay web traffic for affected websites. He may even have been able to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/02/dangerous-domain-corp-com-goes-up-for-sale/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">passively receive Microsoft Windows authentication credentials</a> from employee computers at affected companies.</p>
<p>But the researcher said he didn&#8217;t attempt to do any of that. Instead, he alerted MasterCard that the domain was theirs if they wanted it, copying this author on his notifications. A few hours later, MasterCard acknowledged the mistake, but said there was never any real threat to the security of its operations.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have looked into the matter and there was not a risk to our systems,&#8221; a MasterCard spokesperson wrote. &#8220;This typo has now been corrected.&#8221;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Caturegli received a request submitted through <strong>Bugcrowd</strong>, a program that offers financial rewards and recognition to security researchers who find flaws and work privately with the affected vendor to fix them. The message suggested his public disclosure of the MasterCard DNS error via <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a post on LinkedIn</a> (after he&#8217;d secured the akam.ne domain) was not aligned with ethical security practices, and passed on a request from MasterCard to have the post removed.</p>
<div id="attachment_70126" style="width: 718px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70126" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70126" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-response.png" alt="" width="708" height="855" /><p id="caption-attachment-70126" class="wp-caption-text">MasterCard&#8217;s request to Caturegli, a.k.a. &#8220;Titon&#8221; on infosec.exchange.</p></div>
<p>Caturegli said while he does have an account on Bugcrowd, he has never submitted anything through the Bugcrowd program, and that he reported this issue directly to MasterCard.</p>
<p>&#8220;I did not disclose this issue through Bugcrowd,&#8221; Caturegli wrote in reply. &#8220;Before making any public disclosure, I ensured that the affected domain was registered to prevent exploitation, mitigating any risk to MasterCard or its customers. This action, which we took at our own expense, demonstrates our commitment to ethical security practices and responsible disclosure.&#8221; <span id="more-70117"></span></p>
<p>Most organizations have at least two authoritative domain name servers, but some handle so many DNS requests that they need to spread the load over additional DNS server domains. In MasterCard&#8217;s case, that number is five, so it stands to reason that if an attacker managed to seize control over just one of those domains they would only be able to see about one-fifth of the overall DNS requests coming in.</p>
<p>But Caturegli said the reality is that many Internet users are relying at least to some degree on public traffic forwarders or DNS resolvers like <strong>Cloudflare</strong> and <strong>Google</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;So all we need is for one of these resolvers to query our name server and cache the result,&#8221; Caturegli said. By setting their DNS server records with a long TTL or &#8220;Time To Live&#8221; &#8212; a setting that can adjust the lifespan of data packets on a network &#8212; an attacker&#8217;s poisoned instructions for the target domain can be propagated by large cloud providers.</p>
<p>&#8220;With a long TTL, we may reroute a LOT more than just 1/5 of the traffic,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The researcher said he&#8217;d hoped that the credit card giant might thank him, or at least offer to cover the cost of buying the domain.</p>
<p>&#8220;We obviously disagree with this assessment,&#8221; Caturegli wrote in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285289297706909697%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285289297706909697%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a follow-up post</a> on LinkedIn regarding MasterCard&#8217;s public statement. &#8220;But we’ll let you judge— here are some of the DNS lookups we recorded before reporting the issue.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70125" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70125" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70125" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains.png" alt="" width="790" height="561" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains.png 790w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-768x545.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-782x555.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 790px) 100vw, 790px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70125" class="wp-caption-text">Caturegli posted this screenshot of MasterCard domains that were potentially at risk from the misconfigured domain.</p></div>
<p>As the screenshot above shows, the misconfigured DNS server Caturegli found involved the MasterCard subdomain <strong>az.mastercard.com</strong>. It is not clear exactly how this subdomain is used by MasterCard, however their naming conventions suggest the domains correspond to production servers at Microsoft&#8217;s <strong>Azure</strong> cloud service. Caturegli said the domains all resolve to Internet addresses at Microsoft.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don’t be like Mastercard,&#8221; Caturegli concluded in his LinkedIn post. &#8220;Don’t dismiss risk, and don’t let your marketing team handle security disclosures.&#8221;</p>
<p>One final note: The domain akam.ne has been registered previously &#8212; in December 2016 by someone using the email address um-i-delo@yandex.ru. The Russian search giant Yandex reports this user account belongs to an &#8220;Ivan I.&#8221; from Moscow. Passive DNS records from <a href="https://www.domaintools.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DomainTools.com</a> show that between 2016 and 2018 the domain was connected to an Internet server in Germany, and that the domain was left to expire in 2018.</p>
<p>This is interesting given <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285221445796835329%29&amp;replyUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285223757982363648%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285221445796835329%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29&amp;dashReplyUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285223757982363648%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a comment on Caturegli&#8217;s LinkedIn post from an ex-Cloudflare employee</a> who linked to a report he co-authored on a similar typo domain apparently registered in 2017 for organizations that may have mistyped their AWS DNS server as &#8220;<strong>awsdns-06.ne</strong>&#8221; instead of &#8220;<strong>awsdns-06.net</strong>.&#8221; DomainTools reports that this typo domain also was registered to a Yandex user (playlotto@yandex.ru), and was hosted at the same German ISP &#8212; Team Internet (AS61969).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>107</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 240/269 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2025-02-23 08:59:22 by W3 Total Cache
-->