<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 12:52:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. Sanctions Cloud Provider &#8216;Funnull&#8217; as Top Source of &#8216;Pig Butchering&#8217; Scams</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/u-s-sanctions-cloud-provider-funnull-as-top-source-of-pig-butchering-scams/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/u-s-sanctions-cloud-provider-funnull-as-top-source-of-pig-butchering-scams/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 01:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funnull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infrastructure laundering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ivan Neculiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lazarus Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stark Industrires Solutions Ltd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suncity Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yuri Neculiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. government today imposed economic sanctions on Funnull Technology Inc., a Philippines-based company that provides computer infrastructure for hundreds of thousands of websites involved in virtual currency investment scams, commonly known as “pig butchering." In January 2025, KrebsOnSecurity detailed how Funnull was being used as a content delivery network that catered to cybercriminals seeking to route their traffic through U.S.-based cloud providers.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_70230" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70230" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-70230" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss.png" alt="" width="750" height="452" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss.png 1319w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss-768x463.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss-782x472.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70230" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, ArtHead.</p></div>
<p>The U.S. government today imposed economic sanctions on <strong>Funnull Technology Inc.</strong>, a Philippines-based company that provides computer infrastructure for hundreds of thousands of websites involved in virtual currency investment scams known as “<strong>pig butchering</strong>.&#8221; In January 2025, KrebsOnSecurity detailed how Funnull was being used as a content delivery network that catered to cybercriminals seeking to route their traffic through U.S.-based cloud providers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Americans lose billions of dollars annually to these cyber scams, with revenues generated from these crimes rising to record levels in 2024,&#8221; reads <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sb0149" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a statement</a> from the <strong>U.S. Department of the Treasury</strong>, which sanctioned Funnull and its 40-year-old Chinese administrator <strong>Liu Lizhi</strong>. &#8220;Funnull has directly facilitated several of these schemes, resulting in over $200 million in U.S. victim-reported losses.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Treasury Department said Funnull&#8217;s operations are linked to the majority of virtual currency investment scam websites reported to the FBI. The agency said Funnull directly facilitated pig butchering and other schemes that resulted in more than $200 million in financial losses by Americans.</p>
<p>Pig butchering is a rampant form of fraud wherein people are lured by flirtatious strangers online into investing in fraudulent cryptocurrency trading platforms. Victims are coached to invest more and more money into what appears to be an extremely profitable trading platform, only to find their money is gone when they wish to cash out.</p>
<p>The scammers often insist that investors pay additional &#8220;taxes&#8221; on their crypto &#8220;earnings&#8221; before they can see their invested funds again (spoiler: they never do), and a shocking number of people <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/07/massive-losses-define-epidemic-of-pig-butchering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">have lost six figures or more through these pig butchering scams</a>.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity&#8217;s <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/infrastructure-laundering-blending-in-with-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">January story on Funnull</a> was based on research from the security firm <strong>Silent Push</strong>, which discovered in October 2024 that a vast number of domains hosted via Funnull were promoting gambling sites that bore the logo of the <strong>Suncity Group</strong>, a Chinese entity named in <a href="https://www.unodc.org/roseap/uploads/documents/Publications/2024/Casino_Underground_Banking_Report_2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2024 UN report</a> (PDF) for laundering millions of dollars for the North Korean state-sponsored hacking group <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lazarus_Group" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lazarus</a>.</p>
<p>Silent Push found Funnull was a criminal content delivery network (CDN) that carried a great deal of traffic tied to scam websites, funneling the traffic through a dizzying chain of auto-generated domain names and U.S.-based cloud providers before redirecting to malicious or phishous websites. The FBI has released a <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/CSA/2025/250529.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">technical writeup</a> (PDF) of the infrastructure used to manage the malicious Funnull domains between October 2023 and April 2025.</p>
<div id="attachment_71392" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71392" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71392" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/funnull-network.png" alt="" width="749" height="464" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/funnull-network.png 2556w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/funnull-network-768x476.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/funnull-network-1536x952.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/funnull-network-2048x1269.png 2048w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/funnull-network-782x485.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71392" class="wp-caption-text">A graphic from the FBI explaining how Funnull generated a slew of new domains on a regular basis and mapped them to Internet addresses on U.S. cloud providers.</p></div>
<p>Silent Push <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/infrastructure-laundering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revisited Funnull&#8217;s infrastructure</a> in January 2025 and found Funnull was still using many of the same <strong>Amazon</strong> and <strong>Microsoft</strong> cloud Internet addresses identified as malicious in its October report. Both Amazon and Microsoft pledged to rid their networks of Funnull&#8217;s presence following that story, but according to Silent Push&#8217;s <strong>Zach Edwards</strong> only one of those companies has followed through.</p>
<p>Edwards said Silent Push no longer sees Microsoft Internet addresses showing up in Funnull&#8217;s infrastructure, while Amazon continues to struggle with removing Funnull servers, including one that appears to have first materialized in 2023.</p>
<p>&#8220;Amazon is doing a terrible job &#8212; every day since they made those claims to you and us in our public blog they have had IPs still mapped to Funnull, including some that have stayed mapped for inexplicable periods of time,&#8221; Edwards said.</p>
<p>Amazon said its Amazon Web Services (AWS) hosting platform actively counters abuse attempts.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have stopped hundreds of attempts this year related to this group and we are looking into the information you shared earlier today,&#8221; reads a statement shared by Amazon. &#8220;If anyone suspects that AWS resources are being used for abusive activity, they can report it to AWS Trust &amp; Safety using the report abuse form <a href="https://support.aws.amazon.com/#/contacts/report-abuse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><span id="more-71387"></span></p>
<p>U.S. based cloud providers remain an attractive home base for cybercriminal organizations because many organizations will not be overly aggressive in blocking traffic from U.S.-based cloud networks, as doing so can result in blocking access to many legitimate web destinations that are also on that same shared network segment or host.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, funneling their bad traffic so that it appears to be coming out of U.S. cloud Internet providers allows cybercriminals to connect to websites from web addresses that are geographically close(r) to their targets and victims (to sidestep location-based security controls by your bank, for example).</p>
<p>Funnull is not the only cybercriminal infrastructure-as-a-service provider that was sanctioned this month: On May 20, 2025, the <strong>European Union</strong> <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=OJ:L_202500966" target="_blank" rel="noopener">imposed sanctions</a> on <strong>Stark Industries Solutions</strong>, an ISP that materialized at the start of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and has been used as a global proxy network that conceals the true source of cyberattacks and disinformation campaigns against enemies of Russia.</p>
<p>In May 2024, KrebsOnSecurity published <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-an-iron-hammer-in-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a deep dive on Stark Industries Solutions</a> that found much of the malicious traffic traversing Stark’s network (e.g. vulnerability scanning and password brute force attacks) was being bounced through U.S.-based cloud providers. My reporting showed how deeply Stark had penetrated U.S. ISPs, and that its co-founder for many years sold &#8220;bulletproof&#8221; hosting services that told Russian cybercrime forum customers they would proudly ignore any abuse complaints or police inquiries.</p>
<div id="attachment_67471" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-67471" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-67471" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions.png" alt="" width="748" height="464" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions.png 1197w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-768x477.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-782x485.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-67471" class="wp-caption-text">The homepage of Stark Industries Solutions.</p></div>
<p>That story examined the history of Stark&#8217;s co-founders, Moldovan brothers <strong>Ivan</strong> and <strong>Yuri Neculiti</strong>, who each denied past involvement in cybercrime or any current involvement in assisting Russian disinformation efforts or cyberattacks. Nevertheless, the EU sanctioned both brothers as well.</p>
<p>The EU said Stark and the Neculti brothers &#8220;enabled various Russian state-sponsored and state-affiliated actors to conduct destabilising activities including coordinated information manipulation and interference and cyber-attacks against the Union and third countries by providing services intended to hide these activities from European law enforcement and security agencies.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/u-s-sanctions-cloud-provider-funnull-as-top-source-of-pig-butchering-scams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pakistan Arrests 21 in &#8216;Heartsender&#8217; Malware Service</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/pakistan-arrests-21-in-heartsender-malware-service/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/pakistan-arrests-21-in-heartsender-malware-service/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 17:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abdul Moiz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adnan Munawar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atif Hussain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Awais Rasool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bilal Ahmad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Burhanul Haq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dilbar Hussain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DomainTools.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FudCo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fudpage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fudtools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamad Nawaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HeartSender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hussnain Haider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammad Adeel Akram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammad Aslam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammad Nowsherwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammad Umar Irshad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Cyber Crime Investigation Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NCCIA Director Abdul Ghaffar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rameez Shahzad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saim Raza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scylla Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Syed Saim Ali Shah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Usama Farooq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Usama Mehmood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeCodeSolutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yasir Ali]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71337</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Authorities in Pakistan have arrested 21 individuals accused of operating "Heartsender," a once popular spam and malware dissemination service that operated for more than a decade. The main clientele for HeartSender were organized crime groups that tried to trick victim companies into making payments to a third party, and its alleged proprietors were publicly identified by KrebsOnSecurity in 2021 after they inadvertently infected their computers with malware.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in Pakistan have arrested 21 individuals accused of operating &#8220;<strong>Heartsender</strong>,&#8221; a once popular spam and malware dissemination service that operated for more than a decade. The main clientele for HeartSender were organized crime groups that tried to trick victim companies into making payments to a third party, and its alleged proprietors were publicly identified by KrebsOnSecurity in 2021 after they inadvertently infected their computers with malware.</p>
<div id="attachment_56867" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-56867" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-56867" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcoteam.png" alt="" width="750" height="351" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcoteam.png 1694w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcoteam-768x359.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcoteam-1536x718.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcoteam-782x366.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-56867" class="wp-caption-text">Some of the core developers and sellers of Heartsender posing at a work outing in 2021. WeCodeSolutions boss Rameez Shahzad (in sunglasses) is in the center of this group photo, which was posted by employee Burhan Ul Haq, pictured just to the right of Shahzad.</p></div>
<p>A <a href="https://www.dawn.com/news/1911691" target="_blank" rel="noopener">report</a> from the Pakistani media outlet <strong>Dawn</strong> states that authorities there arrested 21 people alleged to have operated Heartsender, a spam delivery service whose homepage openly advertised phishing kits targeting users of various Internet companies, including Microsoft 365, Yahoo, AOL, Intuit, iCloud and ID.me. Pakistan&#8217;s <strong>National Cyber Crime Investigation Agency</strong> (NCCIA) reportedly conducted raids in Lahore&#8217;s Bahria Town and Multan on May 15 and 16.</p>
<p>The NCCIA told reporters the group’s tools were connected to more than $50m in losses in the United States alone, with European authorities investigating 63 additional cases.</p>
<p>“This wasn’t just a scam operation &#8211; it was essentially a cybercrime university that empowered fraudsters globally,” <strong>NCCIA Director Abdul Ghaffar</strong> said at a press briefing.</p>
<p>In January 2025, the FBI and the Dutch Police <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/fbi-dutch-police-disrupt-manipulaters-phishing-gang/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seized the technical infrastructure</a> for the cybercrime service, which was marketed under the brands Heartsender, <strong>Fudpage</strong> and <strong>Fudtools</strong> (and many other “fud” variations). The “fud” bit stands for “Fully Un-Detectable,” and it refers to cybercrime resources that will evade detection by security tools like antivirus software or anti-spam appliances.</p>
<p>The FBI says transnational organized crime groups that purchased these services primarily used them to run business email compromise (BEC) schemes, wherein the cybercrime actors tricked victim companies into making payments to a third party.</p>
<p>Dawn reported that those arrested included <strong>Rameez Shahzad</strong>, the alleged ringleader of the Heartsender cybercrime business, which most recently operated under the Pakistani front company <strong>WeCodeSolutions</strong>. Mr. Shahzad was named and pictured in a 2021 KrebsOnSecurity story about <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/09/fudco-spam-empire-tied-to-pakistani-software-firm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a series of remarkable operational security mistakes</a> that exposed their identities and Facebook pages showing employees posing for group photos and socializing at work-related outings.<span id="more-71337"></span></p>
<p>Prior to folding their operations behind WeCodeSolutions, Shahzad and others arrested this month operated as a web hosting group calling itself <strong>The Manipulaters</strong>. KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/05/phishing-gang-is-audacious-manipulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first wrote about The Manipulaters in May 2015</a>, mainly because their ads at the time were blanketing a number of popular cybercrime forums, and because they were fairly open and brazen about what they were doing — even who they were in real life.</p>
<p>Sometime in 2019, The Manipulaters <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/09/fudco-spam-empire-tied-to-pakistani-software-firm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">failed to renew their core domain name</a> — manipulaters[.]com — the same one tied to so many of the company’s business operations. That domain was quickly scooped up by <a href="https://www.scyllaintel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Scylla Intel</a>, a cyber intelligence firm that specializes in connecting cybercriminals to their real-life identities. Soon after, Scylla started receiving large amounts of email correspondence intended for the group&#8217;s owners.</p>
<p>In 2024, <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/04/the-manipulaters-improve-phishing-still-fail-at-opsec/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found</a> the web-hosted version of Heartsender leaked an extraordinary amount of user information to unauthenticated users, including customer credentials and email records from Heartsender employees. DomainTools says the malware infections on Manipulaters PCs exposed “vast swaths of account-related data along with an outline of the group’s membership, operations, and position in the broader underground economy.”</p>
<p>Shahzad allegedly used the alias &#8220;<strong>Saim Raza</strong>,&#8221; an identity which has contacted KrebsOnSecurity multiple times over the past decade with demands to remove stories published about the group. The Saim Raza identity most recently contacted this author in November 2024, asserting they had quit the cybercrime industry and turned over a new leaf after a brush with the Pakistani police.</p>
<p>The arrested suspects include Rameez Shahzad, Muhammad Aslam (Rameez’s father), Atif Hussain, Muhammad Umar Irshad, Yasir Ali, Syed Saim Ali Shah, Muhammad Nowsherwan, Burhanul Haq, Adnan Munawar, Abdul Moiz, Hussnain Haider, Bilal Ahmad, Dilbar Hussain, Muhammad Adeel Akram, Awais Rasool, Usama Farooq, Usama Mehmood and Hamad Nawaz.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/pakistan-arrests-21-in-heartsender-malware-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oops: DanaBot Malware Devs Infected Their Own PCs</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/oops-danabot-malware-devs-infected-their-own-pcs/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/oops-danabot-malware-devs-infected-their-own-pcs/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia's War on Ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aleksandr Stepanov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artem Aleksandrovich Kalinkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DanaBot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DCIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Defense Criminal Investigative Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flashpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel 471]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JimmBee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lumen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lumma Stealer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maffiozi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paypal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[proofpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[team cymru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zscaler]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. government today unsealed criminal charges against 16 individuals accused of operating and selling DanaBot, a prolific strain of information-stealing malware that has been sold on Russian cybercrime forums since 2018. The FBI says a newer version of DanaBot was used for espionage, and that many of the defendants exposed their real-life identities after accidentally infecting their own systems with the malware.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. government today unsealed criminal charges against 16 individuals accused of operating and selling <strong>DanaBot</strong>, a prolific strain of information-stealing malware that has been sold on Russian cybercrime forums since 2018. The <strong>FBI</strong> says a newer version of DanaBot was used for espionage, and that many of the defendants exposed their real-life identities after accidentally infecting their own systems with the malware.</p>
<div id="attachment_71354" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71354" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71354" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/danabot.png" alt="" width="749" height="650" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/danabot.png 817w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/danabot-768x666.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/danabot-782x679.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71354" class="wp-caption-text">DanaBot&#8217;s features, as promoted on its support site. Image: welivesecurity.com.</p></div>
<p>Initially <a href="https://www.proofpoint.com/us/threat-insight/post/danabot-new-banking-trojan-surfaces-down-under-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spotted</a> in May 2018 by researchers at the email security firm <strong>Proofpoint</strong>, DanaBot is a malware-as-a-service platform that specializes in credential theft and banking fraud.</p>
<p>Today, the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> unsealed a criminal complaint and indictment from 2022, which said the FBI identified at least 40 affiliates who were paying between $3,000 and $4,000 a month for access to the information stealer platform.</p>
<p>The government says the malware infected more than 300,000 systems globally, causing estimated losses of more than $50 million. The ringleaders of the DanaBot conspiracy are named as <strong>Aleksandr Stepanov</strong>, 39, a.k.a. “<strong>JimmBee</strong>,” and <strong>Artem Aleksandrovich Kalinkin</strong>, 34, a.k.a. “<strong>Onix</strong>”, both of Novosibirsk, Russia. Kalinkin is an IT engineer for the Russian state-owned energy giant <strong>Gazprom</strong>. His Facebook profile name is &#8220;Maffiozi.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to the FBI, there were at least two major versions of DanaBot; the first was sold between 2018 and June 2020, when the malware stopped being offered on Russian cybercrime forums. The government alleges that the second version of DanaBot &#8212; emerging in January 2021 &#8212; was provided to co-conspirators for use in targeting military, diplomatic and non-governmental organization computers in several countries, including the United States, Belarus, the United Kingdom, Germany, and Russia.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unindicted co-conspirators would use the Espionage Variant to compromise computers around the world and steal sensitive diplomatic communications, credentials, and other data from these targeted victims,&#8221; reads a grand jury indictment dated Sept. 20, 2022. &#8220;This stolen data included financial transactions by diplomatic staff, correspondence concerning day-to-day diplomatic activity, as well as summaries of a particular country&#8217;s interactions with the United States.&#8221;</p>
<p>The indictment says the FBI in 2022 seized servers used by the DanaBot authors to control their malware, as well as the servers that stored stolen victim data. The government said the server data also show numerous instances in which the DanaBot defendants infected their own PCs, resulting in their credential data being uploaded to stolen data repositories that were seized by the feds.</p>
<p>&#8220;In some cases, such self-infections appeared to be deliberately done in order to test, analyze, or improve the malware,&#8221; the criminal complaint reads. &#8220;In other cases, the infections seemed to be inadvertent &#8211; one of the hazards of committing cybercrime is that criminals will sometimes infect themselves with their own malware by mistake.&#8221;<span id="more-71351"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_71359" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71359" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71359" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/eset-danabotmap.png" alt="" width="750" height="479" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/eset-danabotmap.png 846w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/eset-danabotmap-768x490.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/eset-danabotmap-782x499.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71359" class="wp-caption-text">Image: welivesecurity.com</p></div>
<p>A <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/pr/16-defendants-federally-charged-connection-danabot-malware-scheme-infected-computers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> from the DOJ says that as part of today&#8217;s operation, agents with the <strong>Defense Criminal Investigative Service</strong> (DCIS) seized the DanaBot control servers, including dozens of virtual servers hosted in the United States. The government says it is now working with industry partners to notify DanaBot victims and help remediate infections. The statement credits a number of security firms with providing assistance to the government, including <strong>ESET</strong>, <strong>Flashpoint</strong>, <strong>Google</strong>, <strong>Intel 471</strong>, <strong>Lumen</strong>, <strong>PayPal</strong>, <strong>Proofpoint</strong>, <strong>Team CYMRU</strong>, and <strong>ZScaler</strong>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not unheard of for financially-oriented malicious software to be repurposed for espionage. A variant of the <strong>ZeuS Trojan</strong>, which was used in countless online banking attacks against companies in the United States and Europe between 2007 and at least 2015, was for a time diverted to espionage tasks by its author.</p>
<p>As detailed <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/08/inside-the-100m-business-club-crime-gang/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in this 2015 story,</a> the author of the ZeuS trojan created a custom version of the malware to serve purely as a spying machine, which scoured infected systems in Ukraine for specific keywords in emails and documents that would likely only be found in classified documents.</p>
<p>The public charging of the 16 DanaBot defendants comes a day after <strong>Microsoft</strong> <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/blog/2025/05/21/lumma-stealer-breaking-down-the-delivery-techniques-and-capabilities-of-a-prolific-infostealer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">joined</a> a slew of tech companies in <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-seizes-domains-behind-major-information-stealing-malware-operation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disrupting the IT infrastructure</a> for another malware-as-a-service offering &#8212; <a href="https://www.welivesecurity.com/en/eset-research/eset-takes-part-global-operation-disrupt-lumma-stealer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lumma Stealer</a>, which is likewise offered to affiliates under tiered subscription prices ranging from $250 to $1,000 per month. Separately, Microsoft filed a civil lawsuit to seize control over 2,300 domain names used by Lumma Stealer and its affiliates.</p>
<p>Further reading:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.welivesecurity.com/en/eset-research/danabot-analyzing-fallen-empire/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Danabot: Analyzing a Fallen Empire</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.zscaler.com/blogs/security-research/danabot-launches-ddos-attack-against-ukrainian-ministry-defense" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ZScaler blog: DanaBot Launches DDoS Attack Against the Ukrainian Ministry of Defense</a></p>
<p><a href="https://flashpoint.io/blog/operation-endgame-danabot-malware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Flashpoint: Operation Endgame DanaBot Malware</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.team-cymru.com/post/inside-danabots-infrastructure-in-support-of-operation-endgame-ii" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Team CYMRU: Inside DanaBot&#8217;s Infrastructure: In Support of Operation Endgame II</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/media/1401361/dl?inline" target="_blank" rel="noopener">March 2022 criminal complaint v. Artem Aleksandrovich Kalinkin</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/media/1401356/dl?inline" target="_blank" rel="noopener">September 2022 grand jury indictment naming the 16 defendants</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/oops-danabot-malware-devs-infected-their-own-pcs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>KrebsOnSecurity Hit With Near-Record 6.3 Tbps DDoS</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/krebsonsecurity-hit-with-near-record-6-3-tbps-ddos/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/krebsonsecurity-hit-with-near-record-6-3-tbps-ddos/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 21:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DDoS-for-Hire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things (IoT)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aisuru botnet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Akamai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[booter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CloudFlare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Damian Menscher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DDoS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaike Southier Leite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mirai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Shield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QiAnXin XLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stresser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yfork]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[KrebsOnSecurity last week was hit by a near record distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack that clocked in at more than 6.3 terabits of data per second (a terabit is one trillion bits of data). The brief attack appears to have been a test run for a massive new Internet of Things (IoT) botnet capable of launching crippling digital assaults that few web destinations can withstand. Read on for more about the botnet, the attack, and the apparent creator of this global menace.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>KrebsOnSecurity last week was hit by a near record distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack that clocked in at more than 6.3 terabits of data per second (a terabit is one trillion bits of data). The brief attack appears to have been a test run for a massive new Internet of Things (IoT) botnet capable of launching crippling digital assaults that few web destinations can withstand. Read on for more about the botnet, the attack, and the apparent creator of this global menace.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-71312" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ddosbomb.png" alt="" width="661" height="542" /></p>
<p>For reference, the 6.3 Tbps attack last week was ten times the size of the assault launched against this site in 2016 by the <strong>Mirai</strong> IoT botnet, which <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/the-democratization-of-censorship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">held KrebsOnSecurity offline for nearly four days</a>. The 2016 assault was so large that <strong>Akamai</strong> &#8211; which was providing pro-bono DDoS protection for KrebsOnSecurity at the time &#8212; asked me to leave their service because the attack was causing problems for their paying customers.</p>
<p>Since the Mirai attack, KrebsOnSecurity.com has been behind the protection of <strong>Project Shield</strong>, a free DDoS defense service that <strong>Google</strong> provides to websites offering news, human rights, and election-related content. Google Security Engineer <strong>Damian Menscher</strong> told KrebsOnSecurity the May 12 attack was the largest Google has ever handled. In terms of sheer size, it is second only to a very similar attack that <strong>Cloudflare</strong> mitigated and <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/ddos-threat-report-for-2025-q1/#hyper-volumetric-attacks-continue-spill-into-q2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote about in April</a>.</p>
<p>After comparing notes with Cloudflare, Menscher said the botnet that launched both attacks bears the fingerprints of <strong>Aisuru</strong>, a digital siege machine that first surfaced less than a year ago. Menscher said the attack on KrebsOnSecurity lasted less than a minute, hurling <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/whitepapers/latest/aws-best-practices-ddos-resiliency/udp-reflection-attacks.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">large UDP data packets</a> at random ports <em>at a rate of approximately 585 million data packets per second</em>.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was the type of attack normally designed to overwhelm network links,&#8221; Menscher said, referring to the throughput connections between and among various Internet service providers (ISPs). &#8220;For most companies, this size of attack would kill them.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_71311" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/cf-6.5ddos.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71311" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71311" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/cf-6.5ddos.png" alt="" width="749" height="340" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/cf-6.5ddos.png 906w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/cf-6.5ddos-768x348.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/cf-6.5ddos-782x355.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-71311" class="wp-caption-text">A graph depicting the 6.5 Tbps attack mitigated by Cloudflare in April 2025. Image: Cloudflare.</p></div>
<p>The Aisuru botnet comprises a globally-dispersed collection of hacked IoT devices, including routers, digital video recorders and other systems that are commandeered via default passwords or software vulnerabilities. As <a href="https://blog.xlab.qianxin.com/large-scale-botnet-airashi-en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">documented</a> by researchers at <strong>QiAnXin XLab</strong>, the botnet was first identified in an August 2024 attack on a large gaming platform.</p>
<p>Aisuru reportedly went quiet after that exposure, only to reappear in November with even more firepower and software exploits. In a <a href="https://blog.xlab.qianxin.com/large-scale-botnet-airashi-en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">January 2025 report</a>, XLab found the new and improved Aisuru (a.k.a. &#8220;<strong>Airashi</strong>&#8220;) had incorporated a previously unknown zero-day vulnerability in Cambium Networks cnPilot routers.</p>
<h2>NOT FORKING AROUND</h2>
<p>The people behind the Aisuru botnet have been peddling access to their DDoS machine in public <strong>Telegram</strong> chat channels that are closely monitored by multiple security firms. In August 2024, the botnet was rented out in subscription tiers ranging from $150 per day to $600 per week, offering attacks of up to two terabits per second.</p>
<p>&#8220;You may not attack any measurement walls, healthcare facilities, schools or government sites,&#8221; read a notice posted on Telegram by the Aisuru botnet owners in August 2024.</p>
<p>Interested parties were told to contact the Telegram handle &#8220;<strong>@yfork</strong>&#8221; to purchase a subscription. The account @yfork previously used the nickname &#8220;<strong>Forky</strong>,&#8221; an identity that has been posting to public DDoS-focused Telegram channels since 2021.</p>
<p>According to the FBI, Forky&#8217;s DDoS-for-hire domains have been seized in multiple law enforcement operations over the years. Last year, Forky said on Telegram he was selling the domain <strong>stresser[.]best</strong>, which saw its servers seized by the FBI in 2022 as part of an ongoing international law enforcement effort aimed at diminishing the supply of and demand for DDoS-for-hire services.</p>
<p>&#8220;The operator of this service, who calls himself &#8216;Forky,&#8217; operates a Telegram channel to advertise features and communicate with current and prospective DDoS customers,&#8221; reads <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Booter-seizure-warrant-Tucows-2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an FBI seizure warrant</a> (PDF) issued for stresser[.]best. The FBI warrant stated that on the same day the seizures were announced, Forky posted <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/12/six-charged-in-mass-takedown-of-ddos-for-hire-sites/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a link to a story on this blog</a> that detailed the domain seizure operation, adding the comment, “We are buying our new domains right now.”</p>
<div id="attachment_71315" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71315" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71315" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/stresserbest.png" alt="" width="748" height="663" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/stresserbest.png 953w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/stresserbest-768x681.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/stresserbest-782x693.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71315" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot from the FBI&#8217;s seizure warrant for Forky&#8217;s DDoS-for-hire domains shows Forky announcing the resurrection of their service at new domains.</p></div>
<p>Approximately ten hours later, Forky posted again, including a screenshot of the stresser[.]best user dashboard, instructing customers to use their saved passwords for the old website on the new one.</p>
<p>A review of Forky&#8217;s posts to public Telegram channels &#8212; as indexed by the cyber intelligence firms <strong>Unit 221B</strong> and <strong>Flashpoint</strong> &#8212; reveals a 21-year-old individual who claims to reside in Brazil [full disclosure: Flashpoint is currently an advertiser on this blog].</p>
<p>Since late 2022, Forky&#8217;s posts have frequently promoted a DDoS mitigation company and ISP that he operates called <strong>botshield[.]io</strong>. The Botshield website is connected to a business entity registered in the United Kingdom called <a href="https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/officers/krPZ3H9McgoRJbksmVWst3yc9G0/appointments" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Botshield LTD</a>, which lists a 21-year-old woman from Sao Paulo, Brazil as the director. Internet routing records indicate Botshield (<a href="https://ipinfo.io/AS213613" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AS213613</a>) currently controls several hundred Internet addresses that were allocated to the company earlier this year.</p>
<p><strong>Domaintools.com</strong> reports that botshield[.]io was registered in July 2022 to a <strong>Kaike Southier Leite</strong> in Sao Paulo. A <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kaike-southier-5074b82b6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LinkedIn profile</a> by the same name says this individual is a network specialist from Brazil who works in &#8220;the planning and implementation of robust network infrastructures, with a focus on security, DDoS mitigation, colocation and cloud server services.&#8221;</p>
<h2>MEET FORKY</h2>
<div id="attachment_71314" style="width: 789px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71314" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71314 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/forky.png" alt="" width="779" height="519" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/forky.png 779w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/forky-768x512.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 779px) 100vw, 779px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71314" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Jaclyn Vernace / Shutterstock.com.</p></div>
<p>In his posts to public Telegram chat channels, Forky has hardly attempted to conceal his whereabouts or identity. In countless chat conversations indexed by Unit 221B, Forky could be seen talking about everyday life in Brazil, often remarking on the extremely low or high prices in Brazil for a range of goods, from computer and networking gear to narcotics and food.</p>
<p>Reached via Telegram, Forky claimed he was &#8220;not involved in this type of illegal actions for years now,&#8221; and that the project had been taken over by other unspecified developers. Forky initially told KrebsOnSecurity he had been out of the botnet scene for years, only to concede this wasn&#8217;t true when presented with public posts on Telegram from late last year that clearly showed otherwise.</p>
<p>Forky denied being involved in the attack on KrebsOnSecurity, but acknowledged that he helped to develop and market the Aisuru botnet. Forky claims he is now merely a staff member for the Aisuru botnet team, and that he stopped running the botnet roughly two months ago after starting a family. Forky also said the woman named as director of Botshield is related to him.</p>
<p>Forky offered equivocal, evasive responses to a number of questions about the Aisuru botnet and his business endeavors. But on one point he was crystal clear:</p>
<p>&#8220;I have zero fear about you, the FBI, or Interpol,&#8221; Forky said, asserting that he is now almost entirely focused on their hosting business &#8212; Botshield.<span id="more-71303"></span></p>
<p>Forky declined to discuss the makeup of his ISP&#8217;s clientele, or to clarify whether Botshield was more of a hosting provider or a DDoS mitigation firm. However, Forky has posted on Telegram about Botshield successfully mitigating large DDoS attacks launched against other DDoS-for-hire services.</p>
<p>DomainTools finds the same Sao Paulo street address in the registration records for botshield[.]io was used to register several other domains, including <strong>cant-mitigate[.]us.</strong> The email address in the WHOIS records for that domain is forkcontato@gmail.com, which DomainTools says was used to register the domain for the now-defunct DDoS-for-hire service <strong>stresser[.]us</strong>, one of the domains seized in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/05/feds-take-down-13-more-ddos-for-hire-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the FBI&#8217;s 2023 crackdown</a>.</p>
<p>On May 8, 2023, the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/pr/federal-authorities-seize-13-internet-domains-associated-booter-websites-offered-ddos" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the seizure of stresser[.]us, along with a dozen other domains offering DDoS services. The DOJ said ten of the 13 domains were reincarnations of services that were seized during a <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/pr/federal-prosecutors-los-angeles-and-alaska-charge-6-defendants-operating-websites" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/pr/federal-prosecutors-los-angeles-and-alaska-charge-6-defendants-operating-websites&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1747842233209000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0Tl0oBqaLrBCwcoLIjUEED">prior sweep in December</a>, which targeted 48 top stresser services (also known as &#8220;booters&#8221;).</p>
<p>Forky claimed he could find out who attacked my site with Aisuru. But when pressed a day later on the question, Forky said he&#8217;d come up empty-handed.</p>
<p>&#8220;I tried to ask around, all the big guys are not retarded enough to attack you,&#8221; Forky explained in an interview on Telegram. &#8220;I didn&#8217;t have anything to do with it. But you are welcome to write the story and try to put the blame on me.&#8221;</p>
<h2>THE GHOST OF MIRAI</h2>
<p>The 6.3 Tbps attack last week caused no visible disruption to this site, in part because it was so brief &#8212; lasting approximately 45 seconds. DDoS attacks of such magnitude and brevity typically are produced when botnet operators wish to test or demonstrate their firepower for the benefit of potential buyers. Indeed, Google&#8217;s Menscher said it is likely that both the May 12 attack and the slightly larger 6.5 Tbps attack against Cloudflare last month were simply tests of the same botnet&#8217;s capabilities.</p>
<p>In many ways, the threat posed by the Aisuru/Airashi botnet is reminiscent of Mirai, an innovative IoT malware strain that emerged in the summer of 2016 and successfully out-competed virtually all other IoT malware strains in existence at the time.</p>
<p>As first revealed by KrebsOnSecurity in January 2017, the Mirai authors were <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/01/who-is-anna-senpai-the-mirai-worm-author/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">two U.S. men who co-ran a DDoS mitigation service</a> &#8212; even as they were selling far more lucrative DDoS-for-hire services using the most powerful botnet on the planet.</p>
<p>Less than a week after the Mirai botnet was used in a days-long DDoS against KrebsOnSecurity, the Mirai authors <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/10/source-code-for-iot-botnet-mirai-released/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published the source code to their botnet</a> so that they would not be the only ones in possession of it in the event of their arrest by federal investigators.</p>
<p>Ironically, the leaking of the Mirai source is precisely what led to the eventual unmasking and arrest of the Mirai authors, who went on to serve probation sentences that <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/mirai-untold-story-three-young-hackers-web-killing-monster/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">required them to consult with FBI investigators on DDoS investigations</a>. But that leak also rapidly led to the creation of dozens of Mirai botnet clones, many of which were harnessed to fuel their own powerful DDoS-for-hire services.</p>
<p>Menscher told KrebsOnSecurity that as counterintuitive as it may sound, the Internet as a whole would probably be better off if the source code for Aisuru became public knowledge. After all, he said, the people behind Aisuru are in constant competition with other IoT botnet operators who are all striving to commandeer a finite number of vulnerable IoT devices globally.</p>
<p>Such a development would almost certainly cause a proliferation of Aisuru botnet clones, he said, but at least then the overall firepower from each individual botnet would be greatly diminished &#8212; or at least within range of the mitigation capabilities of most DDoS protection providers.</p>
<p>Barring a source code leak, Menscher said, it would be nice if someone published the full list of software exploits being used by the Aisuru operators to grow their botnet so quickly.</p>
<p>&#8220;Part of the reason Mirai was so dangerous was that it effectively took out competing botnets,&#8221; he said. &#8220;This attack somehow managed to compromise all these boxes that nobody else knows about. Ideally, we&#8217;d want to see that fragmented out, so that no [individual botnet operator] controls too much.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/krebsonsecurity-hit-with-near-record-6-3-tbps-ddos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breachforums Boss to Pay $700k in Healthcare Breach</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/breachforums-boss-to-pay-700k-in-healthcare-breach/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/breachforums-boss-to-pay-700k-in-healthcare-breach/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BreachForums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cipriani & Werner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conor Brian Fitzpatrick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jill Fertel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark rasch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nonstop Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pompompurin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RaidForums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 221B]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In what experts are calling a novel legal outcome, the 22-year-old former administrator of the cybercrime community Breachforums will forfeit nearly $700,000 to settle a civil lawsuit from a health insurance company whose customer data was posted for sale on the forum in 2023. Conor Brian Fitzpatrick, a.k.a. "Pompompurin," is slated for resentencing next month after pleading guilty to access device fraud and possession of child sexual abuse material (CSAM).]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In what experts are calling a novel legal outcome, the 22-year-old former administrator of the cybercrime community <strong>Breachforums </strong>will forfeit nearly $700,000 to settle a civil lawsuit from a health insurance company whose customer data was posted for sale on the forum in 2023. <strong>Conor Brian Fitzpatrick</strong>, a.k.a. &#8220;<strong>Pompompurin</strong>,&#8221; is slated for resentencing next month after pleading guilty to access device fraud and possession of child sexual abuse material (CSAM).</p>
<div id="attachment_71274" style="width: 985px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71274" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71274" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/breached-nonstop.png" alt="" width="975" height="364" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/breached-nonstop.png 975w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/breached-nonstop-768x287.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/breached-nonstop-782x292.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 975px) 100vw, 975px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71274" class="wp-caption-text">A redacted screenshot of the Breachforums sales thread. Image: Ke-la.com.</p></div>
<p>On January 18, 2023, denizens of Breachforums posted for sale tens of thousands of records &#8212; including Social Security numbers, dates of birth, addresses, and phone numbers  &#8212; stolen from <strong>Nonstop Health</strong>, an insurance provider based in Concord, Calif.</p>
<p>Class-action attorneys sued Nonstop Health, which added Fitzpatrick as a third-party defendant to the civil litigation in November 2023, several months after he was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/03/feds-charge-ny-man-as-breachforums-boss-pompompurin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested by the FBI</a> and criminally charged with access device fraud and CSAM possession. In January 2025, Nonstop <a href="https://topclassactions.com/lawsuit-settlements/closed-settlements/1-6m-nonstop-administration-and-insurance-services-data-breach-class-action-settlement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">agreed to pay $1.5 million</a> to settle the class action.</p>
<p><strong>Jill Fertel</strong> is a former prosecutor who runs the cyber litigation practice at <strong>Cipriani &amp; Werner</strong>, the law firm that represented Nonstop Health. Fertel told KrebsOnSecurity this is the first and only case where a cybercriminal or anyone related to the security incident was actually named in civil litigation.</p>
<p>&#8220;Civil plaintiffs are not at all likely to see money seized from threat actors involved in the incident to be made available to people impacted by the breach,&#8221; Fertel said. &#8220;The best we could do was make this money available to the class, but it&#8217;s still incumbent on the members of the class who are impacted to make that claim.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Mark Rasch</strong> is a former federal prosecutor who now represents <strong>Unit 221B</strong>, a cybersecurity firm based in New York City. Rasch said he doesn&#8217;t doubt that the civil settlement involving Fitzpatrick&#8217;s criminal activity is a novel legal development.</p>
<p>&#8220;It is rare in these civil cases that you know the threat actor involved in the breach, and it&#8217;s also rare that you catch them with sufficient resources to be able to pay a claim,&#8221; Rasch said.</p>
<p>Despite admitting to possessing more than 600 CSAM images and personally operating Breachforums, Fitzpatrick was <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/jailed-breachforums-creator-admin-sentenced-to-20-years-of-supervised-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sentenced in January 2024 to time served</a> and 20 years of supervised release. Federal prosecutors objected, arguing that his punishment failed to adequately reflect the seriousness of his crimes or serve as a deterrent.</p>
<div id="attachment_71269" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71269" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71269" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/pom-csam.png" alt="" width="749" height="299" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/pom-csam.png 789w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/pom-csam-768x307.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/pom-csam-782x312.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71269" class="wp-caption-text">An excerpt from a pre-sentencing report for Fitzpatrick indicates he had more than 600 CSAM images on his devices.</p></div>
<p>Indeed, the same month he was sentenced Fitzpatrick <a href="https://dd80b675424c132b90b3-e48385e382d2e5d17821a5e1d8e4c86b.ssl.cf1.rackcdn.com/external/sdny-24mj003-waiver-jan22024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was rearrested</a> (PDF) for violating the terms of his release, which forbade him from using a computer that didn&#8217;t have court-required monitoring software installed.</p>
<p>Federal prosecutors said Fitzpatrick went on Discord following his guilty plea and <a href="https://law.justia.com/cases/federal/appellate-courts/ca4/24-4102/24-4102-2025-01-21.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">professed innocence</a> to the very crimes to which he&#8217;d pleaded guilty, stating that his plea deal was &#8220;so BS&#8221; and that he had &#8220;wanted to fight it.&#8221; The feds said Fitzpatrick also joked with his friends about selling data to foreign governments, exhorting one user to &#8220;become a foreign asset to china or russia,&#8221; and to &#8220;sell government secrets.&#8221;<span id="more-71263"></span></p>
<p>In January 2025, a federal appeals court agreed with the government&#8217;s assessment, <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/conor-fitzpatrick-resentenced-pompompurin-breachforums/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">vacating Fitzpatrick&#8217;s sentence</a> and ordering him to be resentenced on June 3, 2025.</p>
<p>Fitzpatrick launched BreachForums in March 2022 to replace <strong>RaidForums</strong>, a similarly popular crime forum that was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/raidforums-get-raided-alleged-admin-arrested/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">infiltrated and shut down by the FBI</a> the previous month. As administrator, his alter ego Pompompurin served as the middleman, personally reviewing all databases for sale on the forum and offering an escrow service to those interested in buying stolen data.</p>
<div id="attachment_71270" style="width: 375px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71270" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71270" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/conorfitzpatrick-yearbook.png" alt="" width="365" height="560" /><p id="caption-attachment-71270" class="wp-caption-text">A yearbook photo of Fitzpatrick unearthed by the Yonkers Times.</p></div>
<p>The new site quickly attracted more than 300,000 users, and facilitated the sale of databases stolen from hundreds of hacking victims, including some of the largest consumer data breaches in recent history. In May 2024, a reincarnation of Breachforums was seized by the FBI and international partners. Still more relaunches of the forum occurred after that, with <a href="https://socradar.io/breachforums-is-offline-a-new-twist-or-just-another-cyber-sheningan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the most recent disruption</a> last month.</p>
<p>As KrebsOnSecurity reported last year in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Dark Nexus Between Harm Groups and The Com</a>, it is increasingly common for federal investigators to find CSAM material when searching devices seized from cybercriminal suspects. While the mere possession of CSAM is a serious federal crime, not all of those caught with CSAM are necessarily creators or distributors of it. Fertel said some cybercriminal communities have been known to require new entrants to share CSAM material as a way of proving that they are not a federal investigator.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you&#8217;re going to the darkest corners of Internet, that&#8217;s how you prove you&#8217;re not law enforcement,&#8221; Fertel said. &#8220;Law enforcement would never share that material. It would be criminal for me as a prosecutor, if I obtained and possessed those types of images.&#8221;</p>
<p>Further reading: <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/19420931.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The settlement between Fitzpatrick and Nonstop</a> (PDF).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/breachforums-boss-to-pay-700k-in-healthcare-breach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patch Tuesday, May 2025 Edition</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/patch-tuesday-may-2025-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/patch-tuesday-may-2025-edition/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 11:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-30397]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-30400]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-32701]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-32706]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-32709]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immersive Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kev Breen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Patch Tuesday May 2025]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Common Log File System]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft on Tuesday released software updates to fix at least 70 vulnerabilities in Windows and related products, including five zero-day flaws that are already seeing active exploitation. Adding to the sense of urgency with this month's patch batch from Redmond are fixes for two other weaknesses that now have public proof-of-concept exploits available.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> on Tuesday released software updates to fix at least 70 vulnerabilities in <strong>Windows</strong> and related products, including <em>five zero-day flaws that are already seeing active exploitation</em>. Adding to the sense of urgency with this month&#8217;s patch batch from Redmond are fixes for two other weaknesses that now have public proof-of-concept exploits available.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter  wp-image-60331" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png" alt="" width="749" height="496" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png 923w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-768x508.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-782x518.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>Microsoft and several security firms have disclosed that attackers are exploiting a pair of bugs in the <strong>Windows Common Log File System</strong> (CLFS) driver that allow attackers to elevate their privileges on a vulnerable device. The Windows CLFS is a critical Windows component responsible for logging services, and is widely used by Windows system services and third-party applications for logging. Tracked as <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-32701" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-32701</a> &amp; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-32706" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-32706</a>, these flaws are present in all supported versions of Windows 10 and 11, as well as their server versions.</p>
<p><strong>Kev Breen</strong>, senior director of threat research at <strong>Immersive Labs</strong>, said privilege escalation bugs assume an attacker already has initial access to a compromised host, typically through a phishing attack or by using stolen credentials. But if that access already exists, Breen said, attackers can gain access to the much more powerful Windows SYSTEM account, which can disable security tooling or even gain domain administration level permissions using credential harvesting tools.</p>
<p>&#8220;The patch notes don&#8217;t provide technical details on how this is being exploited, and no Indicators of Compromise (IOCs) are shared, meaning the only mitigation security teams have is to apply these patches immediately,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The average time from public disclosure to exploitation at scale is less than five days, with threat actors, ransomware groups, and affiliates quick to leverage these vulnerabilities.&#8221;</p>
<p>Two other zero-days patched by Microsoft today also were elevation of privilege flaws: <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-32709" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-32709</a>, which concerns afd.sys, the <strong>Windows Ancillary Function Driver</strong> that enables Windows applications to connect to the Internet; and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-30400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-30400</a>, a weakness in the <strong>Desktop Window Manager</strong> (DWM) library for Windows. As <strong>Adam Barnett</strong> at <strong>Rapid7</strong> notes, tomorrow marks the <a href="https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/2024/05/14/patch-tuesday-may-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/2024/05/14/patch-tuesday-may-2024/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1747257386891000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3VPzmtS8Na55bRRDOUkbDw">one-year anniversary</a> of <a href="https://portal.msrc.microsoft.com/en-US/security-guidance/advisory/CVE-2024-30051" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://portal.msrc.microsoft.com/en-US/security-guidance/advisory/CVE-2024-30051&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1747257386891000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2HzZh4Tm-0eKXolluDR0FX">CVE-2024-30051</a>, a previous zero-day elevation of privilege vulnerability in this same DWM component.</p>
<p>The fifth zero-day patched today is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-30397" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-30397</a>, a flaw in the <strong>Microsoft Scripting Engine</strong>, a key component used by <strong>Internet Explorer</strong> and <strong>Internet Explorer mode</strong> in <strong>Microsoft Edge</strong>.<span id="more-71250"></span></p>
<p><strong>Chris Goettl</strong> at <strong>Ivanti</strong> points out that the Windows 11 and Server 2025 updates include some new AI features that carry a lot of baggage and weigh in at around 4 gigabytes. Said baggage includes new artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities, including the controversial <strong>Recall</strong> feature, which constantly takes screenshots of what users are doing on Windows CoPilot-enabled computers.</p>
<p>Microsoft went back to the drawing board on Recall after a fountain of negative feedback from security experts, who warned it would present an attractive target and a potential gold mine for attackers. Microsoft appears to have made some efforts to prevent Recall from scooping up sensitive financial information, but privacy and security concerns still linger. Former Microsoftie <strong>Kevin Beaumont</strong> has <a href="https://cyberplace.social/@GossiTheDog/114360483150635243" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a good teardown</a> on Microsoft&#8217;s updates to Recall.</p>
<p>In any case, <strong>windowslatest.com</strong> reports that <strong>Windows 11 version 24H2</strong> shows up ready for downloads, even if you don&#8217;t want it.</p>
<p>&#8220;It will now show up for &#8216;download and install&#8217; automatically if you go to Settings &gt; Windows Update and click Check for updates, but only when your device does not have a compatibility hold,&#8221; the publication <a href="https://www.windowslatest.com/2025/05/05/windows-11-24h2-now-fully-ready-downloads-even-if-you-dont-want-it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a>. &#8220;Even if you don&#8217;t check for updates, Windows 11 24H2 will automatically download at some point.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apple users likely have their own patching to do. On May 12 Apple released security updates to fix at least 30 vulnerabilities in <strong>iOS</strong> and <strong>iPadOS</strong> (the updated version <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/122404" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is 18.5</a>). <strong>TechCrunch</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/05/12/apple-brings-emergency-satellite-features-to-iphone-13-with-ios-18-5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that iOS 18.5 also expands emergency satellite capabilities to iPhone 13 owners for the first time (previously it was only available on iPhone 14 or later).</p>
<p>Apple also <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/100100" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released updates</a> for <strong>macOS Sequoia</strong>, <strong>macOS Sonoma</strong>, <strong>macOS Ventura</strong>, <strong>WatchOS</strong>, <strong>tvOS</strong> and <strong>visionOS</strong>. Apple said there is no indication of active exploitation for any of the vulnerabilities fixed this month.</p>
<p>As always, please back up your device and/or important data before attempting any updates. And please feel free to sound off in the comments if you run into any problems applying any of these fixes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/patch-tuesday-may-2025-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pakistani Firm Shipped Fentanyl Analogs, Scams to US</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/pakistani-firm-shipped-fentanyl-analogs-scams-to-us/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/pakistani-firm-shipped-fentanyl-analogs-scams-to-us/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 22:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[360 Digital Marketing LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abtach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axact]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azneem Bilwani]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digitonics Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eWorldTrade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Investigation Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intersys Limited]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Junaid Mansoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Majestic Ghostwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muhammad Burhan Mirza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NatInfoSec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Octa Group Technologies AU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qasim Mansoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retrocube LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Patent and Trademark Office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertical Minds LLC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A Texas firm recently charged with conspiring to distribute synthetic opioids in the United States is at the center of a vast network of companies in the U.S. and Pakistan whose employees are accused of using online ads to scam westerners seeking help with trademarks, book writing, mobile app development and logo designs, a new investigation reveals.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Texas firm recently charged with conspiring to distribute synthetic opioids in the United States is at the center of a vast network of companies in the U.S. and Pakistan whose employees are accused of using online ads to scam westerners seeking help with trademarks, book writing, mobile app development and logo designs, a new investigation reveals.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/motion_to_seal_eWorldTrade_Azneem_Bilwani_Abtach_drugs_merged_usa_vs_eworldtradellc-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an indictment</a> (PDF) unsealed last month, the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> said Dallas-based <strong>eWorldTrade</strong> &#8220;operated an online business-to-business marketplace that facilitated the distribution of synthetic opioids such as isotonitazene and carfentanyl, both significantly more potent than fentanyl.&#8221;</p>
<p>Launched in 2017, eWorldTrade[.]com now features <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/us-online-marketplace-operator-charged-trafficking-deadly-synthetic-opioids-stronger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a seizure notice</a> from the DOJ. eWorldTrade operated as a wholesale seller of consumer goods, including clothes, machinery, chemicals, automobiles and appliances. The DOJ&#8217;s indictment includes no additional details about eWorldTrade&#8217;s business, origins or other activity, and at first glance the website might appear to be a legitimate e-commerce platform that also just happened to sell some restricted chemicals.</p>
<div id="attachment_71137" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71137" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71137" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/eworldtrade.png" alt="" width="750" height="310" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/eworldtrade.png 1901w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/eworldtrade-768x318.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/eworldtrade-1536x636.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/eworldtrade-782x324.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71137" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot of the eWorldTrade homepage on March 25, 2025. Image: archive.org.</p></div>
<p>However, an investigation into the company&#8217;s founders reveals they are connected to a sprawling network of websites that have a history of extortionate scams involving trademark registration, book publishing, exam preparation, and the design of logos, mobile applications and websites.</p>
<p><a href="https://uspto.report/TM/98283759/ELR20240903134921/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Records</a> from the <strong>U.S. Patent and Trademark Office </strong>(USPTO) show the eWorldTrade mark is owned by an <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/azneem-bilwani-1630291a/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><b>Azneem Bilwani </b></a>in Karachi (this name also is in the registration records for the now-seized eWorldTrade domain). Mr. Bilwani is perhaps better known as the director of the Pakistan-based IT provider <strong>Abtach Ltd.</strong>, which has been <a href="https://www.uspto.gov/sites/default/files/documents/TM-Show-Cause-Order-Abtach-et-al.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">singled out</a> by the USPTO <a href="https://www.worldtrademarkreview.com/data/wtr-investigation-exclusives/wtr-investigation-exclusives/article/google-blocks-ads-trademark-terminal-operator-abtach-following-uspto-action" target="_blank" rel="noopener">and Google</a> for operating trademark registration scams (the main offices for <span style="font-weight: 400;">eWorldtrade and Abtach share the same address in Pakistan).</span></p>
<p>In November 2021, the USPTO <a href="https://www.worldtrademarkreview.com/data/wtr-investigation-exclusives/wtr-investigation-exclusives/article/the-dangerous-legacy-of-axact-how-diploma-mill-in-pakistan-led-trademark-scam-epidemic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">accused Abtach</a> of perpetrating &#8220;an egregious scheme to deceive and defraud applicants for federal trademark registrations by improperly altering official USPTO correspondence, overcharging application filing fees, misappropriating the USPTO’s trademarks, and impersonating the USPTO.&#8221;</p>
<p>Abtach offered trademark registration at suspiciously low prices compared to legitimate costs of over USD $1,500, and claimed they could register a trademark in 24 hours. Abtach reportedly <a href="https://www.worldtrademarkreview.com/data/wtr-investigation-exclusives/wtr-investigation-exclusives/article/abtach-rebrands-intersys-after-being-banned-uspto" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rebranded </a>to <strong>Intersys Limited</strong> after the USPTO banned Abtach from filing any more trademark applications.</p>
<div id="attachment_71191" style="width: 646px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71191" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71191" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/intersysabtach.png" alt="" width="636" height="870" /><p id="caption-attachment-71191" class="wp-caption-text">In a note published to its LinkedIn profile, Intersys Ltd. asserted last year that certain scam firms in Karachi were impersonating the company.</p></div>
<h2>FROM AXACT TO ABTACH</h2>
<p>Many of Abtach&#8217;s employees are former associates of a similar company in Pakistan called <strong>Axact</strong> that was targeted by Pakistani authorities in a 2015 fraud investigation. Axact came under law enforcement scrutiny after <strong>The New York Times</strong> ran <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/18/world/asia/fake-diplomas-real-cash-pakistani-company-axact-reaps-millions-columbiana-barkley.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a front-page story</a> about the company&#8217;s most lucrative scam business: Hundreds of sites peddling fake college degrees and diplomas.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People who purchased fake certifications were subsequently <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/11/world/asia/pakistan-axact-degree-scam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blackmailed by Axact employees posing as government officials</a>, who would demand additional payments under threats of prosecution or imprisonment for having bought fraudulent “unauthorized” academic degrees. This practice created a continuous cycle of extortion, internally referred to as &#8220;upselling.&#8221; </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Axact took money from at least 215,000 people in 197 countries — one-third of them from the United States,&#8221; The Times reported. &#8220;Sales agents wielded threats and false promises and impersonated government officials, earning the company at least $89 million in its final year of operation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dozens of top Axact employees were arrested, jailed, held for months, tried and sentenced to seven years for various fraud violations. But a 2019 research brief on Axact&#8217;s diploma mills found none of those convicted had started their prison sentence, and that several had fled Pakistan and never returned.</p>
<p>&#8220;In October 2016, a Pakistan district judge acquitted 24 Axact officials at trial due to &#8216;not enough evidence&#8217; and then later admitted he had accepted a bribe (of $35,209) from Axact,&#8221; reads <a href="https://www.aacrao.org/docs/default-source/webinar-documents/94-4-academic-fraud-and-the-worlds-largest-diploma-mill.pdf?sfvrsn=4b276f1f_2#:~:text=Dozens%20of%20top%20Axact%20ex,was%20caught%20at%20the%20airport." target="_blank" rel="noopener">a history</a> (PDF) published by the American Association of Collegiate Registrars and Admissions Officers.</p>
<p>In 2021, Pakistan&#8217;s <strong>Federal Investigation Agency</strong> (FIA) charged Bilwani and nearly four dozen others &#8212; many of them Abtach employees &#8212; with running an elaborate trademark scam. The authorities <a href="https://files.lbr.cloud/public/2021-02/report.pdf?nh3DUDQa7dd3jS63lsAN2dWDbHIQjplS=" target="_blank" rel="noopener">called it</a> &#8220;the biggest money laundering case in the history of Pakistan,&#8221; and named a number of businesses based in Texas that allegedly helped move the proceeds of cybercrime.</p>
<div id="attachment_71216" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71216" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71216" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/fia-report-2021.png" alt="" width="749" height="505" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/fia-report-2021.png 785w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/fia-report-2021-768x518.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/fia-report-2021-782x527.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71216" class="wp-caption-text">A page from the March 2021 FIA report alleging that Digitonics Labs and Abtach employees conspired to extort and defraud consumers.</p></div>
<p>The FIA <a href="https://www.worldtrademarkreview.com/data/wtr-investigation-exclusives/wtr-investigation-exclusives/article/uspto-users-targeted-in-massive-fraud-and-money-laundering-case-in-pakistan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> the defendants operated a large number of websites offering low-cost trademark services to customers, before then “ignoring them after getting the funds and later demanding more funds from clients/victims in the name of up-sale (extortion).&#8221; The Pakistani law enforcement agency said that about 75 percent of customers received fake or fabricated trademarks as a result of the scams.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The FIA <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1dFChoGQHXw7yi-JdVuow3k1XBAuPwAlv/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found</a> Abtach operates in conjunction with a Karachi firm called <strong>Digitonics Labs</strong>, which earned <a href="https://www.worldtrademarkreview.com/data/wtr-investigation-exclusives/wtr-investigation-exclusives/article/bribery-impersonation-abuse-shocking-details-revealed-in-pakistan-fraud-case-targeted-uspto-users" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a monthly revenue of around $2.5 million</a> through the &#8220;extortion of international clients in the name of up-selling, the sale of fake/fabricated USPTO certificates, and the maintaining of phishing websites.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>According the Pakistani authorities, the accused also ran countless scams involving ebook publication and logo creation, wherein customers are subjected to advance-fee fraud and extortion &#8212; with the scammers demanding more money for supposed &#8220;copyright release&#8221; and threatening to release the trademark.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also charged by the FIA was </span><b>Junaid Mansoor</b>, <span style="font-weight: 400;">the owner of Digitonics Labs in Karachi. Mansoor&#8217;s </span><b><span style="font-weight: 400;">U.K.-registered company </span></b><a href="https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/officers/9Xl14hjK0LtYFKRI7kI_werr3As/appointments" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maple Solutions Direct Limited</span></a> <b><span style="font-weight: 400;">has run at least 700 ads for logo design websites since 2015, the Google Ads Transparency page <a href="https://adstransparency.google.com/advertiser/AR16545428366065401857?region=anywhere" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a>. The company has approximately <a href="https://adstransparency.google.com/advertiser/AR16545428366065401857?region=US&amp;preset-date=Today" target="_blank" rel="noopener">88 ads running on Google</a> as of today. </span></b></p>
<div id="attachment_71135" style="width: 702px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71135" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71135" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/junaidmansoor.png" alt="" width="692" height="290" /><p id="caption-attachment-71135" class="wp-caption-text">Junaid Mansoor. Source: youtube/@Olevels․com School.</p></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mr. Mansoor is actively involved with and promoting a Quran study business called <strong>quranmasteronline[.]com</strong>, which was founded by Junaid&#8217;s brother <strong>Qasim Mansoor</strong> (Qasim is also named in the FIA criminal investigation). The Google ads promoting quranmasteronline[.]com were paid for by <a href="https://adstransparency.google.com/advertiser/AR14975696108041273345?region=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the same account</a> advertising a number of scam websites selling logo and web design services. </span></p>
<p>Junaid Mansoor did not respond to requests for comment. An address in Teaneck, New Jersey where Mr. Mansoor previously lived <a href="https://www.mapquest.com/us/new-jersey/exporthub-378873083" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is listed as an official address of exporthub[.]com</a>, a Pakistan-based e-commerce website that appears remarkably similar to eWorldTrade (Exporthub says its offices are in Texas). Interestingly, a search in Google for this domain shows ExportHub currently features <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Aexporthub.com+fentanyl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">multiple listings for fentanyl citrate</a> from suppliers in China and elsewhere.</p>
<p>The CEO of Digitonics Labs is <strong>Muhammad Burhan Mirza</strong>, a former Axact official who was arrested by the FIA as part of its money laundering and trademark fraud investigation in 2021. In 2023, prosecutors in Pakistan charged Mirza, Mansoor and 14 other Digitonics employees with fraud, impersonating government officials, phishing, cheating and extortion. Mirza&#8217;s LinkedIn profile says he currently runs an educational technology/life coach enterprise called <strong>TheCoach360</strong>, which purports to help young kids &#8220;achieve financial independence.&#8221;</p>
<p>Reached via LinkedIn, Mr. Mirza denied having anything to do with eWorldTrade or any of its sister companies in Texas.</p>
<p>&#8220;Moreover, I have no knowledge as to the companies you have mentioned,&#8221; said Mr. Mirza, who did not respond to follow-up questions.</p>
<p>The current disposition of the FIA&#8217;s fraud case against the defendants is unclear. The investigation was marred early on by allegations of corruption and bribery. In 2021, Pakistani authorities alleged Bilwani paid a six-figure bribe to FIA investigators. Meanwhile, attorneys for Mr. Bilwani <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/194s1jG24OE2KjHtOhfGu51i6NhCFGV2X/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">have argued</a> that although their client did pay a bribe, the payment was solicited by government officials. Mr. Bilwani did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<h2>THE TEXAS NEXUS</h2>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity has learned that the people and entities at the center of the FIA investigations have built a significant presence in the United States, with a strong concentration in Texas. The Texas businesses promote websites that sell logo and web design, ghostwriting, and academic cheating services. Many of these entities have recently been sued for fraud and breach of contract by angry former customers, who claimed the companies relentlessly upsold them while failing to produce the work as promised.</p>
<p>For example, the FIA complaints named <strong>Retrocube LLC </strong>and <strong>360 Digital Marketing LLC</strong>, two entities that share a street address with eWorldTrade: 1910 Pacific Avenue, Suite 8025, Dallas, Texas. Also incorporated at that Pacific Avenue address is <strong>abtach[.]ae</strong>, a web design and marketing firm based in Dubai; and <strong>intersyslimited[.]com</strong>, the new name of Abtach after they were banned by the USPTO. Other businesses registered at this address market services for logo design, mobile app development, and ghostwriting.</p>
<div id="attachment_71247" style="width: 727px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/annexure2.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71247" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71247 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/annexure2.png" alt="" width="717" height="699" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-71247" class="wp-caption-text">A list published in 2021 by Pakistan&#8217;s FIA of different front companies allegedly involved in scamming people who are looking for help with trademarks, ghostwriting, logos and web design.</p></div>
<p>360 Digital Marketing&#8217;s website 360digimarketing[.]com is owned by an Abtach front company called <strong>Abtech LTD</strong>. Meanwhile, <a href="https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/company/10311269/officers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">business records show</a> <strong>360 Digi Marketing LTD</strong> is a U.K. company whose officers include former Abtach director Bilwani; <b>Muhammad Saad Iqbal</b>, formerly Abtach, now CEO of Intersys Ltd; <b>Niaz Ahmed</b>, a former Abtach associate; and<b> Muhammad Salman Yousuf</b>, formerly a vice president at Axact, Abtach, and Digitonics Labs.</p>
<p>Google&#8217;s Ads Transparency Center finds 360 Digital Marketing LLC ran at least 500 ads promoting various websites selling ghostwriting services . Another entity tied to Junaid Mansoor &#8212; a company called <strong>Octa Group Technologies AU</strong> &#8212; has run <a href="https://adstransparency.google.com/advertiser/AR08603440443079786497?region=anywhere" target="_blank" rel="noopener">approximately 300 Google ads</a> for book publishing services, promoting confusingly named websites like <span style="font-weight: 400;">amazonlistinghub[.]com and barnesnoblepublishing[.]co.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_71198" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71198" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71198" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/360DigitalMarketingLLC-adstransparency.png" alt="" width="749" height="653" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/360DigitalMarketingLLC-adstransparency.png 1045w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/360DigitalMarketingLLC-adstransparency-768x670.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/360DigitalMarketingLLC-adstransparency-782x682.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71198" class="wp-caption-text">360 Digital Marketing LLC ran approximately 500 ads for scam ghostwriting sites.</p></div>
<p><strong>Rameez Moiz </strong>is a Texas resident and former Abtach product manager who has represented 360 Digital Marketing LLC and RetroCube. Moiz told KrebsOnSecurity he stopped working for 360 Digital Marketing in the summer of 2023. Mr. Moiz did not respond to follow-up questions, but <a href="https://www.upwork.com/agencies/1494464284062437376/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an Upwork profile for him</a> states that as of April 2025 he is employed by Dallas-based <strong>Vertical Minds LLC</strong>.</p>
<p>In April 2025, California resident <strong>Melinda Will</strong> <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qRhvQ6mdyRrFpzWBOdschOo71xIP7ikT/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sued</a> the Texas firm <strong>Majestic Ghostwriting </strong>&#8212; which is doing business as <strong>ghostwritingsquad[.]com</strong> &#8212;  alleging they scammed her out of $100,000 after she hired them to help write her book. Google&#8217;s ad transparency page shows Moiz&#8217;s employer <a href="https://adstransparency.google.com/advertiser/AR06416697976495800321?region=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vertical Minds LLC paid to run approximately 55 ads</a> for <strong>ghostwritingsquad[.]com </strong>and related sites.</p>
<div id="attachment_71190" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/verticalminds-google.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71190" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71190" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/verticalminds-google.png" alt="" width="750" height="455" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/verticalminds-google.png 1437w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/verticalminds-google-768x466.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/verticalminds-google-782x475.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-71190" class="wp-caption-text">Google&#8217;s ad transparency listing for ghostwriting ads paid for by Vertical Minds LLC.</p></div>
<p><span id="more-70782"></span></p>
<h2>VICTIMS SPEAK OUT</h2>
<p>Ms. Will&#8217;s lawsuit is just one of more than two dozen complaints over the past four years wherein plaintiffs sued one of this group&#8217;s web design, wiki editing or ghostwriting services. In 2021, a New Jersey man <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1HOXxv4GP3-zz2tujPYHChmWBY6KUc70P/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sued Octagroup Technologies</a>, alleging they ripped him off when he paid a total of more than $26,000 for the design and marketing of a web-based mapping service.</p>
<p>The plaintiff in that case did not respond to requests for comment, but his complaint alleges Octagroup and a myriad other companies it contracted with produced minimal work product despite subjecting him to relentless upselling. That case was decided in favor of the plaintiff because the defendants never contested the matter in court.</p>
<p>In 2023, 360 Digital Marketing LLC and Retrocube LLC were sued by a woman who said they scammed her out of $40,000 over a book she wanted help writing. That lawsuit helpfully showed <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1w_6-RqZl7GBea-WtdgFkv6xHRVWaG5DV/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an image of the office front door</a> at 1910 Pacific Ave Suite 8025, which featured the logos of 360 Digital Marketing, Retrocube, and eWorldTrade.</p>
<div id="attachment_71140" style="width: 621px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71140" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71140" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/360digitalmarketingfrontdoorintexas.png" alt="" width="611" height="763" /><p id="caption-attachment-71140" class="wp-caption-text">The front door at 1910 Pacific Avenue, Suite 8025, Dallas, Texas.</p></div>
<p>The lawsuit was filed pro se by <strong>Leigh Riley</strong>, a 64-year-old career IT professional who paid 360 Digital Marketing to have a company called <strong>Talented Ghostwriter</strong> co-author and promote a series of books she&#8217;d outlined on spirituality and healing.</p>
<p>&#8220;The main reason I hired them was because I didn&#8217;t understand what I call the formula for writing a book, and I know there&#8217;s a lot of marketing that goes into publishing,&#8221; Riley explained in an interview. &#8220;I know nothing about that stuff, and these guys were convincing that they could handle all aspects of it. Until I discovered they couldn&#8217;t write a damn sentence in English properly.&#8221;</p>
<p>Riley&#8217;s well-documented lawsuit (not linked here because it features a great deal of personal information) includes screenshots of conversations with the ghostwriting team, which was constantly assigning her to new writers and editors, and ghosting her on scheduled conference calls about progress on the project. Riley said she ended up writing most of the book herself because the work they produced was unusable.</p>
<p>&#8220;Finally after months of promising the books were printed and on their way, they show up at my doorstep with the wrong title on the book,&#8221; Riley said. When she demanded her money back, she said the people helping her with the website to promote the book locked her out of the site.</p>
<div id="attachment_71203" style="width: 764px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71203" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71203" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/rileylawsuit.png" alt="" width="754" height="686" /><p id="caption-attachment-71203" class="wp-caption-text">A conversation snippet from Leigh Riley&#8217;s lawsuit against Talented Ghostwriter, aka 360 Digital Marketing LLC. &#8220;Other companies once they have you money they don&#8217;t even respond or do anything,&#8221; the ghostwriting team manager explained.</p></div>
<p>Riley decided to sue, naming 360 Digital Marketing LLC and Retrocube LLC, among others.  The companies offered to settle the matter for $20,000, which she accepted. &#8220;I didn&#8217;t have money to hire a lawyer, and I figured it was time to cut my losses,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Riley said she could have saved herself a great deal of headache by doing some basic research on Talented Ghostwriter, whose website claims the company is based in Los Angeles. According to the California Secretary of State, however, there is no registered entity by that name. Rather, the address claimed by <strong>talentedghostwriter[.]com</strong> is a vacant office building with a &#8220;space available&#8221; sign in the window.</p>
<p>California resident <strong>Walter Horsting </strong>discovered something similar when he sued 360 Digital Marketing in small claims court last year, after hiring a company called <strong>Vox Ghostwriting</strong> to help write, edit and promote a spy novel he&#8217;d been working on. Horsting said he paid Vox $3,300 to ghostwrite a 280-page book, and was upsold an Amazon marketing and publishing package for $7,500.</p>
<p>In an interview, Horsting said the prose that Vox Ghostwriting produced was &#8220;juvenile at best,&#8221; forcing him to rewrite and edit the work himself, and to partner with a graphical artist to produce illustrations. Horsting said that when it came time to begin marketing the novel, Vox Ghostwriting tried to further upsell him on marketing packages, while dodging scheduled meetings with no follow-up.</p>
<p>&#8220;They have a money back guarantee, and when they wouldn&#8217;t refund my money I said I&#8217;m taking you to court,&#8221; Horsting recounted. &#8220;I tried to serve them in Los Angeles but found no such office exists. I talked to a salon next door and they said someone else had recently shown up desperately looking for where the ghostwriting company went, and it appears there are a trail of corpses on this. I finally tracked down where they are in Texas.&#8221;</p>
<p>It was the same office that Ms. Riley served her lawsuit against. Horsting said he has a court hearing scheduled later this month, but he&#8217;s under no illusions that winning the case means he&#8217;ll be able to collect.</p>
<p>&#8220;At this point, I&#8217;m doing it out of pride more than actually expecting anything to come to good fortune for me,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The following mind map was helpful in piecing together key events, individuals and connections mentioned above. It&#8217;s important to note that this graphic only scratches the surface of the operations tied to this group. For example, in Case 2 we can see mention of academic cheating services, wherein people can be hired to take online proctored exams on one&#8217;s behalf. Those who hire these services soon find themselves subject to impersonation and blackmail attempts for larger and larger sums of money, with the threat of publicly exposing their unethical academic cheating activity.</p>
<div id="attachment_71218" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ewt-20.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71218" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71218" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ewt-20.png" alt="" width="750" height="376" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ewt-20.png 1861w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ewt-20-768x385.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ewt-20-1536x771.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ewt-20-782x392.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-71218" class="wp-caption-text">A &#8220;mind map&#8221; illustrating the connections between and among entities referenced in this story. Click to enlarge.</p></div>
<h2>GOOGLE RESPONDS</h2>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity reviewed the Google Ad Transparency links for nearly 500 different websites tied to this network of ghostwriting, logo, app and web development businesses. Those website names were then fed into <strong>spyfu.com</strong>, a competitive intelligence company that tracks the reach and performance of advertising keywords. Spyfu estimates that between April 2023 and April 2025, those websites <em>spent more than $10 million on Google ads</em>.</p>
<p>Reached for comment, Google said in a written statement that it is constantly policing its ad network for bad actors, pointing to <a href="https://services.google.com/fh/files/misc/ads_safety_report_2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an ads safety report</a> (PDF) showing Google blocked or removed 5.1 billion bad ads last year &#8212; including more than 500 million ads related to trademarks.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our policy against Enabling Dishonest Behavior prohibits products or services that help users mislead others, including ads for paper-writing or exam-taking services,&#8221; the statement reads. &#8220;When we identify ads or advertisers that violate our policies, we take action, including by suspending advertiser accounts, disapproving ads, and restricting ads to specific domains when appropriate.&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-71192" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/googleadpolicyenforcement.png" alt="" width="749" height="490" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/googleadpolicyenforcement.png 980w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/googleadpolicyenforcement-768x502.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/googleadpolicyenforcement-782x511.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>Google did not respond to specific questions about the advertising entities mentioned in this story, saying only that &#8220;we are actively investigating this matter and addressing any policy violations, including suspending advertiser accounts when appropriate.&#8221;</p>
<p>From reviewing the ad accounts that have been promoting these scam websites, it appears Google has very recently acted to remove a large number of the offending ads. Prior to my notifying Google about the extent of this ad network on April 28, the Google Ad Transparency network listed over 500 ads for 360 Digital Marketing; as of this publication, that number had <a href="https://adstransparency.google.com/advertiser/AR11727645009044832257?region=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dwindled to 10</a>.</p>
<p>On April 30, Google <a href="https://support.google.com/adspolicy/answer/16189141?hl=en&amp;ref_topic=16083443" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that starting this month its ads transparency page will display the payment profile name as the payer name for verified advertisers, if that name differs from their verified advertiser name. Searchengineland.com <a href="https://searchengineland.com/google-adds-to-its-transparency-rules-for-who-is-paying-for-ads-454899" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> the changes are aimed at increasing accountability in digital advertising.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1xZ4yHTsWxnTtEVrazDbqWQY5Vju8USeBfszCGl6uxfc/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This spreadsheet</a> lists the domain names, advertiser names, and Google Ad Transparency links for more than 350 entities offering ghostwriting, publishing, web design and academic cheating services.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity would like to thank the anonymous security researcher <a href="https://natinfosec.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NatInfoSec</a> for their assistance in this investigation.</p>
<p>For further reading on Abtach and its myriad companies in all of the above-mentioned verticals (ghostwriting, logo design, etc.), see <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/articles/Wikipedia%3AList_of_paid_editing_companies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this Wikiwand entry</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/pakistani-firm-shipped-fentanyl-analogs-scams-to-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>xAI Dev Leaks API Key for Private SpaceX, Tesla LLMs</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/xai-dev-leaks-api-key-for-private-spacex-tesla-llms/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/xai-dev-leaks-api-key-for-private-spacex-tesla-llms/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carole Winqwist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Government Efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Fourrier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Services Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitGuardian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GSAi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippe Caturegli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reuters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seralys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter/X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xAI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A employee at Elon Musk's artificial intelligence company xAI leaked a private key on GitHub that for the past two months could have allowed anyone to query private xAI large language models (LLMs) which appear to have been custom made for working with internal data from Musk's companies, including SpaceX, Tesla and Twitter/X, KrebsOnSecurity has learned.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An employee at Elon Musk&#8217;s artificial intelligence company <strong>xAI</strong> leaked a private key on <strong>GitHub</strong> that for the past two months could have allowed anyone to query private xAI large language models (LLMs) which appear to have been custom made for working with internal data from Musk&#8217;s companies, including <strong>SpaceX</strong>, <strong>Tesla</strong> and <strong>Twitter/X, </strong>KrebsOnSecurity has learned.</p>
<div id="attachment_71170" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71170" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71170" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/x-ai.png" alt="" width="748" height="497" /><p id="caption-attachment-71170" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, @sdx15.</p></div>
<p><strong>Philippe Caturegli</strong>, &#8220;chief hacking officer&#8221; at the security consultancy <strong>Seralys</strong>, was <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/caturegli_yo-xai-your-devs-are-leaking-api-keys-on-activity-7321566948020953088-6KXj?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAAliaMB3BQO-WOS-eUh-XU4HAd5h8pTzkI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the first to publicize the leak</a> of credentials for an x.ai application programming interface (API) exposed in the GitHub code repository of a technical staff member at xAI.</p>
<p>Caturegli&#8217;s post on LinkedIn caught the attention of researchers at <strong>GitGuardian</strong>, a company that specializes in detecting and remediating exposed secrets in public and proprietary environments. GitGuardian&#8217;s systems constantly scan GitHub and other code repositories for exposed API keys, and fire off automated alerts to affected users.</p>
<p>GitGuardian&#8217;s <strong>Eric Fourrier</strong> told KrebsOnSecurity the exposed API key had access to several unreleased models of <strong>Grok</strong>, the AI chatbot developed by xAI. In total, GitGuardian found the key had access to at least 60 fine-tuned and private LLMs.</p>
<p>&#8220;The credentials can be used to access the X.ai API with the identity of the user,&#8221; GitGuardian wrote in an email explaining their findings to xAI. &#8220;The associated account not only has access to public Grok models (grok-2-1212, etc) but also to what appears to be unreleased (grok-2.5V), development (research-grok-2p5v-1018), and private models (tweet-rejector, grok-spacex-2024-11-04).&#8221;</p>
<p>Fourrier found GitGuardian had alerted the xAI employee about the exposed API key nearly two months ago &#8212; on March 2. But as of April 30, when GitGuardian directly alerted xAI&#8217;s security team to the exposure, the key was still valid and usable. xAI told GitGuardian to report the matter through its bug bounty program at <strong>HackerOne</strong>, but just a few hours later the repository containing the API key was removed from GitHub.</p>
<p>&#8220;It looks like some of these internal LLMs were fine-tuned on SpaceX data, and some were fine-tuned with Tesla data,&#8221; Fourrier said. &#8220;I definitely don&#8217;t think a Grok model that&#8217;s fine-tuned on SpaceX data is intended to be exposed publicly.&#8221;</p>
<p>xAI did not respond to a request for comment. Nor did the 28-year-old xAI technical staff member whose key was exposed.<span id="more-71165"></span></p>
<p><strong>Carole Winqwist</strong>, chief marketing officer at GitGuardian, said giving potentially hostile users free access to private LLMs is a recipe for disaster.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you&#8217;re an attacker and you have direct access to the model and the back end interface for things like Grok, it&#8217;s definitely something you can use for further attacking,&#8221; she said. &#8220;An attacker could it use for prompt injection, to tweak the (LLM) model to serve their purposes, or try to implant code into the supply chain.&#8221;</p>
<p>The inadvertent exposure of internal LLMs for xAI comes as Musk&#8217;s so-called <strong>Department of Government Efficiency</strong> (DOGE) has been feeding sensitive government records into artificial intelligence tools. In February, <strong>The Washington Post</strong> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2025/02/06/elon-musk-doge-ai-department-education/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> DOGE officials were feeding data from across the Education Department into AI tools to probe the agency&#8217;s programs and spending.</p>
<p>The Post said DOGE plans to replicate this process across many departments and agencies, accessing the back-end software at different parts of the government and then using AI technology to extract and sift through information about spending on employees and programs.</p>
<p>&#8220;Feeding sensitive data into AI software puts it into the possession of a system&#8217;s operator, increasing the chances it will be leaked or swept up in cyberattacks,&#8221; Post reporters wrote.</p>
<p>Wired reported in March that DOGE has <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/gsai-chatbot-1500-federal-workers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">deployed a proprietary chatbot called GSAi</a> to 1,500 federal workers at the <strong>General Services Administration</strong>, part of an effort to automate tasks previously done by humans as DOGE continues its purge of the federal workforce.</p>
<p>A <strong>Reuters</strong> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/musks-doge-using-ai-snoop-us-federal-workers-sources-say-2025-04-08/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">report</a> last month said Trump administration officials told some U.S. government employees that DOGE is using AI to surveil at least one federal agency&#8217;s communications for hostility to President Trump and his agenda. Reuters wrote that the DOGE team has heavily deployed Musk’s Grok AI chatbot as part of their work slashing the federal government, although Reuters said it could not establish exactly how Grok was being used.</p>
<p>Caturegli said while there is no indication that federal government or user data could be accessed through the exposed x.ai API key, these private models are likely trained on proprietary data and may unintentionally expose details related to internal development efforts at xAI, Twitter, or SpaceX.</p>
<p>&#8220;The fact that this key was publicly exposed for two months and granted access to internal models is concerning,&#8221; Caturegli said. &#8220;This kind of long-lived credential exposure highlights weak key management and insufficient internal monitoring, raising questions about safeguards around developer access and broader operational security.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/xai-dev-leaks-api-key-for-private-spacex-tesla-llms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alleged &#8216;Scattered Spider&#8217; Member Extradited to U.S.</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/alleged-scattered-spider-member-extradited-to-u-s/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/alleged-scattered-spider-member-extradited-to-u-s/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 21:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SIM Swapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[0ktapus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ahmed Elbadawy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Caesars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evans Osiebo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Group-IB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joel Evans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lastpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MGM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah Urban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scattered Spider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SIM swapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyler Robert Buchanan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tylerb]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A 23-year-old Scottish man thought to be a member of the prolific Scattered Spider cybercrime group was extradited last week from Spain to the United States, where he is facing charges of wire fraud, conspiracy and identity theft. U.S. prosecutors allege Tyler Robert Buchanan and co-conspirators hacked into dozens of companies in the United States and abroad, and that he personally controlled more than $26 million stolen from victims.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 23-year-old Scottish man thought to be a member of the prolific <strong>Scattered Spider</strong> cybercrime group was extradited last week from Spain to the United States, where he is facing charges of wire fraud, conspiracy and identity theft. U.S. prosecutors allege <strong>Tyler Robert Buchanan</strong> and co-conspirators hacked into dozens of companies in the United States and abroad, and that he personally controlled more than $26 million stolen from victims.</p>
<p>Scattered Spider is a loosely affiliated criminal hacking group whose members have broken into and stolen data from some of the world&#8217;s largest technology companies. Buchanan was arrested in Spain last year on a warrant from the FBI, which wanted him in connection with a series of SMS-based phishing attacks in the summer of 2022 that led to intrusions at Twilio, LastPass, DoorDash, Mailchimp, and many other tech firms.</p>
<div id="attachment_67783" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-67783" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-67783" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/tylerb.png" alt="" width="748" height="308" /><p id="caption-attachment-67783" class="wp-caption-text">Tyler Buchanan, being escorted by Spanish police at the airport in Palma de Mallorca in June 2024.</p></div>
<p>As <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/06/alleged-boss-of-scattered-spider-hacking-group-arrested/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first reported</a> by KrebsOnSecurity, Buchanan (a.k.a. &#8220;tylerb&#8221;) fled the United Kingdom in February 2023, after a rival cybercrime gang hired thugs to invade his home, assault his mother, and threaten to burn him with a blowtorch unless he gave up the keys to his cryptocurrency wallet. Buchanan was arrested in June 2024 at the airport in Palma de Mallorca while trying to board a flight to Italy. His extradition to the United States was <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-24/scattered-spider-hacking-suspect-extradited-to-us-from-spain" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first reported</a> last week by <strong>Bloomberg</strong>.</p>
<p>Members of Scattered Spider have been <a href="https://cyberscoop.com/youth-hacking-ring-at-the-center-of-cybercrime-spree/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tied</a> to the 2023 ransomware attacks against <strong>MGM</strong> and <strong>Caesars</strong> casinos in Las Vegas, but it remains unclear whether Buchanan was implicated in that incident. The Justice Department&#8217;s complaint against Buchanan makes no mention of the 2023 ransomware attack.</p>
<p>Rather, the investigation into Buchanan appears to center on the SMS phishing campaigns from 2022, and on <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/sim-swapping/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SIM-swapping attacks</a> that siphoned funds from individual cryptocurrency investors. In a SIM-swapping attack, crooks transfer the target’s phone number to a device they control and intercept any text messages or phone calls to the victim&#8217;s device — including one-time passcodes for authentication and password reset links sent via SMS.</p>
<p>In August 2022, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/08/how-1-time-passcodes-became-a-corporate-liability/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reviewed data harvested in a months-long cybercrime campaign by Scattered Spider</a> involving countless SMS-based phishing attacks against employees at major corporations. The security firm <strong>Group-IB</strong> called them by a different name — <strong>0ktapus</strong>, because the group typically spoofed the identity provider <strong>Okta</strong> in their phishing messages to employees at targeted firms.</p>
<div id="attachment_61078" style="width: 654px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-61078" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-61078 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/twiliophish.png" alt="" width="644" height="471" /><p id="caption-attachment-61078" class="wp-caption-text">A Scattered Spider/0Ktapus SMS phishing lure sent to Twilio employees in 2022.</p></div>
<p>The <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/tylerb-complaint.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">complaint against Buchanan</a> (PDF) says the FBI tied him to the 2022 SMS phishing attacks after discovering the same username and email address was used to register numerous Okta-themed phishing domains seen in the campaign. The domain registrar <strong>NameCheap</strong> found that less than a month before the phishing spree, the account that registered those domains logged in from an Internet address in the U.K. FBI investigators said the Scottish police told them the address was leased to Buchanan from January 26, 2022 to November 7, 2022.</p>
<p>Authorities seized at least 20 digital devices when they raided Buchanan&#8217;s residence, and on one of those devices they found usernames and passwords for employees of three different companies targeted in the phishing campaign.</p>
<p>&#8220;The FBI’s investigation to date has gathered evidence showing that Buchanan and his co-conspirators targeted at least 45 companies in the United States and abroad, including Canada, India, and the United Kingdom,&#8221; the FBI complaint reads. &#8220;One of Buchanan&#8217;s devices contained a screenshot of Telegram messages between an account known to be used by Buchanan and other unidentified co-conspirators discussing dividing up the proceeds of SIM swapping.&#8221;<span id="more-71147"></span></p>
<p>U.S. prosecutors allege that records obtained from Discord showed the same U.K. Internet address was used to operate a Discord account that specified a cryptocurrency wallet when asking another user to send funds. The complaint says the publicly available transaction history for that payment address shows approximately 391 bitcoin was transferred in and out of this address between October 2022 and<br />
February 2023; 391 bitcoin is presently worth more than $26 million.</p>
<p>In November 2024, federal prosecutors in Los Angeles <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/feds-charge-five-men-in-scattered-spider-roundup/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unsealed criminal charges against Buchanan</a> and four other alleged Scattered Spider members, including <strong>Ahmed Elbadawy</strong>, 23, of College Station, Texas; <strong>Joel Evans</strong>, 25, of Jacksonville, North Carolina; <strong>Evans Osiebo</strong>, 20, of Dallas; and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/01/fla-man-charged-in-sim-swapping-spree-is-key-suspect-in-hacker-groups-oktapus-scattered-spider/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Noah Urban</strong></a>, 20, of Palm Coast, Florida. KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported last year</a> that another suspected Scattered Spider member &#8212; a 17-year-old from the United Kingdom &#8212; was arrested as part of a joint investigation with the FBI into the MGM hack.</p>
<p>Mr. Buchanan&#8217;s court-appointed attorney did not respond to a request for comment. The accused faces charges of wire fraud conspiracy, conspiracy to obtain information by computer for private financial gain, and aggravated identity theft. Convictions on the latter charge carry a minimum sentence of two years in prison.</p>
<p>Documents from the U.S. District Court for the Central District of California indicate Buchanan is being held without bail pending trial. A preliminary hearing in the case is slated for May 6.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/alleged-scattered-spider-member-extradited-to-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DOGE Worker&#8217;s Code Supports NLRB Whistleblower</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/doge-workers-code-supports-nlrb-whistleblower/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/doge-workers-code-supports-nlrb-whistleblower/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 20:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[async-ip-rotator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Browserless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel J. Berulis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Government Efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Health and Human Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ge0rg3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Integuru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor Department]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marko Elez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Labor Relations Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Wall Street Journal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A whistleblower at the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) alleged last week that denizens of Elon Musk's Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) siphoned gigabytes of data from the agency's sensitive case files in early March. The whistleblower said accounts created for DOGE at the NLRB downloaded three code repositories from GitHub. Further investigation into one of those code bundles shows it is remarkably similar to a program published in January 2025 by Marko Elez, a 25-year-old DOGE employee who has worked at a number of Musk's companies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A whistleblower at the <strong>National Labor Relations Board</strong> (NLRB) alleged last week that denizens of Elon Musk&#8217;s <strong>Department of Government Efficiency</strong> (DOGE) siphoned gigabytes of data from the agency&#8217;s sensitive case files in early March. The whistleblower said accounts created for DOGE at the NLRB downloaded three code repositories from <strong>GitHub</strong>. Further investigation into one of those code bundles shows it is remarkably similar to a program published in January 2025 by <strong>Marko Elez</strong>, a 25-year-old DOGE employee who has worked at a number of Musk&#8217;s companies.</p>
<div id="attachment_71090" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/db-powershellcmds.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71090" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71090" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/db-powershellcmds.png" alt="" width="748" height="323" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/db-powershellcmds.png 1287w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/db-powershellcmds-768x331.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/db-powershellcmds-782x337.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-71090" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot shared by NLRB whistleblower Daniel Berulis shows three downloads from GitHub.</p></div>
<p>According to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/whistleblower-doge-siphoned-nlrb-case-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a whistleblower complaint</a> filed last week by <strong>Daniel J. Berulis</strong>, a 38-year-old security architect at the NLRB, officials from DOGE met with NLRB leaders on March 3 and demanded the creation of several all-powerful “tenant admin” accounts that were to be exempted from network logging activity that would otherwise keep a detailed record of all actions taken by those accounts.</p>
<p>Berulis said the new DOGE accounts had unrestricted permission to read, copy, and alter information contained in NLRB databases. The new accounts also could restrict log visibility, delay retention, route logs elsewhere, or even remove them entirely — top-tier user privileges that neither Berulis nor his boss possessed.</p>
<p>Berulis said he discovered one of the DOGE accounts had downloaded three external code libraries from <strong>GitHub</strong> that neither NLRB nor its contractors ever used. A “readme” file in one of the code bundles explained it was created to rotate connections through a large pool of cloud Internet addresses that serve “<em>as a proxy to generate pseudo-infinite IPs for web scraping and brute forcing</em>.” Brute force attacks involve automated login attempts that try many credential combinations in rapid sequence.</p>
<p>A search on that description in Google brings up a code repository at GitHub for a user with the account name &#8220;<strong>Ge0rg3</strong>&#8221; who published a program roughly four years ago called &#8220;<a href="https://github.com/Ge0rg3/requests-ip-rotator" target="_blank" rel="noopener">requests-ip-rotator</a>,&#8221; described as a library that will allow the user &#8220;to bypass IP-based rate-limits for sites and services.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_71091" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71091" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71091" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ge0rge-gh.png" alt="" width="749" height="543" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ge0rge-gh.png 1171w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ge0rge-gh-768x557.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/ge0rge-gh-782x568.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71091" class="wp-caption-text">The README file from the GitHub user Ge0rg3&#8217;s page for requests-ip-rotator includes the exact wording of a program the whistleblower said was downloaded by one of the DOGE users. Marko Elez created an offshoot of this program in January 2025.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;A Python library to utilize AWS API Gateway&#8217;s large IP pool as a proxy to generate pseudo-infinite IPs for web scraping and brute forcing,&#8221; the description reads.</p>
<p>Ge0rg3&#8217;s code is &#8220;open source,&#8221; in that anyone can copy it and reuse it non-commercially. As it happens, there is a newer version of this project that was derived or &#8220;forked&#8221; from Ge0rg3&#8217;s code &#8212; called &#8220;<a href="https://github.com/markoelez/async-ip-rotator/blob/master/README.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener">async-ip-rotator</a>&#8221; &#8212; and it was committed to GitHub in January 2025 by DOGE captain <a href="https://github.com/markoelez" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marko Elez</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_71085" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/melez-gh.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71085" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71085" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/melez-gh.png" alt="" width="750" height="492" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/melez-gh.png 1150w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/melez-gh-768x504.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/melez-gh-782x513.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-71085" class="wp-caption-text">The whistleblower stated that one of the GitHub files downloaded by the DOGE employees who transferred sensitive files from an NLRB case database was an archive whose README file read: &#8220;Python library to utilize AWS API Gateway&#8217;s large IP pool as a proxy to generate pseudo-infinite IPs for web scraping and brute forcing.&#8221; Elez&#8217;s code pictured here was forked in January 2025 from a code library that shares the same description.</p></div>
<p>A key DOGE staff member who gained access to the Treasury Department&#8217;s central payments system, Elez has worked for a number of Musk companies, including <strong>X</strong>, <strong>SpaceX</strong>, and <strong>xAI</strong>. Elez was among the first DOGE employees to face public scrutiny, after <strong>The Wall Street Journal</strong> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/doge-staffer-resigns-over-racist-posts-d9f11a93" target="_blank" rel="noopener">linked him to social media posts</a> that advocated racism and eugenics.</p>
<p>Elez resigned after that brief scandal, but was rehired after President Donald Trump and Vice President JD Vance expressed support for him. <strong>Politico</strong> <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/03/29/doge-marco-elez-software-engineer-us-payroll-00259303" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> Elez is now a <strong>Labor Department</strong> aide detailed to multiple agencies, including the <strong>Department of Health and Human Services</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;During Elez’s initial stint at Treasury, he violated the agency’s information security policies by sending a spreadsheet containing names and payments information to officials at the General Services Administration,&#8221; Politico wrote, citing court filings.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity sought comment from both the NLRB and DOGE, and will update this story if either responds.<span id="more-71075"></span></p>
<p>The NLRB has been effectively hobbled since <strong>President Trump</strong> fired three board members, leaving the agency without the quorum it needs to function. Both <strong>Amazon</strong> and Musk’s <strong>SpaceX</strong> have <a href="https://apnews.com/article/amazon-nlrb-unconstitutional-spacex-elon-musk-ab42977117d883e97110a7bf8e8b257f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">been suing</a> the NLRB over complaints the agency filed in disputes about workers’ rights and union organizing, arguing that the NLRB’s very existence is unconstitutional. On March 5, a U.S. appeals court <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/government/musks-spacex-loses-early-legal-challenge-us-labor-boards-powers-2025-03-05/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unanimously rejected</a> Musk’s claim that the NLRB’s structure somehow violates the Constitution.</p>
<p>Berulis&#8217;s complaint alleges the DOGE accounts at NLRB downloaded more than 10 gigabytes of data from the agency&#8217;s case files, a database that includes reams of sensitive records including information about employees who want to form unions and proprietary business documents. Berulis said he went public after higher-ups at the agency told him not to report the matter to the US-CERT, as they&#8217;d previously agreed.</p>
<p>Berulis told KrebsOnSecurity he worried the unauthorized data transfer by DOGE could unfairly advantage defendants in a number of ongoing labor disputes before the agency.</p>
<p>&#8220;If any company got the case data that would be an unfair advantage,&#8221; Berulis said. &#8220;They could identify and fire employees and union organizers without saying why.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_71106" style="width: 454px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71106" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71106" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/markoelez.png" alt="" width="444" height="515" /><p id="caption-attachment-71106" class="wp-caption-text">Marko Elez, in a photo from a social media profile.</p></div>
<p>Berulis said the other two GitHub archives that DOGE employees downloaded to NLRB systems included <strong>Integuru</strong>, a software framework designed to reverse engineer application programming interfaces (APIs) that websites use to fetch data; and a &#8220;headless&#8221; browser called <strong>Browserless</strong>, which is made for automating web-based tasks that require a pool of browsers, such as web scraping and automated testing.</p>
<p>On February 6, someone <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250423135719/https://github.com/markoelez/async-ip-rotator/issues/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">posted a lengthy and detailed critique</a> of Elez&#8217;s code on the GitHub &#8220;issues&#8221; page for async-ip-rotator, calling it &#8220;insecure, unscalable and a fundamental engineering failure.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;If this were a side project, it would just be bad code,&#8221; the reviewer wrote. &#8220;But if this is representative of how you build production systems, then there are much larger concerns. This implementation is fundamentally broken, and if anything similar to this is deployed in an environment handling sensitive data, it should be audited immediately.&#8221;</p>
<p>Further reading: <a href="https://whistlebloweraid.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/2025_0414_Berulis-Disclosure-with-Exhibits.s.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Berulis’s complaint</a> (PDF).</p>
<p><strong>Update 7:06 p.m. ET</strong>: Elez&#8217;s code repo was deleted after this story was published. An archived version of it <a href="https://github.com/ricci/async-ip-rotator" target="_blank" rel="noopener">is here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/doge-workers-code-supports-nlrb-whistleblower/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 293/293 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached (User agent is rejected) 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2025-06-03 04:03:33 by W3 Total Cache
-->