<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:27:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Mobile Phishers Target Brokerage Accounts in &#8216;Ramp and Dump&#8217; Cashout Scheme</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/mobile-phishers-target-brokerage-accounts-in-ramp-and-dump-cashout-scheme/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/mobile-phishers-target-brokerage-accounts-in-ramp-and-dump-cashout-scheme/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@chenlun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSIS Security Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Industry Regulatory Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FINRA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Merrill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outsider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pump-and-dump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramp and dump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schwab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SecAlliance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71895</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cybercriminal groups peddling sophisticated phishing kits that convert stolen card data into mobile wallets have recently shifted their focus to targeting customers of brokerage services, new research shows. Undeterred by security controls at these trading platforms that block users from wiring funds directly out of accounts, the phishers have pivoted to using multiple compromised brokerage accounts in unison to manipulate the prices of foreign stocks.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cybercriminal groups peddling sophisticated phishing kits that convert stolen card data into mobile wallets have recently shifted their focus to targeting customers of brokerage services, new research shows. Undeterred by security controls at these trading platforms that block users from wiring funds directly out of accounts, the phishers have pivoted to using multiple compromised brokerage accounts in unison to manipulate the prices of foreign stocks.</p>
<div id="attachment_71919" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71919" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-71919" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/stockfall.png" alt="" width="750" height="315" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/stockfall.png 919w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/stockfall-768x323.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/stockfall-782x328.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71919" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, WhataWin.</p></div>
<p>This so-called &#8216;<strong>ramp and dump</strong>&#8216; scheme borrows its name from age-old &#8220;pump and dump&#8221; scams, wherein fraudsters purchase a large number of shares in some penny stock, and then promote the company in a frenzied social media blitz to build up interest from other investors. The fraudsters dump their shares after the price of the penny stock increases to some degree, which usually then causes a sharp drop in the value of the shares for legitimate investors.</p>
<p>With ramp and dump, the scammers do not need to rely on ginning up interest in the targeted stock on social media. Rather, they will preposition themselves in the stock that they wish to inflate, using compromised accounts to purchase large volumes of it and then dumping the shares after the stock price reaches a certain value. In February 2025, the <strong>FBI</strong> said it was <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/how-we-can-help-you/victim-services/seeking-victim-information/seeking-victim-information-in-ramp-and-dump-investment-fraud-investigation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seeking information from victims of this scheme</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;In this variation, the price manipulation is primarily the result of controlled trading activity conducted by the bad actors behind the scam,&#8221; reads <a href="https://www.finra.org/investors/insights/ramp-and-dump-schemes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an advisory</a> from the <strong>Financial Industry Regulatory Authority</strong> (FINRA), a private, non-profit organization that regulates member brokerage firms. &#8220;Ultimately, the outcome for unsuspecting investors is the same—a catastrophic collapse in share price that leaves investors with unrecoverable losses.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Ford Merrill </strong>is a security researcher at <a href="https://www.secalliance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SecAlliance</a>, a <a href="https://www.csis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSIS Security Group</a> company. Merrill said he has tracked recent ramp-and-dump activity to a bustling Chinese-language community that is quite openly selling advanced mobile phishing kits on Telegram.</p>
<p>&#8220;They will often coordinate with other actors and will wait until a certain time to buy a particular Chinese IPO [initial public offering] stock or penny stock,&#8221; said Merrill, who has been chronicling the rapid maturation and growth of the China-based phishing community over the past three years.</p>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;ll use all these victim brokerage accounts, and if needed they&#8217;ll liquidate the account&#8217;s current positions, and will preposition themselves in that instrument in some account they control, and then sell everything when the price goes up,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The victim will be left with worthless shares of that equity in their account, and the brokerage may not be happy either.&#8221;</p>
<p>Merrill said the early days of these phishing groups &#8212; between 2022 and 2024 &#8212; were typified by phishing kits that used text messages to spoof the <strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong> or some local toll road operator, warning about a delinquent shipping or toll fee that needed paying. Recipients who clicked the link and provided their payment information at a fake USPS or toll operator site were then asked to verify the transaction by sharing a one-time code sent via text message.</p>
<p>In reality, the victim&#8217;s bank is sending that code to the mobile number on file for their customer because the fraudsters have just attempted to enroll that victim’s card details into a mobile wallet. If the visitor supplies that one-time code, their payment card is then added to a new mobile wallet on an Apple or Google device that is physically controlled by the phishers.</p>
<p>The phishing gangs typically load multiple stolen cards to digital wallets on a single Apple or Android device, and then sell those phones in bulk to scammers who <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/arrests-in-tap-to-pay-scheme-powered-by-phishing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">use them for fraudulent e-commerce and tap-to-pay transactions</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_70436" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70436" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70436" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png" alt="" width="750" height="567" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png 1160w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-768x581.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-782x591.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70436" class="wp-caption-text">An image from the Telegram channel for a popular Chinese mobile phishing kit vendor shows 10 mobile phones for sale, each loaded with 4-6 digital wallets from different financial institutions.</p></div>
<p>This China-based phishing collective exposed a major weakness common to many U.S.-based financial institutions that already require multi-factor authentication: The reliance on a single, phishable one-time token for provisioning mobile wallets. Happily, Merrill said many financial institutions that were caught flat-footed on this scam two years ago have since strengthened authentication requirements for onboarding new mobile wallets (such as requiring the card to be enrolled via the bank&#8217;s mobile app).</p>
<p>But just as squeezing one part of a balloon merely forces the air trapped inside to bulge into another area, fraudsters don&#8217;t go away when you make their current enterprise less profitable: They just shift their focus to a less-guarded area. And lately, that gaze has settled squarely on customers of the major brokerage platforms, Merrill said.</p>
<h2>THE OUTSIDER</h2>
<p>Merrill pointed to several Telegram channels operated by some of the more accomplished phishing kit sellers, which are full of videos demonstrating how every feature in their kits can be tailored to the attacker&#8217;s target. The video snippet below comes from the Telegram channel of &#8220;<strong>Outsider</strong>,&#8221; a popular Mandarin-speaking phishing kit vendor whose latest offering includes a number of ready-made templates for using text messages to phish brokerage account credentials and one-time codes.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nuL84VeT6BY?si=C0uWiR7QMH-LNtp_" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></div>
<p>According to Merrill, Outsider is a woman who previously went by the handle &#8220;<strong>Chenlun</strong>.&#8221; KrebsOnSecurity profiled Chenlun&#8217;s phishing empire in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/10/phishers-spoof-usps-12-other-natl-postal-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an October 2023 story</a> about a China-based group that was phishing mobile customers of more than a dozen postal services around the globe. In that case, the phishing sites were using a Telegram bot that sent stolen credentials to the &#8220;@chenlun&#8221; Telegram account.</p>
<p>Chenlun&#8217;s phishing lures are sent via Apple&#8217;s iMessage and Google&#8217;s RCS service and spoof one of the major brokerage platforms, warning that the account has been suspended for suspicious activity and that recipients should log in and verify some information. The missives include a link to a phishing page that collects the customer&#8217;s username and password, and then asks the user to enter a one-time code that will arrive via SMS.</p>
<p>The new phish kit videos on Outsider&#8217;s Telegram channel only feature templates for Schwab customers, but Merrill said the kit can easily be adapted to target other brokerage platforms. One reason the fraudsters are picking on brokerage firms, he said, has to do with the way they <a href="https://www.schwab.com/resource/how-to-set-up-two-factor-authentication" target="_blank" rel="noopener">handle multi-factor authentication</a>.<span id="more-71895"></span></p>
<p>Schwab clients are presented with two options for second factor authentication when they open an account. Users who select the option to only prompt for a code on untrusted devices can choose to receive it via text message, an automated inbound phone call, or an outbound call to Schwab. With the &#8220;always at login&#8221; option selected, users can choose to receive the code through the Schwab app, a text message, or a Symantec VIP mobile app.</p>
<p>In response to questions, Schwab said it regularly updates clients on emerging fraud trends, including this specific type, which the company addressed in communications sent to clients earlier this year.</p>
<div id="attachment_71940" style="width: 606px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71940" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71940" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/schwab-text.png" alt="" width="596" height="600" /><p id="caption-attachment-71940" class="wp-caption-text">The 2FA text message from Schwab warns recipients against giving away their one-time code.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;That message focused on trading-related fraud, highlighting both account intrusions and scams conducted through social media or messaging apps that deceive individuals into executing trades themselves,&#8221; Schwab said in a written statement. &#8220;We are aware and tracking this trend across several channels, as well as others like it, which attempt to exploit SMS-based verification with stolen credentials. We actively monitor for suspicious patterns and take steps to disrupt them. This activity is part of a broader, industry-wide threat, and we take a multi-layered approach to address and mitigate it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other popular brokerage platforms allow similar methods for multi-factor authentication. <strong>Fidelity</strong> requires a username and password on initial login, and offers the ability to receive a one-time token via SMS, an automated phone call, or by approving a push notification sent through the Fidelity mobile app. However, all three of these methods for sending one-time tokens are phishable; even with the brokerage firm&#8217;s app, the phishers could prompt the user to approve a login request that they initiated in the app with the phished credentials.</p>
<p>Vanguard offers customers a range of multi-factor authentication choices, including the option to require <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/07/google-security-keys-neutralized-employee-phishing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a physical security key</a> in addition to one&#8217;s credentials on each login. A security key implements a robust form of multi-factor authentication known as <strong>Universal 2nd Factor (U2F)</strong>, which allows the user to complete the login process simply by connecting an enrolled USB or Bluetooth device and pressing a button. The key works without the need for any special software drivers, and the nice thing about it is your second factor cannot be phished.</p>
<h2>THE PERFECT CRIME?</h2>
<p>Merrill said that in many ways the ramp-and-dump scheme is the perfect crime because it leaves precious few connections between the victim brokerage accounts and the fraudsters.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s really genius because it decouples so many things,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They can buy shares [in the stock to be pumped] in their personal account on the Chinese exchanges, and the price happens to go up. The Chinese or Hong Kong brokerages aren&#8217;t going to see anything funky.&#8221;</p>
<p>Merrill said it&#8217;s unclear exactly how those perpetrating these ramp-and-dump schemes coordinate their activities, such as whether the accounts are phished well in advance or shortly before being used to inflate the stock price of Chinese companies. The latter possibility would fit nicely with the existing human infrastructure these criminal groups already have in place.</p>
<p>For example, KrebsOnSecurity recently wrote about research from Merrill and other researchers showing the phishers behind these slick mobile phishing kits <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">employed people to sit for hours at a time</a> in front of large banks of mobile phones being used to send the text message lures. These technicians were needed to respond in real time to victims who were supplying the one-time code sent from their financial institution.</p>
<div id="attachment_70435" style="width: 528px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70435" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70435" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phonesashtray.png" alt="" width="518" height="688" /><p id="caption-attachment-70435" class="wp-caption-text">The ashtray says: You&#8217;ve been phishing all night.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;You can get access to a victim&#8217;s brokerage with a one-time passcode, but then you sort of have to use it right away if you can&#8217;t set new security settings so you can come back to that account later,&#8221; Merrill said.</p>
<p>The rapid pace of innovations produced by these China-based phishing vendors is due in part to their use of artificial intelligence and large language models to help develop the mobile phishing kits, he added.</p>
<p>&#8220;These guys are vibe coding stuff together and using LLMs to translate things or help put the user interface together,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;It&#8217;s only a matter of time before they start to integrate the LLMs into their development cycle to make it more rapid. The technologies they are building definitely have helped lower the barrier of entry for everyone.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/mobile-phishers-target-brokerage-accounts-in-ramp-and-dump-cashout-scheme/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Patch Tuesday, August 2025 Edition</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/microsoft-patch-tuesday-august-2025-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/microsoft-patch-tuesday-august-2025-edition/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 22:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Akamai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BadSuccessor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben McCarthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-50165]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53733]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53766]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53778]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53779]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Server 2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Server 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Server Subscription Edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immersive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Exchange Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Office 365]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sans internet storm center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows GDI+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yuval Gordon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today released updates to fix more than 100 security flaws in its Windows operating systems and other software. At least 13 of the bugs received Microsoft's most-dire "critical" rating, meaning they could be abused by malware or malcontents to gain remote access to a Windows system with little or no help from users.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today released updates to fix more than 100 security flaws in its <strong>Windows</strong> operating systems and other software. At least 13 of the bugs received Microsoft&#8217;s most-dire &#8220;critical&#8221; rating, meaning they could be abused by malware or malcontents to gain remote access to a Windows system with little or no help from users.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-56287" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png" alt="" width="750" height="528" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png 841w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-768x541.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-782x550.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>August&#8217;s patch batch from Redmond includes an update for <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-53786" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53786</a>, a vulnerability that allows an attacker to pivot from a compromised <strong>Microsoft Exchange Server</strong> directly into an organization&#8217;s cloud environment, potentially gaining control over <strong>Exchange Online</strong> and other connected <strong>Microsoft Office 365</strong> services. Microsoft first warned about this bug on Aug. 6, saying it affects <strong>Exchange Server 2016</strong> and <strong>Exchange Server 2019</strong>, as well as its flagship <strong>Exchange Server Subscription Edition</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Ben McCarthy</strong>, lead cyber security engineer at <strong>Immersive</strong>, said a rough search reveals approximately 29,000 Exchange servers publicly facing on the internet that are vulnerable to this issue, with many of them likely to have even older vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>McCarthy said the fix for CVE-2025-53786 requires more than just installing a patch, such as following Microsoft&#8217;s manual instructions for creating a dedicated service to oversee and lock down the hybrid connection.</p>
<p>&#8220;In effect, this vulnerability turns a significant on-premise Exchange breach into a full-blown, difficult-to-detect cloud compromise with effectively living off the land techniques which are always harder to detect for defensive teams,&#8221; McCarthy said.</p>
<p><a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-53779" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53779</a> is a weakness in the <strong>Windows Kerberos</strong> authentication system that allows an unauthenticated attacker to gain domain administrator privileges. Microsoft credits the discovery of the flaw to Akamai researcher <strong>Yuval Gordon</strong>, who dubbed it &#8220;<strong>BadSuccessor</strong>&#8221; in <a href="https://www.akamai.com/blog/security-research/abusing-dmsa-for-privilege-escalation-in-active-directory" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a May 2025 blog post</a>. The attack exploits a weakness in &#8220;delegated Managed Service Account&#8221; or dMSA &#8212; a feature that was introduced in <strong>Windows Server 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>Some of the critical flaws addressed this month with the highest severity (between 9.0 and 9.9 CVSS scores) include a remote code execution bug in the <strong>Windows GDI+</strong> component that handles graphics rendering (<a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-53766" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53766</a>) and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-50165" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-50165</a>, another graphics rendering weakness. Another critical patch involves <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-53733" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53733</a>, a vulnerability in <strong>Microsoft Word</strong> that can be exploited without user interaction and triggered through the Preview Pane.<span id="more-71899"></span></p>
<p>One final critical bug tackled this month deserves attention: <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-53778" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53778</a>, a bug in <strong>Windows NTLM</strong>, a core function of how Windows systems handle network authentication. According to Microsoft, the flaw could allow an attacker with low-level network access and basic user privileges to exploit NTLM and elevate to SYSTEM-level access — the highest level of privilege in Windows. Microsoft rates the exploitation of this bug as &#8220;more likely,&#8221; although there is no evidence the vulnerability is being exploited at the moment.</p>
<p>Feel free to holler in the comments if you experience problems installing any of these updates. As ever, the <strong>SANS Internet Storm Center</strong> has its <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/diary/Microsoft%20August%202025%20Patch%20Tuesday/32192" target="_blank" rel="noopener">useful breakdown</a> of the Microsoft patches indexed by severity and CVSS score, and <a href="https://www.askwoody.com/2025/august-2025-security-updates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AskWoody.com</a> is keeping an eye out for Windows patches that may cause problems for enterprises and end users.</p>
<h2>GOOD MIGRATIONS</h2>
<p>Windows 10 users out there likely have noticed by now that Microsoft really wants you to upgrade to Windows 11. The reason is that after the Patch Tuesday on October 14, 2025, Microsoft will stop shipping free security updates for <strong>Windows 10</strong> computers. The trouble is, many PCs running Windows 10 do not meet the hardware specifications required to install <strong>Windows 11 </strong>(or they do, but just barely).</p>
<p>If the experience with Windows XP is any indicator, many of these older computers will wind up in landfills or else will be left running in an unpatched state. But if your Windows 10 PC doesn&#8217;t have the hardware chops to run Windows 11 and you&#8217;d still like to get some use out of it safely, consider installing a newbie-friendly version of Linux, like <strong>Linux Mint</strong>.</p>
<p>Like most modern Linux versions, Mint will run on anything with a 64-bit CPU that has at least 2GB of memory, although 4GB is recommended. In other words, it will run on almost any computer produced in the last decade.</p>
<p>There are many versions of Linux available, but Linux Mint is likely to be the most intuitive interface for regular Windows users, and it is largely configurable without any fuss at the text-only command-line prompt. Mint and other flavors of Linux come with <strong>LibreOffice</strong>, which is an open source suite of tools that includes applications similar to Microsoft Office, and it can open, edit and save documents as Microsoft Office files.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;d prefer to give Linux a test drive before installing it on a Windows PC, you can always just download it to a removable USB drive. From there, reboot the computer (with the removable drive plugged in) and select the option at startup to run the operating system from the external USB drive. If you don&#8217;t see an option for that after restarting, try restarting again and hitting the F8 button, which should open a list of bootable drives. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_qZI6i21jB4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Here&#8217;s a fairly thorough tutorial</a> that walks through exactly how to do all this.</p>
<p>And if this is your first time trying out Linux, relax and have fun: The nice thing about a &#8220;live&#8221; version of Linux (as it&#8217;s called when the operating system is run from a removable drive such as a CD or a USB stick) is that none of your changes persist after a reboot. Even if you somehow manage to break something, a restart will return the system back to its original state.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/microsoft-patch-tuesday-august-2025-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>KrebsOnSecurity in New &#8216;Most Wanted&#8217; HBO Max Series</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/krebsonsecurity-in-new-most-wanted-hbo-max-series/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/krebsonsecurity-in-new-most-wanted-hbo-max-series/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 21:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Smedley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joni Soila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julius Kivimäki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lizard Squad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sami Kieski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony Playstation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vastaamo Psychotherapy Center]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new documentary series about cybercrime airing next month on HBO Max features interviews with Yours Truly. The four-part series follows the exploits of Julius Kivimäki, a prolific Finnish hacker recently convicted of leaking tens of thousands of patient records from an online psychotherapy practice while attempting to extort the clinic and its patients.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new documentary series about cybercrime airing next month on <strong>HBO Max</strong> features interviews with Yours Truly. The four-part series follows the exploits of <strong>Julius Kivimäki</strong>, a prolific Finnish hacker recently convicted of leaking tens of thousands of patient records from an online psychotherapy practice while attempting to extort the clinic and its patients.</p>
<p>The documentary, &#8220;<em>Most Wanted: Teen Hacker</em>,&#8221; explores the 27-year-old Kivimäki&#8217;s lengthy and increasingly destructive career, one that was marked by cyber attacks designed to result in real-world physical impacts on their targets.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p0CHYMtORb0?si=LQip-niqEaMZXZM3" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>By the age of 14, Kivimäki had fallen in with a group of criminal hackers who were <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2014/03/the-long-tail-of-coldfusion-fail/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mass-compromising websites and milking them for customer payment card data</a>. Kivimäki and his friends enjoyed harassing and terrorizing others by &#8220;swatting&#8221; their homes &#8212; calling in fake hostage situations or bomb threats at a target&#8217;s address in the hopes of triggering a heavily-armed police response to that location.</p>
<p>On Dec. 26, 2014, Kivimäki and fellow members of a group of online hooligans calling themselves the <strong>Lizard Squad</strong> <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2014/12/cowards-attack-sony-playstation-microsoft-xbox-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched a massive distributed denial-of-service</a> (DDoS) attack against the <strong>Sony Playstation</strong> and <strong>Microsoft Xbox Live</strong> platforms, preventing millions of users from playing with their shiny new gaming rigs the day after Christmas. The Lizard Squad later acknowledged that the stunt was planned to call attention to their new DDoS-for-hire service, which came online and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/01/lizard-stresser-runs-on-hacked-home-routers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">started selling subscriptions</a> shortly after the attack.</p>
<p>Finnish investigators said Kivimäki also was responsible for a 2014 bomb threat against former <strong>Sony Online Entertainment President</strong> <strong>John Smedley</strong> that <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/insertcoin/2014/08/24/sony-online-entertainment-presidents-flight-diverted-by-psn-hackers-bomb-threat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">grounded an American Airlines plane</a>. That incident was widely reported to have started with a Twitter post from the Lizard Squad, after Smedley mentioned some upcoming travel plans online. But according to Smedley and Finnish investigators, the bomb threat started with a phone call from Kivimäki.</p>
<div id="attachment_29338" style="width: 466px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-29338" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-29338" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/ryan-k-285x270.png" alt="" width="456" height="432" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/ryan-k-285x270.png 285w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/ryan-k.png 368w" sizes="(max-width: 456px) 100vw, 456px" /><p id="caption-attachment-29338" class="wp-caption-text">Julius &#8220;Zeekill&#8221; Kivimaki, in December 2014.</p></div>
<p>The creaky wheels of justice seemed to be catching up with Kivimäki in mid-2015, when a Finnish court found him guilty of more than 50,000 cybercrimes, including data breaches, payment fraud, and operating a global botnet of hacked computers. Unfortunately, the defendant was 17 at the time, and received little more than a slap on the wrist: A two-year suspended sentence and a small fine.<span id="more-71873"></span></p>
<p>Kivimäki immediately bragged online about the lenient sentencing, posting on Twitter that he was an &#8220;untouchable hacker god.&#8221; I wrote a column in 2015 <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/07/finnish-decision-is-win-for-internet-trolls/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lamenting his laughable punishment</a> because it was clear even then that this was a person who enjoyed watching other people suffer, and who seemed utterly incapable of remorse about any of it. It was also abundantly clear to everyone who investigated his crimes that he wasn&#8217;t going to quit unless someone made him stop.</p>
<p>In response to some of my early reporting that mentioned Kivimäki, one reader shared that they had been dealing with non-stop harassment and abuse from Kivimäki for years, including swatting incidents, unwanted deliveries and subscriptions, emails to her friends and co-workers, as well as threatening phonecalls and texts at all hours of the night. The reader, who spoke on condition of anonymity, shared that Kivimäki at one point confided that he had no reason whatsoever for harassing her &#8212; that she was picked at random and that it was just something he did for laughs.</p>
<p>Five years after Kivimäki&#8217;s conviction, the <strong>Vastaamo Psychotherapy Center</strong> in Finland became the target of blackmail when a tormentor identified as “ransom_man” demanded payment of 40 bitcoins (~450,000 euros at the time) in return for a promise not to publish highly sensitive therapy session notes Vastaamo had exposed online.</p>
<p>Ransom_man, a.k.a. Kivimäki, announced on the dark web that he would start publishing 100 patient profiles every 24 hours. When Vastaamo declined to pay, ransom_man shifted to extorting individual patients. According to Finnish police, some 22,000 victims reported extortion attempts targeting them personally, targeted emails that threatened to publish their therapy notes online unless paid a 500 euro ransom.</p>
<p>In October 2022, Finnish authorities charged Kivimäki with extorting Vastaamo and its patients. But by that time he was on the run from the law and living it up across Europe, spending lavishly on fancy cars, apartments and a hard-partying lifestyle.</p>
<p>In February 2023, Kivimäki was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/02/finlands-most-wanted-hacker-nabbed-in-france/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested in France</a> after authorities there responded to a domestic disturbance call and found the defendant sleeping off a hangover on the couch of a woman he’d met the night before. The French police grew suspicious when the 6′ 3″ blonde, green-eyed man presented an ID that stated he was of Romanian nationality.</p>
<div id="attachment_65661" style="width: 505px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-65661" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-65661" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/kivimaki-romainianid.png" alt="" width="495" height="338" /><p id="caption-attachment-65661" class="wp-caption-text">A redacted copy of an ID Kivimaki gave to French authorities claiming he was from Romania.</p></div>
<p>In April 2024, Kivimäki was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/04/man-who-mass-extorted-psychotherapy-patients-gets-six-years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sentenced to more than six years in prison</a> after being convicted of extorting Vastaamo and its patients.</p>
<p>The documentary is directed by the award-winning Finnish producer and director <a href="https://fi.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sami_Kieksi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sami Kieski</a> and co-written by <strong>Joni Soila</strong>. According to an August 6 press release, the four 43-minute episodes will drop weekly on Fridays throughout September across Europe, the U.S, Latin America, Australia and South-East Asia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/krebsonsecurity-in-new-most-wanted-hbo-max-series/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Got Arrested in the Raid on the XSS Crime Forum?</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/who-got-arrested-in-the-raid-on-the-xss-crime-forum/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/who-got-arrested-in-the-raid-on-the-xss-crime-forum/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9588693]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anton Gannadievich Medvedovskiy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anton Viktorovich Avdeev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Constella Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DaMaGeLaB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DomainTools.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploit.in]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flycracker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hack-All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel 471]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LockBit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LockBitSupp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[N0klos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paranoidlab.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qiliin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rEvil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SBU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sergeii Vovnenko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sonic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toschka2003@yandex.ru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xss[.]is]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 22, 2025, the European police agency Europol said a long-running investigation led by the French Police resulted in the arrest of a 38-year-old administrator of XSS, a Russian-language cybercrime forum with more than 50,000 members. The action has triggered an ongoing frenzy of speculation and panic among XSS denizens about the identity of the unnamed suspect, but the consensus is that he is a pivotal figure in the crime forum scene who goes by the hacker handle "Toha." Here's a deep dive on what's knowable about Toha, and a short stab at who got nabbed.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On July 22, 2025, the European police agency <strong>Europol</strong> <a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/key-figure-behind-major-russian-speaking-cybercrime-forum-targeted-in-ukraine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> a long-running investigation led by the French Police resulted in the arrest of a 38-year-old administrator of <b>XSS,</b> a Russian-language cybercrime forum with more than 50,000 members. The action has triggered an ongoing frenzy of speculation and panic among XSS denizens about the identity of the unnamed suspect, but the consensus is that he is a pivotal figure in the crime forum scene who goes by the hacker handle &#8220;<strong>Toha</strong>.&#8221; Here&#8217;s a deep dive on what&#8217;s knowable about Toha, and a short stab at who got nabbed.</p>
<div id="attachment_71827" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71827" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71827" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/xss-sbu.png" alt="" width="749" height="499" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/xss-sbu.png 851w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/xss-sbu-768x512.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/xss-sbu-782x521.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71827" class="wp-caption-text">An unnamed 38-year-old man was arrested in Kiev last month on suspicion of administering the cybercrime forum XSS. Image: ssu.gov.ua.</p></div>
<p>Europol did not name the accused, but published partially obscured photos of him from the raid on his residence in Kiev. The police agency said the suspect acted as a trusted third party &#8212; arbitrating disputes between criminals &#8212; and guaranteeing the security of transactions on XSS. A <a href="https://ssu.gov.ua/novyny/sbu-spilno-z-natspolitsiieiu-ta-pravookhorontsiamy-frantsii-vykryla-rozrobnyka-odniiei-z-naividomishykh-u-sviti-khakerskykh-platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> from Ukraine&#8217;s <strong>SBU</strong> security service said XSS counted among its members many cybercriminals from various ransomware groups, including <strong>REvil</strong>, <strong>LockBit</strong>, <strong>Conti</strong>, and <strong>Qiliin</strong>.</p>
<p>Since the Europol announcement, the XSS forum resurfaced at a new address on the deep web (reachable only via the anonymity network <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tor_(network)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tor</a>). But from reviewing the recent posts, there appears to be little consensus among longtime members about the identity of the now-detained XSS administrator.</p>
<p>The most frequent comment regarding the arrest was a message of solidarity and support for Toha, the handle chosen by the longtime administrator of XSS and several other major Russian forums. Toha&#8217;s accounts on other forums have been silent since the raid.</p>
<p>Europol said the suspect has enjoyed a nearly 20-year career in cybercrime, which roughly lines up with Toha&#8217;s history. In 2005, Toha was a founding member of the Russian-speaking forum <strong>Hack-All. </strong>That is, until it got massively hacked a few months after its debut. In 2006, Toha rebranded the forum to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/exploit-in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>exploit[.]in</strong></a>, which would go on to draw tens of thousands of members, including an eventual Who&#8217;s-Who of wanted cybercriminals.</p>
<p>Toha announced in 2018 that he was selling the Exploit forum, prompting rampant speculation on the forums that the buyer was secretly a Russian or Ukrainian government entity or front person. However, those suspicions were unsupported by evidence, and Toha vehemently denied the forum had been given over to authorities.</p>
<p>One of the oldest Russian-language cybercrime forums was <strong>DaMaGeLaB</strong>, which operated from 2004 to 2017, when its administrator &#8220;Ar3s&#8221; was arrested. In 2018, a partial backup of the DaMaGeLaB forum was <a href="https://www.own.security/en/ressources/blog/russian-language-cybercriminal-forums---chapter-iii-analyzing-the-most-active-and-renowned-communities-english-only" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reincarnated as xss[.]is</a>, with Toha as its stated administrator.</p>
<h2>CROSS-SITE GRIFTING</h2>
<p>Clues about Toha&#8217;s early presence on the Internet &#8212; from ~2004 to 2010 &#8212; are available in the archives of <strong>Intel 471</strong>, a cyber intelligence firm that tracks forum activity. Intel 471 shows Toha used the same email address across multiple forum accounts, including at Exploit, <strong>Antichat</strong>, <strong>Carder[.]su</strong> and <strong>inattack[.]ru.</strong></p>
<p><strong>DomainTools.com</strong> finds Toha&#8217;s email address &#8212; <strong>toschka2003@yandex.ru</strong> &#8212; was used to register at least a dozen domain names &#8212; most of them from the mid- to late 2000s. Apart from exploit[.]in and a domain called <strong>ixyq[.]com</strong>, the other domains registered to that email address end in .ua, the top-level domain for Ukraine (e.g. deleted.org[.]ua, lj.com[.]ua, and blogspot.org[.]ua).</p>
<div id="attachment_71853" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71853" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71853" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/exploit-deleted-ua.png" alt="" width="749" height="702" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/exploit-deleted-ua.png 924w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/exploit-deleted-ua-768x721.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/exploit-deleted-ua-782x734.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71853" class="wp-caption-text">A 2008 snapshot of a domain registered to toschka2003@yandex.ru and to Anton Medvedovsky in Kiev. Note the message at the bottom left, &#8220;Protected by Exploit,in.&#8221; Image: archive.org.</p></div>
<p>Nearly all of the domains registered to toschka2003@yandex.ru contain the name <strong>Anton Medvedovskiy</strong> in the registration records, except for the aforementioned ixyq[.]com, which is registered to the name <strong>Yuriy Avdeev</strong> in Moscow.</p>
<p>This Avdeev surname came up in a lengthy conversation with <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/u-s-charges-russian-man-as-boss-of-lockbit-ransomware-group/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lockbitsupp</a>, the leader of the rapacious and destructive ransomware affiliate group <strong>Lockbit</strong>. The conversation took place in February 2024, when Lockbitsupp asked for help identifying Toha&#8217;s real-life identity.</p>
<div id="attachment_71822" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71822" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71822" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/lcokbitsupp-convo.png" alt="" width="749" height="938" /><p id="caption-attachment-71822" class="wp-caption-text">In early 2024, the leader of the Lockbit ransomware group &#8212; Lockbitsupp &#8212; asked for help investigating the identity of the XSS administrator Toha, which he claimed was a Russian man named Anton Avdeev.</p></div>
<p>Lockbitsupp didn&#8217;t share why he wanted Toha&#8217;s details, but he maintained that Toha&#8217;s real name was <strong>Anton Avdeev</strong>. I declined to help Lockbitsupp in whatever revenge he was planning on Toha, but his question made me curious to look deeper.<span id="more-71819"></span></p>
<p>It appears Lockbitsupp&#8217;s query was based on a now-deleted Twitter post from 2022, when a user by the name &#8220;<a href="https://x.com/3xp0rtblog/status/1585357689777164288" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3xp0rt</a>&#8221; asserted that Toha was a Russian man named <strong>Anton Viktorovich Avdeev</strong>, born October 27, 1983.</p>
<p>Searching the web for Toha&#8217;s email address toschka2003@yandex.ru reveals <a href="https://www.bmwclub.ru/threads/bmw-x5-e70.398405/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2010 sales thread</a> on the forum <strong>bmwclub.ru</strong> where a user named Honeypo was selling a 2007 BMW X5. The ad listed the contact person as Anton Avdeev and gave the contact phone number <strong>9588693.</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-71824" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bmw-toha.png" alt="" width="878" height="888" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bmw-toha.png 878w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bmw-toha-768x777.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bmw-toha-782x791.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px" /></p>
<p>A search on the phone number 9588693 in the breach tracking service <strong>Constella Intelligence</strong> finds plenty of official Russian government records with this number, date of birth and the name Anton Viktorovich Avdeev. For example, hacked Russian government records show this person has a Russian tax ID and SIN (Social Security number), and that they were flagged for traffic violations on several occasions by Moscow police; in 2004, 2006, 2009, and 2014.</p>
<p>Astute readers may have noticed by now that the ages of Mr. Avdeev (41) and the XSS admin arrested this month (38) are a bit off. This would seem to suggest that the person arrested is someone other than Mr. Avdeev, who did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<h2>A FLY ON THE WALL</h2>
<p>For further insight on this question, KrebsOnSecurity sought comments from <strong>Sergeii Vovnenko</strong>, a former cybercriminal from Ukraine who now works at the security startup <strong>paranoidlab.com</strong>. I reached out to Vovnenko because for several years beginning around 2010 he was the owner and operator of <strong>thesecure[.]biz</strong>, an encrypted &#8220;Jabber&#8221; instant messaging server that Europol said was operated by the suspect arrested in Kiev. Thesecure[.]biz grew quite popular among many of the top Russian-speaking cybercriminals because it scrupulously kept few records of its users&#8217; activity, and its administrator was always a trusted member of the community.</p>
<p>The reason I know this historic tidbit is that in 2013, Vovnenko &#8212; using the hacker nicknames &#8220;<strong>Fly</strong>,&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Flycracker</strong>&#8221; &#8212; <a href="http://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/07/mail-from-the-velvet-cybercrime-underground/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hatched a plan</a> to have a gram of heroin purchased off of the Silk Road darknet market and shipped to our home in Northern Virginia. The scheme was to spoof a call from one of our neighbors to the local police, saying this guy Krebs down the street was a druggie who was having narcotics delivered to his home.</p>
<p>I happened to be lurking on Flycracker&#8217;s private cybercrime forum when his heroin-framing plan was carried out, and called the police myself before the smack eventually arrived in the U.S. Mail. Vovnenko was later <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2014/06/the-fly-has-been-swatted/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested</a> for unrelated cybercrime activities, extradited to the United States, convicted, and deported after a 16-month stay in the U.S. prison system [on several occasions, he has expressed heartfelt apologies for the incident, and we have since buried the hatchet].</p>
<p>Vovnenko said he purchased a device for cloning credit cards from Toha in 2009, and that Toha shipped the item from Russia. Vovnenko explained that he (Flycracker) was the owner and operator of thesecure[.]biz from 2010 until his arrest in 2014.</p>
<p>Vovnenko believes thesecure[.]biz was stolen while he was in jail, either by Toha and/or an XSS administrator who went by the nicknames <strong>N0klos</strong> and <strong>Sonic</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;When I was in jail, [the] admin of xss.is stole that domain, or probably N0klos bought XSS from Toha or vice versa,&#8221; Vovnenko said of the Jabber domain. &#8220;Nobody from [the forums] spoke with me after my jailtime, so I can only guess what really happened.&#8221;</p>
<p>N0klos was the owner and administrator of an early Russian-language cybercrime forum known as <strong>Darklife[.]ws</strong>. However, N0kl0s also appears to be a lifelong Russian resident, and in any case seems to have vanished from Russian cybercrime forums several years ago.</p>
<p>Asked whether he believes Toha was the XSS administrator who was arrested this month in Ukraine, Vovnenko maintained that Toha is Russian, and that &#8220;the French cops took the wrong guy.&#8221;</p>
<h2>WHO IS TOHA?</h2>
<p>So who did the Ukrainian police arrest in response to the investigation by the French authorities? It seems plausible that the BMW ad invoking Toha&#8217;s email address and the name and phone number of a Russian citizen was simply misdirection on Toha&#8217;s part &#8212; intended to confuse and throw off investigators. Perhaps this even explains the Avdeev surname surfacing in the registration records from one of Toha&#8217;s domains.</p>
<p>But sometimes the simplest answer is the correct one. &#8220;Toha&#8221; is a common Slavic nickname for someone with the first name &#8220;Anton,&#8221; and that matches the name in the registration records for more than a dozen domains tied to Toha&#8217;s toschka2003@yandex.ru email address: Anton Medvedovskiy.</p>
<p>Constella Intelligence finds there is an <strong>Anton Gannadievich Medvedovskiy</strong> living in Kiev who will be 38 years old in December. This individual owns the email address <strong>itsmail@i.ua</strong>, as well an <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/users/show/27040702" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an Airbnb account</a> featuring a profile photo of a man with roughly the same hairline as the suspect in the blurred photos released by the Ukrainian police. Mr. Medvedovskiy did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p>My take on the takedown is that the Ukrainian authorities likely arrested Medvedovskiy. Toha shared on DaMaGeLab in 2005 that he had recently finished the 11th grade and was studying at a university &#8212; a time when Mevedovskiy would have been around 18 years old. On Dec. 11, 2006, fellow Exploit members wished Toha a happy birthday. Records exposed in a 2022 hack at the Ukrainian public services portal diia.gov.ua show that Mr. Medvedovskiy&#8217;s birthday is Dec. 11, 1987.</p>
<p>The law enforcement action and resulting confusion about the identity of the detained has thrown the Russian cybercrime forum scene into disarray in recent weeks, with lengthy and heated arguments about XSS&#8217;s future spooling out across the forums.</p>
<p>XSS relaunched on a new Tor address shortly after the authorities plastered their seizure notice on the forum&#8217;s  homepage, but all of the trusted moderators from the old forum were dismissed without explanation. Existing members saw their forum account balances drop to zero, and were asked to plunk down a deposit to register at the new forum. The new XSS &#8220;admin&#8221; said they were in contact with the previous owners and that the changes were to help rebuild security and trust within the community.</p>
<p>However, the new admin&#8217;s assurances appear to have done little to assuage the worst fears of the forum&#8217;s erstwhile members, most of whom seem to be keeping their distance from the relaunched site for now.</p>
<p>Indeed, if there is one common understanding amid all of these discussions about the seizure of XSS, it is that Ukrainian and French authorities now have several years worth of private messages between XSS forum users, as well as contact rosters and other user data linked to the seized Jabber server.</p>
<p>&#8220;The myth of the &#8216;trusted person&#8217; is shattered,&#8221; the user &#8220;GordonBellford&#8221; cautioned on Aug. 3 in an Exploit forum thread about the XSS admin arrest. &#8220;The forum is run by strangers. They got everything. Two years of Jabber server logs. Full backup and forum database.&#8221;</p>
<p>GordonBellford continued:</p>
<blockquote><p>And the scariest thing is: this data array is not just an archive. It is material for analysis that has ALREADY BEEN DONE . With the help of modern tools, they see everything:</p>
<p>Graphs of your contacts and activity.<br />
Relationships between nicknames, emails, password hashes and Jabber ID.<br />
Timestamps, IP addresses and digital fingerprints.<br />
Your unique writing style, phraseology, punctuation, consistency of grammatical errors, and even typical typos that will link your accounts on different platforms.</p>
<p>They are not looking for a needle in a haystack. They simply sifted the haystack through the AI sieve and got ready-made dossiers.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/who-got-arrested-in-the-raid-on-the-xss-crime-forum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scammers Unleash Flood of Slick Online Gaming Sites</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/scammers-unleash-flood-of-slick-online-gaming-sites/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/scammers-unleash-flood-of-slick-online-gaming-sites/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 18:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B-Ball Blitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beast Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mr. Beast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scambling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thereallo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fraudsters are flooding Discord and other social media platforms with ads for hundreds of polished online gaming and wagering websites that lure people with free credits and eventually abscond with any cryptocurrency funds deposited by players. Here's a closer look at the social engineering tactics and remarkable traits of this sprawling network of more than 1,200 scam sites.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fraudsters are flooding Discord and other social media platforms with ads for hundreds of polished online gaming and wagering websites that lure people with free credits and eventually abscond with any cryptocurrency funds deposited by players. Here&#8217;s a closer look at the social engineering tactics and remarkable traits of this sprawling network of more than 1,200 scam sites.</p>
<p>The scam begins with deceptive ads posted on social media that claim the wagering sites are working in partnership with popular social media personalities, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MrBeast" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mr. Beast</a>, who recently launched a gaming business called <strong>Beast Games</strong>. The ads invariably state that by using a supplied &#8220;promo code,&#8221; interested players can claim a $2,500 credit on the advertised gaming website.</p>
<div id="attachment_71798" style="width: 734px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71798" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71798" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/reddit-gambwex.png" alt="" width="724" height="750" /><p id="caption-attachment-71798" class="wp-caption-text">An ad posted to a Discord channel for a scam gambling website that the proprietors falsely claim was operating in collaboration with the Internet personality Mr. Beast. Image: Reddit.com.</p></div>
<p>The gaming sites all require users to create a free account to claim their $2,500 credit, which they can use to play any number of extremely polished video games that ask users to bet on each action. At the scam website gamblerbeast[.]com, for example, visitors can pick from dozens of games like <strong>B-Ball Blitz</strong>, in which you play a basketball pro who is taking shots from the free throw line against a single opponent, and you bet on your ability to sink each shot.</p>
<p>The financial part of this scam begins when users try to cash out any &#8220;winnings.&#8221; At that point, the gaming site will reject the request and prompt the user to make a &#8220;verification deposit&#8221; of cryptocurrency &#8212; typically around $100 &#8212; before any money can be distributed. Those who deposit cryptocurrency funds are soon asked for additional payments.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lNjqXIq1s5g?si=-30qS1Bw73VdIXow" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>However, any &#8220;winnings&#8221; displayed by these gaming sites are a complete fantasy, and players who deposit cryptocurrency funds will never see that money again. Compounding the problem, victims likely will soon be peppered with come-ons from &#8220;recovery experts&#8221; who peddle dubious claims on social media networks about being able to retrieve funds lost to such scams.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity first learned about this network of phony betting sites from a Discord user who asked to be identified only by their screen name: &#8220;<strong>Thereallo</strong>&#8221; is a 17-year-old developer who operates multiple Discord servers and said they began digging deeper after users started complaining of being inundated with misleading spam messages promoting the sites.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were being spammed relentlessly by these scam posts from compromised or purchased [Discord] accounts,&#8221; Thereallo said. &#8220;I got frustrated with just banning and deleting, so I started to investigate the infrastructure behind the scam messages. This is not a one-off site, it&#8217;s a scalable criminal enterprise with a clear playbook, technical fingerprints, and financial infrastructure.&#8221;</p>
<p>After comparing the code on the gaming sites promoted via spam messages, Thereallo found they all invoked the same API key for an online chatbot that appears to be in limited use or else is custom-made. Indeed, a scan for that API key at the threat hunting platform <strong>Silent Push</strong> reveals at least 1,270 recently-registered and active domains whose names all invoke some type of gaming or wagering theme.</p>
<div id="attachment_71799" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71799" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71799" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-withdrawalerror.png" alt="" width="750" height="374" /><p id="caption-attachment-71799" class="wp-caption-text">The &#8220;verification deposit&#8221; stage of the scam requires the user to deposit cryptocurrency in order to withdraw their &#8220;winnings.&#8221;</p></div>
<p>Thereallo said the operators of this scam empire appear to generate a unique Bitcoin wallet for each gaming domain they deploy.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is a decoy wallet,&#8221; Thereallo explained. &#8220;Once the victim deposits funds, they are never able to withdraw any money. Any attempts to contact the &#8216;Live Support&#8217; are handled by a combination of AI and human operators who eventually block the user. The chat system is self-hosted, making it difficult to report to third-party service providers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thereallo discovered another feature common to all of these scam gambling sites [hereafter referred to simply as &#8220;scambling&#8221; sites]: If you register at one of them and then very quickly try to register at a sister property of theirs from the same Internet address and device, the registration request is denied at the second site.</p>
<p>&#8220;I registered on one site, then hopped to another to register again,&#8221; Thereallo said. Instead, the second site returned an error stating that a new account couldn&#8217;t be created for another 10 minutes.</p>
<div id="attachment_71801" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71801" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71801" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora.png" alt="" width="749" height="404" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora.png 908w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora-768x414.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora-782x422.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora-370x200.png 370w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71801" class="wp-caption-text">The scam gaming site spinora dot cc shares the same chatbot API as more than 1,200 similar fake gaming sites.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;re tracking my VPN IP across their entire network,&#8221; Thereallo explained. &#8220;My password manager also proved it. It tried to use my dummy email on a site I had never visited, and the site told me the account already existed. So it&#8217;s definitely one entity running a single platform with 1,200+ different domain names as front-ends. This explains how their support works, a central pool of agents handling all the sites. It also explains why they&#8217;re so strict about not giving out wallet addresses; it&#8217;s a network-wide policy.&#8221;<span id="more-71791"></span></p>
<p>In many ways, these scambling sites borrow from the playbook of &#8220;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/07/massive-losses-define-epidemic-of-pig-butchering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pig butchering</a>&#8221; schemes, a rampant and far more elaborate crime in which people are gradually lured by flirtatious strangers online into investing in fraudulent cryptocurrency trading platforms.</p>
<p>Pig butchering scams are typically powered by people in Asia who have been kidnapped and threatened with physical harm or worse unless they sit in a cubicle and scam Westerners on the Internet all day. In contrast, these scambling sites tend to steal far less money from individual victims, but their cookie-cutter nature and automated support components may enable their operators to extract payments from a large number of people in far less time, and with considerably less risk and up-front investment.</p>
<p>Silent Push&#8217;s <strong>Zach Edwards</strong> said the proprietors of this scambling empire are spending big money to make the sites look and feel like some fancy new type of casino.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s a very odd type of pig butchering network and not like what we typically see, with much lower investments in the sites and lures,&#8221; Edwards said.</p>
<p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/deduped_scambling_domains.txt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Here is a list of all domains</a> that Silent Push found were using the scambling network&#8217;s chat API.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/scammers-unleash-flood-of-slick-online-gaming-sites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Phishers Target Aviation Execs to Scam Customers</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/phishers-target-aviation-execs-to-scam-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/phishers-target-aviation-execs-to-scam-customers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target: Small Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Association for Financial Professionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BEC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business email compromise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial fraud kill chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Crime Complaint Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justy John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palo Alto Networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roomservice801@gmail.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SilverTerrier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 42]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[KrebsOnSecurity recently heard from a reader whose boss's email account got phished and was used to trick one of the company's customers into sending a large payment to scammers. An investigation into the attacker's infrastructure points to a long-running Nigerian cybercrime group that is actively targeting established companies in the transportation and aviation industries.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>KrebsOnSecurity recently heard from a reader whose boss&#8217;s email account got phished and was used to trick one of the company&#8217;s customers into sending a large payment to scammers. An investigation into the attacker&#8217;s infrastructure points to a long-running Nigerian cybercrime ring that is actively targeting established companies in the transportation and aviation industries.</p>
<div id="attachment_71757" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71757" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71757" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/shutterstock-airplanes.png" alt="" width="749" height="535" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/shutterstock-airplanes.png 666w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/shutterstock-airplanes-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71757" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, Mr. Teerapon Tiuekhom.</p></div>
<p>A reader who works in the transportation industry sent a tip about a recent successful phishing campaign that tricked an executive at the company into entering their credentials at a fake Microsoft 365 login page. From there, the attackers quickly mined the executive&#8217;s inbox for past communications about invoices, copying and modifying some of those messages with new invoice demands that were sent to some of the company&#8217;s customers and partners.</p>
<p>Speaking on condition of anonymity, the reader said the resulting phishing emails to customers came from a newly registered domain name that was remarkably similar to their employer&#8217;s domain, and that at least one of their customers fell for the ruse and paid a phony invoice. They said the attackers had spun up a look-alike domain just a few hours after the executive&#8217;s inbox credentials were phished, and that the scam resulted in a customer suffering a six-figure financial loss.</p>
<p>The reader also shared that the email addresses in the registration records for the imposter domain &#8212; <strong>roomservice801@gmail.com</strong> &#8212; is tied to many such phishing domains. Indeed, a search on this email address at <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> finds it is associated with at least 240 domains registered in 2024 or 2025. Virtually all of them mimic legitimate domains for companies in the aerospace and transportation industries worldwide.</p>
<p>An Internet search for this email address reveals <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20220514070749/https://hackware.ru/?p=12106" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a humorous blog post from 2020</a> on the Russian forum hackware[.]ru, which found roomservice801@gmail.com was tied to a phishing attack that used the lure of phony invoices to trick the recipient into logging in at a fake Microsoft login page. We&#8217;ll come back to this research in a moment.</p>
<h2>JUSTY JOHN</h2>
<p>DomainTools shows that some of the early domains registered to roomservice801@gmail.com in 2016 include other useful information. For example, the WHOIS records for <strong>alhhomaidhicentre[.]biz</strong> reference the technical contact of &#8220;<strong>Justy John</strong>&#8221; and the email address <strong>justyjohn50@yahoo.com</strong>.</p>
<p>A search at DomainTools found justyjohn50@yahoo.com has been registering one-off phishing domains since at least 2012. At this point, I was convinced that some security company surely had already published an analysis of this particular threat group, but I didn&#8217;t yet have enough information to draw any solid conclusions.</p>
<p>DomainTools says the Justy John email address is tied to more than two dozen domains registered since 2012, but we can find hundreds more phishing domains and related email addresses simply by pivoting on details in the registration records for these Justy John domains. For example, the street address used by the Justy John domain <strong>axisupdate[.]net</strong> &#8212; 7902 Pelleaux Road in Knoxville, TN &#8212; also appears in the registration records for accountauthenticate[.]com, acctlogin[.]biz, and loginaccount[.]biz, all of which at one point included the email address <strong>rsmith60646@gmail.com</strong>.</p>
<p>That Rsmith Gmail address is connected to the 2012 phishing domain alibala[.]biz (one character off of the Chinese e-commerce giant alibaba.com, with a different top-level domain of .biz). A search in DomainTools on the phone number in those domain records &#8212; 1.7736491613 &#8212; reveals even more phishing domains as well as the Nigerian phone number &#8220;2348062918302&#8221; and the email address <strong>michsmith59@gmail.com</strong>.</p>
<p>DomainTools shows michsmith59@gmail.com appears in the registration records for the domain <strong>seltrock[.]com</strong>, which was used in the phishing attack documented in <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20220514070749/https://hackware.ru/?p=12106" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the 2020 Russian blog post</a> mentioned earlier. At this point, we are just two steps away from identifying the threat actor group.</p>
<p>The same Nigerian phone number shows up in dozens of domain registrations that reference the email address <strong>sebastinekelly69@gmail.com</strong>, including <strong>26i3[.]net</strong>, <strong>costamere[.]com</strong>, <strong>danagruop[.]us</strong>, and <strong>dividrilling[.]com</strong>. A Web search on any of those domains finds they were indexed in <a href="https://github.com/pan-unit42/iocs/blob/master/silverterrier/domains.csv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an &#8220;indicator of compromise&#8221; list on GitHub</a> maintained by <strong>Palo Alto Networks</strong>&#8216; <strong>Unit 42</strong> research team.<span id="more-71635"></span></p>
<h2>SILVERTERRIER</h2>
<p>According to Unit 42, the domains are the handiwork of a vast cybercrime group based in Nigeria that it dubbed &#8220;<strong>SilverTerrier</strong>&#8221; back in 2014. In <a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/silverterrier-nigerian-business-email-compromise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an October 2021 report</a>, Palo Alto said SilverTerrier excels at so-called &#8220;<strong>business e-mail compromise</strong>&#8221; or <strong>BEC</strong> scams, which target legitimate business email accounts through social engineering or computer intrusion activities. BEC criminals use that access to initiate or redirect the transfer of business funds for personal gain.</p>
<p>Palo Alto says SilverTerrier encompasses hundreds of BEC fraudsters, some of whom have been arrested in various international law enforcement operations by <strong>Interpol</strong>. In 2022, Interpol and the Nigeria Police Force <a href="https://www.interpol.int/en/News-and-Events/News/2022/Nigerian-cybercrime-fraud-11-suspects-arrested-syndicate-busted" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested 11 alleged SilverTerrier members</a>, including <a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/operation-delilah-business-email-compromise-actor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a prominent SilverTerrier leader</a> who&#8217;d been flaunting his wealth on social media for years. Unfortunately, the lure of easy money, endemic poverty and corruption, and low barriers to entry for cybercrime in Nigeria conspire to provide a constant stream of new recruits.</p>
<p>BEC scams were the 7th most reported crime tracked by the FBI&#8217;s <strong>Internet Crime Complaint Center</strong> (IC3) in 2024, generating more than 21,000 complaints. However, BEC scams were the second most costly form of cybercrime reported to the feds last year, with <em>nearly $2.8 billion in claimed losses</em>. In its <a href="https://www.afponline.org/training-resources/resources/survey-research-economic-data/Details/payments-fraud" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2025 Fraud and Control Survey Report</a>, the <strong>Association for Financial Professionals</strong> found 63 percent of organizations experienced a BEC last year.</p>
<p>Poking at some of the email addresses that spool out from this research reveals a number of Facebook accounts for people residing in Nigeria or in the United Arab Emirates, many of whom do not appear to have tried to mask their real-life identities. Palo Alto&#8217;s Unit 42 researchers reached a similar conclusion, noting that although a small subset of these crooks went to great lengths to conceal their identities, it was usually simple to learn their identities on social media accounts and the major messaging services.</p>
<p>Palo Alto said BEC actors have become far more organized over time, and that while it remains easy to find actors working as a group, the practice of using one phone number, email address or alias to register malicious infrastructure in support of multiple actors has made it far more time consuming (but not impossible) for cybersecurity and law enforcement organizations to sort out which actors committed specific crimes.</p>
<p>&#8220;We continue to find that SilverTerrier actors, regardless of geographical location, are often connected through only a few degrees of separation on social media platforms,&#8221; the researchers wrote.</p>
<h2>FINANCIAL FRAUD KILL CHAIN</h2>
<p>Palo Alto has published <a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/operation-falcon-ii-silverterrier-nigerian-bec/#protections-and-mitigations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a useful list of recommendations</a> that organizations can adopt to minimize the incidence and impact of BEC attacks. Many of those tips are prophylactic, such as conducting regular employee security training and reviewing network security policies.</p>
<p>But one recommendation &#8212; getting familiar with a process known as the &#8220;<strong>financial fraud kill chain</strong>&#8221; or FFKC &#8212; bears specific mention because it offers the single best hope for BEC victims who are seeking to claw back payments made to fraudsters, and yet far too many victims don&#8217;t know it exists until it is too late.</p>
<div id="attachment_71758" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71758" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71758" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ffkc-fbi.png" alt="" width="749" height="786" /><p id="caption-attachment-71758" class="wp-caption-text">Image: ic3.gov.</p></div>
<p>As explained in <a href="https://www.justice.gov/elderjustice/media/1364056/dl?inline" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this FBI primer</a>, the International Financial Fraud Kill Chain is a partnership between federal law enforcement and financial entities whose purpose is to freeze fraudulent funds wired by victims. According to the FBI, viable victim <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/CrimeInfo/BEC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">complaints filed with ic3.gov</a> promptly after a fraudulent transfer (generally less than 72 hours) will be automatically triaged by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_Crimes_Enforcement_Network" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</a> (FinCEN).</p>
<p>The FBI noted in its <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/AnnualReport/Reports/2024_IC3Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IC3 annual report</a> (PDF) that the FFKC had a 66 percent success rate in 2024. Viable ic3.gov complaints involve losses of at least $50,000, and include all records from the victim or victim bank, as well as a completed FFKC form (provided by FinCEN) containing victim information, recipient information, bank names, account numbers, location, SWIFT, and any additional information.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/phishers-target-aviation-execs-to-scam-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Fix Targets Attacks on SharePoint Zero-Day</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/microsoft-fix-targets-attacks-on-sharepoint-zero-day/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/microsoft-fix-targets-attacks-on-sharepoint-zero-day/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CISA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-49704]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-49706]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53770]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53771]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity & Infrastructure Security Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eye Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Corp.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SharePoint Server]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Sunday, July 20, Microsoft Corp. issued an emergency security update for a vulnerability in SharePoint Server that is actively being exploited to compromise vulnerable organizations. The patch comes amid reports that malicious hackers have used the Sharepoint flaw to breach U.S. federal and state agencies, universities, and energy companies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Sunday, July 20, <strong>Microsoft Corp.</strong> issued an emergency security update for a vulnerability in <strong>SharePoint Server</strong> that is actively being exploited to compromise vulnerable organizations. The patch comes amid reports that malicious hackers have used the SharePoint flaw to breach U.S. federal and state agencies, universities, and energy companies.</p>
<div id="attachment_71741" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71741" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71741" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ms-sharepoint-ss.png" alt="" width="749" height="491" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ms-sharepoint-ss.png 987w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ms-sharepoint-ss-768x503.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ms-sharepoint-ss-782x513.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71741" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, by Ascannio.</p></div>
<p>In <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/blog/2025/07/customer-guidance-for-sharepoint-vulnerability-cve-2025-53770/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an advisory</a> about the SharePoint security hole, a.k.a. <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-53770" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53770</a>, Microsoft said it is aware of active attacks targeting on-premises SharePoint Server customers and exploiting vulnerabilities that were only partially addressed by <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/microsoft-patch-tuesday-july-2025-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the July 8, 2025 security update</a>.</p>
<p>The <strong>Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA) <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/alerts/2025/07/20/microsoft-releases-guidance-exploitation-sharepoint-vulnerability-cve-2025-53770" target="_blank" rel="noopener">concurred</a>, saying CVE-2025-53770 is a variant on a flaw Microsoft patched earlier this month (<a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-49706" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-49706)</a>. Microsoft notes the weakness applies only to SharePoint Servers that organizations use in-house, and that SharePoint Online and Microsoft 365 are not affected.</p>
<p><strong>The Washington Post</strong> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/07/20/microsoft-sharepoint-hack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> on Sunday that the U.S. government and partners in Canada and Australia are investigating the hack of SharePoint servers, which provide a platform for sharing and managing documents. The Post reports at least two U.S. federal agencies have seen their servers breached via the SharePoint vulnerability.</p>
<p>According to CISA, attackers exploiting the newly-discovered flaw are retrofitting compromised servers with a backdoor dubbed &#8220;<strong>ToolShell</strong>&#8221; that provides unauthenticated, remote access to systems. CISA said ToolShell enables attackers to fully access SharePoint content &#8212; including file systems and internal configurations &#8212; and execute code over the network.</p>
<p>Researchers at <strong>Eye Security</strong> said they first spotted large-scale exploitation of the SharePoint flaw on July 18, 2025, and soon found dozens of separate servers compromised by the bug and infected with ToolShell. In <a href="https://research.eye.security/sharepoint-under-siege/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a blog post</a>, the researchers said the attacks sought to steal SharePoint server ASP.NET machine keys.</p>
<p>&#8220;These keys can be used to facilitate further attacks, even at a later date,&#8221; Eye Security warned. &#8220;It is critical that affected servers rotate SharePoint server ASP.NET machine keys and restart IIS on all SharePoint servers. Patching alone is not enough. We strongly advise defenders not to wait for a vendor fix before taking action. This threat is already operational and spreading rapidly.&#8221;<span id="more-71737"></span></p>
<p>Microsoft&#8217;s advisory says the company has issued updates for <strong>SharePoint Server Subscription Edition</strong> and <strong>SharePoint Server 2019</strong>, but that it is still working on updates for supported versions of <strong>SharePoint 2019</strong> and <strong>SharePoint 2016</strong>.</p>
<p>CISA advises vulnerable organizations to enable the anti-malware scan interface (AMSI) in SharePoint, to deploy Microsoft Defender AV on all SharePoint servers, and to disconnect affected products from the public-facing Internet until an official patch is available.</p>
<p>The security firm <strong>Rapid7</strong> <a href="https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/etr-zero-day-exploitation-of-microsoft-sharepoint-servers-cve-2025-53770/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notes</a> that Microsoft has described CVE-2025-53770 as related to a previous vulnerability &#8212; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-49704" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-49704</a>, patched earlier this month &#8212; and that CVE-2025-49704 was part of an exploit chain demonstrated at the <strong>Pwn2Own</strong> hacking competition in May 2025. That exploit chain invoked a second SharePoint weakness &#8212; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-49706" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-49706</a> &#8212; which Microsoft unsuccessfully tried to fix in this month&#8217;s Patch Tuesday.</p>
<p>Microsoft also has issued a patch for a related SharePoint vulnerability &#8212; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-53771" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53771</a>; Microsoft says there are no signs of active attacks on CVE-2025-53771, and that the patch is to provide more robust protections than the update for CVE-2025-49706.</p>
<p><em>This is a rapidly developing story. Any updates will be noted with timestamps.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/microsoft-fix-targets-attacks-on-sharepoint-zero-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Poor Passwords Tattle on AI Hiring Bot Maker Paradox.ai</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/poor-passwords-tattle-on-ai-hiring-bot-maker-paradox-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/poor-passwords-tattle-on-ai-hiring-bot-maker-paradox-ai/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 01:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aramark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hive Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ian Carroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lockheed martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lowes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McDonald's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexus Stealer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paradox.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pepsi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Curry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Security researchers recently revealed that the personal information of millions of people who applied for jobs at McDonald's was exposed after they guessed the password ("123456") for the fast food chain's account at Paradox.ai, a company that makes artificial intelligence based hiring chatbots used by many Fortune 500 companies. Paradox.ai said the security oversight was an isolated incident that did not affect its other customers, but recent security breaches involving its employees in Vietnam tell a more nuanced story.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Security researchers recently revealed that the personal information of millions of people who applied for jobs at <strong>McDonald&#8217;s</strong> was exposed after they guessed the password (&#8220;123456&#8221;) for the fast food chain&#8217;s account at <strong>Paradox.ai</strong>, a company that makes artificial intelligence based hiring chatbots used by many Fortune 500 firms. Paradox.ai said the security oversight was an isolated incident that did not affect its other customers, but recent security breaches involving its employees in Vietnam tell a more nuanced story.</p>
<div id="attachment_71672" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71672" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71672" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/paradoxai.png" alt="" width="749" height="330" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/paradoxai.png 1438w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/paradoxai-768x339.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/paradoxai-782x345.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71672" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot of the paradox.ai homepage showing its AI hiring chatbot &#8220;Olivia&#8221; interacting with potential hires.</p></div>
<p>Earlier this month, security researchers <strong>Ian Carroll</strong> and <strong>Sam Curry</strong> <a href="https://ian.sh/mcdonalds" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote about</a> simple methods they found to access the backend of the AI chatbot platform on McHire.com, the McDonald&#8217;s website that many of its franchisees use to screen job applicants. As first reported by <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/mcdonalds-ai-hiring-chat-bot-paradoxai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wired</a>, the researchers discovered that the weak password used by Paradox exposed 64 million records, including applicants&#8217; names, email addresses and phone numbers.</p>
<p>Paradox.ai acknowledged the researchers&#8217; findings but said the company&#8217;s other client instances were not affected, and that no sensitive information &#8212; such as Social Security numbers &#8212; was exposed.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are confident, based on our records, this test account was not accessed by any third party other than the security researchers,&#8221; the company wrote in <a href="https://www.paradox.ai/blog/responsible-security-update" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a July 9 blog post</a>. &#8220;It had not been logged into since 2019 and frankly, should have been decommissioned. We want to be very clear that while the researchers may have briefly had access to the system containing all chat interactions (NOT job applications), they only viewed and downloaded five chats in total that had candidate information within. Again, at no point was any data leaked online or made public.&#8221;</p>
<p>However, a review of stolen password data gathered by multiple breach-tracking services shows that at the end of June 2025, a Paradox.ai administrator in Vietnam suffered a malware compromise on their device that stole usernames and passwords for a variety of internal and third-party online services. The results were not pretty.</p>
<p>The password data from the Paradox.ai developer was stolen by a malware strain known as &#8220;<strong>Nexus Stealer</strong>,&#8221; a form grabber and password stealer that is sold on cybercrime forums. The information snarfed by stealers like Nexus is often recovered and indexed by data leak aggregator services like <b>Intelligence X</b>, which reports that the malware on the Paradox.ai developer&#8217;s device exposed hundreds of mostly poor and recycled passwords (using the same base password but slightly different characters at the end).</p>
<p>Those purloined credentials show the developer in question at one point used the same seven-digit password to log in to Paradox.ai accounts for a number of <a href="https://www.paradox.ai/clients-stories" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fortune 500 firms listed as customers on the company&#8217;s website</a>, including <strong>Aramark</strong>, <strong>Lockheed Martin</strong>, <strong>Lowes</strong>, and <strong>Pepsi.</strong></p>
<p>Seven-character passwords, particularly those consisting entirely of numerals, are highly vulnerable to &#8220;brute-force&#8221; attacks that can try a large number of possible password combinations in quick succession. According to <a href="https://www.hivesystems.com/blog/are-your-passwords-in-the-green" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a much-referenced password strength guide</a> maintained by <strong>Hive Systems</strong>, modern password-cracking systems can work out a seven number password more or less instantly.</p>
<div id="attachment_71671" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71671" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71671" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/hivesystems-pwdcrack.png" alt="" width="749" height="395" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/hivesystems-pwdcrack.png 1646w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/hivesystems-pwdcrack-768x405.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/hivesystems-pwdcrack-1536x810.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/hivesystems-pwdcrack-782x412.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/hivesystems-pwdcrack-267x140.png 267w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71671" class="wp-caption-text">Image: hivesystems.com.</p></div>
<p>In response to questions from KrebsOnSecurity, Paradox.ai confirmed that the password data was recently stolen by a malware infection on the personal device of a longtime Paradox developer based in Vietnam, and said the company was made aware of the compromise shortly after it happened. Paradox maintains that few of the exposed passwords were still valid, and that a majority of them were present on the employee&#8217;s personal device only because he had migrated the contents of a password manager from an old computer.</p>
<p>Paradox also pointed out that it has been requiring single sign-on (SSO) authentication since 2020 that enforces multi-factor authentication for its partners. Still, a review of the exposed passwords shows they included the Vietnamese administrator&#8217;s credentials to the company&#8217;s SSO platform &#8212; paradoxai.okta.com. The password for that account ended in 202506 &#8212; possibly a reference to the month of June 2025 &#8212; and the digital cookie left behind after a successful Okta login with those credentials says it was valid until December 2025.<span id="more-71668"></span></p>
<p>Also exposed were the administrator&#8217;s credentials and authentication cookies for an account at <strong>Atlassian</strong>, a platform made for software development and project management. The expiration date for that authentication token likewise was December 2025.</p>
<p>Infostealer infections are among the leading causes of data breaches and ransomware attacks today, and they result in the theft of stored passwords and any credentials the victim types into a browser. Most infostealer malware also will siphon authentication cookies stored on the victim&#8217;s device, and depending on how those tokens are configured thieves may be able to use them to bypass login prompts and/or multi-factor authentication.</p>
<p>Quite often these infostealer infections will open a backdoor on the victim&#8217;s device that allows attackers to access the infected machine remotely. Indeed, it appears that remote access to the Paradox administrator&#8217;s compromised device was offered for sale recently.</p>
<p>In February 2019, Paradox.ai <a href="https://www.paradox.ai/news/paradox-receives-iso-27001-and-soc-2-type-ii-security-certifications" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> it had successfully completed audits for two fairly comprehensive security standards (ISO 27001 and SOC 2 Type II). Meanwhile, the company&#8217;s security disclosure this month says the test account with the atrocious 123456 username and password was last accessed in 2019, but somehow missed in their annual penetration tests. So how did it manage to pass such stringent security audits with these practices in place?</p>
<p>Paradox.ai told KrebsOnSecurity that at the time of the 2019 audit, the company&#8217;s various contractors were not held to the same security standards the company practices internally. Paradox emphasized that this has changed, and that it has updated its security and password requirements multiple times since then.</p>
<p>It is unclear how the Paradox developer in Vietnam infected his computer with malware, but a closer review finds a Windows device for another Paradox.ai employee from Vietnam was compromised by similar data-stealing malware at the end of 2024 (that compromise included the victim&#8217;s GitHub credentials). In the case of both employees, the stolen credential data includes Web browser logs that indicate the victims repeatedly downloaded pirated movies and television shows, which are often bundled with malware disguised as a video codec needed to view the pirated content.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/poor-passwords-tattle-on-ai-hiring-bot-maker-paradox-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DOGE Denizen Marko Elez Leaked API Key for xAI</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/doge-denizen-marko-elez-leaked-api-key-for-xai/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/doge-denizen-marko-elez-leaked-api-key-for-xai/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 01:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business Insider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitGuardian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marko Elez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippe Caturegli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seralys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Techcrunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Wall Street Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vice President J.D. Vance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xAI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Marko Elez, a 25-year-old employee at Elon Musk's Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE), has been granted access to sensitive databases at the U.S. Social Security Administration, the Treasury and Justice departments, and the Department of Homeland Security. So it should fill all Americans with a deep sense of confidence to learn that Mr. Elez over the weekend inadvertently published a private key that allowed anyone to interact directly with more than four dozen large language models (LLMs) developed by Musk's artificial intelligence company xAI.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Marko Elez</strong>, a 25-year-old employee at Elon Musk&#8217;s <strong>Department of Government Efficiency</strong> (DOGE), has been granted access to sensitive databases at the U.S. Social Security Administration, the Treasury and Justice departments, and the Department of Homeland Security. So it should fill all Americans with a deep sense of confidence to learn that Mr. Elez over the weekend inadvertently published a private key that allowed anyone to interact directly with more than four dozen large language models (LLMs) developed by Musk&#8217;s artificial intelligence company <strong>xAI</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_71170" style="width: 756px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71170" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71170" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/x-ai.png" alt="" width="746" height="496" /><p id="caption-attachment-71170" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, @sdx15.</p></div>
<p>On July 13, Mr. Elez committed a code script to GitHub called &#8220;agent.py&#8221; that included a private application programming interface (API) key for xAI. The inclusion of the private key was first flagged by <strong>GitGuardian</strong>, a company that specializes in detecting and remediating exposed secrets in public and proprietary environments. GitGuardian’s systems constantly scan GitHub and other code repositories for exposed API keys, and fire off automated alerts to affected users.</p>
<p><strong>Philippe Caturegli</strong>, “chief hacking officer” at the security consultancy <strong>Seralys, </strong>said the exposed API key allowed access to at least 52 different LLMs used by xAI. The most recent LLM in the list was called &#8220;grok-4-0709&#8221; and was created on July 9, 2025.</p>
<p><strong>Grok</strong>, the <a href="https://x.ai/grok" target="_blank" rel="noopener">generative AI chatbot</a> developed by xAI and integrated into <strong>Twitter/X</strong>, relies on these and other LLMs (a query to Grok before publication shows Grok currently uses Grok-3, which was launched in Feburary 2025). Earlier today, xAI <a href="https://x.com/xai/status/1944776899420377134" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that the Department of Defense will begin using Grok as part of <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/07/14/elon-musk-grok-defense-department/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a contract worth up to $200 million</a>. The contract award came less than a week after Grok began <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/07/09/nx-s1-5462609/grok-elon-musk-antisemitic-racist-content" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spewing antisemitic rants and invoking Adolf Hitler</a>.</p>
<p>Mr. Elez did not respond to a request for comment. The code repository containing the private xAI key was removed shortly after Caturegli notified Elez via email. However, Caturegli said the exposed API key still works and has not yet been revoked.</p>
<p>&#8220;If a developer can&#8217;t keep an API key private, it raises questions about how they&#8217;re handling far more sensitive government information behind closed doors,&#8221; Caturegli told KrebsOnSecurity.<span id="more-71676"></span></p>
<p>Prior to joining DOGE, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marko_Elez" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marko Elez</a> worked for a number of Musk&#8217;s companies. His DOGE career began at the Department of the Treasury, and a legal battle over DOGE&#8217;s access to Treasury databases showed Elez was sending unencrypted personal information <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/630894/doge-treasury-lawsuit-marko-elez-unencrypted-emails" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in violation of the agency&#8217;s policies</a>.</p>
<p>While still at Treasury, Elez resigned after <strong>The Wall Street Journal</strong> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/doge-staffer-resigns-over-racist-posts-d9f11a93" target="_blank" rel="noopener">linked him to social media posts</a> that advocated racism and eugenics. When <strong>Vice President J.D. Vance</strong> lobbied for Elez to be rehired, <strong>President Trump</strong> agreed and Musk reinstated him.</p>
<p>Since his re-hiring as a DOGE employee, Elez has been granted access to databases at one federal agency after another. <strong>TechCrunch</strong> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/17/doge-staffer-violated-treasury-rules-by-emailing-unencrypted-personal-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported in February 2025</a> that he was working at the Social Security Administration. In March, <strong>Business Insider</strong> <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/doge-staffer-fertility-clinic-pronatalist-department-of-labor" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found</a> Elez was part of a DOGE detachment <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/04/doge-workers-code-supports-nlrb-whistleblower/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">assigned to the Department of Labor</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_71106" style="width: 548px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71106" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71106" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/markoelez.png" alt="" width="538" height="624" /><p id="caption-attachment-71106" class="wp-caption-text">Marko Elez, in a photo from a social media profile.</p></div>
<p>In April, <strong>The New York Times</strong> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/02/27/us/politics/doge-staff-list.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that Elez held positions at the <strong>U.S. Customs and Border Protection</strong> and the <strong>Immigration and Customs Enforcement</strong> (ICE) bureaus, as well as the Department of Homeland Security. <strong>The Washington Post</strong> later <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/immigration/2025/04/21/doge-ecas-justice-immigration-courts-trump/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that Elez, while serving as a DOGE advisor at the <strong>Department of Justice</strong>, had gained access to the Executive Office for Immigration Review&#8217;s Courts and Appeals System (EACS).</p>
<p>Elez is not the first DOGE worker to publish internal API keys for xAI: In May, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/xai-dev-leaks-api-key-for-private-spacex-tesla-llms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">detailed</a> how another DOGE employee leaked a private xAI key on GitHub for two months, exposing LLMs that were custom made for working with internal data from Musk&#8217;s companies, including SpaceX, Tesla and Twitter/X.</p>
<p>Caturegli said it&#8217;s difficult to trust someone with access to confidential government systems when they can&#8217;t even manage the basics of operational security.</p>
<p>&#8220;One leak is a mistake,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But when the same type of sensitive key gets exposed again and again, it’s not just bad luck, it’s a sign of deeper negligence and a broken security culture.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/doge-denizen-marko-elez-leaked-api-key-for-xai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK Arrests Four in &#8216;Scattered Spider&#8217; Ransom Group</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/uk-charges-four-in-scattered-spider-ransom-group/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/uk-charges-four-in-scattered-spider-ransom-group/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allison Nixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amtrak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asyntax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bo764]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Co-op Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doxbin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earth2Star]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Everlynn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harrods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LAPSUS$]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marks & Spencer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MGM Casino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Crime Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Owen David Flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scattered Spider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Fraud Chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thalha Jubair]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Authorities in the United Kingdom this week arrested four alleged members of "Scattered Spider," a prolific data theft and extortion group whose recent victims include multiple airlines and the U.K. retail chain Marks &#038; Spencer.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in the United Kingdom this week arrested four people aged 17 to 20 in connection with recent data theft and extortion attacks against the retailers <strong>Marks &amp; Spencer</strong> and <strong>Harrods</strong>, and the British food retailer <strong>Co-op Group. </strong>The breaches have been linked to a prolific but loosely-affiliated cybercrime group dubbed &#8220;<strong>Scattered Spider</strong>,&#8221; whose other recent victims include multiple airlines.</p>
<p>The U.K.&#8217;s <strong>National Crime Agency</strong> (NCA) declined verify the names of those arrested, <a href="https://www.nationalcrimeagency.gov.uk/news/retail-cyber-attacks-nca-arrest-four-for-attacks-on-m-s-co-op-and-harrods" target="_blank" rel="noopener">saying</a> only that they included two males aged 19, another aged 17, and 20-year-old female.</p>
<p>Scattered Spider is the name given to an English-speaking cybercrime group known for using social engineering tactics to break into companies and steal data for ransom, often impersonating employees or contractors to deceive IT help desks into granting access. The <strong>FBI</strong> warned last month that Scattered Spider had recently shifted to targeting companies in the retail and airline sectors.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity has learned the identities of two of the suspects. Multiple sources close to the investigation said those arrested include <strong>Owen David Flowers</strong>, a U.K. man alleged to have been involved in the cyber intrusion and ransomware attack that shut down several <strong>MGM Casino</strong> properties in September 2023. Those same sources said the woman arrested is or recently was in a relationship with Flowers.</p>
<p>Sources told KrebsOnSecurity that Flowers, who allegedly went by the hacker handles &#8220;bo764,&#8221; &#8220;Holy,&#8221; and &#8220;Nazi,&#8221; was the group member who anonymously gave interviews to the media in the days after the MGM hack. His real name was omitted from <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a September 2024 story about the group</a> because he was not yet charged in that incident.</p>
<p>The bigger fish arrested this week is 19-year-old <strong>Thalha Jubair</strong>, a U.K. man whose alleged exploits under various monikers have been well-documented in stories on this site. Jubair is believed to have used the nickname &#8220;<strong>Earth2Star</strong>,&#8221; which corresponds to a founding member of the cybercrime-focused Telegram channel &#8220;<strong>Star Fraud Chat</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>In 2023, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/02/hackers-claim-they-breached-t-mobile-more-than-100-times-in-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published an investigation</a> into the work of three different SIM-swapping groups that phished credentials from T-Mobile employees and used that access to offer a service whereby any T-Mobile phone number could be swapped to a new device. Star Chat was by far the most active and consequential of the three SIM-swapping groups, who collectively broke into T-Mobile&#8217;s network more than 100 times in the second half of 2022.</p>
<div id="attachment_71644" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71644" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71644" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ace-earth2star-starchat.png" alt="" width="747" height="306" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ace-earth2star-starchat.png 1153w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ace-earth2star-starchat-768x314.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ace-earth2star-starchat-782x320.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71644" class="wp-caption-text">Jubair allegedly used the handles &#8220;Earth2Star&#8221; and &#8220;Star Ace,&#8221; and was a core member of a prolific SIM-swapping group operating in 2022. Star Ace posted this image to the Star Fraud chat channel on Telegram, and it lists various prices for SIM-swaps.</p></div>
<p>Sources tell KrebsOnSecurity that Jubair also was a core member of the <strong>LAPSUS$</strong> cybercrime group that <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/a-closer-look-at-the-lapsus-data-extortion-group/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">broke into dozens of technology companies in 2022</a>, stealing source code and other internal data from tech giants including <strong>Microsoft</strong>, <strong>Nvidia</strong>, <strong>Okta</strong>, <strong>Rockstar Games</strong>, <strong>Samsung</strong>, <strong>T-Mobile</strong>, and <strong>Uber</strong>.</p>
<p>In April 2022, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/leaked-chats-show-lapsus-stole-t-mobile-source-code/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published internal chat records from LAPSUS$</a>, and those chats indicated Jubair was using the nicknames <strong>Amtrak</strong> and <strong>Asyntax</strong>. At one point in the chats, Amtrak told the LAPSUS$ group leader not to share T-Mobile&#8217;s logo in images sent to the group because he&#8217;d been previously busted for SIM-swapping and his parents would suspect he was back at it again.</p>
<p>As shown in those chats, the leader of LAPSUS$ eventually decided to betray Amtrak by posting his real name, phone number, and other hacker handles into a public chat room on Telegram.</p>
<div id="attachment_59487" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59487" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59487" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/amtraxdox.png" alt="" width="749" height="207" /><p id="caption-attachment-59487" class="wp-caption-text">In March 2022, the leader of the LAPSUS$ data extortion group exposed Thalha Jubair&#8217;s name and hacker handles in a public chat room on Telegram.</p></div>
<p><span id="more-70968"></span>That story about the leaked LAPSUS$ chats connected Amtrak/Asyntax/Jubair to the identity &#8220;<strong>Everlynn</strong>,&#8221; the founder of a cybercriminal service that <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/hackers-gaining-power-of-subpoena-via-fake-emergency-data-requests/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sold fraudulent &#8220;emergency data requests&#8221;</a> targeting the major social media and email providers. In such schemes, the hackers compromise email accounts tied to police departments and government agencies, and then send unauthorized demands for subscriber data while claiming the information being requested can’t wait for a court order because it relates to an urgent matter of life and death.</p>
<div id="attachment_59127" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-59127" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-59127" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion.png" alt="" width="748" height="622" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion.png 864w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion-768x638.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/infinityrecursion-782x650.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-59127" class="wp-caption-text">The roster of the now-defunct &#8220;Infinity Recursion&#8221; hacking team, from which some member of LAPSUS$ hail.</p></div>
<p>Sources say Jubair also used the nickname &#8220;<strong>Operator</strong>,&#8221; and that until recently he was the administrator of the <strong>Doxbin</strong>, a long-running and highly toxic online community that is used to “dox” or post deeply personal information on people. In May 2024, several popular cybercrime channels on Telegram ridiculed Operator after it was revealed that he&#8217;d staged his own kidnapping in a botched plan to throw off law enforcement investigators.</p>
<p>In November 2024, U.S. authorities <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/feds-charge-five-men-in-scattered-spider-roundup/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">charged five men aged 20 to 25</a> in connection with the Scattered Spider group, which has long relied on recruiting minors to carry out its most risky activities. Indeed, many of the group&#8217;s core members were recruited from online gaming platforms like Roblox and Minecraft in their early teens, and have been perfecting their social engineering tactics for years.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is a clear pattern that some of the most depraved threat actors first joined cybercrime gangs at an exceptionally young age,&#8221; said <strong>Allison Nixon</strong>, chief research officer at the New York based security firm <a href="https://www.unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a>. &#8220;Cybercriminals arrested at 15 or younger need serious intervention and monitoring to prevent a years long massive escalation.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/uk-charges-four-in-scattered-spider-ransom-group/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>52</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 255/255 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached (User agent is rejected) 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2025-08-17 13:58:38 by W3 Total Cache
-->