<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 23:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>DSLRoot, Proxies, and the Threat of &#8216;Legal Botnets&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/dslroot-proxies-and-the-threat-of-legal-botnets/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/dslroot-proxies-and-the-threat-of-legal-botnets/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things (IoT)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aliaksandr Holas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrei Holas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlackHatWorld]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Constella Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DomainTools.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DSLRoot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GlobalSolutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incorptoday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[incorptoday@gmail.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrawatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel 471]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lloyd Davies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prepaidsolutions@yahoo.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reddit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ryzhik777@gmail.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sacapoopie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USProxyKing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WebHostingTalk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cybersecurity community on Reddit responded in disbelief this month when a self-described Air National Guard member with top secret security clearance began questioning the arrangement they'd made with company called DSLRoot, which was paying $250 a month to plug a pair of laptops into the Redditor's high-speed Internet connection in the United States. This post examines the history and provenance of DSLRoot, one of the oldest "residential proxy" networks with origins in Russia and Eastern Europe.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The cybersecurity community on <strong>Reddit</strong> responded in disbelief this month when a self-described Air National Guard member with top secret security clearance began questioning the arrangement they&#8217;d made with company called <strong>DSLRoot</strong>, which was paying $250 a month to plug a pair of laptops into the Redditor&#8217;s high-speed Internet connection in the United States. This post examines the history and provenance of DSLRoot, one of the oldest &#8220;residential proxy&#8221; networks with origins in Russia and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-71989" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/sacapoopiepost.png" alt="" width="748" height="379" /></p>
<p>The query about DSLRoot came from a Reddit user &#8220;<strong>Sacapoopie</strong>,&#8221; who did not respond to questions. This user has since deleted the original question from their post, although some of their replies to other Reddit cybersecurity enthusiasts <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/cybersecurity/comments/1mksa8q/hosting_residential_ip_network_nodes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">remain in the thread</a>. The original post was indexed <a href="https://archive.is/qsozu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here by archive.is</a>, and it began with a question:</p>
<p>&#8220;I have been getting paid 250$ a month by a residential IP network provider named DSL root to host devices in my home,&#8221; Sacapoopie wrote. &#8220;They are on a separate network than what we use for personal use. They have dedicated DSL connections (one per host) to the ISP that provides the DSL coverage. My family used Starlink. Is this stupid for me to do? They just sit there and I get paid for it. The company pays the internet bill too.&#8221;</p>
<p>Many Redditors said they assumed Sacapoopie&#8217;s post was a joke, and that nobody with a cybersecurity background and top-secret (TS/SCI) clearance would agree to let some shady residential proxy company introduce hardware into their network. Other readers pointed to a slew of posts from Sacapoopie in the Cybersecurity subreddit over the past two years about their work on cybersecurity for the Air National Guard.</p>
<p>When pressed for more details by fellow Redditors, Sacapoopie described the equipment supplied by DSLRoot as &#8220;just two laptops hardwired into a modem, which then goes to a dsl port in the wall.&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-71990" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/saca-twolaptops.png" alt="" width="747" height="218" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/saca-twolaptops.png 922w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/saca-twolaptops-768x224.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/saca-twolaptops-782x228.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /></p>
<p>&#8220;When I open the computer, it looks like [they] have some sort of custom application that runs and spawns several cmd prompts,&#8221; the Redditor explained. &#8220;All I can infer from what I see in them is they are making connections.&#8221;</p>
<p>When asked how they became acquainted with DSLRoot, Sacapoopie told another user they discovered the company and reached out after viewing an advertisement on a social media platform.</p>
<p>&#8220;This was probably 5-6 years ago,&#8221; Sacapoopie wrote. &#8220;Since then I just communicate with a technician from that company and I help trouble shoot connectivity issues when they arise.&#8221;</p>
<p>Reached for comment, DSLRoot said its brand has been unfairly maligned thanks to that Reddit discussion. The unsigned email said DSLRoot is fully transparent about its goals and operations, adding that it operates under full consent from its &#8220;regional agents,&#8221; the company&#8217;s term for U.S. residents like Sacapoopie.</p>
<p>&#8220;As although we support honest journalism, we&#8217;re against of all kinds of &#8216;low rank/misleading Yellow Journalism&#8217; done for the sake of cheap hype,&#8221; DSLRoot wrote in reply. &#8220;It&#8217;s obvious to us that whoever is doing this, is either lacking a proper understanding of the subject or doing it intentionally to gain exposure by misleading those who lack proper understanding,&#8221; DSLRoot wrote in answer to questions about the company&#8217;s intentions.</p>
<p>&#8220;We monitor our clients and prohibit any illegal activity associated with our residential proxies,&#8221; DSLRoot continued. &#8220;We honestly didn&#8217;t know that the guy who made the Reddit post was a military guy. Be it an African-American granny trying to pay her rent or a white kid trying to get through college, as long as they can provide an Internet line or host phones for us &#8212; we&#8217;re good.&#8221;<span id="more-71984"></span></p>
<h2>WHAT IS DSLROOT?</h2>
<p>DSLRoot is sold as a residential proxy service on the forum <strong>BlackHatWorld</strong> under the name DSLRoot and <strong>GlobalSolutions</strong>. The company is based in the Bahamas and was formed in 2012. The service is advertised to people who are not in the United States but who want to seem like they are. DSLRoot pays people in the United States to run the company&#8217;s hardware and software &#8212; including 5G mobile devices &#8212; and in return it rents those IP addresses as dedicated proxies to customers anywhere in the world &#8212; priced at $190 per month for unrestricted access to all locations.</p>
<div id="attachment_71996" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71996" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71996" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/dslroot.png" alt="" width="748" height="425" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/dslroot.png 1194w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/dslroot-768x436.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/dslroot-782x444.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71996" class="wp-caption-text">The DSLRoot website.</p></div>
<p>The GlobalSolutions account on BlackHatWorld lists a Telegram account and a WhatsApp number in Mexico. DSLRoot&#8217;s profile on the marketing agency digitalpoint.com from 2010 shows their previous username on the forum was &#8220;<strong>Incorptoday</strong>.&#8221; GlobalSolutions user accounts at bitcointalk[.]org and roclub[.]com include the email <strong>clickdesk@instantvirtualcreditcards[.]com</strong>.</p>
<p>Passive DNS records from <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> show instantvirtualcreditcards[.]com shared a host back then &#8212; 208.85.1.164 &#8212; with just a handful of domains, including dslroot[.]com, regacard[.]com, 4groot[.]com, residential-ip[.]com, 4gemperor[.]com, ip-teleport[.]com, <strong>proxysource[.]net</strong> and proxyrental[.]net.</p>
<p>Cyber intelligence firm <strong>Intel 471</strong> finds GlobalSolutions registered on BlackHatWorld in 2016 using the email address <strong>prepaidsolutions@yahoo.com</strong>. This user shared that their birthday is March 7, 1984.</p>
<p>Several negative reviews about DSLRoot on the forums noted that the service was operated by a BlackHatWorld user calling himself &#8220;<strong>USProxyKing</strong>.&#8221; Indeed, Intel 471 shows this user told fellow forum members in 2013 to contact him at the Skype username &#8220;dslroot.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_71993" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71993" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71993" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bhw-usproxyking.png" alt="" width="750" height="336" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bhw-usproxyking.png 1312w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bhw-usproxyking-768x344.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bhw-usproxyking-782x350.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71993" class="wp-caption-text">USProxyKing on BlackHatWorld, soliciting installations of his adware via torrents and file-sharing sites.</p></div>
<p>USProxyKing had a reputation for spamming the forums with ads for his residential proxy service, and he ran a &#8220;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2011/06/pay-per-install-a-major-source-of-badness/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pay-per-install</a>&#8221; program where he paid affiliates a small commission each time one of their websites resulted in the installation of his unspecified &#8220;adware&#8221; programs &#8212; presumably a program that turned host PCs into proxies. On the other end of the business, USProxyKing sold that pay-per-install access to others wishing to distribute questionable software &#8212; at $1 per installation.</p>
<p>Private messages indexed by Intel 471 show USProxyKing also raised money from nearly 20 different BlackHatWorld members who were promised shareholder positions in a new business that would offer robocalling services capable of placing 2,000 calls per minute.</p>
<p><strong>Constella Intelligence</strong>, a platform that tracks data exposed in breaches, finds that same IP address GlobalSolutions used to register at BlackHatWorld was also used to create accounts at a handful of sites, including a GlobalSolutions user account at <strong>WebHostingTalk </strong>that supplied the email address <strong>incorptoday@gmail.com</strong>. Also registered to incorptoday@gmail.com are the domains dslbay[.]com, dslhub[.]net, localsim[.]com, rdslpro[.]com, virtualcards[.]biz/cc, and virtualvisa[.]cc.</p>
<p>Recall that DSLRoot&#8217;s profile on digitalpoint.com was previously named Incorptoday. DomainTools says incorptoday@gmail.com is associated with almost two dozen domains going back to 2008, including <strong>incorptoday[.]com</strong>, a website that offers to incorporate businesses in several states, including Delaware, Florida and Nevada, for prices ranging from $450 to $550.</p>
<p>As we can see in <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130210060312/http://www.incorptoday.com/services/business_bank_account_nonus_residents" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this archived copy of the site from 2013</a>, IncorpToday also offered a premiere service for $750 that would allow the customer&#8217;s new company to have a retail checking account, with no questions asked.</p>
<p>Global Solutions is able to provide access to the U.S. banking system by offering customers prepaid cards that can be loaded with a variety of virtual payment instruments that were popular in Russian-speaking countries at the time, including WebMoney. The cards are limited to $500 balances, but non-Westerners can use them to anonymously pay for goods and services at a variety of Western companies. <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20111013132649/http://www.cardnow.ru/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cardnow[.]ru</a>, another domain registered to incorptoday@gmail.com, demonstrates this in action.</p>
<div id="attachment_71992" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71992" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71992" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/incorptoday-bankaccount.png" alt="" width="750" height="648" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/incorptoday-bankaccount.png 993w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/incorptoday-bankaccount-768x664.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/incorptoday-bankaccount-782x676.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71992" class="wp-caption-text">A copy of Incorptoday&#8217;s website from 2013 offers non-US residents a service to incorporate a business in Florida, Delaware or Nevada, along with a no-questions-asked checking account, for $750.</p></div>
<h2>WHO IS ANDREI HOLAS?</h2>
<p>The oldest domain (2008) registered to incorptoday@gmail.com is <strong>andrei[.]me</strong>; another is called <strong>andreigolos[.]com</strong>. DomainTools says these and other domains registered to that email address include the registrant name <strong>Andrei Holas</strong>, from Huntsville, Ala.</p>
<p>Public records indicate Andrei Holas has lived with his brother &#8212; <strong>Aliaksandr Holas</strong> &#8212; at two different addresses in Alabama. Those records state that Andrei Holas&#8217; birthday is in March 1984, and that his brother is slightly younger. The younger brother did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p>Andrei Holas maintained an account on the Russian social network <strong>Vkontakte</strong> under the email address <strong>ryzhik777@gmail.com</strong>, an address that shows up in numerous records hacked and leaked from Russian government entities over the past few years.</p>
<p>Those records indicate Andrei Holas and his brother are from Belarus and have maintained an address in Moscow for some time (that address is roughly three blocks away from the main headquarters of the Russian FSB, the successor intelligence agency to the KGB). Hacked Russian banking records show Andrei Holas&#8217; birthday is March 7, 1984 &#8212; the same birth date listed by GlobalSolutions on BlackHatWorld.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www-ulitka-com.translate.goog/forum/%D0%B6%D0%B8%D0%B7%D0%BD%D1%8C-%D0%B8-%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%B1%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%B0-%D0%B2-%D0%B0%D0%BC%D0%B5%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%B5/%D0%B6%D0%B8%D0%B7%D0%BD%D1%8C-%D0%B2-%D0%B0%D0%BC%D0%B5%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%B5/%D0%B2%D0%BE%D1%81%D1%81%D0%BE%D0%B5%D0%B4%D0%B8%D0%BD%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B5-%D1%81%D0%B5%D0%BC%D1%8C%D0%B8/27020-%D0%BF%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%B8%D1%82%D0%B5-%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%B7%D0%BE%D0%B1%D1%80%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%8C%D1%81%D1%8F?_x_tr_sl=auto&amp;_x_tr_tl=en&amp;_x_tr_hl=en-US&amp;_x_tr_pto=wapp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2010 post by ryzhik777@gmail.com</a> at the Russian-language forum Ulitka explains that the poster was having trouble getting his B1/B2 visa to visit his brother in the United States, even though he&#8217;d previously been approved for two separate guest visas and a student visa. It remains unclear if one, both, or neither of the Holas brothers still lives in the United States. Andrei explained in 2010 that his brother was an American citizen.</p>
<h2>LEGAL BOTNETS</h2>
<p>We can all wag our fingers at military personnel who should undoubtedly know better than to install Internet hardware from strangers, but in truth there is an endless supply of U.S. residents who will resell their Internet connection if it means they can make a few bucks out of it. And these days, there are plenty of residential proxy providers who will make it worth your while.</p>
<p>Traditionally, residential proxy networks have been constructed using malicious software that quietly turns infected systems into traffic relays that are then sold in shadowy online forums. Most often, this malware gets bundled with popular cracked software and video files that are uploaded to file-sharing networks and that secretly turn the host device into a traffic relay. In fact, USPRoxyKing bragged that he routinely achieved thousands of installs per week via this method alone.</p>
<p>These days, there a number of residential proxy networks that entice users to monetize their unused bandwidth (inviting you to violate the terms of service of your ISP in the process); others, like DSLRoot, act as a communal VPN, and by using the service you gain access to the connections of other proxies (users) by default, but you also agree to share your connection with others.</p>
<p>Indeed, Intel 471&#8217;s archives show the GlobalSolutions and DSLRoot accounts routinely received private messages from forum users who were college students or young people trying to make ends meet. Those messages show that many of DSLRoot&#8217;s &#8220;regional agents&#8221; often sought commissions to refer friends interested in reselling their home Internet connections (DSLRoot would offer to cover the monthly cost of the agent&#8217;s home Internet connection).</p>
<p>But in an era when North Korean hackers are relentlessly posing as Western IT workers by paying people to host laptop farms in the United States, letting strangers run laptops, mobile devices or any other hardware on your network seems like an awfully risky move regardless of your station in life. As several Redditors pointed out in Sacapoopie&#8217;s thread, an Arizona woman <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/arizona-woman-sentenced-17m-information-technology-worker-fraud-scheme-generated-revenue" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was sentenced in July 2025 to 102 months in prison</a> for hosting a laptop farm that helped North Korean hackers secure jobs at more than 300 U.S. companies, including Fortune 500 firms.</p>
<p><strong>Lloyd Davies</strong> is the founder of <strong>Infrawatch</strong>, a London-based security startup that tracks residential proxy networks. Davies said he reverse engineered <a href="https://www.virustotal.com/gui/file/042a8fa307e585952ada30070a2aa5606a9a8fbdf7c9f15d50753fcf33736bc9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the software that powers DSLRoot&#8217;s proxy service</a>, and found it phones home to the aforementioned domain proxysource[.]net, which sells a service that promises to &#8220;get your ads live in multiple cities without getting banned, flagged or ghosted&#8221; (presumably a reference to CraigsList ads).</p>
<p>Davies said he found the DSLRoot installer had capabilities to remotely control residential networking equipment across multiple vendor brands.</p>
<div id="attachment_72002" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-72002" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-72002" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/DSLROOT-map.png" alt="" width="749" height="489" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/DSLROOT-map.png 1194w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/DSLROOT-map-768x501.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/DSLROOT-map-782x510.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-72002" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Infrawatch.app.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;The software employs vendor-specific exploits and hardcoded administrative credentials, suggesting DSLRoot pre-configures equipment before deployment,&#8221; Davies wrote in <a href="https://infrawatch.app/blog/dslroot-us-proxy-investigation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an analysis published today</a>. He said the software performs WiFi network enumeration to identify nearby wireless networks, thereby &#8220;potentially expanding targeting capabilities beyond the primary internet connection.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear exactly when the USProxyKing was usurped from his throne, but DSLRoot and its proxy offerings are not what they used to be. Davies said the entire DSLRoot network now has fewer than 300 nodes nationwide, mostly systems on DSL providers like CenturyLink and Frontier.</p>
<p>On Aug. 17, GlobalSolutions posted to BlackHatWorld saying, &#8220;We&#8217;re restructuring our business model by downgrading to &#8216;DSL only&#8217; lines (no mobile or cable).&#8221; Asked via email about the changes, DSLRoot blamed the decline in his customers on the proliferation of residential proxy services.</p>
<p>&#8220;These days it has become almost impossible to compete in this niche as everyone is selling residential proxies and many companies want you to install a piece of software on your phone or desktop so they can resell your residential IPs on a much larger scale,&#8221; DSLRoot explained. &#8220;So-called &#8216;legal botnets&#8217; as we see them.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/dslroot-proxies-and-the-threat-of-legal-botnets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SIM-Swapper, Scattered Spider Hacker Gets 10 Years</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/sim-swapper-scattered-spider-hacker-gets-10-years/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/sim-swapper-scattered-spider-hacker-gets-10-years/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 01:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SIM Swapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DoorDash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judge Harvey E. Schlesinger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Bob]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lastpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News4Jax.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah Michael Urban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oktapus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scatter Swine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scattered Spider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sosa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UNC3944]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A 21-year-old Florida man at the center of a prolific cybercrime group known as "Scattered Spider" was sentenced to 10 years in federal prison today, and ordered to pay roughly $13 million in restitution to victims.

Noah Michael Urban of Palm Coast, Fla. pleaded guilty in April 2025 to charges of wire fraud and conspiracy. Florida prosecutors alleged Urban conspired with others to steal at least $800,000 from five victims via SIM-swapping attacks that diverted their mobile phone calls and text messages to devices controlled by Urban and his co-conspirators.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 20-year-old Florida man at the center of a prolific cybercrime group known as &#8220;<strong>Scattered Spider</strong>&#8221; was sentenced to 10 years in federal prison today, and ordered to pay roughly $13 million in restitution to victims.</p>
<p><strong>Noah Michael Urban</strong> of Palm Coast, Fla. pleaded guilty in April 2025 to charges of wire fraud and conspiracy. Florida prosecutors alleged Urban <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/01/fla-man-charged-in-sim-swapping-spree-is-key-suspect-in-hacker-groups-oktapus-scattered-spider/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conspired with others to steal at least $800,000</a> from five victims via <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/category/sim-swapping/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SIM-swapping attacks</a> that diverted their mobile phone calls and text messages to devices controlled by Urban and his co-conspirators.</p>
<div id="attachment_66236" style="width: 456px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-66236" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-66236" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/noahmichaelurban.png" alt="" width="446" height="559" /><p id="caption-attachment-66236" class="wp-caption-text">A booking photo of Noah Michael Urban released by the Volusia County Sheriff.</p></div>
<p>Although prosecutors had asked for Urban to serve eight years, Jacksonville news outlet <strong>News4Jax.com</strong> <a href="https://www.news4jax.com/news/local/2025/08/20/palm-coast-man-linked-to-scattered-spider-cybercrime-gang-sentenced-to-10-years-for-cryptocurrency-theft/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> the federal judge in the case today opted to sentence Urban to 120 months in federal prison, ordering him to pay $13 million in restitution and undergo three years of supervised release after his sentence is completed.</p>
<p>In November 2024 Urban was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/feds-charge-five-men-in-scattered-spider-roundup/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">charged by federal prosecutors in Los Angeles</a> as one of five members of Scattered Spider (a.k.a. &#8220;Oktapus,&#8221; &#8220;Scatter Swine&#8221; and &#8220;UNC3944&#8221;), which specialized in SMS and voice phishing attacks that tricked employees at victim companies into entering their credentials and one-time passcodes at phishing websites. Urban pleaded guilty to one count of conspiracy to commit wire fraud in the California case, and the $13 million in restitution is intended to cover victims from both cases.</p>
<p>The targeted SMS scams <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/08/how-1-time-passcodes-became-a-corporate-liability/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">spanned several months during the summer of 2022</a>, asking employees to click a link and log in at a website that mimicked their employer’s Okta authentication page. Some SMS phishing messages told employees their VPN credentials were expiring and needed to be changed; other missives advised employees about changes to their upcoming work schedule.</p>
<p>That phishing spree netted Urban and others access to more than 130 companies, including <strong>Twilio</strong>, <strong>LastPass</strong>, <strong>DoorDash</strong>, <strong>MailChimp</strong>, and <strong>Plex</strong>. The government says the group used that access to steal proprietary company data and customer information, and that members also phished people to steal millions of dollars worth of cryptocurrency.</p>
<p>For many years, Urban&#8217;s online hacker aliases &#8220;<strong>King Bob</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Sosa</strong>&#8221; were fixtures of <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Com</a>, a mostly Telegram and Discord-based community of English-speaking cybercriminals wherein hackers boast loudly about high-profile exploits and hacks that almost invariably begin with social engineering. King Bob constantly bragged on the Com about stealing unreleased rap music recordings from popular artists, presumably through SIM-swapping attacks. Many of those purloined tracks or &#8220;grails&#8221; he later sold or gave away on forums.</p>
<div id="attachment_71970" style="width: 611px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71970" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71970" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/kingbobtweets.png" alt="" width="601" height="485" /><p id="caption-attachment-71970" class="wp-caption-text">Noah &#8220;King Bob&#8221; Urban, posting to Twitter/X around the time of his sentencing today.</p></div>
<p>Sosa also was active in a particularly destructive group of accomplished criminal SIM-swappers known as &#8220;<strong>Star Fraud</strong>.&#8221; Cyberscoop’s AJ Vicens reported in 2023 that individuals within Star Fraud were likely involved in the high-profile Caesars Entertainment and MGM Resorts extortion attacks that same year.</p>
<p>The Star Fraud SIM-swapping group gained the ability to temporarily move targeted mobile numbers to devices they controlled by constantly phishing employees of the major mobile providers. In February 2023, KrebsOnSecurity published data taken from the Telegram channels for Star Fraud and two other SIM-swapping groups showing these crooks focused on SIM-swapping T-Mobile customers, and that they collectively <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/02/hackers-claim-they-breached-t-mobile-more-than-100-times-in-2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">claimed internal access to T-Mobile on 100 separate occasions over a 7-month period in 2022</a>.<span id="more-71967"></span></p>
<p>Reached via one of his King Bob accounts on Twitter/X, Urban called the sentence unjust, and said the judge in his case discounted his age as a factor.</p>
<p>&#8220;The judge purposefully ignored my age as a factor because of the fact another Scattered Spider member hacked him personally during the course of my case,&#8221; Urban said in reply to questions, noting that he was sending the messages from a Florida county jail. &#8220;He should have been removed as a judge much earlier on. But staying in county jail is torture.&#8221;</p>
<p>A <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/urban-status-hack.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">court transcript</a> (PDF) from a status hearing in February 2025 shows Urban was telling the truth about the hacking incident that happened while he was in federal custody. It involved an intrusion into a magistrate judge&#8217;s email account, where a copy of Urban&#8217;s sealed indictment was stolen. The judge told attorneys for both sides that a co-defendant in the California case was trying to find out about Mr. Urban&#8217;s activity in the Florida case.</p>
<p>&#8220;What it ultimately turned into a was a big faux pas,&#8221; <strong>Judge Harvey E. Schlesinger</strong> said. &#8220;The Court&#8217;s password&#8230;business is handled by an outside contractor. And somebody called the outside contractor representing Judge Toomey saying, &#8216;I need a password change.&#8217; And they gave out the password change. That&#8217;s how whoever was making the phone call got into the court.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/sim-swapper-scattered-spider-hacker-gets-10-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oregon Man Charged in &#8216;Rapper Bot&#8217; DDoS Service</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/oregon-man-charged-in-rapper-bot-ddos-service/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/oregon-man-charged-in-rapper-bot-ddos-service/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DDoS-for-Hire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Defense Criminal Investigative Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elliott Peterson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethan J. Foltz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gmail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paypal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Shield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapper Bot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slaykings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A 22-year-old Oregon man has been arrested on suspicion of operating "Rapper Bot," a massive botnet used to power a service for launching distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks against targets -- including a March 2025 DDoS that knocked Twitter/X offline. The Justice Department asserts the suspect and an unidentified co-conspirator rented out the botnet to online extortionists, and tried to stay off the radar of law enforcement by ensuring that their botnet was never pointed at KrebsOnSecurity.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 22-year-old Oregon man has been arrested on suspicion of operating &#8220;<strong>Rapper Bot</strong>,&#8221; a massive botnet used to power a service for launching distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks against targets &#8212; including a March 2025 DDoS that knocked Twitter/X offline. The Justice Department asserts the suspect and an unidentified co-conspirator rented out the botnet to online extortionists, and tried to stay off the radar of law enforcement by ensuring that their botnet was never pointed at KrebsOnSecurity.</p>
<div id="attachment_71952" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71952" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71952" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbotpanel.png" alt="" width="747" height="553" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbotpanel.png 1190w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbotpanel-768x568.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbotpanel-782x578.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71952" class="wp-caption-text">The control panel for the Rapper Bot botnet greets users with the message &#8220;Welcome to the Ball Pit, Now with refrigerator support,&#8221; an apparent reference to a handful of IoT-enabled refrigerators that were enslaved in their DDoS botnet.</p></div>
<p>On August 6, 2025, federal agents arrested <strong>Ethan J. Foltz</strong> of Springfield, Ore. on suspicion of operating Rapper Bot, a globally dispersed collection of tens of thousands of hacked Internet of Things (IoT) devices.</p>
<p>The complaint against Foltz explains the attacks usually clocked in at more than two terabits of junk data per second (a terabit is one trillion bits of data), which is more than enough traffic to cause serious problems for all but the most well-defended targets. The government says Rapper Bot consistently launched attacks that were &#8220;hundreds of times larger than the expected capacity of a typical server located in a data center,&#8221; and that some of its biggest attacks exceeded six terabits per second.</p>
<p>Indeed, Rapper Bot was <a href="https://cyberpress.org/rapperbot-exploits-dvrs-to-take-control-of-surveillance-cameras/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reportedly responsible</a> for the March 10, 2025 attack that caused intermittent outages on Twitter/X. The government says Rapper Bot&#8217;s most lucrative and frequent customers were involved in extorting online businesses &#8212; including numerous gambling operations based in China.</p>
<p>The criminal complaint was written by <strong>Elliott Peterson</strong>, an investigator with the <strong>Defense Criminal Investigative Service</strong> (DCIS), the criminal investigative division of the <strong>Department of Defense</strong> (DoD) Office of Inspector General. The complaint notes the DCIS got involved because several Internet addresses maintained by the DoD were the target of Rapper Bot attacks.</p>
<p>Peterson said he tracked Rapper Bot to Foltz after a subpoena to an ISP in Arizona that was hosting one of the botnet&#8217;s control servers showed the account was paid for via <strong>PayPal</strong>. More legal process to PayPal revealed Foltz&#8217;s <strong>Gmail</strong> account and previously used IP addresses. A subpoena to Google showed the defendant searched security blogs constantly for news about Rapper Bot, and for updates about competing DDoS-for-hire botnets.</p>
<p>According to the complaint, after having a search warrant served on his residence the defendant admitted to building and operating Rapper Bot, sharing the profits 50/50 with a person he claimed to know only by the hacker handle &#8220;<strong>Slaykings</strong>.&#8221; Foltz also shared with investigators the logs from his Telegram chats, wherein Foltz and Slaykings discussed how best to stay off the radar of law enforcement investigators while their competitors were getting busted.</p>
<p>Specifically, the two hackers chatted about <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/05/krebsonsecurity-hit-with-near-record-6-3-tbps-ddos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a May 20 attack against KrebsOnSecurity.com</a> that clocked in at more than 6.3 terabits of data per second. The brief attack was notable because at the time it was the largest DDoS that Google had ever mitigated (KrebsOnSecurity sits behind the protection of <strong>Project Shield</strong>, a free DDoS defense service that <strong>Google</strong> provides to websites offering news, human rights, and election-related content).</p>
<p>The May 2025 DDoS was launched by an IoT botnet called <strong>Aisuru</strong>, which I discovered was operated by a 21-year-old man in Brazil named <strong>Kaike Southier Leite</strong>. This individual was more commonly known online as &#8220;<strong>Forky</strong>,&#8221; and Forky told me he wasn&#8217;t afraid of me or U.S. federal investigators. Nevertheless, the complaint against Foltz notes that Forky&#8217;s botnet seemed to diminish in size and firepower at the same time that Rapper Bot&#8217;s infection numbers were on the upswing.</p>
<p>&#8220;Both FOLTZ and Slaykings were very dismissive of attention seeking activities, the most extreme of which, in their view, was to launch DDoS attacks against the website of the prominent cyber security journalist Brian Krebs,&#8221; Peterson wrote in the criminal complaint.</p>
<p>&#8220;You see, they’ll get themselves [expletive],&#8221; Slaykings wrote in response to Foltz&#8217;s comments about Forky and Aisuru bringing too much heat on themselves.</p>
<p>&#8220;Prob cuz [redacted] hit krebs,&#8221; Foltz wrote in reply.</p>
<p>&#8220;Going against Krebs isn’t a good move,&#8221; Slaykings concurred. &#8220;It isn’t about being a [expletive] or afraid, you just get a lot of problems for zero money. Childish, but good. Let them die.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Ye, it’s good tho, they will die,&#8221; Foltz replied.</p>
<p>The government states that just prior to Foltz&#8217;s arrest, Rapper Bot had enslaved an estimated 65,000 devices globally. That may sound like a lot, but the complaint notes the defendants weren&#8217;t interested in making headlines for building the world&#8217;s largest or most powerful botnet.</p>
<p>Quite the contrary: The complaint asserts that the accused took care to maintain their botnet in a &#8220;Goldilocks&#8221; size &#8212; ensuring that &#8220;the number of devices afforded powerful attacks while still being manageable to control and, in the hopes of Foltz and his partners, small enough to not be detected.&#8221;</p>
<p>The complaint states that several days later, Foltz and Slaykings returned to discussing what that they expected to befall their rival group, with Slaykings stating, &#8220;Krebs is very revenge. He won’t stop until they are [expletive] to the bone.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Surprised they have any bots left,&#8221; Foltz answered.</p>
<p>&#8220;Krebs is not the one you want to have on your back. Not because he is scary or something, just because he will not give up UNTIL you are [expletive] [expletive]. Proved it with Mirai and many other cases.&#8221;<span id="more-71944"></span></p>
<p>[Unknown expletives aside, that may well be the highest compliment I&#8217;ve ever been paid by a cybercriminal. I might even have part of that quote made into a t-shirt or mug or something. It&#8217;s also nice that they didn&#8217;t let any of their customers attack my site &#8212; if even only out of a paranoid sense of self-preservation.]</p>
<p>Foltz admitted to wiping the user and attack logs for the botnet approximately once a week, so investigators were unable to tally the total number of attacks, customers and targets of this vast crime machine. But the data that was still available showed that from April 2025 to early August, Rapper Bot conducted over 370,000 attacks, targeting 18,000 unique victims across 1,000 networks, with the bulk of victims residing in China, Japan, the United States, Ireland and Hong Kong (in that order).</p>
<p>According to the government, Rapper Bot borrows much of its code from <strong>fBot</strong>, a DDoS malware strain also known as <strong>Satori</strong>. In 2020, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/06/new-charges-sentencing-in-satori-iot-botnet-conspiracy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">authorities in Northern Ireland charged a then 20-year-old man</a> named <strong>Aaron &#8220;Vamp&#8221; Sterritt</strong> with operating fBot with a co-conspirator. U.S. prosecutors are still seeking Sterritt&#8217;s extradition to the United States. fBot is itself a variation of the <strong>Mirai IoT botnet</strong> that has <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/krebsonsecurity-hit-with-record-ddos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ravaged the Internet with DDoS attacks</a> since <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/10/source-code-for-iot-botnet-mirai-released/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its source code was leaked back in 2016</a>.</p>
<p>The complaint says Foltz and his partner did not allow most customers to launch attacks that were more than 60 seconds in duration &#8212; another way they tried to keep public attention to the botnet at a minimum. However, the government says the proprietors also had special arrangements with certain high-paying clients that allowed much larger and longer attacks.</p>
<div id="attachment_71951" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71951" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71951" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbot-mad.png" alt="" width="750" height="610" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbot-mad.png 1046w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbot-mad-768x625.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbot-mad-782x636.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71951" class="wp-caption-text">The accused and his alleged partner made light of this blog post about the fallout from one of their botnet attacks.</p></div>
<p>Most people who have never been on the receiving end of a monster DDoS attack have no idea of the cost and disruption that such sieges can bring. The DCIS&#8217;s Peterson wrote that he was able to test the botnet&#8217;s capabilities while interviewing Foltz, and that found that &#8220;if this had been a server upon which I was running a website, using services such as load balancers, and paying for both outgoing and incoming data, at estimated industry average rates the attack (2+ Terabits per second times 30 seconds) might have cost the victim anywhere from $500 to $10,000.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;DDoS attacks at this scale often expose victims to devastating financial impact, and a potential alternative, network engineering solutions that mitigate the expected attacks such as overprovisioning, i.e. increasing potential Internet capacity, or DDoS defense technologies, can themselves be prohibitively expensive,&#8221; the complaint continues. &#8220;This &#8216;rock and a hard place&#8217; reality for many victims can leave them acutely exposed to extortion demands – &#8216;pay X dollars and the DDoS attacks stop&#8217;.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Telegram chat records show that the day before Peterson and other federal agents raided Foltz&#8217;s residence, Foltz allegedly told his partner he&#8217;d found 32,000 new devices that were vulnerable to a previously unknown exploit.</p>
<div id="attachment_71950" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71950" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71950" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbot-exploit.png" alt="" width="749" height="483" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbot-exploit.png 1255w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbot-exploit-768x495.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/rapperbot-exploit-782x504.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71950" class="wp-caption-text">Foltz and Slaykings discussing the discovery of an IoT vulnerability that will give them 32,000 new devices.</p></div>
<p>Shortly before the search warrant was served on his residence, Foltz allegedly told his partner that &#8220;Once again we have the biggest botnet in the community.&#8221; The following day, Foltz told his partner that it was going to be a great day &#8212; the biggest so far in terms of income generated by Rapper Bot.</p>
<p>&#8220;I sat next to Foltz while the messages poured in &#8212; promises of $800, then $1,000, the proceeds ticking up as the day went on,&#8221; Peterson wrote. &#8220;Noticing a change in Foltz&#8217; behavior and concerned that Foltz was making changes to the botnet configuration in real time, Slaykings asked him &#8216;What&#8217;s up?&#8217; Foltz deftly typed out some quick responses. Reassured by Foltz&#8217; answer, Slaykings responded, &#8216;Ok, I&#8217;m the paranoid one.&#8221;</p>
<p>The case is being prosecuted by <strong>Assistant U.S. Attorney Adam Alexander</strong> in the District of Alaska (at least some of the devices found to be infected with Rapper Bot were located there, and it is where Peterson is stationed). Foltz faces one count of aiding and abetting computer intrusions. If convicted, he faces a maximum penalty of 10 years in prison, although a federal judge is unlikely to award anywhere near that kind of sentence for a first-time conviction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/oregon-man-charged-in-rapper-bot-ddos-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mobile Phishers Target Brokerage Accounts in &#8216;Ramp and Dump&#8217; Cashout Scheme</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/mobile-phishers-target-brokerage-accounts-in-ramp-and-dump-cashout-scheme/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/mobile-phishers-target-brokerage-accounts-in-ramp-and-dump-cashout-scheme/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@chenlun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSIS Security Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Industry Regulatory Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FINRA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Merrill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outsider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pump-and-dump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramp and dump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schwab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SecAlliance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71895</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cybercriminal groups peddling sophisticated phishing kits that convert stolen card data into mobile wallets have recently shifted their focus to targeting customers of brokerage services, new research shows. Undeterred by security controls at these trading platforms that block users from wiring funds directly out of accounts, the phishers have pivoted to using multiple compromised brokerage accounts in unison to manipulate the prices of foreign stocks.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cybercriminal groups peddling sophisticated phishing kits that convert stolen card data into mobile wallets have recently shifted their focus to targeting customers of brokerage services, new research shows. Undeterred by security controls at these trading platforms that block users from wiring funds directly out of accounts, the phishers have pivoted to using multiple compromised brokerage accounts in unison to manipulate the prices of foreign stocks.</p>
<div id="attachment_71919" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71919" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71919" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/stockfall.png" alt="" width="750" height="315" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/stockfall.png 919w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/stockfall-768x323.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/stockfall-782x328.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71919" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, WhataWin.</p></div>
<p>This so-called &#8216;<strong>ramp and dump</strong>&#8216; scheme borrows its name from age-old &#8220;pump and dump&#8221; scams, wherein fraudsters purchase a large number of shares in some penny stock, and then promote the company in a frenzied social media blitz to build up interest from other investors. The fraudsters dump their shares after the price of the penny stock increases to some degree, which usually then causes a sharp drop in the value of the shares for legitimate investors.</p>
<p>With ramp and dump, the scammers do not need to rely on ginning up interest in the targeted stock on social media. Rather, they will preposition themselves in the stock that they wish to inflate, using compromised accounts to purchase large volumes of it and then dumping the shares after the stock price reaches a certain value. In February 2025, the <strong>FBI</strong> said it was <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/how-we-can-help-you/victim-services/seeking-victim-information/seeking-victim-information-in-ramp-and-dump-investment-fraud-investigation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seeking information from victims of this scheme</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;In this variation, the price manipulation is primarily the result of controlled trading activity conducted by the bad actors behind the scam,&#8221; reads <a href="https://www.finra.org/investors/insights/ramp-and-dump-schemes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an advisory</a> from the <strong>Financial Industry Regulatory Authority</strong> (FINRA), a private, non-profit organization that regulates member brokerage firms. &#8220;Ultimately, the outcome for unsuspecting investors is the same—a catastrophic collapse in share price that leaves investors with unrecoverable losses.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Ford Merrill </strong>is a security researcher at <a href="https://www.secalliance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SecAlliance</a>, a <a href="https://www.csis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSIS Security Group</a> company. Merrill said he has <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/dk/podcast/mnemonic-security-podcast/id1482626821?i=1000722355011" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tracked recent ramp-and-dump activity</a> to a bustling Chinese-language community that is quite openly selling advanced mobile phishing kits on Telegram.</p>
<p>&#8220;They will often coordinate with other actors and will wait until a certain time to buy a particular Chinese IPO [initial public offering] stock or penny stock,&#8221; said Merrill, who has been chronicling the rapid maturation and growth of the China-based phishing community over the past three years.</p>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;ll use all these victim brokerage accounts, and if needed they&#8217;ll liquidate the account&#8217;s current positions, and will preposition themselves in that instrument in some account they control, and then sell everything when the price goes up,&#8221; he said. &#8220;The victim will be left with worthless shares of that equity in their account, and the brokerage may not be happy either.&#8221;</p>
<p>Merrill said the early days of these phishing groups &#8212; between 2022 and 2024 &#8212; were typified by phishing kits that used text messages to spoof the <strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong> or some local toll road operator, warning about a delinquent shipping or toll fee that needed paying. Recipients who clicked the link and provided their payment information at a fake USPS or toll operator site were then asked to verify the transaction by sharing a one-time code sent via text message.</p>
<p>In reality, the victim&#8217;s bank is sending that code to the mobile number on file for their customer because the fraudsters have just attempted to enroll that victim’s card details into a mobile wallet. If the visitor supplies that one-time code, their payment card is then added to a new mobile wallet on an Apple or Google device that is physically controlled by the phishers.</p>
<p>The phishing gangs typically load multiple stolen cards to digital wallets on a single Apple or Android device, and then sell those phones in bulk to scammers who <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/arrests-in-tap-to-pay-scheme-powered-by-phishing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">use them for fraudulent e-commerce and tap-to-pay transactions</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_70436" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70436" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70436" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png" alt="" width="750" height="567" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png 1160w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-768x581.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-782x591.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70436" class="wp-caption-text">An image from the Telegram channel for a popular Chinese mobile phishing kit vendor shows 10 mobile phones for sale, each loaded with 4-6 digital wallets from different financial institutions.</p></div>
<p>This China-based phishing collective exposed a major weakness common to many U.S.-based financial institutions that already require multi-factor authentication: The reliance on a single, phishable one-time token for provisioning mobile wallets. Happily, Merrill said many financial institutions that were caught flat-footed on this scam two years ago have since strengthened authentication requirements for onboarding new mobile wallets (such as requiring the card to be enrolled via the bank&#8217;s mobile app).</p>
<p>But just as squeezing one part of a balloon merely forces the air trapped inside to bulge into another area, fraudsters don&#8217;t go away when you make their current enterprise less profitable: They just shift their focus to a less-guarded area. And lately, that gaze has settled squarely on customers of the major brokerage platforms, Merrill said.</p>
<h2>THE OUTSIDER</h2>
<p>Merrill pointed to several Telegram channels operated by some of the more accomplished phishing kit sellers, which are full of videos demonstrating how every feature in their kits can be tailored to the attacker&#8217;s target. The video snippet below comes from the Telegram channel of &#8220;<strong>Outsider</strong>,&#8221; a popular Mandarin-speaking phishing kit vendor whose latest offering includes a number of ready-made templates for using text messages to phish brokerage account credentials and one-time codes.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nuL84VeT6BY?si=C0uWiR7QMH-LNtp_" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></div>
<p>According to Merrill, Outsider is a woman who previously went by the handle &#8220;<strong>Chenlun</strong>.&#8221; KrebsOnSecurity profiled Chenlun&#8217;s phishing empire in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/10/phishers-spoof-usps-12-other-natl-postal-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an October 2023 story</a> about a China-based group that was phishing mobile customers of more than a dozen postal services around the globe. In that case, the phishing sites were using a Telegram bot that sent stolen credentials to the &#8220;@chenlun&#8221; Telegram account.</p>
<p>Chenlun&#8217;s phishing lures are sent via Apple&#8217;s iMessage and Google&#8217;s RCS service and spoof one of the major brokerage platforms, warning that the account has been suspended for suspicious activity and that recipients should log in and verify some information. The missives include a link to a phishing page that collects the customer&#8217;s username and password, and then asks the user to enter a one-time code that will arrive via SMS.</p>
<p>The new phish kit videos on Outsider&#8217;s Telegram channel only feature templates for Schwab customers, but Merrill said the kit can easily be adapted to target other brokerage platforms. One reason the fraudsters are picking on brokerage firms, he said, has to do with the way they <a href="https://www.schwab.com/resource/how-to-set-up-two-factor-authentication" target="_blank" rel="noopener">handle multi-factor authentication</a>.<span id="more-71895"></span></p>
<p>Schwab clients are presented with two options for second factor authentication when they open an account. Users who select the option to only prompt for a code on untrusted devices can choose to receive it via text message, an automated inbound phone call, or an outbound call to Schwab. With the &#8220;always at login&#8221; option selected, users can choose to receive the code through the Schwab app, a text message, or a Symantec VIP mobile app.</p>
<p>In response to questions, Schwab said it regularly updates clients on emerging fraud trends, including this specific type, which the company addressed in communications sent to clients earlier this year.</p>
<div id="attachment_71940" style="width: 606px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71940" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71940" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/schwab-text.png" alt="" width="596" height="600" /><p id="caption-attachment-71940" class="wp-caption-text">The 2FA text message from Schwab warns recipients against giving away their one-time code.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;That message focused on trading-related fraud, highlighting both account intrusions and scams conducted through social media or messaging apps that deceive individuals into executing trades themselves,&#8221; Schwab said in a written statement. &#8220;We are aware and tracking this trend across several channels, as well as others like it, which attempt to exploit SMS-based verification with stolen credentials. We actively monitor for suspicious patterns and take steps to disrupt them. This activity is part of a broader, industry-wide threat, and we take a multi-layered approach to address and mitigate it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Other popular brokerage platforms allow similar methods for multi-factor authentication. <strong>Fidelity</strong> requires a username and password on initial login, and offers the ability to receive a one-time token via SMS, an automated phone call, or by approving a push notification sent through the Fidelity mobile app. However, all three of these methods for sending one-time tokens are phishable; even with the brokerage firm&#8217;s app, the phishers could prompt the user to approve a login request that they initiated in the app with the phished credentials.</p>
<p>Vanguard offers customers a range of multi-factor authentication choices, including the option to require <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/07/google-security-keys-neutralized-employee-phishing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a physical security key</a> in addition to one&#8217;s credentials on each login. A security key implements a robust form of multi-factor authentication known as <strong>Universal 2nd Factor (U2F)</strong>, which allows the user to complete the login process simply by connecting an enrolled USB or Bluetooth device and pressing a button. The key works without the need for any special software drivers, and the nice thing about it is your second factor cannot be phished.</p>
<h2>THE PERFECT CRIME?</h2>
<p>Merrill said that in many ways the ramp-and-dump scheme is the perfect crime because it leaves precious few connections between the victim brokerage accounts and the fraudsters.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s really genius because it decouples so many things,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They can buy shares [in the stock to be pumped] in their personal account on the Chinese exchanges, and the price happens to go up. The Chinese or Hong Kong brokerages aren&#8217;t going to see anything funky.&#8221;</p>
<p>Merrill said it&#8217;s unclear exactly how those perpetrating these ramp-and-dump schemes coordinate their activities, such as whether the accounts are phished well in advance or shortly before being used to inflate the stock price of Chinese companies. The latter possibility would fit nicely with the existing human infrastructure these criminal groups already have in place.</p>
<p>For example, KrebsOnSecurity recently wrote about research from Merrill and other researchers showing the phishers behind these slick mobile phishing kits <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">employed people to sit for hours at a time</a> in front of large banks of mobile phones being used to send the text message lures. These technicians were needed to respond in real time to victims who were supplying the one-time code sent from their financial institution.</p>
<div id="attachment_70435" style="width: 528px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70435" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70435" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phonesashtray.png" alt="" width="518" height="688" /><p id="caption-attachment-70435" class="wp-caption-text">The ashtray says: You&#8217;ve been phishing all night.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;You can get access to a victim&#8217;s brokerage with a one-time passcode, but then you sort of have to use it right away if you can&#8217;t set new security settings so you can come back to that account later,&#8221; Merrill said.</p>
<p>The rapid pace of innovations produced by these China-based phishing vendors is due in part to their use of artificial intelligence and large language models to help develop the mobile phishing kits, he added.</p>
<p>&#8220;These guys are vibe coding stuff together and using LLMs to translate things or help put the user interface together,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;It&#8217;s only a matter of time before they start to integrate the LLMs into their development cycle to make it more rapid. The technologies they are building definitely have helped lower the barrier of entry for everyone.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/mobile-phishers-target-brokerage-accounts-in-ramp-and-dump-cashout-scheme/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Patch Tuesday, August 2025 Edition</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/microsoft-patch-tuesday-august-2025-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/microsoft-patch-tuesday-august-2025-edition/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 22:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Akamai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BadSuccessor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben McCarthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-50165]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53733]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53766]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53778]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53779]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Server 2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Server 2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange Server Subscription Edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immersive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Exchange Server]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Office 365]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sans internet storm center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows GDI+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yuval Gordon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today released updates to fix more than 100 security flaws in its Windows operating systems and other software. At least 13 of the bugs received Microsoft's most-dire "critical" rating, meaning they could be abused by malware or malcontents to gain remote access to a Windows system with little or no help from users.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today released updates to fix more than 100 security flaws in its <strong>Windows</strong> operating systems and other software. At least 13 of the bugs received Microsoft&#8217;s most-dire &#8220;critical&#8221; rating, meaning they could be abused by malware or malcontents to gain remote access to a Windows system with little or no help from users.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-56287" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png" alt="" width="750" height="528" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png 841w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-768x541.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-782x550.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>August&#8217;s patch batch from Redmond includes an update for <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-53786" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53786</a>, a vulnerability that allows an attacker to pivot from a compromised <strong>Microsoft Exchange Server</strong> directly into an organization&#8217;s cloud environment, potentially gaining control over <strong>Exchange Online</strong> and other connected <strong>Microsoft Office 365</strong> services. Microsoft first warned about this bug on Aug. 6, saying it affects <strong>Exchange Server 2016</strong> and <strong>Exchange Server 2019</strong>, as well as its flagship <strong>Exchange Server Subscription Edition</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Ben McCarthy</strong>, lead cyber security engineer at <strong>Immersive</strong>, said a rough search reveals approximately 29,000 Exchange servers publicly facing on the internet that are vulnerable to this issue, with many of them likely to have even older vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>McCarthy said the fix for CVE-2025-53786 requires more than just installing a patch, such as following Microsoft&#8217;s manual instructions for creating a dedicated service to oversee and lock down the hybrid connection.</p>
<p>&#8220;In effect, this vulnerability turns a significant on-premise Exchange breach into a full-blown, difficult-to-detect cloud compromise with effectively living off the land techniques which are always harder to detect for defensive teams,&#8221; McCarthy said.</p>
<p><a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-53779" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53779</a> is a weakness in the <strong>Windows Kerberos</strong> authentication system that allows an unauthenticated attacker to gain domain administrator privileges. Microsoft credits the discovery of the flaw to Akamai researcher <strong>Yuval Gordon</strong>, who dubbed it &#8220;<strong>BadSuccessor</strong>&#8221; in <a href="https://www.akamai.com/blog/security-research/abusing-dmsa-for-privilege-escalation-in-active-directory" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a May 2025 blog post</a>. The attack exploits a weakness in &#8220;delegated Managed Service Account&#8221; or dMSA &#8212; a feature that was introduced in <strong>Windows Server 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>Some of the critical flaws addressed this month with the highest severity (between 9.0 and 9.9 CVSS scores) include a remote code execution bug in the <strong>Windows GDI+</strong> component that handles graphics rendering (<a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-53766" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53766</a>) and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-50165" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-50165</a>, another graphics rendering weakness. Another critical patch involves <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-53733" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53733</a>, a vulnerability in <strong>Microsoft Word</strong> that can be exploited without user interaction and triggered through the Preview Pane.<span id="more-71899"></span></p>
<p>One final critical bug tackled this month deserves attention: <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-53778" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53778</a>, a bug in <strong>Windows NTLM</strong>, a core function of how Windows systems handle network authentication. According to Microsoft, the flaw could allow an attacker with low-level network access and basic user privileges to exploit NTLM and elevate to SYSTEM-level access — the highest level of privilege in Windows. Microsoft rates the exploitation of this bug as &#8220;more likely,&#8221; although there is no evidence the vulnerability is being exploited at the moment.</p>
<p>Feel free to holler in the comments if you experience problems installing any of these updates. As ever, the <strong>SANS Internet Storm Center</strong> has its <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/diary/Microsoft%20August%202025%20Patch%20Tuesday/32192" target="_blank" rel="noopener">useful breakdown</a> of the Microsoft patches indexed by severity and CVSS score, and <a href="https://www.askwoody.com/2025/august-2025-security-updates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AskWoody.com</a> is keeping an eye out for Windows patches that may cause problems for enterprises and end users.</p>
<h2>GOOD MIGRATIONS</h2>
<p>Windows 10 users out there likely have noticed by now that Microsoft really wants you to upgrade to Windows 11. The reason is that after the Patch Tuesday on October 14, 2025, Microsoft will stop shipping free security updates for <strong>Windows 10</strong> computers. The trouble is, many PCs running Windows 10 do not meet the hardware specifications required to install <strong>Windows 11 </strong>(or they do, but just barely).</p>
<p>If the experience with Windows XP is any indicator, many of these older computers will wind up in landfills or else will be left running in an unpatched state. But if your Windows 10 PC doesn&#8217;t have the hardware chops to run Windows 11 and you&#8217;d still like to get some use out of it safely, consider installing a newbie-friendly version of Linux, like <strong>Linux Mint</strong>.</p>
<p>Like most modern Linux versions, Mint will run on anything with a 64-bit CPU that has at least 2GB of memory, although 4GB is recommended. In other words, it will run on almost any computer produced in the last decade.</p>
<p>There are many versions of Linux available, but Linux Mint is likely to be the most intuitive interface for regular Windows users, and it is largely configurable without any fuss at the text-only command-line prompt. Mint and other flavors of Linux come with <strong>LibreOffice</strong>, which is an open source suite of tools that includes applications similar to Microsoft Office, and it can open, edit and save documents as Microsoft Office files.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;d prefer to give Linux a test drive before installing it on a Windows PC, you can always just download it to a removable USB drive. From there, reboot the computer (with the removable drive plugged in) and select the option at startup to run the operating system from the external USB drive. If you don&#8217;t see an option for that after restarting, try restarting again and hitting the F8 button, which should open a list of bootable drives. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_qZI6i21jB4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Here&#8217;s a fairly thorough tutorial</a> that walks through exactly how to do all this.</p>
<p>And if this is your first time trying out Linux, relax and have fun: The nice thing about a &#8220;live&#8221; version of Linux (as it&#8217;s called when the operating system is run from a removable drive such as a CD or a USB stick) is that none of your changes persist after a reboot. Even if you somehow manage to break something, a restart will return the system back to its original state.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/microsoft-patch-tuesday-august-2025-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>KrebsOnSecurity in New &#8216;Most Wanted&#8217; HBO Max Series</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/krebsonsecurity-in-new-most-wanted-hbo-max-series/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/krebsonsecurity-in-new-most-wanted-hbo-max-series/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 21:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Smedley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joni Soila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julius Kivimäki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lizard Squad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sami Kieski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony Playstation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vastaamo Psychotherapy Center]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new documentary series about cybercrime airing next month on HBO Max features interviews with Yours Truly. The four-part series follows the exploits of Julius Kivimäki, a prolific Finnish hacker recently convicted of leaking tens of thousands of patient records from an online psychotherapy practice while attempting to extort the clinic and its patients.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new documentary series about cybercrime airing next month on <strong>HBO Max</strong> features interviews with Yours Truly. The four-part series follows the exploits of <strong>Julius Kivimäki</strong>, a prolific Finnish hacker recently convicted of leaking tens of thousands of patient records from an online psychotherapy practice while attempting to extort the clinic and its patients.</p>
<p>The documentary, &#8220;<em>Most Wanted: Teen Hacker</em>,&#8221; explores the 27-year-old Kivimäki&#8217;s lengthy and increasingly destructive career, one that was marked by cyber attacks designed to result in real-world physical impacts on their targets.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p0CHYMtORb0?si=LQip-niqEaMZXZM3" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>By the age of 14, Kivimäki had fallen in with a group of criminal hackers who were <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2014/03/the-long-tail-of-coldfusion-fail/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mass-compromising websites and milking them for customer payment card data</a>. Kivimäki and his friends enjoyed harassing and terrorizing others by &#8220;swatting&#8221; their homes &#8212; calling in fake hostage situations or bomb threats at a target&#8217;s address in the hopes of triggering a heavily-armed police response to that location.</p>
<p>On Dec. 26, 2014, Kivimäki and fellow members of a group of online hooligans calling themselves the <strong>Lizard Squad</strong> <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2014/12/cowards-attack-sony-playstation-microsoft-xbox-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launched a massive distributed denial-of-service</a> (DDoS) attack against the <strong>Sony Playstation</strong> and <strong>Microsoft Xbox Live</strong> platforms, preventing millions of users from playing with their shiny new gaming rigs the day after Christmas. The Lizard Squad later acknowledged that the stunt was planned to call attention to their new DDoS-for-hire service, which came online and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/01/lizard-stresser-runs-on-hacked-home-routers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">started selling subscriptions</a> shortly after the attack.</p>
<p>Finnish investigators said Kivimäki also was responsible for a 2014 bomb threat against former <strong>Sony Online Entertainment President</strong> <strong>John Smedley</strong> that <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/insertcoin/2014/08/24/sony-online-entertainment-presidents-flight-diverted-by-psn-hackers-bomb-threat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">grounded an American Airlines plane</a>. That incident was widely reported to have started with a Twitter post from the Lizard Squad, after Smedley mentioned some upcoming travel plans online. But according to Smedley and Finnish investigators, the bomb threat started with a phone call from Kivimäki.</p>
<div id="attachment_29338" style="width: 466px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-29338" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-29338" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/ryan-k-285x270.png" alt="" width="456" height="432" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/ryan-k-285x270.png 285w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/ryan-k.png 368w" sizes="(max-width: 456px) 100vw, 456px" /><p id="caption-attachment-29338" class="wp-caption-text">Julius &#8220;Zeekill&#8221; Kivimaki, in December 2014.</p></div>
<p>The creaky wheels of justice seemed to be catching up with Kivimäki in mid-2015, when a Finnish court found him guilty of more than 50,000 cybercrimes, including data breaches, payment fraud, and operating a global botnet of hacked computers. Unfortunately, the defendant was 17 at the time, and received little more than a slap on the wrist: A two-year suspended sentence and a small fine.<span id="more-71873"></span></p>
<p>Kivimäki immediately bragged online about the lenient sentencing, posting on Twitter that he was an &#8220;untouchable hacker god.&#8221; I wrote a column in 2015 <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/07/finnish-decision-is-win-for-internet-trolls/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lamenting his laughable punishment</a> because it was clear even then that this was a person who enjoyed watching other people suffer, and who seemed utterly incapable of remorse about any of it. It was also abundantly clear to everyone who investigated his crimes that he wasn&#8217;t going to quit unless someone made him stop.</p>
<p>In response to some of my early reporting that mentioned Kivimäki, one reader shared that they had been dealing with non-stop harassment and abuse from Kivimäki for years, including swatting incidents, unwanted deliveries and subscriptions, emails to her friends and co-workers, as well as threatening phonecalls and texts at all hours of the night. The reader, who spoke on condition of anonymity, shared that Kivimäki at one point confided that he had no reason whatsoever for harassing her &#8212; that she was picked at random and that it was just something he did for laughs.</p>
<p>Five years after Kivimäki&#8217;s conviction, the <strong>Vastaamo Psychotherapy Center</strong> in Finland became the target of blackmail when a tormentor identified as “ransom_man” demanded payment of 40 bitcoins (~450,000 euros at the time) in return for a promise not to publish highly sensitive therapy session notes Vastaamo had exposed online.</p>
<p>Ransom_man, a.k.a. Kivimäki, announced on the dark web that he would start publishing 100 patient profiles every 24 hours. When Vastaamo declined to pay, ransom_man shifted to extorting individual patients. According to Finnish police, some 22,000 victims reported extortion attempts targeting them personally, targeted emails that threatened to publish their therapy notes online unless paid a 500 euro ransom.</p>
<p>In October 2022, Finnish authorities charged Kivimäki with extorting Vastaamo and its patients. But by that time he was on the run from the law and living it up across Europe, spending lavishly on fancy cars, apartments and a hard-partying lifestyle.</p>
<p>In February 2023, Kivimäki was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/02/finlands-most-wanted-hacker-nabbed-in-france/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested in France</a> after authorities there responded to a domestic disturbance call and found the defendant sleeping off a hangover on the couch of a woman he’d met the night before. The French police grew suspicious when the 6′ 3″ blonde, green-eyed man presented an ID that stated he was of Romanian nationality.</p>
<div id="attachment_65661" style="width: 505px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-65661" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-65661" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/kivimaki-romainianid.png" alt="" width="495" height="338" /><p id="caption-attachment-65661" class="wp-caption-text">A redacted copy of an ID Kivimaki gave to French authorities claiming he was from Romania.</p></div>
<p>In April 2024, Kivimäki was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/04/man-who-mass-extorted-psychotherapy-patients-gets-six-years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sentenced to more than six years in prison</a> after being convicted of extorting Vastaamo and its patients.</p>
<p>The documentary is directed by the award-winning Finnish producer and director <a href="https://fi.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sami_Kieksi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sami Kieski</a> and co-written by <strong>Joni Soila</strong>. According to an August 6 press release, the four 43-minute episodes will drop weekly on Fridays throughout September across Europe, the U.S, Latin America, Australia and South-East Asia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/krebsonsecurity-in-new-most-wanted-hbo-max-series/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Got Arrested in the Raid on the XSS Crime Forum?</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/who-got-arrested-in-the-raid-on-the-xss-crime-forum/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/who-got-arrested-in-the-raid-on-the-xss-crime-forum/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9588693]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anton Gannadievich Medvedovskiy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anton Viktorovich Avdeev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Constella Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DaMaGeLaB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DomainTools.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploit.in]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flycracker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hack-All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel 471]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LockBit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LockBitSupp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[N0klos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paranoidlab.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qiliin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rEvil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SBU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sergeii Vovnenko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sonic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toschka2003@yandex.ru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xss[.]is]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 22, 2025, the European police agency Europol said a long-running investigation led by the French Police resulted in the arrest of a 38-year-old administrator of XSS, a Russian-language cybercrime forum with more than 50,000 members. The action has triggered an ongoing frenzy of speculation and panic among XSS denizens about the identity of the unnamed suspect, but the consensus is that he is a pivotal figure in the crime forum scene who goes by the hacker handle "Toha." Here's a deep dive on what's knowable about Toha, and a short stab at who got nabbed.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On July 22, 2025, the European police agency <strong>Europol</strong> <a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/key-figure-behind-major-russian-speaking-cybercrime-forum-targeted-in-ukraine" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> a long-running investigation led by the French Police resulted in the arrest of a 38-year-old administrator of <b>XSS,</b> a Russian-language cybercrime forum with more than 50,000 members. The action has triggered an ongoing frenzy of speculation and panic among XSS denizens about the identity of the unnamed suspect, but the consensus is that he is a pivotal figure in the crime forum scene who goes by the hacker handle &#8220;<strong>Toha</strong>.&#8221; Here&#8217;s a deep dive on what&#8217;s knowable about Toha, and a short stab at who got nabbed.</p>
<div id="attachment_71827" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71827" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71827" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/xss-sbu.png" alt="" width="749" height="499" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/xss-sbu.png 851w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/xss-sbu-768x512.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/xss-sbu-782x521.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71827" class="wp-caption-text">An unnamed 38-year-old man was arrested in Kiev last month on suspicion of administering the cybercrime forum XSS. Image: ssu.gov.ua.</p></div>
<p>Europol did not name the accused, but published partially obscured photos of him from the raid on his residence in Kiev. The police agency said the suspect acted as a trusted third party &#8212; arbitrating disputes between criminals &#8212; and guaranteeing the security of transactions on XSS. A <a href="https://ssu.gov.ua/novyny/sbu-spilno-z-natspolitsiieiu-ta-pravookhorontsiamy-frantsii-vykryla-rozrobnyka-odniiei-z-naividomishykh-u-sviti-khakerskykh-platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> from Ukraine&#8217;s <strong>SBU</strong> security service said XSS counted among its members many cybercriminals from various ransomware groups, including <strong>REvil</strong>, <strong>LockBit</strong>, <strong>Conti</strong>, and <strong>Qiliin</strong>.</p>
<p>Since the Europol announcement, the XSS forum resurfaced at a new address on the deep web (reachable only via the anonymity network <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tor_(network)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tor</a>). But from reviewing the recent posts, there appears to be little consensus among longtime members about the identity of the now-detained XSS administrator.</p>
<p>The most frequent comment regarding the arrest was a message of solidarity and support for Toha, the handle chosen by the longtime administrator of XSS and several other major Russian forums. Toha&#8217;s accounts on other forums have been silent since the raid.</p>
<p>Europol said the suspect has enjoyed a nearly 20-year career in cybercrime, which roughly lines up with Toha&#8217;s history. In 2005, Toha was a founding member of the Russian-speaking forum <strong>Hack-All. </strong>That is, until it got massively hacked a few months after its debut. In 2006, Toha rebranded the forum to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/exploit-in/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>exploit[.]in</strong></a>, which would go on to draw tens of thousands of members, including an eventual Who&#8217;s-Who of wanted cybercriminals.</p>
<p>Toha announced in 2018 that he was selling the Exploit forum, prompting rampant speculation on the forums that the buyer was secretly a Russian or Ukrainian government entity or front person. However, those suspicions were unsupported by evidence, and Toha vehemently denied the forum had been given over to authorities.</p>
<p>One of the oldest Russian-language cybercrime forums was <strong>DaMaGeLaB</strong>, which operated from 2004 to 2017, when its administrator &#8220;Ar3s&#8221; was arrested. In 2018, a partial backup of the DaMaGeLaB forum was <a href="https://www.own.security/en/ressources/blog/russian-language-cybercriminal-forums---chapter-iii-analyzing-the-most-active-and-renowned-communities-english-only" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reincarnated as xss[.]is</a>, with Toha as its stated administrator.</p>
<h2>CROSS-SITE GRIFTING</h2>
<p>Clues about Toha&#8217;s early presence on the Internet &#8212; from ~2004 to 2010 &#8212; are available in the archives of <strong>Intel 471</strong>, a cyber intelligence firm that tracks forum activity. Intel 471 shows Toha used the same email address across multiple forum accounts, including at Exploit, <strong>Antichat</strong>, <strong>Carder[.]su</strong> and <strong>inattack[.]ru.</strong></p>
<p><strong>DomainTools.com</strong> finds Toha&#8217;s email address &#8212; <strong>toschka2003@yandex.ru</strong> &#8212; was used to register at least a dozen domain names &#8212; most of them from the mid- to late 2000s. Apart from exploit[.]in and a domain called <strong>ixyq[.]com</strong>, the other domains registered to that email address end in .ua, the top-level domain for Ukraine (e.g. deleted.org[.]ua, lj.com[.]ua, and blogspot.org[.]ua).</p>
<div id="attachment_71853" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71853" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71853" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/exploit-deleted-ua.png" alt="" width="749" height="702" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/exploit-deleted-ua.png 924w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/exploit-deleted-ua-768x721.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/exploit-deleted-ua-782x734.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71853" class="wp-caption-text">A 2008 snapshot of a domain registered to toschka2003@yandex.ru and to Anton Medvedovsky in Kiev. Note the message at the bottom left, &#8220;Protected by Exploit,in.&#8221; Image: archive.org.</p></div>
<p>Nearly all of the domains registered to toschka2003@yandex.ru contain the name <strong>Anton Medvedovskiy</strong> in the registration records, except for the aforementioned ixyq[.]com, which is registered to the name <strong>Yuriy Avdeev</strong> in Moscow.</p>
<p>This Avdeev surname came up in a lengthy conversation with <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/u-s-charges-russian-man-as-boss-of-lockbit-ransomware-group/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lockbitsupp</a>, the leader of the rapacious and destructive ransomware affiliate group <strong>Lockbit</strong>. The conversation took place in February 2024, when Lockbitsupp asked for help identifying Toha&#8217;s real-life identity.</p>
<div id="attachment_71822" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71822" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71822" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/lcokbitsupp-convo.png" alt="" width="749" height="938" /><p id="caption-attachment-71822" class="wp-caption-text">In early 2024, the leader of the Lockbit ransomware group &#8212; Lockbitsupp &#8212; asked for help investigating the identity of the XSS administrator Toha, which he claimed was a Russian man named Anton Avdeev.</p></div>
<p>Lockbitsupp didn&#8217;t share why he wanted Toha&#8217;s details, but he maintained that Toha&#8217;s real name was <strong>Anton Avdeev</strong>. I declined to help Lockbitsupp in whatever revenge he was planning on Toha, but his question made me curious to look deeper.<span id="more-71819"></span></p>
<p>It appears Lockbitsupp&#8217;s query was based on a now-deleted Twitter post from 2022, when a user by the name &#8220;<a href="https://x.com/3xp0rtblog/status/1585357689777164288" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3xp0rt</a>&#8221; asserted that Toha was a Russian man named <strong>Anton Viktorovich Avdeev</strong>, born October 27, 1983.</p>
<p>Searching the web for Toha&#8217;s email address toschka2003@yandex.ru reveals <a href="https://www.bmwclub.ru/threads/bmw-x5-e70.398405/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2010 sales thread</a> on the forum <strong>bmwclub.ru</strong> where a user named Honeypo was selling a 2007 BMW X5. The ad listed the contact person as Anton Avdeev and gave the contact phone number <strong>9588693.</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-71824" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bmw-toha.png" alt="" width="878" height="888" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bmw-toha.png 878w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bmw-toha-768x777.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/bmw-toha-782x791.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px" /></p>
<p>A search on the phone number 9588693 in the breach tracking service <strong>Constella Intelligence</strong> finds plenty of official Russian government records with this number, date of birth and the name Anton Viktorovich Avdeev. For example, hacked Russian government records show this person has a Russian tax ID and SIN (Social Security number), and that they were flagged for traffic violations on several occasions by Moscow police; in 2004, 2006, 2009, and 2014.</p>
<p>Astute readers may have noticed by now that the ages of Mr. Avdeev (41) and the XSS admin arrested this month (38) are a bit off. This would seem to suggest that the person arrested is someone other than Mr. Avdeev, who did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<h2>A FLY ON THE WALL</h2>
<p>For further insight on this question, KrebsOnSecurity sought comments from <strong>Sergeii Vovnenko</strong>, a former cybercriminal from Ukraine who now works at the security startup <strong>paranoidlab.com</strong>. I reached out to Vovnenko because for several years beginning around 2010 he was the owner and operator of <strong>thesecure[.]biz</strong>, an encrypted &#8220;Jabber&#8221; instant messaging server that Europol said was operated by the suspect arrested in Kiev. Thesecure[.]biz grew quite popular among many of the top Russian-speaking cybercriminals because it scrupulously kept few records of its users&#8217; activity, and its administrator was always a trusted member of the community.</p>
<p>The reason I know this historic tidbit is that in 2013, Vovnenko &#8212; using the hacker nicknames &#8220;<strong>Fly</strong>,&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Flycracker</strong>&#8221; &#8212; <a href="http://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/07/mail-from-the-velvet-cybercrime-underground/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hatched a plan</a> to have a gram of heroin purchased off of the Silk Road darknet market and shipped to our home in Northern Virginia. The scheme was to spoof a call from one of our neighbors to the local police, saying this guy Krebs down the street was a druggie who was having narcotics delivered to his home.</p>
<p>I happened to be lurking on Flycracker&#8217;s private cybercrime forum when his heroin-framing plan was carried out, and called the police myself before the smack eventually arrived in the U.S. Mail. Vovnenko was later <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2014/06/the-fly-has-been-swatted/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested</a> for unrelated cybercrime activities, extradited to the United States, convicted, and deported after a 16-month stay in the U.S. prison system [on several occasions, he has expressed heartfelt apologies for the incident, and we have since buried the hatchet].</p>
<p>Vovnenko said he purchased a device for cloning credit cards from Toha in 2009, and that Toha shipped the item from Russia. Vovnenko explained that he (Flycracker) was the owner and operator of thesecure[.]biz from 2010 until his arrest in 2014.</p>
<p>Vovnenko believes thesecure[.]biz was stolen while he was in jail, either by Toha and/or an XSS administrator who went by the nicknames <strong>N0klos</strong> and <strong>Sonic</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;When I was in jail, [the] admin of xss.is stole that domain, or probably N0klos bought XSS from Toha or vice versa,&#8221; Vovnenko said of the Jabber domain. &#8220;Nobody from [the forums] spoke with me after my jailtime, so I can only guess what really happened.&#8221;</p>
<p>N0klos was the owner and administrator of an early Russian-language cybercrime forum known as <strong>Darklife[.]ws</strong>. However, N0kl0s also appears to be a lifelong Russian resident, and in any case seems to have vanished from Russian cybercrime forums several years ago.</p>
<p>Asked whether he believes Toha was the XSS administrator who was arrested this month in Ukraine, Vovnenko maintained that Toha is Russian, and that &#8220;the French cops took the wrong guy.&#8221;</p>
<h2>WHO IS TOHA?</h2>
<p>So who did the Ukrainian police arrest in response to the investigation by the French authorities? It seems plausible that the BMW ad invoking Toha&#8217;s email address and the name and phone number of a Russian citizen was simply misdirection on Toha&#8217;s part &#8212; intended to confuse and throw off investigators. Perhaps this even explains the Avdeev surname surfacing in the registration records from one of Toha&#8217;s domains.</p>
<p>But sometimes the simplest answer is the correct one. &#8220;Toha&#8221; is a common Slavic nickname for someone with the first name &#8220;Anton,&#8221; and that matches the name in the registration records for more than a dozen domains tied to Toha&#8217;s toschka2003@yandex.ru email address: Anton Medvedovskiy.</p>
<p>Constella Intelligence finds there is an <strong>Anton Gannadievich Medvedovskiy</strong> living in Kiev who will be 38 years old in December. This individual owns the email address <strong>itsmail@i.ua</strong>, as well an <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/users/show/27040702" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an Airbnb account</a> featuring a profile photo of a man with roughly the same hairline as the suspect in the blurred photos released by the Ukrainian police. Mr. Medvedovskiy did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p>My take on the takedown is that the Ukrainian authorities likely arrested Medvedovskiy. Toha shared on DaMaGeLab in 2005 that he had recently finished the 11th grade and was studying at a university &#8212; a time when Mevedovskiy would have been around 18 years old. On Dec. 11, 2006, fellow Exploit members wished Toha a happy birthday. Records exposed in a 2022 hack at the Ukrainian public services portal diia.gov.ua show that Mr. Medvedovskiy&#8217;s birthday is Dec. 11, 1987.</p>
<p>The law enforcement action and resulting confusion about the identity of the detained has thrown the Russian cybercrime forum scene into disarray in recent weeks, with lengthy and heated arguments about XSS&#8217;s future spooling out across the forums.</p>
<p>XSS relaunched on a new Tor address shortly after the authorities plastered their seizure notice on the forum&#8217;s  homepage, but all of the trusted moderators from the old forum were dismissed without explanation. Existing members saw their forum account balances drop to zero, and were asked to plunk down a deposit to register at the new forum. The new XSS &#8220;admin&#8221; said they were in contact with the previous owners and that the changes were to help rebuild security and trust within the community.</p>
<p>However, the new admin&#8217;s assurances appear to have done little to assuage the worst fears of the forum&#8217;s erstwhile members, most of whom seem to be keeping their distance from the relaunched site for now.</p>
<p>Indeed, if there is one common understanding amid all of these discussions about the seizure of XSS, it is that Ukrainian and French authorities now have several years worth of private messages between XSS forum users, as well as contact rosters and other user data linked to the seized Jabber server.</p>
<p>&#8220;The myth of the &#8216;trusted person&#8217; is shattered,&#8221; the user &#8220;GordonBellford&#8221; cautioned on Aug. 3 in an Exploit forum thread about the XSS admin arrest. &#8220;The forum is run by strangers. They got everything. Two years of Jabber server logs. Full backup and forum database.&#8221;</p>
<p>GordonBellford continued:</p>
<blockquote><p>And the scariest thing is: this data array is not just an archive. It is material for analysis that has ALREADY BEEN DONE . With the help of modern tools, they see everything:</p>
<p>Graphs of your contacts and activity.<br />
Relationships between nicknames, emails, password hashes and Jabber ID.<br />
Timestamps, IP addresses and digital fingerprints.<br />
Your unique writing style, phraseology, punctuation, consistency of grammatical errors, and even typical typos that will link your accounts on different platforms.</p>
<p>They are not looking for a needle in a haystack. They simply sifted the haystack through the AI sieve and got ready-made dossiers.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/08/who-got-arrested-in-the-raid-on-the-xss-crime-forum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scammers Unleash Flood of Slick Online Gaming Sites</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/scammers-unleash-flood-of-slick-online-gaming-sites/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/scammers-unleash-flood-of-slick-online-gaming-sites/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 18:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B-Ball Blitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beast Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mr. Beast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scambling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thereallo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fraudsters are flooding Discord and other social media platforms with ads for hundreds of polished online gaming and wagering websites that lure people with free credits and eventually abscond with any cryptocurrency funds deposited by players. Here's a closer look at the social engineering tactics and remarkable traits of this sprawling network of more than 1,200 scam sites.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fraudsters are flooding Discord and other social media platforms with ads for hundreds of polished online gaming and wagering websites that lure people with free credits and eventually abscond with any cryptocurrency funds deposited by players. Here&#8217;s a closer look at the social engineering tactics and remarkable traits of this sprawling network of more than 1,200 scam sites.</p>
<p>The scam begins with deceptive ads posted on social media that claim the wagering sites are working in partnership with popular social media personalities, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MrBeast" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mr. Beast</a>, who recently launched a gaming business called <strong>Beast Games</strong>. The ads invariably state that by using a supplied &#8220;promo code,&#8221; interested players can claim a $2,500 credit on the advertised gaming website.</p>
<div id="attachment_71798" style="width: 734px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71798" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-71798" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/reddit-gambwex.png" alt="" width="724" height="750" /><p id="caption-attachment-71798" class="wp-caption-text">An ad posted to a Discord channel for a scam gambling website that the proprietors falsely claim was operating in collaboration with the Internet personality Mr. Beast. Image: Reddit.com.</p></div>
<p>The gaming sites all require users to create a free account to claim their $2,500 credit, which they can use to play any number of extremely polished video games that ask users to bet on each action. At the scam website gamblerbeast[.]com, for example, visitors can pick from dozens of games like <strong>B-Ball Blitz</strong>, in which you play a basketball pro who is taking shots from the free throw line against a single opponent, and you bet on your ability to sink each shot.</p>
<p>The financial part of this scam begins when users try to cash out any &#8220;winnings.&#8221; At that point, the gaming site will reject the request and prompt the user to make a &#8220;verification deposit&#8221; of cryptocurrency &#8212; typically around $100 &#8212; before any money can be distributed. Those who deposit cryptocurrency funds are soon asked for additional payments.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lNjqXIq1s5g?si=-30qS1Bw73VdIXow" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>However, any &#8220;winnings&#8221; displayed by these gaming sites are a complete fantasy, and players who deposit cryptocurrency funds will never see that money again. Compounding the problem, victims likely will soon be peppered with come-ons from &#8220;recovery experts&#8221; who peddle dubious claims on social media networks about being able to retrieve funds lost to such scams.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity first learned about this network of phony betting sites from a Discord user who asked to be identified only by their screen name: &#8220;<strong>Thereallo</strong>&#8221; is a 17-year-old developer who operates multiple Discord servers and said they began digging deeper after users started complaining of being inundated with misleading spam messages promoting the sites.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were being spammed relentlessly by these scam posts from compromised or purchased [Discord] accounts,&#8221; Thereallo said. &#8220;I got frustrated with just banning and deleting, so I started to investigate the infrastructure behind the scam messages. This is not a one-off site, it&#8217;s a scalable criminal enterprise with a clear playbook, technical fingerprints, and financial infrastructure.&#8221;</p>
<p>After comparing the code on the gaming sites promoted via spam messages, Thereallo found they all invoked the same API key for an online chatbot that appears to be in limited use or else is custom-made. Indeed, a scan for that API key at the threat hunting platform <strong>Silent Push</strong> reveals at least 1,270 recently-registered and active domains whose names all invoke some type of gaming or wagering theme.</p>
<div id="attachment_71799" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71799" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71799" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-withdrawalerror.png" alt="" width="750" height="374" /><p id="caption-attachment-71799" class="wp-caption-text">The &#8220;verification deposit&#8221; stage of the scam requires the user to deposit cryptocurrency in order to withdraw their &#8220;winnings.&#8221;</p></div>
<p>Thereallo said the operators of this scam empire appear to generate a unique Bitcoin wallet for each gaming domain they deploy.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is a decoy wallet,&#8221; Thereallo explained. &#8220;Once the victim deposits funds, they are never able to withdraw any money. Any attempts to contact the &#8216;Live Support&#8217; are handled by a combination of AI and human operators who eventually block the user. The chat system is self-hosted, making it difficult to report to third-party service providers.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thereallo discovered another feature common to all of these scam gambling sites [hereafter referred to simply as &#8220;scambling&#8221; sites]: If you register at one of them and then very quickly try to register at a sister property of theirs from the same Internet address and device, the registration request is denied at the second site.</p>
<p>&#8220;I registered on one site, then hopped to another to register again,&#8221; Thereallo said. Instead, the second site returned an error stating that a new account couldn&#8217;t be created for another 10 minutes.</p>
<div id="attachment_71801" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71801" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-71801" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora.png" alt="" width="749" height="404" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora.png 908w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora-768x414.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora-782x422.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/scambling-spinora-370x200.png 370w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71801" class="wp-caption-text">The scam gaming site spinora dot cc shares the same chatbot API as more than 1,200 similar fake gaming sites.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;re tracking my VPN IP across their entire network,&#8221; Thereallo explained. &#8220;My password manager also proved it. It tried to use my dummy email on a site I had never visited, and the site told me the account already existed. So it&#8217;s definitely one entity running a single platform with 1,200+ different domain names as front-ends. This explains how their support works, a central pool of agents handling all the sites. It also explains why they&#8217;re so strict about not giving out wallet addresses; it&#8217;s a network-wide policy.&#8221;<span id="more-71791"></span></p>
<p>In many ways, these scambling sites borrow from the playbook of &#8220;<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/07/massive-losses-define-epidemic-of-pig-butchering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pig butchering</a>&#8221; schemes, a rampant and far more elaborate crime in which people are gradually lured by flirtatious strangers online into investing in fraudulent cryptocurrency trading platforms.</p>
<p>Pig butchering scams are typically powered by people in Asia who have been kidnapped and threatened with physical harm or worse unless they sit in a cubicle and scam Westerners on the Internet all day. In contrast, these scambling sites tend to steal far less money from individual victims, but their cookie-cutter nature and automated support components may enable their operators to extract payments from a large number of people in far less time, and with considerably less risk and up-front investment.</p>
<p>Silent Push&#8217;s <strong>Zach Edwards</strong> said the proprietors of this scambling empire are spending big money to make the sites look and feel like some fancy new type of casino.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s a very odd type of pig butchering network and not like what we typically see, with much lower investments in the sites and lures,&#8221; Edwards said.</p>
<p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/deduped_scambling_domains.txt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Here is a list of all domains</a> that Silent Push found were using the scambling network&#8217;s chat API.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/scammers-unleash-flood-of-slick-online-gaming-sites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Phishers Target Aviation Execs to Scam Customers</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/phishers-target-aviation-execs-to-scam-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/phishers-target-aviation-execs-to-scam-customers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Target: Small Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Association for Financial Professionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BEC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business email compromise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial fraud kill chain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Crime Complaint Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justy John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palo Alto Networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roomservice801@gmail.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SilverTerrier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 42]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[KrebsOnSecurity recently heard from a reader whose boss's email account got phished and was used to trick one of the company's customers into sending a large payment to scammers. An investigation into the attacker's infrastructure points to a long-running Nigerian cybercrime group that is actively targeting established companies in the transportation and aviation industries.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>KrebsOnSecurity recently heard from a reader whose boss&#8217;s email account got phished and was used to trick one of the company&#8217;s customers into sending a large payment to scammers. An investigation into the attacker&#8217;s infrastructure points to a long-running Nigerian cybercrime ring that is actively targeting established companies in the transportation and aviation industries.</p>
<div id="attachment_71757" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71757" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71757" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/shutterstock-airplanes.png" alt="" width="749" height="535" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/shutterstock-airplanes.png 666w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/shutterstock-airplanes-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71757" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, Mr. Teerapon Tiuekhom.</p></div>
<p>A reader who works in the transportation industry sent a tip about a recent successful phishing campaign that tricked an executive at the company into entering their credentials at a fake Microsoft 365 login page. From there, the attackers quickly mined the executive&#8217;s inbox for past communications about invoices, copying and modifying some of those messages with new invoice demands that were sent to some of the company&#8217;s customers and partners.</p>
<p>Speaking on condition of anonymity, the reader said the resulting phishing emails to customers came from a newly registered domain name that was remarkably similar to their employer&#8217;s domain, and that at least one of their customers fell for the ruse and paid a phony invoice. They said the attackers had spun up a look-alike domain just a few hours after the executive&#8217;s inbox credentials were phished, and that the scam resulted in a customer suffering a six-figure financial loss.</p>
<p>The reader also shared that the email addresses in the registration records for the imposter domain &#8212; <strong>roomservice801@gmail.com</strong> &#8212; is tied to many such phishing domains. Indeed, a search on this email address at <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> finds it is associated with at least 240 domains registered in 2024 or 2025. Virtually all of them mimic legitimate domains for companies in the aerospace and transportation industries worldwide.</p>
<p>An Internet search for this email address reveals <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20220514070749/https://hackware.ru/?p=12106" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a humorous blog post from 2020</a> on the Russian forum hackware[.]ru, which found roomservice801@gmail.com was tied to a phishing attack that used the lure of phony invoices to trick the recipient into logging in at a fake Microsoft login page. We&#8217;ll come back to this research in a moment.</p>
<h2>JUSTY JOHN</h2>
<p>DomainTools shows that some of the early domains registered to roomservice801@gmail.com in 2016 include other useful information. For example, the WHOIS records for <strong>alhhomaidhicentre[.]biz</strong> reference the technical contact of &#8220;<strong>Justy John</strong>&#8221; and the email address <strong>justyjohn50@yahoo.com</strong>.</p>
<p>A search at DomainTools found justyjohn50@yahoo.com has been registering one-off phishing domains since at least 2012. At this point, I was convinced that some security company surely had already published an analysis of this particular threat group, but I didn&#8217;t yet have enough information to draw any solid conclusions.</p>
<p>DomainTools says the Justy John email address is tied to more than two dozen domains registered since 2012, but we can find hundreds more phishing domains and related email addresses simply by pivoting on details in the registration records for these Justy John domains. For example, the street address used by the Justy John domain <strong>axisupdate[.]net</strong> &#8212; 7902 Pelleaux Road in Knoxville, TN &#8212; also appears in the registration records for accountauthenticate[.]com, acctlogin[.]biz, and loginaccount[.]biz, all of which at one point included the email address <strong>rsmith60646@gmail.com</strong>.</p>
<p>That Rsmith Gmail address is connected to the 2012 phishing domain alibala[.]biz (one character off of the Chinese e-commerce giant alibaba.com, with a different top-level domain of .biz). A search in DomainTools on the phone number in those domain records &#8212; 1.7736491613 &#8212; reveals even more phishing domains as well as the Nigerian phone number &#8220;2348062918302&#8221; and the email address <strong>michsmith59@gmail.com</strong>.</p>
<p>DomainTools shows michsmith59@gmail.com appears in the registration records for the domain <strong>seltrock[.]com</strong>, which was used in the phishing attack documented in <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20220514070749/https://hackware.ru/?p=12106" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the 2020 Russian blog post</a> mentioned earlier. At this point, we are just two steps away from identifying the threat actor group.</p>
<p>The same Nigerian phone number shows up in dozens of domain registrations that reference the email address <strong>sebastinekelly69@gmail.com</strong>, including <strong>26i3[.]net</strong>, <strong>costamere[.]com</strong>, <strong>danagruop[.]us</strong>, and <strong>dividrilling[.]com</strong>. A Web search on any of those domains finds they were indexed in <a href="https://github.com/pan-unit42/iocs/blob/master/silverterrier/domains.csv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an &#8220;indicator of compromise&#8221; list on GitHub</a> maintained by <strong>Palo Alto Networks</strong>&#8216; <strong>Unit 42</strong> research team.<span id="more-71635"></span></p>
<h2>SILVERTERRIER</h2>
<p>According to Unit 42, the domains are the handiwork of a vast cybercrime group based in Nigeria that it dubbed &#8220;<strong>SilverTerrier</strong>&#8221; back in 2014. In <a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/silverterrier-nigerian-business-email-compromise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an October 2021 report</a>, Palo Alto said SilverTerrier excels at so-called &#8220;<strong>business e-mail compromise</strong>&#8221; or <strong>BEC</strong> scams, which target legitimate business email accounts through social engineering or computer intrusion activities. BEC criminals use that access to initiate or redirect the transfer of business funds for personal gain.</p>
<p>Palo Alto says SilverTerrier encompasses hundreds of BEC fraudsters, some of whom have been arrested in various international law enforcement operations by <strong>Interpol</strong>. In 2022, Interpol and the Nigeria Police Force <a href="https://www.interpol.int/en/News-and-Events/News/2022/Nigerian-cybercrime-fraud-11-suspects-arrested-syndicate-busted" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested 11 alleged SilverTerrier members</a>, including <a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/operation-delilah-business-email-compromise-actor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a prominent SilverTerrier leader</a> who&#8217;d been flaunting his wealth on social media for years. Unfortunately, the lure of easy money, endemic poverty and corruption, and low barriers to entry for cybercrime in Nigeria conspire to provide a constant stream of new recruits.</p>
<p>BEC scams were the 7th most reported crime tracked by the FBI&#8217;s <strong>Internet Crime Complaint Center</strong> (IC3) in 2024, generating more than 21,000 complaints. However, BEC scams were the second most costly form of cybercrime reported to the feds last year, with <em>nearly $2.8 billion in claimed losses</em>. In its <a href="https://www.afponline.org/training-resources/resources/survey-research-economic-data/Details/payments-fraud" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2025 Fraud and Control Survey Report</a>, the <strong>Association for Financial Professionals</strong> found 63 percent of organizations experienced a BEC last year.</p>
<p>Poking at some of the email addresses that spool out from this research reveals a number of Facebook accounts for people residing in Nigeria or in the United Arab Emirates, many of whom do not appear to have tried to mask their real-life identities. Palo Alto&#8217;s Unit 42 researchers reached a similar conclusion, noting that although a small subset of these crooks went to great lengths to conceal their identities, it was usually simple to learn their identities on social media accounts and the major messaging services.</p>
<p>Palo Alto said BEC actors have become far more organized over time, and that while it remains easy to find actors working as a group, the practice of using one phone number, email address or alias to register malicious infrastructure in support of multiple actors has made it far more time consuming (but not impossible) for cybersecurity and law enforcement organizations to sort out which actors committed specific crimes.</p>
<p>&#8220;We continue to find that SilverTerrier actors, regardless of geographical location, are often connected through only a few degrees of separation on social media platforms,&#8221; the researchers wrote.</p>
<h2>FINANCIAL FRAUD KILL CHAIN</h2>
<p>Palo Alto has published <a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/operation-falcon-ii-silverterrier-nigerian-bec/#protections-and-mitigations" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a useful list of recommendations</a> that organizations can adopt to minimize the incidence and impact of BEC attacks. Many of those tips are prophylactic, such as conducting regular employee security training and reviewing network security policies.</p>
<p>But one recommendation &#8212; getting familiar with a process known as the &#8220;<strong>financial fraud kill chain</strong>&#8221; or FFKC &#8212; bears specific mention because it offers the single best hope for BEC victims who are seeking to claw back payments made to fraudsters, and yet far too many victims don&#8217;t know it exists until it is too late.</p>
<div id="attachment_71758" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71758" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71758" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ffkc-fbi.png" alt="" width="749" height="786" /><p id="caption-attachment-71758" class="wp-caption-text">Image: ic3.gov.</p></div>
<p>As explained in <a href="https://www.justice.gov/elderjustice/media/1364056/dl?inline" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this FBI primer</a>, the International Financial Fraud Kill Chain is a partnership between federal law enforcement and financial entities whose purpose is to freeze fraudulent funds wired by victims. According to the FBI, viable victim <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/CrimeInfo/BEC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">complaints filed with ic3.gov</a> promptly after a fraudulent transfer (generally less than 72 hours) will be automatically triaged by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_Crimes_Enforcement_Network" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</a> (FinCEN).</p>
<p>The FBI noted in its <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/AnnualReport/Reports/2024_IC3Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IC3 annual report</a> (PDF) that the FFKC had a 66 percent success rate in 2024. Viable ic3.gov complaints involve losses of at least $50,000, and include all records from the victim or victim bank, as well as a completed FFKC form (provided by FinCEN) containing victim information, recipient information, bank names, account numbers, location, SWIFT, and any additional information.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/phishers-target-aviation-execs-to-scam-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Fix Targets Attacks on SharePoint Zero-Day</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/microsoft-fix-targets-attacks-on-sharepoint-zero-day/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/microsoft-fix-targets-attacks-on-sharepoint-zero-day/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CISA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-49704]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-49706]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53770]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-53771]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity & Infrastructure Security Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eye Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Corp.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SharePoint Server]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=71737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Sunday, July 20, Microsoft Corp. issued an emergency security update for a vulnerability in SharePoint Server that is actively being exploited to compromise vulnerable organizations. The patch comes amid reports that malicious hackers have used the Sharepoint flaw to breach U.S. federal and state agencies, universities, and energy companies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Sunday, July 20, <strong>Microsoft Corp.</strong> issued an emergency security update for a vulnerability in <strong>SharePoint Server</strong> that is actively being exploited to compromise vulnerable organizations. The patch comes amid reports that malicious hackers have used the SharePoint flaw to breach U.S. federal and state agencies, universities, and energy companies.</p>
<div id="attachment_71741" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-71741" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-71741" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ms-sharepoint-ss.png" alt="" width="749" height="491" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ms-sharepoint-ss.png 987w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ms-sharepoint-ss-768x503.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/ms-sharepoint-ss-782x513.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-71741" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, by Ascannio.</p></div>
<p>In <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/blog/2025/07/customer-guidance-for-sharepoint-vulnerability-cve-2025-53770/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an advisory</a> about the SharePoint security hole, a.k.a. <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-53770" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53770</a>, Microsoft said it is aware of active attacks targeting on-premises SharePoint Server customers and exploiting vulnerabilities that were only partially addressed by <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/microsoft-patch-tuesday-july-2025-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the July 8, 2025 security update</a>.</p>
<p>The <strong>Cybersecurity &amp; Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA) <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/alerts/2025/07/20/microsoft-releases-guidance-exploitation-sharepoint-vulnerability-cve-2025-53770" target="_blank" rel="noopener">concurred</a>, saying CVE-2025-53770 is a variant on a flaw Microsoft patched earlier this month (<a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-49706" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-49706)</a>. Microsoft notes the weakness applies only to SharePoint Servers that organizations use in-house, and that SharePoint Online and Microsoft 365 are not affected.</p>
<p><strong>The Washington Post</strong> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/07/20/microsoft-sharepoint-hack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> on Sunday that the U.S. government and partners in Canada and Australia are investigating the hack of SharePoint servers, which provide a platform for sharing and managing documents. The Post reports at least two U.S. federal agencies have seen their servers breached via the SharePoint vulnerability.</p>
<p>According to CISA, attackers exploiting the newly-discovered flaw are retrofitting compromised servers with a backdoor dubbed &#8220;<strong>ToolShell</strong>&#8221; that provides unauthenticated, remote access to systems. CISA said ToolShell enables attackers to fully access SharePoint content &#8212; including file systems and internal configurations &#8212; and execute code over the network.</p>
<p>Researchers at <strong>Eye Security</strong> said they first spotted large-scale exploitation of the SharePoint flaw on July 18, 2025, and soon found dozens of separate servers compromised by the bug and infected with ToolShell. In <a href="https://research.eye.security/sharepoint-under-siege/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a blog post</a>, the researchers said the attacks sought to steal SharePoint server ASP.NET machine keys.</p>
<p>&#8220;These keys can be used to facilitate further attacks, even at a later date,&#8221; Eye Security warned. &#8220;It is critical that affected servers rotate SharePoint server ASP.NET machine keys and restart IIS on all SharePoint servers. Patching alone is not enough. We strongly advise defenders not to wait for a vendor fix before taking action. This threat is already operational and spreading rapidly.&#8221;<span id="more-71737"></span></p>
<p>Microsoft&#8217;s advisory says the company has issued updates for <strong>SharePoint Server Subscription Edition</strong> and <strong>SharePoint Server 2019</strong>, but that it is still working on updates for supported versions of <strong>SharePoint 2019</strong> and <strong>SharePoint 2016</strong>.</p>
<p>CISA advises vulnerable organizations to enable the anti-malware scan interface (AMSI) in SharePoint, to deploy Microsoft Defender AV on all SharePoint servers, and to disconnect affected products from the public-facing Internet until an official patch is available.</p>
<p>The security firm <strong>Rapid7</strong> <a href="https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/etr-zero-day-exploitation-of-microsoft-sharepoint-servers-cve-2025-53770/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notes</a> that Microsoft has described CVE-2025-53770 as related to a previous vulnerability &#8212; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-49704" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-49704</a>, patched earlier this month &#8212; and that CVE-2025-49704 was part of an exploit chain demonstrated at the <strong>Pwn2Own</strong> hacking competition in May 2025. That exploit chain invoked a second SharePoint weakness &#8212; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-49706" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-49706</a> &#8212; which Microsoft unsuccessfully tried to fix in this month&#8217;s Patch Tuesday.</p>
<p>Microsoft also has issued a patch for a related SharePoint vulnerability &#8212; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-53771" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-53771</a>; Microsoft says there are no signs of active attacks on CVE-2025-53771, and that the patch is to provide more robust protections than the update for CVE-2025-49706.</p>
<p><em>This is a rapidly developing story. Any updates will be noted with timestamps.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/07/microsoft-fix-targets-attacks-on-sharepoint-zero-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 260/260 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached (User agent is rejected) 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2025-08-28 10:55:05 by W3 Total Cache
-->