<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/?ref=blog.netmanageit.com" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 19:25:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>FBI, Dutch Police Disrupt &#8216;Manipulaters&#8217; Phishing Gang</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/fbi-dutch-police-disrupt-manipulaters-phishing-gang/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/fbi-dutch-police-disrupt-manipulaters-phishing-gang/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 18:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BEC fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business email compromise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cracked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch National Police]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FudCo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fudpage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fudtools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HeartSender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operation Talent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saim Raza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sellix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Manipulaters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WeCodeSolutions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The FBI and authorities in The Netherlands this week seized a number of servers and domains for a hugely popular spam and malware dissemination service operating out of Pakistan. The proprietors of the service, who use the collective nickname "The Manipulaters," have been the subject of three stories published here since 2015. The FBI said the main clientele are organized crime groups that try to trick victim companies into making payments to a third party.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The FBI and authorities in The Netherlands this week seized dozens of servers and domains for a hugely popular spam and malware dissemination service operating out of Pakistan. The proprietors of the service, who use the collective nickname &#8220;<strong>The Manipulaters</strong>,&#8221; have been the subject of three stories published here since 2015. The FBI said the main clientele are organized crime groups that try to trick victim companies into making payments to a third party.</p>
<div id="attachment_56857" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-56857" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-56857" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit.png" alt="" width="749" height="530" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit.png 1208w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit-768x544.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit-782x553.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ftexploit-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-56857" class="wp-caption-text">One of several current Fudtools sites run by the principals of The Manipulators.</p></div>
<p>On January 29, the FBI and the Dutch national police seized the technical infrastructure for a cybercrime service marketed under the brands <strong>Heartsender</strong>, <strong>Fudpage</strong> and <strong>Fudtools</strong> (and many other &#8220;fud&#8221; variations). The &#8220;fud&#8221; bit stands for &#8220;Fully Un-Detectable,&#8221; and it refers to cybercrime resources that will evade detection by security tools like antivirus software or anti-spam appliances.</p>
<p>The Dutch authorities <a href="https://www.politie.nl/nieuws/2025/januari/27/09-verstoringsactie-deelt-klap-uit-aan-crimineel-cybernetwerk-heartsender.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> 39 servers and domains abroad were seized, and that the servers contained millions of records from victims worldwide &#8212; including at least 100,000 records pertaining to Dutch citizens.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdtx/pr/cybercrime-websites-selling-hacking-tools-transnational-organized-crime-groups-seized" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> from the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> refers to the cybercrime group as <strong>Saim Raza</strong>, after a pseudonym The Manipulaters communally used to promote their spam, malware and phishing services on social media.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Saim Raza-run websites operated as marketplaces that advertised and facilitated the sale of tools such as phishing kits, scam pages and email extractors often used to build and maintain fraud operations,&#8221; the DOJ explained.</p>
<p>The core Manipulaters product is <strong>Heartsender</strong>, a spam delivery service whose homepage openly advertised phishing kits targeting users of various Internet companies, including <strong>Microsoft 365</strong>, <strong>Yahoo</strong>, <strong>AOL</strong>, <strong>Intuit</strong>, <strong>iCloud</strong> and <strong>ID.me</strong>, to name a few.</p>
<p>The government says transnational organized crime groups that purchased these services primarily used them to run <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/business-email-compromise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">business email compromise</a> (BEC) schemes, wherein the cybercrime actors tricked victim companies into making payments to a third party.</p>
<p>&#8220;Those payments would instead be redirected to a financial account the perpetrators controlled, resulting in significant losses to victims,&#8221; the DOJ wrote. &#8220;These tools were also used to acquire victim user credentials and utilize those credentials to further these fraudulent schemes. The seizure of these domains is intended to disrupt the ongoing activity of these groups and stop the proliferation of these tools within the cybercriminal community.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_67010" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-67010" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-67010" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/manipulaters-o365.png" alt="" width="748" height="291" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/manipulaters-o365.png 1097w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/manipulaters-o365-768x299.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/manipulaters-o365-782x304.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-67010" class="wp-caption-text">Manipulaters advertisement for “Office 365 Private Page with Antibot” phishing kit sold via Heartsender. “Antibot” refers to functionality that attempts to evade automated detection techniques, keeping a phish deployed and accessible as long as possible. Image: DomainTools.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity first wrote about The Manipulaters <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/05/phishing-gang-is-audacious-manipulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in May 2015</a>, mainly because their ads at the time were blanketing a number of popular cybercrime forums, and because they were fairly open and brazen about what they were doing &#8212; even who they were in real life.</p>
<p>We caught up with The Manipulaters again in 2021, with <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/09/fudco-spam-empire-tied-to-pakistani-software-firm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a story</a> that found the core employees had started a web coding company in Lahore called <strong>WeCodeSolutions</strong> &#8212; presumably as a way to account for their considerable Heartsender income. That piece examined how WeCodeSolutions employees had all doxed themselves on Facebook by posting pictures from company parties each year featuring a large cake with the words <strong>FudCo</strong> written in icing.<span id="more-70250"></span></p>
<p>A <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/04/the-manipulaters-improve-phishing-still-fail-at-opsec/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">follow-up story last year</a> about The Manipulaters prompted messages from various WeCodeSolutions employees who pleaded with this publication to remove stories about them. The Saim Raza identity told KrebsOnSecurity they were recently released from jail after being arrested and charged by local police, although they declined to elaborate on the charges.</p>
<p>The Manipulaters never seemed to care much about protecting their own identities, so it&#8217;s not surprising that they were unable or unwilling to protect their own customers. In <a href="https://www.domaintools.com/resources/blog/the-resurgence-of-the-manipulaters-team-breaking-heartsenders?utm_source=Krebs-on-Security" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an analysis</a> released last year, <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> found the web-hosted version of Heartsender leaked an extraordinary amount of user information to unauthenticated users, including customer credentials and email records from Heartsender employees.</p>
<div id="attachment_56860" style="width: 761px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-56860" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-56860" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcocake.png" alt="" width="751" height="773" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcocake.png 834w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcocake-768x790.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/fudcocake-782x805.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 751px) 100vw, 751px" /><p id="caption-attachment-56860" class="wp-caption-text">Almost every year since their founding, The Manipulaters have posted a picture of a FudCo cake from a company party celebrating its anniversary.</p></div>
<p>DomainTools also uncovered evidence that the computers used by The Manipulaters were all infected with the same password-stealing malware, and that vast numbers of credentials were stolen from the group and sold online.</p>
<p>&#8220;Ironically, the Manipulaters may create more short-term risk to their own customers than law enforcement,&#8221; DomainTools wrote. &#8220;The data table &#8216;User Feedbacks&#8217; (sic) exposes what appear to be customer authentication tokens, user identifiers, and even a customer support request that exposes root-level SMTP credentials–all visible by an unauthenticated user on a Manipulaters-controlled domain.&#8221;</p>
<p>Police in The Netherlands said the investigation into the owners and customers of the service is ongoing.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Cybercrime Team is on the trail of a number of buyers of the tools,&#8221; the Dutch national police said. &#8220;Presumably, these buyers also include Dutch nationals. The investigation into the makers and buyers of this phishing software has not yet been completed with the seizure of the servers and domains.&#8221;</p>
<p>U.S. authorities this week also joined law enforcement in Australia, France, Greece, Italy, Romania and Spain in seizing a number of domains for several long-running cybercrime forums and services, including <strong>Cracked</strong> and <strong>Nulled</strong>. According to <a href="https://www.europol.europa.eu/media-press/newsroom/news/law-enforcement-takes-down-two-largest-cybercrime-forums-in-world" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a statement</a> from the European police agency <strong>Europol</strong>, the two communities attracted more than 10 million users in total.</p>
<p>Other domains seized as part of &#8220;<strong>Operation Talent</strong>&#8221; included <strong>Sellix</strong>, an e-commerce platform that was frequently used by cybercrime forum members to buy and sell illicit goods and services.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/fbi-dutch-police-disrupt-manipulaters-phishing-gang/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Infrastructure Laundering: Blending in with the Cloud</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/infrastructure-laundering-blending-in-with-the-cloud/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/infrastructure-laundering-blending-in-with-the-cloud/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ACB Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anjie CDN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crowell & Moring LLP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fangneng CDN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funnull]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infrastructure laundering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NETSCOUT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NoName057(16)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polyfill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richard Hummel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suncity Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70065</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an effort to blend in and make their malicious traffic tougher to block, hosting firms catering to cybercriminals in China and Russia increasingly are funneling their operations through major U.S. cloud providers. Research published this week on one such outfit -- a sprawling network tied to Chinese organized crime gangs and aptly named "Funnull" -- highlights a persistent whac-a-mole problem facing cloud services.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_70230" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70230" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70230" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss.png" alt="" width="749" height="452" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss.png 1319w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss-768x463.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnell-ss-782x472.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70230" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, ArtHead.</p></div>
<p>In an effort to blend in and make their malicious traffic tougher to block, hosting firms catering to cybercriminals in China and Russia increasingly are funneling their operations through major U.S. cloud providers. Research published this week on one such outfit &#8212; a sprawling network tied to Chinese organized crime gangs and aptly named &#8220;<strong>Funnull</strong>&#8221; &#8212; highlights a persistent whac-a-mole problem facing cloud services.</p>
<p>In October 2024, the security firm <strong>Silent Push</strong> published a <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/triad-nexus-funnull/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lengthy analysis</a> of how <strong>Amazon AWS</strong> and <strong>Microsoft Azure</strong> were providing services to Funnull, a two-year-old Chinese content delivery network that hosts a wide variety of fake trading apps, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/07/massive-losses-define-epidemic-of-pig-butchering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pig butchering scams</a>, gambling websites, and retail phishing pages.</p>
<p>Funnull made headlines last summer after it acquired the domain name <strong>polyfill[.]io</strong>, previously the home of a widely-used open source code library that allowed older browsers to handle advanced functions that weren&#8217;t natively supported. There were still tens of thousands of legitimate domains linking to the Polyfill domain at the time of its acquisition, and Funnull soon after <a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/07/384000-sites-link-to-code-library-caught-performing-supply-chain-attack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conducted a supply-chain attack that redirected visitors to malicious sites</a>.</p>
<p>Silent Push&#8217;s October 2024 report found a vast number of domains hosted via Funnull promoting gambling sites that bear the logo of the <strong>Suncity Group</strong>, a Chinese entity named in <a href="https://www.unodc.org/roseap/uploads/documents/Publications/2024/Casino_Underground_Banking_Report_2024.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2024 UN report</a> (PDF) for laundering millions of dollars for the North Korean <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lazarus_Group" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lazarus Group</a>.</p>
<p>In 2023, Suncity’s CEO was <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/business/companies/ex-suncity-boss-alvin-chau-jailed-for-18-years-in-macau-20230118-p5cdmj.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sentenced to 18 years in prison</a> on charges of fraud, illegal gambling, and “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triad_(organized_crime)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">triad</a> offenses,” i.e. working with Chinese transnational organized crime syndicates. Suncity is alleged to have built an underground banking system that <a href="https://macaonews.org/news/city/former-suncity-boss-alvin-chau-sentenced-to-18-years-in-prison/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">laundered billions of dollars for criminals</a>.</p>
<p>It is likely the gambling sites coming through Funnull are abusing top casino brands as part of their money laundering schemes. In reporting on Silent Push&#8217;s October report, <em>TechCrunch</em> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/10/22/researchers-link-polyfill-supply-chain-attack-to-huge-network-of-copycat-gambling-sites/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">obtained</a> a comment from Bwin, one of the casinos being advertised en masse through Funnull, and Bwin said those websites did not belong to them.</p>
<p>Gambling is illegal in China except in Macau, a special administrative region of China. Silent Push researchers say Funnull may be helping online gamblers in China evade the Communist party&#8217;s &#8220;Great Firewall,&#8221; which blocks access to gambling destinations.</p>
<p>Silent Push&#8217;s <strong>Zach Edwards</strong> said that upon <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/infrastructure-laundering/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revisiting Funnull&#8217;s infrastructure again this month</a>, they found dozens of the same Amazon and Microsoft cloud Internet addresses still forwarding Funnull traffic through a dizzying chain of auto-generated domain names before redirecting malicious or phishous websites.</p>
<p>Edwards said Funnull is a textbook example of an increasing trend Silent Push calls &#8220;infrastructure laundering,&#8221; wherein crooks selling cybercrime services will relay some or all of their malicious traffic through U.S. cloud providers.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s crucial for global hosting companies based in the West to wake up to the fact that extremely low quality and suspicious web hosts based out of China are deliberately renting IP space from multiple companies and then mapping those IPs to their criminal client websites,&#8221; Edwards told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;We need these major hosts to create internal policies so that if they are renting IP space to one entity, who further rents it to host numerous criminal websites, all of those IPs should be reclaimed and the CDN who purchased them should be banned from future IP rentals or purchases.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70232" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70232" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70232" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/suncity-funnull.png" alt="" width="750" height="370" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/suncity-funnull.png 958w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/suncity-funnull-768x379.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/suncity-funnull-782x386.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70232" class="wp-caption-text">A Suncity gambling site promoted via Funnull. The sites feature a prompt for a Tether/USDT deposit program.</p></div>
<p>Reached for comment, Amazon referred this reporter to a statement Silent Push included in <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/infrastructure-laundering" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a report released today</a>. Amazon said AWS was already aware of the Funnull addresses tracked by Silent Push, and that it had suspended all known accounts linked to the activity.</p>
<p>Amazon said that contrary to implications in the Silent Push report, it has every reason to aggressively police its network against this activity, noting the accounts tied to Funnull used &#8220;fraudulent methods to temporarily acquire infrastructure, for which it never pays. Thus, AWS incurs damages as a result of the abusive activity.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;When AWS&#8217;s automated or manual systems detect potential abuse, or when we receive reports of potential abuse, we act quickly to investigate and take action to stop any prohibited activity,&#8221; Amazon&#8217;s statement continues. &#8220;In the event anyone suspects that AWS resources are being used for abusive activity, we encourage them to report it to AWS Trust &amp; Safety using the <a href="https://support.aws.amazon.com/#/contacts/report-abuse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">report abuse form</a>. In this case, the authors of the report never notified AWS of the findings of their research via our easy-to-find security and abuse reporting channels. Instead, AWS first learned of their research from a journalist to whom the researchers had provided a draft.&#8221;</p>
<p>Microsoft likewise said it takes such abuse seriously, and encouraged others to report suspicious activity found on its network.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are committed to protecting our customers against this kind of activity and actively enforce acceptable use policies when violations are detected,&#8221; Microsoft said in a written statement. &#8220;We encourage <a href="https://protect.checkpoint.com/v2/r01/___https://msrc.microsoft.com/report/___.YzJ1OndlY29tbXVuaWNhdGlvbnM6YzpvOjQwMWQyNWE1OWIxMDNiNWUyZGQ5ZmY2MmZiYTMxMTNiOjc6NDRlNzoyZDg4NzY5MmI4MGVmYWY2M2NmZWVjOGMxMjhkNTRhYjhmODc4Mzk3MjJkYjdkMTEzMjk0MDdmMzA4NDUxNDczOmg6VDpG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reporting</a> suspicious activity to Microsoft so we can investigate and take appropriate actions.&#8221;<span id="more-70065"></span></p>
<p><strong>Richard Hummel</strong> is threat intelligence lead at <strong>NETSCOUT</strong>. Hummel said it used to be that &#8220;noisy&#8221; and frequently disruptive malicious traffic &#8212; such as automated application layer attacks, and &#8220;brute force&#8221; efforts to crack passwords or find vulnerabilities in websites &#8212; came mostly from botnets, or large collections of hacked devices.</p>
<p>But he said the vast majority of the infrastructure used to funnel this type of traffic is now proxied through major cloud providers, which can make it difficult for organizations to block at the network level.</p>
<p>&#8220;From a defenders point of view, you can&#8217;t wholesale block cloud providers, because a single IP can host thousands or tens of thousands of domains,&#8221; Hummel said.</p>
<p>In May 2024, KrebsOnSecurity published <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-an-iron-hammer-in-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a deep dive on Stark Industries Solutions</a>, an ISP that materialized at the start of Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine and has been used as a global proxy network that conceals the true source of cyberattacks and disinformation campaigns against enemies of Russia. Experts said much of the malicious traffic  traversing Stark&#8217;s network (e.g. vulnerability scanning and password brute force attacks) was being bounced through U.S.-based cloud providers.</p>
<p>Stark&#8217;s network has been a favorite of the Russian hacktivist group called <strong>NoName057(16)</strong>, which frequently launches huge distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks against a variety of targets seen as opposed to Moscow. Hummel said NoName&#8217;s history suggests they are adept at cycling through new cloud provider accounts, making anti-abuse efforts into a game of whac-a-mole.</p>
<p>&#8220;It almost doesn&#8217;t matter if the cloud provider is on point and takes it down because the bad guys will just spin up a new one,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Even if they&#8217;re only able to use it for an hour, they&#8217;ve already done their damage. It&#8217;s a really difficult problem.&#8221;</p>
<p>Edwards said Amazon declined to specify whether the banned Funnull users were operating using compromised accounts or stolen payment card data, or something else.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m surprised they wanted to lean into &#8216;We&#8217;ve caught this 1,200+ times and have taken these down!&#8217; and yet didn&#8217;t connect that each of those IPs was mapped to [the same] Chinese CDN,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We&#8217;re just thankful Amazon confirmed that account mules are being used for this and it isn&#8217;t some front-door relationship. We haven&#8217;t heard the same thing from Microsoft but it&#8217;s very likely that the same thing is happening.&#8221;</p>
<p>Funnull wasn&#8217;t always a bulletproof hosting network for scam sites. Prior to 2022, the network was known as <strong>Anjie CDN</strong>, based in the Philippines. One of Anjie&#8217;s properties was a website called <strong>funnull[.]app</strong>. Loading that domain reveals a pop-up message by the original Anjie CDN owner, who said their operations had been seized by an entity known as <strong>Fangneng CDN</strong> and <strong>ACB Group</strong>, the parent company of Funnull.</p>
<div id="attachment_70228" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70228" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70228" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app.png" alt="" width="749" height="533" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app.png 1079w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app-768x546.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app-782x556.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/funnull-app-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70228" class="wp-caption-text">A machine-translated message from the former owner of Anjie CDN, a Chinese content delivery network that is now Funnull.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;After I got into trouble, the company was managed by my family,&#8221; the message explains. &#8220;Because my family was isolated and helpless, they were persuaded by villains to sell the company. Recently, many companies have contacted my family and threatened them, believing that Fangneng CDN used penetration and mirroring technology through customer domain names to steal member information and financial transactions, and stole customer programs by renting and selling servers. This matter has nothing to do with me and my family. Please contact Fangneng CDN to resolve it.&#8221;</p>
<p>In January 2024, the <strong>U.S. Department of Commerce</strong> issued <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2024/01/29/2024-01580/taking-additional-steps-to-address-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-significant-malicious" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a proposed rule</a> that would require cloud providers to create a &#8220;Customer Identification Program&#8221; that includes procedures to collect data sufficient to determine whether each potential customer is a foreign or U.S. person.</p>
<p>According to the law firm <strong>Crowell &amp; Moring LLP</strong>, the Commerce rule also would require &#8220;infrastructure as a service&#8221; (IaaS) providers to report knowledge of any transactions with foreign persons that might allow the foreign entity to train a large AI model with potential capabilities that could be used in malicious cyber-enabled activity.</p>
<p>&#8220;The proposed rulemaking has garnered global attention, as its cross-border data collection requirements are unprecedented in the cloud computing space,&#8221; Crowell <a href="https://www.crowell.com/en/insights/client-alerts/who-iaas-your-foreign-customer-department-of-commerce-proposes-foreign-customer-identification-requirements-for-us-iaas-providers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>. &#8220;To the extent the U.S. alone imposes these requirements, there is concern that U.S. IaaS providers could face a competitive disadvantage, as U.S. allies have not yet announced similar foreign customer identification requirements.&#8221;</p>
<p>It remains unclear if the new White House administration will push forward with the requirements. The Commerce action was mandated as part of an executive order President Trump issued a day before leaving office in January 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/infrastructure-laundering-blending-in-with-the-cloud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Tumultuous Week for Federal Cybersecurity Efforts</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-tumultuous-week-for-federal-cybersecurity-efforts/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-tumultuous-week-for-federal-cybersecurity-efforts/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 02:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alfa Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Sacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House Judiciary Committee's Select Subcommittee on the Weaponization of the Federal Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jack Goldsmith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Hall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Durham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Melania Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Sussman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quinta Jurecic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rep. Jim Jordan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Council on Transnational Organized Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Liberty Financial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Trump last week issued a flurry of executive orders that upended a number of government initiatives focused on improving the nation's cybersecurity posture. The president fired all advisors from the Department of Homeland Security's Cyber Safety Review Board, called for the creation of a strategic cryptocurrency reserve, and voided a Biden administration action that sought to reduce the risks that artificial intelligence poses to consumers, workers and national security.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_70185" style="width: 761px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70185" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70185" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/whitehousenight.png" alt="" width="751" height="495" /><p id="caption-attachment-70185" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock. Greg Meland.</p></div>
<p><strong>President Trump</strong> last week issued a flurry of executive orders that upended a number of government initiatives focused on improving the nation&#8217;s cybersecurity posture. The president fired all advisors from the Department of Homeland Security&#8217;s Cyber Safety Review Board, called for the creation of a strategic cryptocurrency reserve, and voided a Biden administration action that sought to reduce the risks that artificial intelligence poses to consumers, workers and national security.</p>
<p>On his first full day back in the White House, Trump dismissed all 15 advisory committee members of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyber_Safety_Review_Board" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cyber Safety Review Board</a> (CSRB), a nonpartisan government entity established in February 2022 with a mandate to investigate the causes of major cybersecurity events. The CSRB has so far produced three detailed reports, including an analysis of the <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/log4j-log4shell/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Log4Shell vulnerability</a> crisis, attacks from <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/lapsus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the cybercrime group LAPSUS$</a>, and the 2023 <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/resources-tools/resources/CSRB-Review-Summer-2023-MEO-Intrusion" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Exchange Online breach</a>.</p>
<p>The CSRB was in the midst of an inquiry into cyber intrusions uncovered recently across a broad spectrum of U.S. telecommunications providers at the hands of Chinese state-sponsored hackers. One of the CSRB&#8217;s most recognizable names is <strong>Chris Krebs </strong>(no relation), the former director of the <strong>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA). Krebs was fired by President Trump in November 2020 for declaring the presidential contest was the most secure in American history, and for refuting Trump&#8217;s false claims of election fraud.</p>
<p>South Dakota Governor <strong>Kristi Noem</strong>, confirmed by the U.S. Senate last week as the new director of the DHS, criticized CISA at her confirmation hearing, <em>TheRecord</em> <a href="https://therecord.media/kristi-noem-cisa-smaller-nimble?utm_medium=email&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-80A9JU5jFUojRnewo-h4MRW17b74bMAW6oR5rGLelMqQ7jRJp3Ors1qYeq5RFK2jrpXM9V5J2o-RGJSorsePm_8KCvoZ8nFsrOw8h_pdBDQggry0c&amp;_hsmi=343361648&amp;utm_content=343361495&amp;utm_source=hs_email" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a>.</p>
<p>Noem told lawmakers CISA needs to be &#8220;much more effective, smaller, more nimble, to really fulfill their mission,&#8221; which she said should be focused on hardening federal IT systems and hunting for digital intruders. Noem said the agency&#8217;s work on fighting misinformation shows it has &#8220;gotten far off mission&#8221; and involved &#8220;using their resources in ways that was never intended.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The misinformation and disinformation that they have stuck their toe into and meddled with, should be refocused back onto what their job is,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p><strong>Moses Frost</strong>, a cybersecurity instructor with the SANS Institute, compared the sacking of the CSRB members to firing all of the experts at the <strong>National Transportation Safety Board</strong> (NTSB) while they&#8217;re in the middle of an investigation into a string of airline disasters.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don’t recall seeing an &#8216;NTSB Board&#8217; being fired during the middle of a plane crash investigation,&#8221; Frost said in a recent SANS newsletter. &#8220;I can say that the attackers in the phone companies will not stop because the review board has gone away. We do need to figure out how these attacks occurred, and CISA did appear to be doing some good for the vast majority of the federal systems.&#8221;</p>
<p>Speaking of transportation, <em>The Record</em> notes that Transportation Security Administration chief <strong>David Pekoske</strong> <a href="https://therecord.media/tsa-chief-behind-cyber-directives-ousted-trump-administration?utm_medium=email&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-_a5PHD4Ff2FlOiHIlYbcfVNbftiTItDbxlH5TxzCLZicEcan3et6L6nmVmhC57_5AXp-a1k45WwHO6jbVxejLlMjPtTTdVzGtbreDzSl6fzHhGdkg&amp;_hsmi=343497657&amp;utm_content=343496082&amp;utm_source=hs_email" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was fired</a> despite overseeing critical cybersecurity improvements across pipeline, rail and aviation sectors. Pekoske was appointed by Trump in 2017 and had his 5-year tenure renewed in 2022 by former President Joe Biden.</p>
<h2>AI &amp; CRYPTOCURRENCY</h2>
<p>Shortly after being sworn in for a second time, Trump voided a Biden executive order that focused on supporting research and development in artificial intelligence. The previous administration&#8217;s order on AI was crafted with an eye toward managing <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/PSA/2024/PSA241203" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the safety and security risks introduced by the technology</a>. But a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/01/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-takes-action-to-enhance-americas-ai-leadership/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">statement</a> released by the White House said Biden&#8217;s approach to AI had hindered development, and that the United States would support AI systems that are &#8220;free from ideological bias or engineered social agendas,&#8221; to maintain leadership.</p>
<p>The Trump administration issued <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/01/fact-sheet-executive-order-to-establish-united-states-leadership-in-digital-financial-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its own executive order on AI</a>, which calls for an &#8220;AI Action Plan&#8221; to be led by the assistant to the president for science and technology, the White House &#8220;AI &amp; crypto czar,&#8221; and the national security advisor. It also directs the White House to revise and reissue policies to federal agencies on the government&#8217;s acquisition and governance of AI &#8220;to ensure that harmful barriers to America&#8217;s AI leadership are eliminated.&#8221;</p>
<p>Trump&#8217;s AI &amp; crypto czar is <strong>David Sacks</strong>, an entrepreneur and Silicon Valley venture capitalist who argues that the Biden administration&#8217;s approach to AI and cryptocurrency has driven innovation overseas. Sacks recently asserted that non-fungible cryptocurrency tokens and memecoins are neither securities nor commodities, but rather should be treated as &#8220;collectibles&#8221; like baseball cards and stamps.</p>
<p><span class="s1">There is already a legal definition of collectibles under the U.S. tax code that applies to things like art or antiques, which can be subject to high capital gains taxes. But <strong>Joe Hall</strong>, a capital markets attorney and partner at Davis Polk, <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/crypto-czar-david-sacks-says-224508277.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAL0Zay1PbdGAe14O3Q6FoNdB1zkg6wbzSRDfb7oPUC6Wd6zrQ6vU2RRSCVbDRAzdKV-8hUw3m5wdMKoCzprArK-YuIyoeEjJwTP3ZNk1AoW8dVIhp4KFD3-c9i7NrrUPaY3u2e2yLSFfzlqeJDnJ55BTbyBLHx9pM_KywC0pCxWf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told <em>Fortune</em></a> there are</span> no market regulations that apply to collectibles under U.S. securities law. Hall said Sacks’ comments “suggest a viewpoint that it would not be appropriate to regulate these things the way we regulate securities.”</p>
<p>The new administration&#8217;s position makes sense considering that the Trump family is deeply and personally invested in a number of recent memecoin ventures that have attracted billions from investors. President Trump and First Lady Melania Trump each launched their own vanity memecoins this month, dubbed <strong>$TRUMP</strong> and <strong>$MELANIA</strong>.</p>
<p><em>The Wall Street Journal</em> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/finance/trump-meme-coin-crypto-explained-c881afff" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported Thursday</a> the market capitalization of $TRUMP stood at about $7 billion, down from a peak of near $15 billion, while $MELANIA is hovering somewhere in the $460 million mark. Just two months before the 2024 election, Trump&#8217;s three sons debuted a cryptocurrency token called <strong>World Liberty Financial</strong>.</p>
<p>Despite maintaining a considerable personal stake in how cryptocurrency is regulated, Trump issued <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/01/fact-sheet-executive-order-to-establish-united-states-leadership-in-digital-financial-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an executive order on January 23</a> calling for a working group to be chaired by Sacks that would develop &#8220;a federal regulatory framework governing digital assets, including stablecoins,&#8221; and evaluate the creation of a &#8220;strategic national digital assets stockpile.&#8221;</p>
<p>Translation: Using taxpayer dollars to prop up the speculative, volatile, and highly risky cryptocurrency industry, which has been marked by endless scams, rug-pulls, 8-figure cyber heists, rampant fraud, and unrestrained innovations in money laundering.<span id="more-70172"></span></p>
<h2>WEAPONIZATION &amp; DISINFORMATION</h2>
<p>Prior to the election, President Trump frequently vowed to use a second term to exact retribution against his perceived enemies. Part of that promise materialized in an executive order Trump issued last week titled &#8220;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/ending-the-weaponization-of-the-federal-government/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ending the Weaponization of the Federal Government</a>,&#8221; which decried &#8220;an unprecedented, third-world weaponization of prosecutorial power to upend the democratic process,&#8221; in the prosecution of more than 1,500 people who invaded the U.S. Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021.</p>
<p>On Jan. 21, Trump <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/justice-department/trump-set-pardon-defendants-stormed-capitol-jan-6-2021-rcna187735" target="_blank" rel="noopener">commuted the sentences</a> of several leaders of the Proud Boys and Oath Keepers who were convicted of seditious conspiracy. He also issued &#8220;a full, complete and unconditional pardon to all other individuals convicted of offenses related to events that occurred at or near the United States Capitol on January 6, 2021,&#8221; which include those who assaulted law enforcement officers.</p>
<p>The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/20/us/politics/weaponization-government-executive-order-trump.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> &#8220;the language of the document suggests — but does not explicitly state — that the Trump administration review will examine the actions of local district attorneys or state officials, such as the district attorneys in Manhattan or Fulton County, Ga., or the New York attorney general, all of whom filed cases against President Trump.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another Trump order called &#8220;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/restoring-freedom-of-speech-and-ending-federal-censorship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Restoring Freedom of Speech and Ending Federal Censorship</a>&#8221; asserts:</p>
<p>&#8220;Over the last 4 years, the previous administration trampled free speech rights by censoring Americans’ speech on online platforms, often by exerting substantial coercive pressure on third parties, such as social media companies, to moderate, deplatform, or otherwise suppress speech that the Federal Government did not approve,&#8221; the Trump administration alleged. &#8220;Under the guise of combatting &#8216;misinformation,&#8217; &#8216;disinformation,&#8217; and &#8216;malinformation,&#8217; the Federal Government infringed on the constitutionally protected speech rights of American citizens across the United States in a manner that advanced the Government’s preferred narrative about significant matters of public debate.&#8221;</p>
<p>Both of these executive orders have <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/katestarbird.bsky.social/post/3kdu7ucy3jd2f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">potential implications</a> for security, privacy and civil liberties activists who have sought to track conspiracy theories and raise awareness about disinformation efforts on social media coming from U.S. adversaries.</p>
<p>In the wake of the 2020 election, Republicans created the <strong>House Judiciary Committee&#8217;s Select Subcommittee on the Weaponization of the Federal Government</strong>. Led by GOP <strong>Rep. Jim Jordan</strong> of Ohio, the committee&#8217;s stated purpose was to investigate alleged collusion between the Biden administration and tech companies to unconstitutionally shut down political speech.</p>
<p>The GOP committee focused much of its ire at members of the short-lived <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disinformation_Governance_Board" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Disinformation Governance Board</a>, an advisory board to DHS created in 2022 (the &#8220;combating misinformation, disinformation, and malinformation&#8221; quote from Trump&#8217;s executive order is a reference to the board&#8217;s stated mission). Conservative groups seized on social media posts made by the director of the board, who <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/05/21/1100438703/dhs-disinformation-board-nina-jankowicz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">resigned</a> after facing death threats. The board was dissolved by DHS soon after.</p>
<p>In his first administration, President Trump created a special prosecutor to probe the origins of the FBI&#8217;s investigation into possible collusion between the Trump campaign and Russian operatives seeking to influence the 2016 election. Part of that inquiry examined evidence gathered by some of the world’s most renowned cybersecurity experts who identified <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/09/lawsuits-indictments-revive-trump-alfa-bank-story/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">frequent and unexplained communications</a> between an email server used by the <strong>Trump Organization</strong> and <strong>Alfa Bank</strong>, one of Russia’s largest financial institutions.</p>
<p>Trump&#8217;s Special Prosecutor <strong>John Durham</strong> later subpoenaed and/or deposed dozens of security experts who&#8217;d collected, viewed or merely commented on the data. Similar harassment and deposition demands would come from lawyers for Alfa Bank. Durham ultimately indicted <strong>Michael Sussman</strong>, the former federal cybercrime prosecutor who reported the oddity to the FBI. Sussman was acquitted in May 2022. Last week, Trump appointed Durham to lead the U.S. attorney&#8217;s office in Brooklyn, NY.</p>
<p><strong>Quinta Jurecic</strong> at <em>Lawfare</em> <a href="https://www.lawfaremedia.org/article/what-do-trump-s-weaponization-and-censorship-executive-orders-actually-do" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notes</a> that while the executive actions are ominous, they are also vague, and could conceivably generate either a campaign of retaliation, or nothing at all.</p>
<p>&#8220;The two orders establish that there will be investigations but leave open the questions of what kind of investigations, what will be investigated, how long this will take, and what the consequences might be,&#8221; Jurecic wrote. &#8220;It is difficult to draw firm conclusions as to what to expect. Whether this ambiguity is intentional or the result of sloppiness or disagreement within Trump’s team, it has at least one immediate advantage as far as the president is concerned: generating fear among the broad universe of potential subjects of those investigations.&#8221;</p>
<p>On Friday, Trump moved <a href="https://www.lawfaremedia.org/article/trump-fired-17-inspectors-general-was-it-legal" target="_blank" rel="noopener">to fire at least 17 inspectors general</a>, the government watchdogs who conduct audits and investigations of executive branch actions, and who often uncover instances of government waste, fraud and abuse. Lawfare&#8217;s <strong>Jack Goldsmith</strong> argues that the removals are probably legal even though Trump defied a 2022 law that required congressional notice of the terminations, which Trump did not give.</p>
<p>&#8220;Trump probably acted lawfully, I think, because the notice requirement is probably unconstitutional,&#8221; Goldsmith wrote. &#8220;The real bite in the 2022 law, however, comes in the limitations it places on Trump’s power <em>to replace</em> the terminated IGs—limitations that I believe are constitutional. This aspect of the law will make it hard, but not impossible, for Trump to put loyalists atop the dozens of vacant IG offices around the executive branch. The ultimate fate of IG independence during Trump 2.0, however, depends less on legal protections than on whether Congress, which traditionally protects IGs, stands up for them now. Don’t hold your breath.&#8221;</p>
<p>Among the many Biden administration executive orders revoked by President Trump last week was an action from December 2021 establishing the <strong>United States Council on Transnational Organized Crime</strong>, which is charged with advising the White House on a range of criminal activities, including drug and weapons trafficking, migrant smuggling, human trafficking, cybercrime, intellectual property theft, money laundering, wildlife and timber trafficking, illegal fishing, and illegal mining.</p>
<p>So far, the White House doesn&#8217;t appear to have revoked <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250117143627/https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2025/01/16/executive-order-on-strengthening-and-promoting-innovation-in-the-nations-cybersecurity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an executive order</a> that former President Biden issued less than a week before President Trump took office. On Jan. 16, 2025, Biden released a directive that focused on improving the security of federal agencies and contractors, and giving the government more power to sanction the hackers who target critical infrastructure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-tumultuous-week-for-federal-cybersecurity-efforts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>106</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MasterCard DNS Error Went Unnoticed for Years</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to Break Into Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akam.ne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akam.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Akamai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awsdns-06.ne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[az.mastercard.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bugcrowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CloudFlare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippe Caturegli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seralys]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The payment card giant MasterCard just fixed a glaring error in its domain name server settings that could have allowed anyone to intercept or divert Internet traffic for the company by registering an unused domain name. The misconfiguration persisted for nearly five years until a security researcher spent $300 to register the domain and prevent it from being grabbed by cybercriminals.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The payment card giant <strong>MasterCard</strong> just fixed a glaring error in its domain name server settings that could have allowed anyone to intercept or divert Internet traffic for the company by registering an unused domain name. The misconfiguration persisted for nearly five years until a security researcher spent $300 to register the domain and prevent it from being grabbed by cybercriminals.</p>
<div id="attachment_70128" style="width: 677px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70128" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70128" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/akamne.png" alt="" width="667" height="478" /><p id="caption-attachment-70128" class="wp-caption-text">A DNS lookup on the domain az.mastercard.com on Jan. 14, 2025 shows the mistyped domain name a22-65.akam.ne.</p></div>
<p>From June 30, 2020 until January 14, 2025, one of the core Internet servers that MasterCard uses to direct traffic for portions of the mastercard.com network was misnamed. MasterCard.com relies on five shared Domain Name System (DNS) servers at the Internet infrastructure provider <strong>Akamai </strong>[DNS acts as a kind of Internet phone book, by translating website names to numeric Internet addresses that are easier for computers to manage].</p>
<p>All of the Akamai DNS server names that MasterCard uses are supposed to end in &#8220;akam.net&#8221; but one of them was misconfigured to rely on the domain &#8220;<strong>akam.ne</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>This tiny but potentially critical typo was discovered recently by <strong>Philippe Caturegli</strong>, founder of the security consultancy <a href="https://www.seralys.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Seralys</a>. Caturegli said he guessed that nobody had yet registered the domain akam.ne, which is under the purview of the top-level domain authority for the West Africa nation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Niger</a>.</p>
<p>Caturegli said it took $300 and nearly three months of waiting to secure the domain with the registry in Niger. After enabling a DNS server on akam.ne, he noticed hundreds of thousands of DNS requests hitting his server each day from locations around the globe. Apparently, MasterCard wasn&#8217;t the only organization that had fat-fingered a DNS entry to include &#8220;akam.ne,&#8221; but they were by far the largest.</p>
<p>Had he enabled an email server on his new domain akam.ne, Caturegli likely would have received wayward emails directed toward mastercard.com or other affected domains. If he&#8217;d abused his access, he probably could have <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/local-networks-go-global-when-domain-names-collide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">obtained website encryption certificates (SSL/TLS certs)</a> that were authorized to accept and relay web traffic for affected websites. He may even have been able to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/02/dangerous-domain-corp-com-goes-up-for-sale/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">passively receive Microsoft Windows authentication credentials</a> from employee computers at affected companies.</p>
<p>But the researcher said he didn&#8217;t attempt to do any of that. Instead, he alerted MasterCard that the domain was theirs if they wanted it, copying this author on his notifications. A few hours later, MasterCard acknowledged the mistake, but said there was never any real threat to the security of its operations.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have looked into the matter and there was not a risk to our systems,&#8221; a MasterCard spokesperson wrote. &#8220;This typo has now been corrected.&#8221;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Caturegli received a request submitted through <strong>Bugcrowd</strong>, a program that offers financial rewards and recognition to security researchers who find flaws and work privately with the affected vendor to fix them. The message suggested his public disclosure of the MasterCard DNS error via <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a post on LinkedIn</a> (after he&#8217;d secured the akam.ne domain) was not aligned with ethical security practices, and passed on a request from MasterCard to have the post removed.</p>
<div id="attachment_70126" style="width: 718px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70126" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70126" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-response.png" alt="" width="708" height="855" /><p id="caption-attachment-70126" class="wp-caption-text">MasterCard&#8217;s request to Caturegli, a.k.a. &#8220;Titon&#8221; on infosec.exchange.</p></div>
<p>Caturegli said while he does have an account on Bugcrowd, he has never submitted anything through the Bugcrowd program, and that he reported this issue directly to MasterCard.</p>
<p>&#8220;I did not disclose this issue through Bugcrowd,&#8221; Caturegli wrote in reply. &#8220;Before making any public disclosure, I ensured that the affected domain was registered to prevent exploitation, mitigating any risk to MasterCard or its customers. This action, which we took at our own expense, demonstrates our commitment to ethical security practices and responsible disclosure.&#8221; <span id="more-70117"></span></p>
<p>Most organizations have at least two authoritative domain name servers, but some handle so many DNS requests that they need to spread the load over additional DNS server domains. In MasterCard&#8217;s case, that number is five, so it stands to reason that if an attacker managed to seize control over just one of those domains they would only be able to see about one-fifth of the overall DNS requests coming in.</p>
<p>But Caturegli said the reality is that many Internet users are relying at least to some degree on public traffic forwarders or DNS resolvers like <strong>Cloudflare</strong> and <strong>Google</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;So all we need is for one of these resolvers to query our name server and cache the result,&#8221; Caturegli said. By setting their DNS server records with a long TTL or &#8220;Time To Live&#8221; &#8212; a setting that can adjust the lifespan of data packets on a network &#8212; an attacker&#8217;s poisoned instructions for the target domain can be propagated by large cloud providers.</p>
<p>&#8220;With a long TTL, we may reroute a LOT more than just 1/5 of the traffic,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The researcher said he&#8217;d hoped that the credit card giant might thank him, or at least offer to cover the cost of buying the domain.</p>
<p>&#8220;We obviously disagree with this assessment,&#8221; Caturegli wrote in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285289297706909697%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285289297706909697%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a follow-up post</a> on LinkedIn regarding MasterCard&#8217;s public statement. &#8220;But we’ll let you judge— here are some of the DNS lookups we recorded before reporting the issue.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70125" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70125" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70125" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains.png" alt="" width="790" height="561" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains.png 790w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-768x545.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-782x555.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 790px) 100vw, 790px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70125" class="wp-caption-text">Caturegli posted this screenshot of MasterCard domains that were potentially at risk from the misconfigured domain.</p></div>
<p>As the screenshot above shows, the misconfigured DNS server Caturegli found involved the MasterCard subdomain <strong>az.mastercard.com</strong>. It is not clear exactly how this subdomain is used by MasterCard, however their naming conventions suggest the domains correspond to production servers at Microsoft&#8217;s <strong>Azure</strong> cloud service. Caturegli said the domains all resolve to Internet addresses at Microsoft.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don’t be like Mastercard,&#8221; Caturegli concluded in his LinkedIn post. &#8220;Don’t dismiss risk, and don’t let your marketing team handle security disclosures.&#8221;</p>
<p>One final note: The domain akam.ne has been registered previously &#8212; in December 2016 by someone using the email address um-i-delo@yandex.ru. The Russian search giant Yandex reports this user account belongs to an &#8220;Ivan I.&#8221; from Moscow. Passive DNS records from <a href="https://www.domaintools.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DomainTools.com</a> show that between 2016 and 2018 the domain was connected to an Internet server in Germany, and that the domain was left to expire in 2018.</p>
<p>This is interesting given <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285221445796835329%29&amp;replyUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285223757982363648%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285221445796835329%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29&amp;dashReplyUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285223757982363648%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a comment on Caturegli&#8217;s LinkedIn post from an ex-Cloudflare employee</a> who linked to a report he co-authored on a similar typo domain apparently registered in 2017 for organizations that may have mistyped their AWS DNS server as &#8220;<strong>awsdns-06.ne</strong>&#8221; instead of &#8220;<strong>awsdns-06.net</strong>.&#8221; DomainTools reports that this typo domain also was registered to a Yandex user (playlotto@yandex.ru), and was hosted at the same German ISP &#8212; Team Internet (AS61969).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>104</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese Innovations Spawn Wave of Toll Phishing Via SMS</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/chinese-innovations-spawn-wave-of-toll-phishing-via-sms/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/chinese-innovations-spawn-wave-of-toll-phishing-via-sms/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 21:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@chenlun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSIS Security Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EZDriveMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Merrill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ic3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iMessage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lighthouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MassDOT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Texas Toll Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RCS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SecAlliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Toll Roads]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Residents across the United States are being inundated with text messages purporting to come from toll road operators like E-ZPass, warning that recipients face fines if a delinquent toll fee remains unpaid. Researchers say the surge in SMS spam coincides with new features added to a popular commercial phishing kit sold in China that makes it simple to set up convincing lures spoofing toll road operators in multiple U.S. states.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Residents across the United States are being inundated with text messages purporting to come from toll road operators like <strong>E-ZPass</strong>, warning that recipients face fines if a delinquent toll fee remains unpaid. Researchers say the surge in SMS spam coincides with new features added to a popular commercial phishing kit sold in China that makes it simple to set up convincing lures spoofing toll road operators in multiple U.S. states.</p>
<p>Last week, the <strong>Massachusetts Department of Transportation</strong> (MassDOT) <a href="https://www.ezdrivema.com/About-EzdriveMA/Smishing-Alert" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warned residents</a> to be on the lookout for a new SMS phishing or &#8220;smishing&#8221; scam targeting users of <strong>EZDriveMA</strong>, MassDOT&#8217;s all electronic tolling program. Those who fall for the scam are asked to provide payment card data, and eventually will be asked to supply a one-time password sent via SMS or a mobile authentication app.</p>
<p>Reports of similar SMS phishing attacks against customers of other U.S. state-run toll facilities surfaced around the same time as the MassDOT alert. People in Florida reported receiving SMS phishing that spoofed <strong>Sunpass</strong>, Florida&#8217;s prepaid toll program.</p>
<div id="attachment_70096" style="width: 503px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70096" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70096" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/lighthouse-ezdrive.png" alt="" width="493" height="683" /><p id="caption-attachment-70096" class="wp-caption-text">This phishing module for spoofing MassDOT&#8217;s EZDrive toll system was offered on Jan. 10, 2025 by a China-based SMS phishing service called &#8220;Lighthouse.&#8221;</p></div>
<p>In Texas, residents said they received text messages about unpaid tolls with the <strong>North Texas Toll Authority</strong>. Similar reports came from readers in California, Colorado, Connecticut, Minnesota, and Washington. This is by no means a comprehensive list.</p>
<div id="attachment_70097" style="width: 503px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70097" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70097" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/lighthouse-ntta.png" alt="" width="493" height="683" /><p id="caption-attachment-70097" class="wp-caption-text">A new module from the Lighthouse SMS phishing kit released Jan. 14 targets customers of the North Texas Toll Authority (NTTA).</p></div>
<p>In each case, the emergence of these SMS phishing attacks coincided with the release of new phishing kit capabilities that closely mimic these toll operator websites as they appear on mobile devices. Notably, none of the phishing pages will even load unless the website detects that the visitor is coming from a mobile device.</p>
<p><strong>Ford Merrill</strong> works in security research at <a href="https://www.secalliance.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SecAlliance</a>, a <a href="https://www.csis.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSIS Security Group</a> company. Merrill said the volume of SMS phishing attacks spoofing toll road operators skyrocketed after the New Year, when at least one Chinese cybercriminal group known for selling sophisticated SMS phishing kits began offering new phishing pages designed to spoof toll operators in various U.S. states.</p>
<p>According to Merrill, multiple China-based cybercriminals are selling distinct SMS-based phishing kits that each have hundreds or thousands of customers. The ultimate goal of these kits, he said, is to phish enough information from victims that their payment cards can be added to mobile wallets and used to buy goods at physical stores, online, or to launder money through shell companies.<span id="more-70091"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_70098" style="width: 503px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70098" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70098" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/lighthouse-tollroads.png" alt="" width="493" height="683" /><p id="caption-attachment-70098" class="wp-caption-text">A component of the Chinese SMS phishing kit Lighthouse made to target customers of The Toll Roads, which refers to several state routes through Orange County, Calif.</p></div>
<p>Merrill said the different purveyors of these SMS phishing tools traditionally have impersonated shipping companies, customs authorities, and even governments with tax refund lures and visa or immigration renewal scams targeting people who may be living abroad or new to a country.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re seeing with these tolls scams is just a continuation of the Chinese smishing groups rotating from package redelivery schemes to toll road scams,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;Every one of us by now is sick and tired of receiving these package smishing attacks, so now it&#8217;s a new twist on an existing scam.”</p>
<p>In October 2023, KrebsOnSecurity wrote about <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/10/phishers-spoof-usps-12-other-natl-postal-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a massive uptick in SMS phishing scams targeting <strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong> customers</a>. That story revealed the surge was tied to innovations introduced by &#8220;<strong>Chenlun</strong>,&#8221; a mainland China-based proprietor of a popular phishing kit and service. At the time, Chenlun had just introduced new phishing pages made to impersonate postal services in the United States and at least a dozen other countries.</p>
<p>SMS phishing kits are hardly new, but Merrill said Chinese smishing groups recently have introduced innovations in deliverability, by more seamlessly integrating their spam messages with Apple&#8217;s <strong>iMessage</strong> technology, and with <a href="https://support.google.com/messages/answer/7189714?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RCS</a>, the equivalent &#8220;rich text&#8221; messaging capability built into <strong>Android</strong> devices.</p>
<p>“While traditional smishing kits relied heavily on SMS for delivery, nowadays the actors make heavy use of iMessage and RCS because telecom operators can’t filter them and they likely have a higher success rate with these delivery channels,” he said.</p>
<p>It remains unclear how the phishers have selected their targets, or from where their data may be sourced. A notice from MassDOT cautions that &#8220;the targeted phone numbers seem to be chosen at random and are not uniquely associated with an account or usage of toll roads.&#8221;</p>
<p>Indeed, one reader shared on Mastodon yesterday that they&#8217;d received one of these SMS phishing attacks spoofing a local toll operator, when they didn&#8217;t even own a vehicle.</p>
<p>Targeted or not, these phishing websites are dangerous because they are operated dynamically in real-time by criminals. If you receive one of these messages, just ignore it or delete it, but please do not visit the phishing site. The FBI asks that before you bin the missives, consider filing a complaint with the agency&#8217;s <a href="https://www.ic3.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Internet Crime Complaint Center</a> (IC3), including the phone number where the text originated, and the website listed within the text.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/chinese-innovations-spawn-wave-of-toll-phishing-via-sms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft: Happy 2025. Here&#8217;s 161 Security Updates</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/microsoft-happy-2025-heres-161-security-updates/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/microsoft-happy-2025-heres-161-security-updates/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 22:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben Hopkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitlocker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-49142]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21186]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21210]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21298]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21311]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21333]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21334]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21335]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21366]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21395]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kev Breen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Patch Tuesday January 2025]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satnam Narang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unpatched.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Hyper-V]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows NTLMv1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70070</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today unleashed updates to plug a whopping 161 security vulnerabilities in Windows and related software, including three "zero-day" weaknesses that are already under active attack. Redmond's inaugural Patch Tuesday of 2025 bundles more fixes than the company has shipped in one go since 2017.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today unleashed updates to plug a whopping 161 security vulnerabilities in <strong>Windows</strong> and related software, including three &#8220;zero-day&#8221; weaknesses that are already under active attack. Redmond&#8217;s inaugural Patch Tuesday of 2025 bundles more fixes than the company has shipped in one go since 2017.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-60331" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png" alt="" width="749" height="496" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png 923w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-768x508.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-782x518.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p><strong>Rapid7</strong>&#8216;s <strong>Adam Barnett</strong> says January marks the fourth consecutive month where Microsoft has published zero-day vulnerabilities on Patch Tuesday without evaluating any of them as critical severity at time of publication. Today also saw the publication of nine critical remote code execution (RCE) vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>The Microsoft flaws already seeing active attacks include <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21333" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21333</a>, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21334" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21334</a> and, you guessed it&#8211; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21335" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21335</a>. These are sequential because all reside in <strong>Windows Hyper-V</strong>, a component that is heavily embedded in modern <strong>Windows 11</strong> operating systems and used for security features including device guard and credential guard.</p>
<p>Tenable&#8217;s <strong>Satnam Narang</strong> says little is known about the in-the-wild exploitation of these flaws, apart from the fact that they are all &#8220;privilege escalation&#8221; vulnerabilities. Narang said we tend to see a lot of elevation of privilege bugs exploited in the wild as zero-days in Patch Tuesday because it&#8217;s not always initial access to a system that&#8217;s a challenge for attackers as they have various avenues in their pursuit.</p>
<p>&#8220;As elevation of privilege bugs, they’re being used as part of post-compromise activity, where an attacker has already accessed a target system,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It&#8217;s kind of like if an attacker is able to enter a secure building, they’re unable to access more secure parts of the facility because they have to prove that they have clearance. In this case, they’re able to trick the system into believing they should have clearance.&#8221;<span id="more-70070"></span></p>
<p>Several bugs addressed today earned CVSS (threat rating) scores of 9.8 out of a possible 10, including <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21298" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21298</a>, a weakness in Windows that could allow attackers to run arbitrary code by getting a target to open a malicious <strong>.rtf</strong> file, documents typically opened on Office applications like Microsoft Word. Microsoft has rated this flaw &#8220;exploitation more likely.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Ben Hopkins</strong> at <strong>Immersive Labs</strong> called attention to the <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21311" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21311</a>, a 9.8 &#8220;critical&#8221; bug in <strong>Windows NTLMv1</strong> (NT LAN Manager version 1), an older Microsoft authentication protocol that is still used by many organizations.</p>
<p>&#8220;What makes this vulnerability so impactful is the fact that it is remotely exploitable, so attackers can reach the compromised machine(s) over the internet, and the attacker does not need significant knowledge or skills to achieve repeatable success with the same payload across any vulnerable component,&#8221; Hopkins wrote.</p>
<p><strong>Kev Breen</strong> at Immersive points to an interesting flaw (<a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21210" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21210</a>) that Microsoft fixed in its full disk encryption suite <strong>Bitlocker</strong> that the software giant has dubbed &#8220;exploitation more likely.&#8221; Specifically, this bug holds out the possibility that in some situations the hibernation image created when one closes the laptop lid on an open Windows session may not be fully encrypted and could be recovered in plain text.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hibernation images are used when a laptop goes to sleep and contains the contents that were stored in RAM at the moment the device powered down,&#8221; Breen noted. &#8220;This presents a significant potential impact as RAM can contain sensitive data (such as passwords, credentials and PII) that may have been in open documents or browser sessions and can all be recovered with free tools from hibernation files.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tenable&#8217;s Narang also highlighted a trio of vulnerabilities in <strong>Microsoft Access</strong> fixed this month and credited to Unpatched.ai, a security research effort that is aided by artificial intelligence looking for vulnerabilities in code. Tracked as <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21186" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21186</a>, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21366" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21366</a>, and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21395" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21395</a>, these are remote code execution bugs that are exploitable if an attacker convinces a target to download and run a malicious file through social engineering. Unpatched.ai was also credited with discovering a flaw in the December 2024 Patch Tuesday release (<a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-49142" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-49142</a>).</p>
<p>&#8220;Automated vulnerability detection using AI has garnered a lot of attention recently, so it’s noteworthy to see this service being credited with finding bugs in Microsoft products,&#8221; Narang observed. &#8220;It may be the first of many in 2025.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a Windows user who has automatic updates turned off and haven&#8217;t updated in a while, it&#8217;s probably time to play catch up. Please consider backing up important files and/or the entire hard drive before updating. And if you run into any problems installing this month&#8217;s patch batch, drop a line in the comments below, please.</p>
<p>Further reading on today&#8217;s patches from Microsoft:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tenable.com/blog/microsofts-january-2025-patch-tuesday-157-cves-cve-2025-21333-cve-2025-21334-cve-2025-21335" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tenable blog</a></p>
<p><a href="https://isc.sans.edu/forums/diary/Microsoft%20January%202025%20Patch%20Tuesday/31590/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SANS Internet Storm Center</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.askwoody.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ask Woody</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/microsoft-happy-2025-heres-161-security-updates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Day in the Life of a Prolific Voice Phishing Crew</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 23:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[800-275-2273]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allison Nixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aristotle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autodoxers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Chameleon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lookout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Cuban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shark Tank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stotle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trezor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 221B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice phishing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Besieged by scammers seeking to phish user accounts over the telephone, Apple and Google frequently caution that they will never reach out unbidden to users this way. However, new details about the internal operations of a prolific voice phishing gang show the group routinely abuses legitimate services at Apple and Google to force a variety of outbound communications to their users, including emails, automated phone calls and system-level messages sent to all signed-in devices.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Besieged by scammers seeking to phish user accounts over the telephone, <strong>Apple</strong> and <strong>Google</strong> frequently caution that they will never reach out unbidden to users this way. However, new details about the internal operations of a prolific voice phishing gang show the group routinely abuses legitimate services at Apple and Google to force a variety of outbound communications to their users, including emails, automated phone calls and system-level messages sent to all signed-in devices.</p>
<div id="attachment_69859" style="width: 711px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69859" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-69859" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/thumb-mobile.png" alt="" width="701" height="413" /><p id="caption-attachment-69859" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, iHaMoo.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity recently told the saga of a cryptocurrency investor named <strong>Tony</strong> who was robbed of more than $4.7 million in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-to-lose-a-fortune-with-just-one-bad-click/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an elaborate voice phishing attack</a>. In Tony&#8217;s ordeal, the crooks appear to have initially contacted him via <strong>Google Assistant</strong>, an AI-based service that can engage in two-way conversations. The phishers also abused legitimate Google services to send Tony an email from google.com, and to send a Google account recovery prompt to all of his signed-in devices.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s story pivots off of Tony&#8217;s heist and new details shared by a scammer to explain how these voice phishing groups are abusing a legitimate Apple telephone support line to generate &#8220;account confirmation&#8221; message prompts from Apple to their customers.</p>
<p>Before we get to the Apple scam in detail, we need to revisit Tony&#8217;s case. The phishing domain used to steal roughly $4.7 million in cryptocurrencies from Tony was <strong>verify-trezor[.]io</strong>. This domain was featured in <a href="https://www.lookout.com/threat-intelligence/article/cryptochameleon-fcc-phishing-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a writeup from February 2024</a> by the security firm <strong>Lookout</strong>, which found it was one of dozens being used by a prolific and audacious voice phishing group it dubbed &#8220;<strong>Crypto Chameleon</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Crypto Chameleon was brazenly trying to voice phish employees at the <strong>U.S. Federal Communications Commission</strong> (FCC), as well as those working at the cryptocurrency exchanges <strong>Coinbase</strong> and <strong>Binance</strong>. Lookout researchers discovered multiple voice phishing groups were using a new phishing kit that closely mimicked the single sign-on pages for <strong>Okta</strong> and other authentication providers.</p>
<p>As we&#8217;ll see in a moment, that phishing kit is operated and rented out by a cybercriminal known as &#8220;<strong>Perm</strong>&#8221; a.k.a. &#8220;<strong>Annie</strong>.&#8221; Perm is the current administrator of <strong>Star Fraud</strong>, one of the more consequential cybercrime communities on Telegram and one that has emerged as a foundry of innovation in voice phishing attacks.</p>
<p>A review of the many messages that Perm posted to Star Fraud and other Telegram channels showed they worked closely with another cybercriminal who went by the handles &#8220;<strong>Aristotle</strong>&#8221; and just &#8220;<strong>Stotle</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>It is not clear what caused the rift, but at some point last year Stotle decided to turn on his erstwhile business partner Perm, sharing extremely detailed videos, tutorials and secrets that shed new light on how these phishing panels operate.</p>
<p>Stotle explained that the division of spoils from each robbery is decided in advance by all participants. Some co-conspirators will be paid a set fee for each call, while others are promised a percentage of any overall amount stolen. The person in charge of managing or renting out the phishing panel to others will generally take a percentage of each theft, which in Perm&#8217;s case is 10 percent.</p>
<p>When the phishing group settles on a target of interest, the scammers will create and join a new <strong>Discord</strong> channel. This allows each logged on member to share what is currently on their screen, and these screens are tiled in a series of boxes so that everyone can see all other call participant screens at once.</p>
<p>Each participant in the call has a specific role, including:</p>
<p>-The Caller: The person speaking and trying to social engineer the target.<br />
-The Operator: The individual managing the phishing panel, silently moving the victim from page to page.<br />
-The Drainer: The person who logs into compromised accounts to drain the victim&#8217;s funds.<br />
-The Owner: The phishing panel owner, who will frequently listen in on and participate in scam calls.</p>
<h2>&#8216;OKAY, SO THIS REALLY IS APPLE&#8217;</h2>
<p>In one video of a live voice phishing attack shared by Stotle, scammers using Perm&#8217;s panel targeted a musician in California. Throughout the video, we can see Perm monitoring the conversation and operating the phishing panel in the upper right corner of the screen.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F44un1_y2fs?si=fmYxbcLS3TDtHjrs" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></div>
<p>In the first step of the attack, they <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/recent-mfa-bombing-attacks-targeting-apple-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">peppered the target&#8217;s Apple device with notifications from Apple</a> by attempting to reset his password. Then a &#8220;<strong>Michael Keen</strong>&#8221; called him, spoofing Apple&#8217;s phone number and saying they were with Apple&#8217;s account recovery team.</p>
<p>The target told Michael that someone was trying to change his password, which Michael calmly explained they would investigate. Michael said he was going to send a prompt to the man&#8217;s device, and proceeded to place a call to an automated line that answered as Apple support saying, &#8220;I&#8217;d like to send a consent notification to your Apple devices. Do I have permission to do that?&#8221;</p>
<p>In this segment of the video, we can see the operator of the panel is calling the real Apple customer support phone number <strong>800-275-2273</strong>, but they are doing so by spoofing the target&#8217;s phone number (the victim&#8217;s number is redacted in the video above). That&#8217;s because calling this support number from a phone number tied to an Apple account and selecting &#8220;1&#8221; for &#8220;yes&#8221; will then send an alert from Apple that displays the following message on all associated devices:</p>
<div id="attachment_70000" style="width: 403px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70000" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70000" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/appleconfirmation.png" alt="" width="393" height="448" /><p id="caption-attachment-70000" class="wp-caption-text">Calling the Apple support number 800-275-2273 from a phone number tied to an Apple account will cause a prompt similar to this one to appear on all connected Apple devices.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity asked two different security firms to test this using the caller ID spoofing service shown in Perm&#8217;s video, and sure enough calling that 800 number for Apple by spoofing my phone number as the source caused the Apple Account Confirmation to pop up on all of my signed-in Apple devices.</p>
<p>In essence, the voice phishers are using an automated Apple phone support line to send notifications from Apple and to trick people into thinking they&#8217;re really talking with Apple. The phishing panel video leaked by Stotle shows this technique fooled the target, who felt completely at ease that he was talking to Apple after receiving the support prompt on his iPhone.</p>
<p>&#8220;Okay, so this really is Apple,&#8221; the man said after receiving the alert from Apple. &#8220;Yeah, that&#8217;s definitely not me trying to reset my password.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Not a problem, we can go ahead and take care of this today,&#8221; Michael replied. &#8220;I&#8217;ll go ahead and prompt your device with the steps to close out this ticket. Before I do that, I do highly suggest that you change your password in the settings app of your device.&#8221;</p>
<p>The target said they weren&#8217;t sure exactly how to do that. Michael replied &#8220;no problem,&#8221; and then described how to change the account password, which the man said he did on his own device. At this point, the musician was still in control of his iCloud account.</p>
<p>&#8220;Password is changed,&#8221; the man said. &#8220;I don&#8217;t know what that was, but I appreciate the call.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Yup,&#8221; Michael replied, setting up the killer blow. &#8220;I&#8217;ll go ahead and prompt you with the next step to close out this ticket. Please give me one moment.&#8221;</p>
<p>The target then received a text message that referenced information about his account, stating that he was in a support call with Michael. Included in the message was a link to a website that mimicked Apple&#8217;s iCloud login page &#8212; <strong>17505-apple[.]com</strong>. Once the target navigated to the phishing page, the video showed Perm&#8217;s screen in the upper right corner opening the phishing page from their end.</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh okay, now I log in with my Apple ID?,&#8221; the man asked.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yup, then just follow the steps it requires, and if you need any help, just let me know,&#8221; Michael replied.</p>
<p>As the victim typed in their Apple password and one-time passcode at the fake Apple site, Perm&#8217;s screen could be seen in the background logging into the victim&#8217;s iCloud account.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear whether the phishers were able to steal any cryptocurrency from the victim in this case, who did not respond to requests for comment. However, shortly after this video was recorded, someone leaked several music recordings stolen from the victim&#8217;s iCloud account.</p>
<p>At the conclusion of the call, Michael offered to configure the victim&#8217;s Apple profile so that any further changes to the account would need to happen in person at a physical Apple store. This appears to be one of several scripted ploys used by these voice phishers to gain and maintain the target&#8217;s confidence.</p>
<p>A tutorial shared by Stotle titled &#8220;Social Engineering Script&#8221; includes a number of tips for scam callers that can help establish trust or a rapport with their prey. When the callers are impersonating Coinbase employees, for example, they will offer to sign the user up for the company&#8217;s free security email newsletter.</p>
<p>&#8220;Also, for your security, we are able to subscribe you to Coinbase Bytes, which will basically give you updates to your email about data breaches and updates to your Coinbase account,&#8221; the script reads. &#8220;So we should have gone ahead and successfully subscribed you, and you should have gotten an email confirmation. Please let me know if that is the case. Alright, perfect.&#8221;</p>
<p>In reality, all they are doing is entering the target&#8217;s email address into Coinbase&#8217;s public email newsletter signup page, but it&#8217;s a remarkably effective technique because it demonstrates to the would-be victim that the caller has the ability to send emails from Coinbase.com.</p>
<p>Asked to comment for this story, Apple said there has been no breach, hack, or technical exploit of iCloud or Apple services, and that the company is continuously adding new protections to address new and emerging threats. For example, it said it has implemented rate limiting for multi-factor authentication requests, which <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/recent-mfa-bombing-attacks-targeting-apple-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">have been abused by voice phishing groups to impersonate Apple</a>.</p>
<p>Apple said its representatives will never ask users to provide their password, device passcode, or two-factor authentication code or to enter it into a web page, even if it looks like an official Apple website. If a user receives a message or call that claims to be from Apple, <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/120569" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here is what the user should expect</a>.</p>
<p><span id="more-69922"></span></p>
<h2>AUTODOXERS</h2>
<p>According to Stotle, the target lists used by their phishing callers originate mostly from a few crypto-related data breaches, including the 2022 and <a href="https://blog.trezor.io/trezor-security-update-stay-vigilant-against-potential-phishing-attack-bb05015a21f8?gi=4a9e1da3b8b2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2024 breaches</a> involving user account data stolen from cryptocurrency hardware wallet vendor <strong>Trezor</strong>.</p>
<p>Perm&#8217;s group and other crypto phishing gangs rely on a mix of homemade code and third-party data broker services to refine their target lists. Known as &#8220;<strong>autodoxers</strong>,&#8221; these tools help phishing gangs quickly automate the acquisition and/or verification of personal data on a target prior to each call attempt.</p>
<div id="attachment_69998" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69998" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69998" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vbals-autodoxer.png" alt="" width="748" height="592" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vbals-autodoxer.png 1067w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vbals-autodoxer-768x607.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vbals-autodoxer-782x619.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69998" class="wp-caption-text">One &#8220;autodoxer&#8221; service advertised on Telegram that promotes a range of voice phishing tools and services.</p></div>
<p>Stotle said their autodoxer used a Telegram bot that leverages hacked accounts at consumer data brokers to gather a wealth of information about their targets, including their full Social Security number, date of birth, current and previous addresses, employer, and the names of family members.</p>
<p>The autodoxers are used to verify that each email address on a target list has an active account at Coinbase or another cryptocurrency exchange, ensuring that the attackers don&#8217;t waste time calling people who have no cryptocurrency to steal.</p>
<p>Some of these autodoxer tools also will check the value of the target&#8217;s home address at property search services online, and then sort the target lists so that the wealthiest are at the top.</p>
<h2>CRYPTO THIEVES IN THE SHARK TANK</h2>
<p>Stotle&#8217;s messages on Discord and Telegram show that a phishing group renting Perm&#8217;s panel voice-phished tens of thousands of dollars worth of cryptocurrency from the billionaire <strong>Mark Cuban</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was an idiot,&#8221; Cuban told KrebsOnsecurity when asked about <a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/business/2024/06/23/mark-cubans-public-email-was-hacked-after-receiving-call-from-a-fake-google-rep/?outputType=amp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the June 2024 attack</a>, which he first disclosed in a short-lived post on Twitter/X. &#8220;We were shooting Shark Tank and I was rushing between pitches.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70008" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70008" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70008" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/sharktank.png" alt="" width="749" height="435" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/sharktank.png 780w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/sharktank-768x446.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70008" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, ssi77.</p></div>
<p>Cuban said he first received a notice from Google that someone had tried to log in to his account. Then he got a call from what appeared to be a Google phone number. Cuban said he ignored several of these emails and calls until he decided they probably wouldn&#8217;t stop unless he answered.</p>
<p>&#8220;So I answered, and wasn&#8217;t paying enough attention,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They asked for the circled number that comes up on the screen. Like a moron, I gave it to them, and they were in.&#8221;</p>
<p>Unfortunately for Cuban, somewhere in his inbox were the secret &#8220;seed phrases&#8221; protecting two of his cryptocurrency accounts, and armed with those credentials the crooks were able to drain his funds. All told, the thieves managed to steal roughly $43,000 worth of cryptocurrencies from Cuban&#8217;s wallets &#8212; a relatively small heist for this crew.</p>
<p>&#8220;They must have done some keyword searches,&#8221; once inside his Gmail account, Cuban said. &#8220;I had sent myself an email I had forgotten about that had my seed words for 2 accounts that weren&#8217;t very active any longer. I had moved almost everything but some smaller balances to Coinbase.&#8221;</p>
<h2>LIFE IS A GAME: MONEY IS HOW WE KEEP SCORE</h2>
<p>Cybercriminals involved in voice phishing communities on Telegram are universally obsessed with their crypto holdings, mainly because in this community one&#8217;s demonstrable wealth is primarily what confers social status. It is not uncommon to see members sizing one another up using a verbal shorthand of &#8220;figs,&#8221; as in figures of crypto wealth.</p>
<p>For example, a low-level caller with no experience will sometimes be mockingly referred to as a 3fig or 3f, as in a person with less than $1,000 to their name. Salaries for callers are often also referenced this way, e.g. &#8220;Weekly salary: 5f.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70058" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70058" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70058" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/howitstartedhowitsgoing.png" alt="" width="749" height="416" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/howitstartedhowitsgoing.png 1265w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/howitstartedhowitsgoing-768x426.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/howitstartedhowitsgoing-782x434.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70058" class="wp-caption-text">This meme shared by Stotle uses humor to depict an all-too-common pathway for voice phishing callers, who are often minors recruited from gaming networks like Minecraft and Roblox. The image that Lookout used in its blog post for Crypto Chameleon can be seen in the lower right hooded figure.</p></div>
<p>Voice phishing groups frequently require new members to provide &#8220;proof of funds&#8221; &#8212; screenshots of their crypto holdings, ostensibly to demonstrate they are not penniless &#8212; before they&#8217;re allowed to join.</p>
<p>This proof of funds (POF) demand is typical among thieves selling high-dollar items, because it tends to cut down on the time-wasting inquiries from criminals who can&#8217;t afford what&#8217;s for sale anyway. But it has become so common in cybercrime communities that there are now several services designed to create fake POF images and videos, allowing customers to brag about large crypto holdings without actually possessing said wealth.</p>
<p>Several of the phishing panel videos shared by Stotle feature audio that suggests co-conspirators were practicing responses to certain call scenarios, while other members of the phishing group critiqued them or tried disrupt their social engineering by being verbally abusive.</p>
<p>These groups will organize and operate for a few weeks, but tend to disintegrate when one member of the conspiracy decides to steal some or all of the loot, referred to in these communities as &#8220;snaking&#8221; others out of their agreed-upon sums. Almost invariably, the phishing groups will splinter apart over the drama caused by one of these snaking events, and individual members eventually will then re-form a new phishing group.</p>
<p><strong>Allison Nixon</strong> is the chief research officer for <a href="https://www.unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a>, a cybersecurity firm in New York that has worked on a number of investigations involving these voice phishing groups. Nixon said the constant snaking within the voice phishing circles points to a psychological self-selection phenomenon that is in desperate need of academic study.</p>
<p>&#8220;In short, a person whose moral compass lets them rob old people will also be a bad business partner,&#8221; Nixon said. &#8220;This is another fundamental flaw in this ecosystem and why most groups end in betrayal. This structural problem is great for journalists and the police too. Lots of snitching.&#8221;</p>
<h2>POINTS FOR BRAZENNESS</h2>
<p>Asked about the size of Perm&#8217;s phishing enterprise, Stotle said there were dozens of distinct phishing groups paying to use Perm&#8217;s panel. He said each group was assigned their own subdomain on Perm&#8217;s main &#8220;command and control server,&#8221; which naturally uses the domain name <strong>commandandcontrolserver[.]com</strong>.</p>
<p>A review of that domain&#8217;s history via <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> shows there are at least 57 separate subdomains scattered across commandandcontrolserver[.]com and two other related control domains &#8212; <strong>thebackendserver[.]com</strong> and <strong>lookoutsucks[.]com</strong>. That latter domain was created and deployed shortly after Lookout published its blog post on Crypto Chameleon.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://urlscan.io/search/#page.url%3A%22captcha%3Forigin%3D%22" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dozens of phishing domains that phone home to these control servers</a> are all kept offline when they are not actively being used in phishing attacks. A social engineering training guide shared by Stotle explains this practice minimizes the chances that a phishing domain will get &#8220;redpaged,&#8221; a reference to the default red warning pages served by Google Chrome or Firefox whenever someone tries to visit a site that&#8217;s been flagged for phishing or distributing malware.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, while the phishing sites are live their operators typically place a CAPTCHA challenge in front of the main page to prevent security services from scanning and flagging the sites as malicious.</p>
<p>It may seem odd that so many cybercriminal groups operate so openly on instant collaboration networks like Telegram and Discord. After all, this blog is replete with stories about cybercriminals getting caught thanks to personal details they inadvertently leaked or disclosed themselves.</p>
<p>Nixon said the relative openness of these cybercrime communities makes them inherently risky, but it also allows for the rapid formation and recruitment of new potential co-conspirators. Moreover, today&#8217;s English-speaking cybercriminals tend to be <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/10/lamborghini-carjackers-lured-by-243m-cyberheist/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more afraid of getting home invaded or mugged by fellow cyber thieves</a> than they are of being arrested by authorities.</p>
<p>&#8220;The biggest structural threat to the online criminal ecosystem is not the police or researchers, it is fellow criminals,&#8221; Nixon said. &#8220;To protect them from themselves, every criminal forum and marketplace has a reputation system, even though they know it&#8217;s a major liability when the police come. That is why I am not worried as we see criminals migrate to various &#8216;encrypted&#8217; platforms that promise to ignore the police. To protect themselves better against the law, they have to ditch their protections against fellow criminals and that&#8217;s not going to happen.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Army Soldier Arrested in AT&#038;T, Verizon Extortions</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-army-soldier-arrested-in-att-verizon-extortions/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-army-soldier-arrested-in-att-verizon-extortions/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 04:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allison Nixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cameron John Wagenius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Connor Riley Moucka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judische]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiberphant0m]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 221B]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Federal authorities have arrested and indicted a 20-year-old U.S. Army soldier on suspicion of being Kiberphant0m, a cybercriminal who has been selling and leaking sensitive customer call records stolen earlier this year from AT&#038;T and Verizon. As first reported by KrebsOnSecurity last month, the accused is a communications specialist who was recently stationed in South Korea.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Federal authorities have arrested and indicted a 20-year-old U.S. Army soldier on suspicion of being <strong>Kiberphant0m</strong>, a cybercriminal who has been selling and leaking sensitive customer call records stolen earlier this year from <strong>AT&amp;T</strong> and <strong>Verizon</strong>. As first reported by KrebsOnSecurity last month, the accused is a communications specialist who was recently stationed in South Korea.</p>
<div id="attachment_69974" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69974" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69974" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie.png" alt="" width="750" height="743" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie.png 779w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie-768x761.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69974" class="wp-caption-text">One of several selfies on the Facebook page of Cameron Wagenius.</p></div>
<p><strong>Cameron John Wagenius</strong> was arrested near the Army base in Fort Hood, Texas on Dec. 20, after being indicted on two criminal counts of unlawful transfer of confidential phone records.</p>
<p>The sparse, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/wagenius-indictment.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">two-page indictment</a> (PDF) doesn&#8217;t reference specific victims or hacking activity, nor does it include any personal details about the accused. But a conversation with Wagenius&#8217; mother &#8212; Minnesota native <strong>Alicia Roen </strong>&#8212; filled in the gaps.</p>
<p>Roen said that prior to her son&#8217;s arrest he&#8217;d acknowledged being associated with <strong>Connor Riley Moucka</strong>, a.k.a. &#8220;<strong>Judische</strong>,&#8221; a prolific cybercriminal from Canada who was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested in late October</a> for stealing data from and extorting dozens of companies that stored data at the cloud service <strong>Snowflake</strong>.</p>
<p>In an interview with KrebsOnSecurity, Judische said he had no interest in selling the data he&#8217;d stolen from Snowflake customers and telecom providers, and that he preferred to outsource that to Kiberphant0m and others. Meanwhile, Kiberphant0m claimed in posts on Telegram that he was responsible for hacking into at least 15 telecommunications firms, including AT&amp;T and Verizon.</p>
<p>On November 26, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published a story</a> that followed a trail of clues left behind by Kiberphantom indicating he was a U.S. Army soldier stationed in South Korea.</p>
<p>Ms. Roen said Cameron worked on radio signals and network communications at an Army base in South Korea for the past two years, returning to the United States periodically. She said Cameron was always good with computers, but that she had no idea he might have been involved in criminal hacking.</p>
<p>&#8220;I never was aware he was into hacking,&#8221; Roen said. &#8220;It was definitely a shock to me when we found this stuff out.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ms. Roen said Cameron joined the Army as soon as he was of age, following in his older brother&#8217;s footsteps.</p>
<p>&#8220;He and his brother when they were like 6 and 7 years old would ask for MREs from other countries,&#8221; she recalled, referring to military-issued &#8220;meals ready to eat&#8221; food rations. &#8220;They both always wanted to be in the Army. I&#8217;m not sure where things went wrong.&#8221;<span id="more-69925"></span></p>
<p>Immediately after news broke of Moucka’s arrest, Kiberphant0m posted on the hacker community <strong>BreachForums</strong> what they claimed were the AT&amp;T call logs for <strong>President-elect</strong> <strong>Donald J. Trump</strong> and for <strong>Vice President Kamala Harris</strong>.</p>
<p>“In the event you do not reach out to us @ATNT all presidential government call logs will be leaked,” Kiberphant0m threatened, signing their post with multiple “#FREEWAIFU” tags. “You don’t think we don’t have plans in the event of an arrest? Think again.”</p>
<div id="attachment_69624" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69624" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69624" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema.png" alt="" width="750" height="239" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema.png 1417w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema-768x245.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema-782x249.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69624" class="wp-caption-text">Kiberphant0m posting what he claimed was a &#8220;data schema&#8221; stolen from the NSA via AT&amp;T.</p></div>
<p>On that same day, Kiberphant0m posted what they claimed was the “data schema” from the <strong>U.S. National Security Agency</strong>.</p>
<p>On Nov. 5, Kiberphant0m offered call logs stolen from Verizon’s push-to-talk (PTT) customers — mainly U.S. government agencies and emergency first responders. On Nov. 9, Kiberphant0m posted a sales thread on BreachForums offering a “SIM-swapping” service targeting Verizon PTT customers. In a SIM-swap, fraudsters use credentials that are phished or stolen from mobile phone company employees to divert a target’s phone calls and text messages to a device they control.</p>
<p>The profile photo on Wagenius&#8217; Facebook page was deleted within hours of my Nov. 26 story identifying Kiberphant0m as a likely U.S. Army soldier. Still, many of his original profile photos remain, including several that show Wagenius in uniform while holding various Army-issued weapons.</p>
<div id="attachment_69972" style="width: 612px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69972" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69972" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/wagenius-fb.png" alt="" width="602" height="842" /><p id="caption-attachment-69972" class="wp-caption-text">Several profile photos visible on the Facebook page of Cameron Wagenius.</p></div>
<p>November&#8217;s story on Kiberphant0m cited his own Telegram messages saying he maintained a large botnet that was used for distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks to knock websites, users and networks offline. In 2023, Kiberphant0m sold remote access credentials for a major U.S. defense contractor.</p>
<p><strong>Allison Nixon,</strong> chief research officer at the New York-based cybersecurity firm <a href="https://www.unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a>, helped track down Kiberphant0m&#8217;s real life identity. Nixon was among several security researchers who faced harassment and specific threats of violence from Judische and his associates.</p>
<p>&#8220;Anonymously extorting the President and VP as a member of the military is a bad idea, but it&#8217;s an even worse idea to harass people who specialize in de-anonymizing cybercriminals,&#8221; Nixon told KrebsOnSecurity. She said the investigation into Kiberphant0m shows that law enforcement is getting better and faster at going after cybercriminals &#8212; especially those who are actually living in the United States.</p>
<p>&#8220;Between when we, and an anonymous colleague, found his opsec mistake on November 10th to his last Telegram activity on December 6, law enforcement set the speed record for the fastest turnaround time for an American federal cyber case that I have witnessed in my career,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Nixon asked to share a message for all the other Kiberphant0ms out there who think they can&#8217;t be found and arrested.</p>
<p>&#8220;I know that young people involved in cybercrime will read these articles,&#8221; Nixon said. &#8220;You need to stop doing stupid shit and get a lawyer. Law enforcement wants to put all of you in prison for a long time.&#8221;</p>
<p>The indictment against Wagenius was filed in Texas, but the case has been transferred to the U.S. District Court for the Western District of Washington in Seattle.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-army-soldier-arrested-in-att-verizon-extortions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 15th Anniversary, KrebsOnSecurity!</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/happy-15th-anniversary-krebsonsecurity/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/happy-15th-anniversary-krebsonsecurity/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 23:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[KrebsOnSecurity.com turns 15 years old today! Maybe it's indelicate to celebrate the birthday of a cybercrime blog that mostly publishes bad news, but happily many of 2024's most engrossing security stories were about bad things happening to bad guys. It's also an occasion to note that despite my publishing fewer stories than ever this past year, we somehow managed to attract near record levels of readership (thank you!).]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_69961" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69961" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69961" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/15bday.png" alt="" width="749" height="486" /><p id="caption-attachment-69961" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, Dreamansions.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity.com turns 15 years old today! Maybe it&#8217;s indelicate to celebrate the birthday of a cybercrime blog that mostly publishes bad news, but happily many of 2024&#8217;s most engrossing security stories were about bad things happening to bad guys. It&#8217;s also an occasion to note that despite my publishing fewer stories than ever this past year, we somehow managed to attract near record levels of readership (thank you!).</p>
<p>In case you missed any of them, here&#8217;s a recap of 2024&#8217;s most-read stories. In January, KrebsOnSecurity told the story of a Canadian man who was falsely charged with larceny and lost his job after becoming the victim of a <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/01/canadian-man-stuck-in-triangle-of-e-commerce-fraud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">complex e-commerce scam known as triangulation fraud.</a> This can occur when you buy something online — from a seller on <strong>Amazon</strong> or <strong>eBay</strong>, for example — but the seller doesn’t actually own the item for sale. Instead, they purchase the item using stolen payment card data and your shipping address. In this scam, you receive what you ordered, and the only party left to dispute the transaction is the owner of the stolen payment card.</p>
<div id="attachment_32692" style="width: 590px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-32692" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-32692" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/triangulationfraud-580x318.png" alt="" width="580" height="318" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/triangulationfraud-580x318.png 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/triangulationfraud.png 637w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /><p id="caption-attachment-32692" class="wp-caption-text">Triangulation fraud. Image: eBay Enterprise.</p></div>
<p>March featured several investigations into the history of various people-search data broker services. One story exposed how the Belarusian CEO of the privacy and data removal service <strong>OneRep</strong> had actually <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/ceo-of-data-privacy-company-onerep-com-founded-dozens-of-people-search-firms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">founded dozens of people-search services</a>, including many that OneRep was offering to remove people from for a fee. That story quickly <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/mozilla-drops-onerep-after-ceo-admits-to-running-people-search-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prompted Mozilla to terminate its partnership with OneRep</a>, which Mozilla had bundled as a privacy option for Firefox users.</p>
<p>A story digging into the consumer data broker <strong>Radaris</strong> <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/a-close-up-look-at-the-consumer-data-broker-radaris/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found its CEO was a fabricated identity</a>, and that the company&#8217;s founders were Russian brothers in Massachusetts who operated multiple Russian language dating services and affiliate programs, in addition to a dizzying array of people-search websites.</p>
<p>Radaris repeatedly threatened to sue KrebsOnSecurity unless that publication was retracted in full, alleging that it was replete with errors both factual and malicious. Instead, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/06/krebsonsecurity-threatened-with-defamation-lawsuit-over-fake-radaris-ceo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we doubled down and published all of the supporting evidence</a> that wasn&#8217;t included in the original story, leaving little room for doubt about its conclusions. Fittingly, Radaris now pimps OneRep as a service when consumers request that their personal information be removed from the data broker&#8217;s website.</p>
<p>Easily the longest story this year was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-an-iron-hammer-in-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an investigation into Stark Industries Solutions</a>, a large, mysterious new Internet hosting firm that materialized when Russia invaded Ukraine. That piece revealed how Stark was being used as a global proxy network to conceal the true source of cyberattacks and disinformation campaigns against enemies of Russia.</p>
<div id="attachment_67471" style="width: 756px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-67471" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-67471" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions.png" alt="" width="746" height="463" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions.png 1197w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-768x477.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-782x485.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 746px) 100vw, 746px" /><p id="caption-attachment-67471" class="wp-caption-text">The homepage of Stark Industries Solutions.</p></div>
<p>Much of my summer was spent reporting a story about how advertising and marketing firms have created <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/10/the-global-surveillance-free-for-all-in-mobile-ad-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a global free-for-all where anyone can track the daily movements and associations of hundreds of millions of mobile devices</a>, thanks to the ubiquity of mobile location data that is broadly and cheaply available.<span id="more-69936"></span></p>
<p>Research published in September explored <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the dark nexus between harm groups and cybercrime communities consumed with perpetrating financial fraud</a>. That analysis found an increasing number of young, Western cybercriminals are also members of fast-growing online groups that exist solely to bully, stalk, harass and extort vulnerable teens into physically harming themselves and others.</p>
<p>One focus of that story was a Canadian cybercriminal who used the nickname <strong>Judische. </strong>Identified by the Mandiant as one of the most consequential threat actors of 2024, Judische was responsible for a hacking rampage that exposed private information on hundreds of millions of Americans.  That story withheld Judische&#8217;s real name, but the reporting came in handy in late October when <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 25-year-old Canadian man named Connor Riley Moucka was arrested and charged with 20 criminal counts connected to the Snowflake data extortions</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_69625" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69625" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69625" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance.png" alt="" width="747" height="573" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance.png 1137w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance-768x590.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance-782x600.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69625" class="wp-caption-text">A surveillance photo of Connor Riley Moucka, a.k.a. &#8220;Judische&#8221; and &#8220;Waifu,&#8221; dated Oct 21, 2024, 9 days before Moucka&#8217;s arrest. This image was included in an affidavit filed by an investigator with the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP).</p></div>
<p>In November, KrebsOnSecurity published a profile of Judische&#8217;s accomplice &#8212; a hacker known as <strong>Kiberphant0m</strong> &#8212; detailing how Kiberphant0m had left a trail of clues strongly suggesting that <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">they are or recently were a U.S. Army soldier stationed in South Korea</a>.</p>
<p>My reporting in December was mainly split between two investigations. The first profiled <strong>Cryptomus</strong>, a dodgy cryptocurrency exchange allegedly based in Canada that has become a major payment processor and sanctions evasion platform <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-cryptocurrency-turns-to-cash-in-russian-banks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for dozens of Russian exchanges and cybercrime services online</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-to-lose-a-fortune-with-just-one-bad-click/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to Lose a Fortune with Just One Bad Click</a> told the sad tales of two cryptocurrency heist victims who were scammed out of six and seven figures after falling for complex social engineering schemes over the phone. In these attacks, the phishers abused at least four different Google services to trick targets into believing they were speaking with a Google representative, and into giving thieves control over their account with a single click. Look for a story here in early 2025 that will explore the internal operations of these ruthless and ephemeral voice phishing gangs.</p>
<p>Before signing off for 2024, allow me to remind readers that the reporting we&#8217;re able to provide here is made possible primarily by the ads you may see at the top of this website. If you currently don&#8217;t see any ads when you load this website, please consider enabling an exception in your ad blocker for KrebsOnSecurity.com. There is zero third-party content on this website, apart from the occasional Youtube video embedded as part of a story. More importantly, all of our ads are static images or GIFs that are vetted by me and served in-house directly.</p>
<p>Fundamentally, my work is supported and improved by <em>your</em> <em>readership</em>, tips, encouragement and, yes, criticism. So thank you for that, and keep it coming, please.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s to a happy, healthy, wealthy and wary 2025. Hope to see you all again in the New Year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/happy-15th-anniversary-krebsonsecurity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>56</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web Hacking Service &#8216;Araneida&#8217; Tied to Turkish IT Firm</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/web-hacking-service-araneida-tied-to-turkish-it-firm/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/web-hacking-service-araneida-tied-to-turkish-it-firm/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acunetix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altug Sara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altugsara321@gmail.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Araneida Scanner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bilitro Yazilim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fin7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Invicti Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Sciberras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neil Roseman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ori0nbusiness@protonmail.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Health and Human Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cybercriminals are selling hundreds of thousands of credential sets stolen with the help of a cracked version of Acunetix, a powerful commercial web app vulnerability scanner, new research finds. The cracked software is being resold as a cloud-based attack tool by at least two different services, one of which KrebsOnSecurity traced to an information technology firm based in Turkey.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cybercriminals are selling hundreds of thousands of credential sets stolen with the help of a cracked version of <strong>Acunetix</strong>, a powerful commercial web app vulnerability scanner, new research finds. The cracked software is being resold as a cloud-based attack tool by at least two different services, one of which KrebsOnSecurity traced to an information technology firm based in Turkey.</p>
<div id="attachment_69895" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69895" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69895" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-scanner.png" alt="" width="749" height="562" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-scanner.png 1126w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-scanner-768x576.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-scanner-782x587.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69895" class="wp-caption-text">Araneida Scanner.</p></div>
<p>Cyber threat analysts at <strong>Silent Push</strong> said they recently received reports from a partner organization that identified an aggressive scanning effort against their website using an Internet address previously associated with a campaign by <a href="https://resources.prodaft.com/fin7-cybercrime-gang" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FIN7</a>, a notorious Russia-based hacking group.</p>
<p>But on closer inspection they discovered the address contained an HTML title of &#8220;<strong>Araneida Customer Panel</strong>,&#8221; and found they could search on that text string to find dozens of unique addresses hosting the same service.</p>
<p>It soon became apparent that Araneida was being resold as a cloud-based service using a cracked version of Acunetix, allowing paying customers to conduct offensive reconnaissance on potential target websites, scrape user data, and find vulnerabilities for exploitation.</p>
<p>Silent Push also learned Araneida bundles its service with a robust proxy offering, so that customer scans appear to come from Internet addresses that are randomly selected from a large pool of available traffic relays.</p>
<p>The makers of Acunetix, Texas-based application security vendor <strong>Invicti Security</strong>, confirmed Silent Push&#8217;s findings, saying someone had figured out how to crack the free trial version of the software so that it runs without a valid license key.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have been playing cat and mouse for a while with these guys,&#8221; said <strong>Matt Sciberras</strong>, chief information security officer at Invicti.</p>
<p>Silent Push said Araneida is being advertised by an eponymous user on multiple cybercrime forums. The service&#8217;s Telegram channel boasts nearly 500 subscribers and explains how to use the tool for malicious purposes.</p>
<p>In a &#8220;Fun Facts&#8221; list posted to the channel in late September, Araneida said their service was used to take over more than 30,000 websites in just six months, and that one customer used it to buy a Porsche with the payment card data (&#8220;dumps&#8221;) they sold.</p>
<div id="attachment_69898" style="width: 668px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69898" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69898" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-tg.png" alt="" width="658" height="273" /><p id="caption-attachment-69898" class="wp-caption-text">Araneida Scanner&#8217;s Telegram channel bragging about how customers are using the service for cybercrime.</p></div>
<p>“They are constantly bragging with their community about the crimes that are being committed, how it’s making criminals money,” said <strong>Zach Edwards</strong>, a senior threat researcher at Silent Push. “They are also selling bulk data and dumps which appear to have been acquired with this tool or due to vulnerabilities found with the tool.”</p>
<p>Silent Push also found a cracked version of Acunetix was powering at least 20 instances of a similar cloud-based vulnerability testing service catering to Mandarin speakers, but they were unable to find any apparently related sales threads about them on the dark web.</p>
<p>Rumors of a cracked version of Acunetix being used by attackers surfaced <a href="https://x.com/FalconFeedsio/status/1665690661377691649" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in June 2023 on Twitter/X</a>, when researchers <a href="https://x.com/TLP_R3D/status/1665777020767293447" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first posited a connection between observed scanning activity and Araneida</a>.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/china-based-threat-actor-profiles-tlpclear.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an August 2023 report</a> (PDF) from the <strong>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</strong> (HHS), Acunetix (presumably a cracked version) is among several tools used by <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/09/chinese-antivirus-firm-was-part-of-apt41-supply-chain-attack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">APT 41</a>, a prolific Chinese state-sponsored hacking group.<span id="more-69811"></span></p>
<h2>THE TURKISH CONNECTION</h2>
<p>Silent Push notes that the website where Araneida is being sold &#8212; <strong>araneida[.]co</strong> &#8212; first came online in February 2023. But a review of this Araneida nickname on the cybercrime forums shows they have been active in the criminal hacking scene since at least 2018.</p>
<p>A search in the threat intelligence platform <a href="https://www.intel471.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel 471</a> shows a user by the name Araneida promoted the scanner on two cybercrime forums since 2022, including <strong>Breached</strong> and <strong>Nulled</strong>. In 2022, Araneida told fellow Breached members they could be reached on Discord at the username &#8220;<strong>Ornie#9811</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to Intel 471, this same Discord account was advertised in 2019 by a person on the cybercrime forum <strong>Cracked</strong> who used the monikers &#8220;<strong>ORN</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>ori0n</strong>.&#8221; The user &#8220;ori0n&#8221; mentioned in several posts that they could be reached on Telegram at the username &#8220;<strong>@sirorny</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_69912" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69912" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69912" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/orn-araneida.png" alt="" width="749" height="411" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/orn-araneida.png 1002w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/orn-araneida-768x422.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/orn-araneida-782x429.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69912" class="wp-caption-text">Orn advertising Araneida Scanner in Feb. 2023 on the forum Cracked. Image: Ke-la.com.</p></div>
<p>The Sirorny Telegram identity also was referenced as a point of contact for a current user on the cybercrime forum Nulled who is selling website development services, and who references araneida[.]co as one of their projects. That user, &#8220;<strong>Exorn</strong>,&#8221; has posts dating back to August 2018.</p>
<p>In early 2020, Exorn promoted a website called &#8220;<strong>orndorks[.]com</strong>,&#8221; which they described as a service for automating the scanning for web-based vulnerabilities. A passive DNS lookup on this domain at <a href="https://www.domaintools.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DomainTools.com</a> shows that its email records pointed to the address <strong>ori0nbusiness@protonmail.com</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.constella.ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Constella Intelligence</a>, a company that tracks information exposed in data breaches, finds this email address was used to register an account at <strong>Breachforums</strong> in July 2024 under the nickname &#8220;<strong>Ornie</strong>.&#8221; Constella also finds the same email registered at the website netguard[.]codes in 2021 using the password &#8220;<strong>ceza2003</strong>&#8221; [full disclosure: Constella is currently an advertiser on KrebsOnSecurity].</p>
<p>A search on the password ceza2003 in Constella finds roughly a dozen email addresses that used it in an exposed data breach, most of them featuring some variation on the name &#8220;<strong>altugsara</strong>,&#8221; including <strong>altugsara321@gmail.com</strong>. Constella further finds altugsara321@gmail.com was used to create an account at the cybercrime community <strong>RaidForums</strong> under the username &#8220;<strong>ori0n</strong>,&#8221; from an Internet address in Istanbul.</p>
<p>According to DomainTools, altugsara321@gmail.com was used in 2020 to register the domain name <strong>altugsara[.]com</strong>. <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211125114845/http://altugsara.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Archive.org&#8217;s history for that domain</a> shows that in 2021 it featured a website for a then 18-year-old <strong>Altuğ Şara</strong> from Ankara, Turkey.</p>
<div id="attachment_69893" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69893" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-69893" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/altugsaradotcom.png" alt="" width="749" height="345" /><p id="caption-attachment-69893" class="wp-caption-text">Archive.org&#8217;s recollection of what altugsara dot com looked like in 2021.</p></div>
<p><strong>LinkedIn</strong> finds this same <strong>altugsara[.]com</strong> domain listed in the &#8220;contact info&#8221; section of <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/altu%C4%9F-%C5%9Fara-58957b212/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a profile</a> for an <strong>Altug Sara</strong> from Ankara, who says he has worked the past two years as a senior software developer for a Turkish IT firm called <strong>Bilitro Yazilim</strong>.</p>
<p>Neither Altug Sara nor Bilitro Yazilim responded to requests for comment.</p>
<p>Invicti&#8217;s website states that it has offices in Ankara, but the company&#8217;s CEO said none of their employees recognized either name.</p>
<p>&#8220;We do have a small team in Ankara, but as far as I know we have no connection to the individual other than the fact that they are also in Ankara,&#8221; Invicti CEO <strong>Neil Roseman</strong> told KrebsOnSecurity.</p>
<p>Researchers at Silent Push say despite Araneida using a seemingly endless supply of proxies to mask the true location of its users, it is a fairly &#8220;noisy&#8221; scanner that will kick off a large volume of requests to various API endpoints, and make requests to random URLs associated with different content management systems.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, the cracked version of Acunetix being resold to cybercriminals invokes legacy Acunetix SSL certificates on active control panels, which Silent Push says provides a solid pivot for finding some of this infrastructure, particularly from the Chinese threat actors.</p>
<p>Further reading: <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/araneida-scanner-acunetix" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Silent Push&#8217;s research on Araneida Scanner</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/web-hacking-service-araneida-tied-to-turkish-it-firm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 257/257 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2025-02-02 14:22:02 by W3 Total Cache
-->