<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/?ref=blog.netmanageit.com" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:46:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>MasterCard DNS Error Went Unnoticed for Years</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to Break Into Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akam.ne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akam.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Akamai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awsdns-06.ne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[az.mastercard.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bugcrowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CloudFlare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastercard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philippe Caturegli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seralys]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The payment card giant MasterCard just fixed a glaring error in its domain name server settings that could have allowed anyone to intercept or divert Internet traffic for the company by registering an unused domain name. The misconfiguration persisted for nearly five years until a security researcher spent $300 to register the domain and prevent it from being grabbed by cybercriminals.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The payment card giant <strong>MasterCard</strong> just fixed a glaring error in its domain name server settings that could have allowed anyone to intercept or divert Internet traffic for the company by registering an unused domain name. The misconfiguration persisted for nearly five years until a security researcher spent $300 to register the domain and prevent it from being grabbed by cybercriminals.</p>
<div id="attachment_70128" style="width: 677px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70128" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-70128" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/akamne.png" alt="" width="667" height="478" /><p id="caption-attachment-70128" class="wp-caption-text">A DNS lookup on the domain az.mastercard.com on Jan. 14, 2025 shows the mistyped domain name a22-65.akam.ne.</p></div>
<p>From June 30, 2020 until January 14, 2025, one of the core Internet servers that MasterCard uses to direct traffic for portions of the mastercard.com network was misnamed. MasterCard.com relies on five shared Domain Name System (DNS) servers at the Internet infrastructure provider <strong>Akamai </strong>[DNS acts as a kind of Internet phone book, by translating website names to numeric Internet addresses that are easier for computers to manage].</p>
<p>All of the Akamai DNS server names that MasterCard uses are supposed to end in &#8220;akam.net&#8221; but one of them was misconfigured to rely on the domain &#8220;<strong>akam.ne</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>This tiny but potentially critical typo was discovered recently by <strong>Philippe Caturegli</strong>, founder of the security consultancy <a href="https://www.seralys.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Seralys</a>. Caturegli said he guessed that nobody had yet registered the domain akam.ne, which is under the purview of the top-level domain authority for the West Africa nation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Niger</a>.</p>
<p>Caturegli said it took $300 and nearly three months of waiting to secure the domain with the registry in Niger. After enabling a DNS server on akam.ne, he noticed hundreds of thousands of DNS requests hitting his server each day from locations around the globe. Apparently, MasterCard wasn&#8217;t the only organization that had fat-fingered a DNS entry to include &#8220;akam.ne,&#8221; but they were by far the largest.</p>
<p>Had he enabled an email server on his new domain akam.ne, Caturegli likely would have received wayward emails directed toward mastercard.com or other affected domains. If he&#8217;d abused his access, he probably could have <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/08/local-networks-go-global-when-domain-names-collide/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">obtained website encryption certificates (SSL/TLS certs)</a> that were authorized to accept and relay web traffic for affected websites. He may even have been able to <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/02/dangerous-domain-corp-com-goes-up-for-sale/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">passively receive Microsoft Windows authentication credentials</a> from employee computers at affected companies.</p>
<p>But the researcher said he didn&#8217;t attempt to do any of that. Instead, he alerted MasterCard that the domain was theirs if they wanted it, copying this author on his notifications. A few hours later, MasterCard acknowledged the mistake, but said there was never any real threat to the security of its operations.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have looked into the matter and there was not a risk to our systems,&#8221; a MasterCard spokesperson wrote. &#8220;This typo has now been corrected.&#8221;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Caturegli received a request submitted through <strong>Bugcrowd</strong>, a program that offers financial rewards and recognition to security researchers who find flaws and work privately with the affected vendor to fix them. The message suggested his public disclosure of the MasterCard DNS error via <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a post on LinkedIn</a> (after he&#8217;d secured the akam.ne domain) was not aligned with ethical security practices, and passed on a request from MasterCard to have the post removed.</p>
<div id="attachment_70126" style="width: 718px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70126" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70126" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-response.png" alt="" width="708" height="855" /><p id="caption-attachment-70126" class="wp-caption-text">MasterCard&#8217;s request to Caturegli, a.k.a. &#8220;Titon&#8221; on infosec.exchange.</p></div>
<p>Caturegli said while he does have an account on Bugcrowd, he has never submitted anything through the Bugcrowd program, and that he reported this issue directly to MasterCard.</p>
<p>&#8220;I did not disclose this issue through Bugcrowd,&#8221; Caturegli wrote in reply. &#8220;Before making any public disclosure, I ensured that the affected domain was registered to prevent exploitation, mitigating any risk to MasterCard or its customers. This action, which we took at our own expense, demonstrates our commitment to ethical security practices and responsible disclosure.&#8221; <span id="more-70117"></span></p>
<p>Most organizations have at least two authoritative domain name servers, but some handle so many DNS requests that they need to spread the load over additional DNS server domains. In MasterCard&#8217;s case, that number is five, so it stands to reason that if an attacker managed to seize control over just one of those domains they would only be able to see about one-fifth of the overall DNS requests coming in.</p>
<p>But Caturegli said the reality is that many Internet users are relying at least to some degree on public traffic forwarders or DNS resolvers like <strong>Cloudflare</strong> and <strong>Google</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;So all we need is for one of these resolvers to query our name server and cache the result,&#8221; Caturegli said. By setting their DNS server records with a long TTL or &#8220;Time To Live&#8221; &#8212; a setting that can adjust the lifespan of data packets on a network &#8212; an attacker&#8217;s poisoned instructions for the target domain can be propagated by large cloud providers.</p>
<p>&#8220;With a long TTL, we may reroute a LOT more than just 1/5 of the traffic,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>The researcher said he&#8217;d hoped that the credit card giant might thank him, or at least offer to cover the cost of buying the domain.</p>
<p>&#8220;We obviously disagree with this assessment,&#8221; Caturegli wrote in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285289297706909697%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285289297706909697%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a follow-up post</a> on LinkedIn regarding MasterCard&#8217;s public statement. &#8220;But we’ll let you judge— here are some of the DNS lookups we recorded before reporting the issue.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70125" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70125" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70125" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains.png" alt="" width="790" height="561" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains.png 790w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-768x545.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-782x555.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mastercard-domains-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 790px) 100vw, 790px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70125" class="wp-caption-text">Caturegli posted this screenshot of MasterCard domains that were potentially at risk from the misconfigured domain.</p></div>
<p>As the screenshot above shows, the misconfigured DNS server Caturegli found involved the MasterCard subdomain <strong>az.mastercard.com</strong>. It is not clear exactly how this subdomain is used by MasterCard, however their naming conventions suggest the domains correspond to production servers at Microsoft&#8217;s <strong>Azure</strong> cloud service. Caturegli said the domains all resolve to Internet addresses at Microsoft.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don’t be like Mastercard,&#8221; Caturegli concluded in his LinkedIn post. &#8220;Don’t dismiss risk, and don’t let your marketing team handle security disclosures.&#8221;</p>
<p>One final note: The domain akam.ne has been registered previously &#8212; in December 2016 by someone using the email address um-i-delo@yandex.ru. The Russian search giant Yandex reports this user account belongs to an &#8220;Ivan I.&#8221; from Moscow. Passive DNS records from <a href="https://www.domaintools.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DomainTools.com</a> show that between 2016 and 2018 the domain was connected to an Internet server in Germany, and that the domain was left to expire in 2018.</p>
<p>This is interesting given <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7285038365236682753?commentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285221445796835329%29&amp;replyUrn=urn%3Ali%3Acomment%3A%28activity%3A7285038365236682753%2C7285223757982363648%29&amp;dashCommentUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285221445796835329%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29&amp;dashReplyUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afsd_comment%3A%287285223757982363648%2Curn%3Ali%3Aactivity%3A7285038365236682753%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a comment on Caturegli&#8217;s LinkedIn post from an ex-Cloudflare employee</a> who linked to a report he co-authored on a similar typo domain apparently registered in 2017 for organizations that may have mistyped their AWS DNS server as &#8220;<strong>awsdns-06.ne</strong>&#8221; instead of &#8220;<strong>awsdns-06.net</strong>.&#8221; DomainTools reports that this typo domain also was registered to a Yandex user (playlotto@yandex.ru), and was hosted at the same German ISP &#8212; Team Internet (AS61969).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>74</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese Innovations Spawn Wave of Toll Phishing Via SMS</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/chinese-innovations-spawn-wave-of-toll-phishing-via-sms/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/chinese-innovations-spawn-wave-of-toll-phishing-via-sms/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 21:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@chenlun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSIS Security Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EZDriveMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Merrill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ic3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iMessage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lighthouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MassDOT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Texas Toll Authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RCS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SecAlliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Toll Roads]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Residents across the United States are being inundated with text messages purporting to come from toll road operators like E-ZPass, warning that recipients face fines if a delinquent toll fee remains unpaid. Researchers say the surge in SMS spam coincides with new features added to a popular commercial phishing kit sold in China that makes it simple to set up convincing lures spoofing toll road operators in multiple U.S. states.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Residents across the United States are being inundated with text messages purporting to come from toll road operators like <strong>E-ZPass</strong>, warning that recipients face fines if a delinquent toll fee remains unpaid. Researchers say the surge in SMS spam coincides with new features added to a popular commercial phishing kit sold in China that makes it simple to set up convincing lures spoofing toll road operators in multiple U.S. states.</p>
<p>Last week, the <strong>Massachusetts Department of Transportation</strong> (MassDOT) <a href="https://www.ezdrivema.com/About-EzdriveMA/Smishing-Alert" target="_blank" rel="noopener">warned residents</a> to be on the lookout for a new SMS phishing or &#8220;smishing&#8221; scam targeting users of <strong>EZDriveMA</strong>, MassDOT&#8217;s all electronic tolling program. Those who fall for the scam are asked to provide payment card data, and eventually will be asked to supply a one-time password sent via SMS or a mobile authentication app.</p>
<p>Reports of similar SMS phishing attacks against customers of other U.S. state-run toll facilities surfaced around the same time as the MassDOT alert. People in Florida reported receiving SMS phishing that spoofed <strong>Sunpass</strong>, Florida&#8217;s prepaid toll program.</p>
<div id="attachment_70096" style="width: 503px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70096" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70096" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/lighthouse-ezdrive.png" alt="" width="493" height="683" /><p id="caption-attachment-70096" class="wp-caption-text">This phishing module for spoofing MassDOT&#8217;s EZDrive toll system was offered on Jan. 10, 2025 by a China-based SMS phishing service called &#8220;Lighthouse.&#8221;</p></div>
<p>In Texas, residents said they received text messages about unpaid tolls with the <strong>North Texas Toll Authority</strong>. Similar reports came from readers in California, Colorado, Connecticut, Minnesota, and Washington. This is by no means a comprehensive list.</p>
<div id="attachment_70097" style="width: 503px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70097" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70097" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/lighthouse-ntta.png" alt="" width="493" height="683" /><p id="caption-attachment-70097" class="wp-caption-text">A new module from the Lighthouse SMS phishing kit released Jan. 14 targets customers of the North Texas Toll Authority (NTTA).</p></div>
<p>In each case, the emergence of these SMS phishing attacks coincided with the release of new phishing kit capabilities that closely mimic these toll operator websites as they appear on mobile devices. Notably, none of the phishing pages will even load unless the website detects that the visitor is coming from a mobile device.</p>
<p><strong>Ford Merrill</strong> works in security research at <a href="https://www.secalliance.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SecAlliance</a>, a <a href="https://www.csis.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSIS Security Group</a> company. Merrill said the volume of SMS phishing attacks spoofing toll road operators skyrocketed after the New Year, when at least one Chinese cybercriminal group known for selling sophisticated SMS phishing kits began offering new phishing pages designed to spoof toll operators in various U.S. states.</p>
<p>According to Merrill, multiple China-based cybercriminals are selling distinct SMS-based phishing kits that each have hundreds or thousands of customers. The ultimate goal of these kits, he said, is to phish enough information from victims that their payment cards can be added to mobile wallets and used to buy goods at physical stores, online, or to launder money through shell companies.<span id="more-70091"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_70098" style="width: 503px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70098" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70098" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/lighthouse-tollroads.png" alt="" width="493" height="683" /><p id="caption-attachment-70098" class="wp-caption-text">A component of the Chinese SMS phishing kit Lighthouse made to target customers of The Toll Roads, which refers to several state routes through Orange County, Calif.</p></div>
<p>Merrill said the different purveyors of these SMS phishing tools traditionally have impersonated shipping companies, customs authorities, and even governments with tax refund lures and visa or immigration renewal scams targeting people who may be living abroad or new to a country.</p>
<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re seeing with these tolls scams is just a continuation of the Chinese smishing groups rotating from package redelivery schemes to toll road scams,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;Every one of us by now is sick and tired of receiving these package smishing attacks, so now it&#8217;s a new twist on an existing scam.”</p>
<p>In October 2023, KrebsOnSecurity wrote about <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/10/phishers-spoof-usps-12-other-natl-postal-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a massive uptick in SMS phishing scams targeting <strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong> customers</a>. That story revealed the surge was tied to innovations introduced by &#8220;<strong>Chenlun</strong>,&#8221; a mainland China-based proprietor of a popular phishing kit and service. At the time, Chenlun had just introduced new phishing pages made to impersonate postal services in the United States and at least a dozen other countries.</p>
<p>SMS phishing kits are hardly new, but Merrill said Chinese smishing groups recently have introduced innovations in deliverability, by more seamlessly integrating their spam messages with Apple&#8217;s <strong>iMessage</strong> technology, and with <a href="https://support.google.com/messages/answer/7189714?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RCS</a>, the equivalent &#8220;rich text&#8221; messaging capability built into <strong>Android</strong> devices.</p>
<p>“While traditional smishing kits relied heavily on SMS for delivery, nowadays the actors make heavy use of iMessage and RCS because telecom operators can’t filter them and they likely have a higher success rate with these delivery channels,” he said.</p>
<p>It remains unclear how the phishers have selected their targets, or from where their data may be sourced. A notice from MassDOT cautions that &#8220;the targeted phone numbers seem to be chosen at random and are not uniquely associated with an account or usage of toll roads.&#8221;</p>
<p>Indeed, one reader shared on Mastodon yesterday that they&#8217;d received one of these SMS phishing attacks spoofing a local toll operator, when they didn&#8217;t even own a vehicle.</p>
<p>Targeted or not, these phishing websites are dangerous because they are operated dynamically in real-time by criminals. If you receive one of these messages, just ignore it or delete it, but please do not visit the phishing site. The FBI asks that before you bin the missives, consider filing a complaint with the agency&#8217;s <a href="https://www.ic3.gov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Internet Crime Complaint Center</a> (IC3), including the phone number where the text originated, and the website listed within the text.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/chinese-innovations-spawn-wave-of-toll-phishing-via-sms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft: Happy 2025. Here&#8217;s 161 Security Updates</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/microsoft-happy-2025-heres-161-security-updates/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/microsoft-happy-2025-heres-161-security-updates/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 22:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben Hopkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitlocker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-49142]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21186]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21210]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21298]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21311]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21333]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21334]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21335]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21366]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21395]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kev Breen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Patch Tuesday January 2025]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satnam Narang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unpatched.ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Hyper-V]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows NTLMv1]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70070</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today unleashed updates to plug a whopping 161 security vulnerabilities in Windows and related software, including three "zero-day" weaknesses that are already under active attack. Redmond's inaugural Patch Tuesday of 2025 bundles more fixes than the company has shipped in one go since 2017.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today unleashed updates to plug a whopping 161 security vulnerabilities in <strong>Windows</strong> and related software, including three &#8220;zero-day&#8221; weaknesses that are already under active attack. Redmond&#8217;s inaugural Patch Tuesday of 2025 bundles more fixes than the company has shipped in one go since 2017.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-60331" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png" alt="" width="749" height="496" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate.png 923w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-768x508.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/winupdatedate-782x518.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p><strong>Rapid7</strong>&#8216;s <strong>Adam Barnett</strong> says January marks the fourth consecutive month where Microsoft has published zero-day vulnerabilities on Patch Tuesday without evaluating any of them as critical severity at time of publication. Today also saw the publication of nine critical remote code execution (RCE) vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>The Microsoft flaws already seeing active attacks include <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21333" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21333</a>, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21334" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21334</a> and, you guessed it&#8211; <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21335" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21335</a>. These are sequential because all reside in <strong>Windows Hyper-V</strong>, a component that is heavily embedded in modern <strong>Windows 11</strong> operating systems and used for security features including device guard and credential guard.</p>
<p>Tenable&#8217;s <strong>Satnam Narang</strong> says little is known about the in-the-wild exploitation of these flaws, apart from the fact that they are all &#8220;privilege escalation&#8221; vulnerabilities. Narang said we tend to see a lot of elevation of privilege bugs exploited in the wild as zero-days in Patch Tuesday because it&#8217;s not always initial access to a system that&#8217;s a challenge for attackers as they have various avenues in their pursuit.</p>
<p>&#8220;As elevation of privilege bugs, they’re being used as part of post-compromise activity, where an attacker has already accessed a target system,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It&#8217;s kind of like if an attacker is able to enter a secure building, they’re unable to access more secure parts of the facility because they have to prove that they have clearance. In this case, they’re able to trick the system into believing they should have clearance.&#8221;<span id="more-70070"></span></p>
<p>Several bugs addressed today earned CVSS (threat rating) scores of 9.8 out of a possible 10, including <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21298" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21298</a>, a weakness in Windows that could allow attackers to run arbitrary code by getting a target to open a malicious <strong>.rtf</strong> file, documents typically opened on Office applications like Microsoft Word. Microsoft has rated this flaw &#8220;exploitation more likely.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Ben Hopkins</strong> at <strong>Immersive Labs</strong> called attention to the <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21311" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21311</a>, a 9.8 &#8220;critical&#8221; bug in <strong>Windows NTLMv1</strong> (NT LAN Manager version 1), an older Microsoft authentication protocol that is still used by many organizations.</p>
<p>&#8220;What makes this vulnerability so impactful is the fact that it is remotely exploitable, so attackers can reach the compromised machine(s) over the internet, and the attacker does not need significant knowledge or skills to achieve repeatable success with the same payload across any vulnerable component,&#8221; Hopkins wrote.</p>
<p><strong>Kev Breen</strong> at Immersive points to an interesting flaw (<a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21210" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21210</a>) that Microsoft fixed in its full disk encryption suite <strong>Bitlocker</strong> that the software giant has dubbed &#8220;exploitation more likely.&#8221; Specifically, this bug holds out the possibility that in some situations the hibernation image created when one closes the laptop lid on an open Windows session may not be fully encrypted and could be recovered in plain text.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hibernation images are used when a laptop goes to sleep and contains the contents that were stored in RAM at the moment the device powered down,&#8221; Breen noted. &#8220;This presents a significant potential impact as RAM can contain sensitive data (such as passwords, credentials and PII) that may have been in open documents or browser sessions and can all be recovered with free tools from hibernation files.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tenable&#8217;s Narang also highlighted a trio of vulnerabilities in <strong>Microsoft Access</strong> fixed this month and credited to Unpatched.ai, a security research effort that is aided by artificial intelligence looking for vulnerabilities in code. Tracked as <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21186" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21186</a>, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21366" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21366</a>, and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2025-21395" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21395</a>, these are remote code execution bugs that are exploitable if an attacker convinces a target to download and run a malicious file through social engineering. Unpatched.ai was also credited with discovering a flaw in the December 2024 Patch Tuesday release (<a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-49142" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-49142</a>).</p>
<p>&#8220;Automated vulnerability detection using AI has garnered a lot of attention recently, so it’s noteworthy to see this service being credited with finding bugs in Microsoft products,&#8221; Narang observed. &#8220;It may be the first of many in 2025.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a Windows user who has automatic updates turned off and haven&#8217;t updated in a while, it&#8217;s probably time to play catch up. Please consider backing up important files and/or the entire hard drive before updating. And if you run into any problems installing this month&#8217;s patch batch, drop a line in the comments below, please.</p>
<p>Further reading on today&#8217;s patches from Microsoft:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tenable.com/blog/microsofts-january-2025-patch-tuesday-157-cves-cve-2025-21333-cve-2025-21334-cve-2025-21335" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tenable blog</a></p>
<p><a href="https://isc.sans.edu/forums/diary/Microsoft%20January%202025%20Patch%20Tuesday/31590/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SANS Internet Storm Center</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.askwoody.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ask Woody</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/microsoft-happy-2025-heres-161-security-updates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Day in the Life of a Prolific Voice Phishing Crew</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 23:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[800-275-2273]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allison Nixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aristotle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autodoxers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Chameleon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lookout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Cuban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shark Tank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stotle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trezor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 221B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voice phishing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Besieged by scammers seeking to phish user accounts over the telephone, Apple and Google frequently caution that they will never reach out unbidden to users this way. However, new details about the internal operations of a prolific voice phishing gang show the group routinely abuses legitimate services at Apple and Google to force a variety of outbound communications to their users, including emails, automated phone calls and system-level messages sent to all signed-in devices.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Besieged by scammers seeking to phish user accounts over the telephone, <strong>Apple</strong> and <strong>Google</strong> frequently caution that they will never reach out unbidden to users this way. However, new details about the internal operations of a prolific voice phishing gang show the group routinely abuses legitimate services at Apple and Google to force a variety of outbound communications to their users, including emails, automated phone calls and system-level messages sent to all signed-in devices.</p>
<div id="attachment_69859" style="width: 711px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69859" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-69859" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/thumb-mobile.png" alt="" width="701" height="413" /><p id="caption-attachment-69859" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, iHaMoo.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity recently told the saga of a cryptocurrency investor named <strong>Tony</strong> who was robbed of more than $4.7 million in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-to-lose-a-fortune-with-just-one-bad-click/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an elaborate voice phishing attack</a>. In Tony&#8217;s ordeal, the crooks appear to have initially contacted him via <strong>Google Assistant</strong>, an AI-based service that can engage in two-way conversations. The phishers also abused legitimate Google services to send Tony an email from google.com, and to send a Google account recovery prompt to all of his signed-in devices.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s story pivots off of Tony&#8217;s heist and new details shared by a scammer to explain how these voice phishing groups are abusing a legitimate Apple telephone support line to generate &#8220;account confirmation&#8221; message prompts from Apple to their customers.</p>
<p>Before we get to the Apple scam in detail, we need to revisit Tony&#8217;s case. The phishing domain used to steal roughly $4.7 million in cryptocurrencies from Tony was <strong>verify-trezor[.]io</strong>. This domain was featured in <a href="https://www.lookout.com/threat-intelligence/article/cryptochameleon-fcc-phishing-kit" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a writeup from February 2024</a> by the security firm <strong>Lookout</strong>, which found it was one of dozens being used by a prolific and audacious voice phishing group it dubbed &#8220;<strong>Crypto Chameleon</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Crypto Chameleon was brazenly trying to voice phish employees at the <strong>U.S. Federal Communications Commission</strong> (FCC), as well as those working at the cryptocurrency exchanges <strong>Coinbase</strong> and <strong>Binance</strong>. Lookout researchers discovered multiple voice phishing groups were using a new phishing kit that closely mimicked the single sign-on pages for <strong>Okta</strong> and other authentication providers.</p>
<p>As we&#8217;ll see in a moment, that phishing kit is operated and rented out by a cybercriminal known as &#8220;<strong>Perm</strong>&#8221; a.k.a. &#8220;<strong>Annie</strong>.&#8221; Perm is the current administrator of <strong>Star Fraud</strong>, one of the more consequential cybercrime communities on Telegram and one that has emerged as a foundry of innovation in voice phishing attacks.</p>
<p>A review of the many messages that Perm posted to Star Fraud and other Telegram channels showed they worked closely with another cybercriminal who went by the handles &#8220;<strong>Aristotle</strong>&#8221; and just &#8220;<strong>Stotle</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>It is not clear what caused the rift, but at some point last year Stotle decided to turn on his erstwhile business partner Perm, sharing extremely detailed videos, tutorials and secrets that shed new light on how these phishing panels operate.</p>
<p>Stotle explained that the division of spoils from each robbery is decided in advance by all participants. Some co-conspirators will be paid a set fee for each call, while others are promised a percentage of any overall amount stolen. The person in charge of managing or renting out the phishing panel to others will generally take a percentage of each theft, which in Perm&#8217;s case is 10 percent.</p>
<p>When the phishing group settles on a target of interest, the scammers will create and join a new <strong>Discord</strong> channel. This allows each logged on member to share what is currently on their screen, and these screens are tiled in a series of boxes so that everyone can see all other call participant screens at once.</p>
<p>Each participant in the call has a specific role, including:</p>
<p>-The Caller: The person speaking and trying to social engineer the target.<br />
-The Operator: The individual managing the phishing panel, silently moving the victim from page to page.<br />
-The Drainer: The person who logs into compromised accounts to drain the victim&#8217;s funds.<br />
-The Owner: The phishing panel owner, who will frequently listen in on and participate in scam calls.</p>
<h2>&#8216;OKAY, SO THIS REALLY IS APPLE&#8217;</h2>
<p>In one video of a live voice phishing attack shared by Stotle, scammers using Perm&#8217;s panel targeted a musician in California. Throughout the video, we can see Perm monitoring the conversation and operating the phishing panel in the upper right corner of the screen.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F44un1_y2fs?si=fmYxbcLS3TDtHjrs" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></div>
<p>In the first step of the attack, they <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/recent-mfa-bombing-attacks-targeting-apple-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">peppered the target&#8217;s Apple device with notifications from Apple</a> by attempting to reset his password. Then a &#8220;<strong>Michael Keen</strong>&#8221; called him, spoofing Apple&#8217;s phone number and saying they were with Apple&#8217;s account recovery team.</p>
<p>The target told Michael that someone was trying to change his password, which Michael calmly explained they would investigate. Michael said he was going to send a prompt to the man&#8217;s device, and proceeded to place a call to an automated line that answered as Apple support saying, &#8220;I&#8217;d like to send a consent notification to your Apple devices. Do I have permission to do that?&#8221;</p>
<p>In this segment of the video, we can see the operator of the panel is calling the real Apple customer support phone number <strong>800-275-2273</strong>, but they are doing so by spoofing the target&#8217;s phone number (the victim&#8217;s number is redacted in the video above). That&#8217;s because calling this support number from a phone number tied to an Apple account and selecting &#8220;1&#8221; for &#8220;yes&#8221; will then send an alert from Apple that displays the following message on all associated devices:</p>
<div id="attachment_70000" style="width: 403px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70000" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70000" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/appleconfirmation.png" alt="" width="393" height="448" /><p id="caption-attachment-70000" class="wp-caption-text">Calling the Apple support number 800-275-2273 from a phone number tied to an Apple account will cause a prompt similar to this one to appear on all connected Apple devices.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity asked two different security firms to test this using the caller ID spoofing service shown in Perm&#8217;s video, and sure enough calling that 800 number for Apple by spoofing my phone number as the source caused the Apple Account Confirmation to pop up on all of my signed-in Apple devices.</p>
<p>In essence, the voice phishers are using an automated Apple phone support line to send notifications from Apple and to trick people into thinking they&#8217;re really talking with Apple. The phishing panel video leaked by Stotle shows this technique fooled the target, who felt completely at ease that he was talking to Apple after receiving the support prompt on his iPhone.</p>
<p>&#8220;Okay, so this really is Apple,&#8221; the man said after receiving the alert from Apple. &#8220;Yeah, that&#8217;s definitely not me trying to reset my password.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Not a problem, we can go ahead and take care of this today,&#8221; Michael replied. &#8220;I&#8217;ll go ahead and prompt your device with the steps to close out this ticket. Before I do that, I do highly suggest that you change your password in the settings app of your device.&#8221;</p>
<p>The target said they weren&#8217;t sure exactly how to do that. Michael replied &#8220;no problem,&#8221; and then described how to change the account password, which the man said he did on his own device. At this point, the musician was still in control of his iCloud account.</p>
<p>&#8220;Password is changed,&#8221; the man said. &#8220;I don&#8217;t know what that was, but I appreciate the call.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Yup,&#8221; Michael replied, setting up the killer blow. &#8220;I&#8217;ll go ahead and prompt you with the next step to close out this ticket. Please give me one moment.&#8221;</p>
<p>The target then received a text message that referenced information about his account, stating that he was in a support call with Michael. Included in the message was a link to a website that mimicked Apple&#8217;s iCloud login page &#8212; <strong>17505-apple[.]com</strong>. Once the target navigated to the phishing page, the video showed Perm&#8217;s screen in the upper right corner opening the phishing page from their end.</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh okay, now I log in with my Apple ID?,&#8221; the man asked.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yup, then just follow the steps it requires, and if you need any help, just let me know,&#8221; Michael replied.</p>
<p>As the victim typed in their Apple password and one-time passcode at the fake Apple site, Perm&#8217;s screen could be seen in the background logging into the victim&#8217;s iCloud account.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear whether the phishers were able to steal any cryptocurrency from the victim in this case, who did not respond to requests for comment. However, shortly after this video was recorded, someone leaked several music recordings stolen from the victim&#8217;s iCloud account.</p>
<p>At the conclusion of the call, Michael offered to configure the victim&#8217;s Apple profile so that any further changes to the account would need to happen in person at a physical Apple store. This appears to be one of several scripted ploys used by these voice phishers to gain and maintain the target&#8217;s confidence.</p>
<p>A tutorial shared by Stotle titled &#8220;Social Engineering Script&#8221; includes a number of tips for scam callers that can help establish trust or a rapport with their prey. When the callers are impersonating Coinbase employees, for example, they will offer to sign the user up for the company&#8217;s free security email newsletter.</p>
<p>&#8220;Also, for your security, we are able to subscribe you to Coinbase Bytes, which will basically give you updates to your email about data breaches and updates to your Coinbase account,&#8221; the script reads. &#8220;So we should have gone ahead and successfully subscribed you, and you should have gotten an email confirmation. Please let me know if that is the case. Alright, perfect.&#8221;</p>
<p>In reality, all they are doing is entering the target&#8217;s email address into Coinbase&#8217;s public email newsletter signup page, but it&#8217;s a remarkably effective technique because it demonstrates to the would-be victim that the caller has the ability to send emails from Coinbase.com.</p>
<p>Asked to comment for this story, Apple said there has been no breach, hack, or technical exploit of iCloud or Apple services, and that the company is continuously adding new protections to address new and emerging threats. For example, it said it has implemented rate limiting for multi-factor authentication requests, which <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/recent-mfa-bombing-attacks-targeting-apple-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">have been abused by voice phishing groups to impersonate Apple</a>.</p>
<p>Apple said its representatives will never ask users to provide their password, device passcode, or two-factor authentication code or to enter it into a web page, even if it looks like an official Apple website. If a user receives a message or call that claims to be from Apple, <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/120569" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here is what the user should expect</a>.</p>
<p><span id="more-69922"></span></p>
<h2>AUTODOXERS</h2>
<p>According to Stotle, the target lists used by their phishing callers originate mostly from a few crypto-related data breaches, including the 2022 and <a href="https://blog.trezor.io/trezor-security-update-stay-vigilant-against-potential-phishing-attack-bb05015a21f8?gi=4a9e1da3b8b2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2024 breaches</a> involving user account data stolen from cryptocurrency hardware wallet vendor <strong>Trezor</strong>.</p>
<p>Perm&#8217;s group and other crypto phishing gangs rely on a mix of homemade code and third-party data broker services to refine their target lists. Known as &#8220;<strong>autodoxers</strong>,&#8221; these tools help phishing gangs quickly automate the acquisition and/or verification of personal data on a target prior to each call attempt.</p>
<div id="attachment_69998" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69998" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69998" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vbals-autodoxer.png" alt="" width="748" height="592" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vbals-autodoxer.png 1067w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vbals-autodoxer-768x607.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/vbals-autodoxer-782x619.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69998" class="wp-caption-text">One &#8220;autodoxer&#8221; service advertised on Telegram that promotes a range of voice phishing tools and services.</p></div>
<p>Stotle said their autodoxer used a Telegram bot that leverages hacked accounts at consumer data brokers to gather a wealth of information about their targets, including their full Social Security number, date of birth, current and previous addresses, employer, and the names of family members.</p>
<p>The autodoxers are used to verify that each email address on a target list has an active account at Coinbase or another cryptocurrency exchange, ensuring that the attackers don&#8217;t waste time calling people who have no cryptocurrency to steal.</p>
<p>Some of these autodoxer tools also will check the value of the target&#8217;s home address at property search services online, and then sort the target lists so that the wealthiest are at the top.</p>
<h2>CRYPTO THIEVES IN THE SHARK TANK</h2>
<p>Stotle&#8217;s messages on Discord and Telegram show that a phishing group renting Perm&#8217;s panel voice-phished tens of thousands of dollars worth of cryptocurrency from the billionaire <strong>Mark Cuban</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was an idiot,&#8221; Cuban told KrebsOnsecurity when asked about <a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/business/2024/06/23/mark-cubans-public-email-was-hacked-after-receiving-call-from-a-fake-google-rep/?outputType=amp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the June 2024 attack</a>, which he first disclosed in a short-lived post on Twitter/X. &#8220;We were shooting Shark Tank and I was rushing between pitches.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70008" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70008" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70008" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/sharktank.png" alt="" width="749" height="435" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/sharktank.png 780w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/sharktank-768x446.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70008" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, ssi77.</p></div>
<p>Cuban said he first received a notice from Google that someone had tried to log in to his account. Then he got a call from what appeared to be a Google phone number. Cuban said he ignored several of these emails and calls until he decided they probably wouldn&#8217;t stop unless he answered.</p>
<p>&#8220;So I answered, and wasn&#8217;t paying enough attention,&#8221; he said. &#8220;They asked for the circled number that comes up on the screen. Like a moron, I gave it to them, and they were in.&#8221;</p>
<p>Unfortunately for Cuban, somewhere in his inbox were the secret &#8220;seed phrases&#8221; protecting two of his cryptocurrency accounts, and armed with those credentials the crooks were able to drain his funds. All told, the thieves managed to steal roughly $43,000 worth of cryptocurrencies from Cuban&#8217;s wallets &#8212; a relatively small heist for this crew.</p>
<p>&#8220;They must have done some keyword searches,&#8221; once inside his Gmail account, Cuban said. &#8220;I had sent myself an email I had forgotten about that had my seed words for 2 accounts that weren&#8217;t very active any longer. I had moved almost everything but some smaller balances to Coinbase.&#8221;</p>
<h2>LIFE IS A GAME: MONEY IS HOW WE KEEP SCORE</h2>
<p>Cybercriminals involved in voice phishing communities on Telegram are universally obsessed with their crypto holdings, mainly because in this community one&#8217;s demonstrable wealth is primarily what confers social status. It is not uncommon to see members sizing one another up using a verbal shorthand of &#8220;figs,&#8221; as in figures of crypto wealth.</p>
<p>For example, a low-level caller with no experience will sometimes be mockingly referred to as a 3fig or 3f, as in a person with less than $1,000 to their name. Salaries for callers are often also referenced this way, e.g. &#8220;Weekly salary: 5f.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70058" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70058" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70058" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/howitstartedhowitsgoing.png" alt="" width="749" height="416" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/howitstartedhowitsgoing.png 1265w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/howitstartedhowitsgoing-768x426.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/howitstartedhowitsgoing-782x434.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70058" class="wp-caption-text">This meme shared by Stotle uses humor to depict an all-too-common pathway for voice phishing callers, who are often minors recruited from gaming networks like Minecraft and Roblox. The image that Lookout used in its blog post for Crypto Chameleon can be seen in the lower right hooded figure.</p></div>
<p>Voice phishing groups frequently require new members to provide &#8220;proof of funds&#8221; &#8212; screenshots of their crypto holdings, ostensibly to demonstrate they are not penniless &#8212; before they&#8217;re allowed to join.</p>
<p>This proof of funds (POF) demand is typical among thieves selling high-dollar items, because it tends to cut down on the time-wasting inquiries from criminals who can&#8217;t afford what&#8217;s for sale anyway. But it has become so common in cybercrime communities that there are now several services designed to create fake POF images and videos, allowing customers to brag about large crypto holdings without actually possessing said wealth.</p>
<p>Several of the phishing panel videos shared by Stotle feature audio that suggests co-conspirators were practicing responses to certain call scenarios, while other members of the phishing group critiqued them or tried disrupt their social engineering by being verbally abusive.</p>
<p>These groups will organize and operate for a few weeks, but tend to disintegrate when one member of the conspiracy decides to steal some or all of the loot, referred to in these communities as &#8220;snaking&#8221; others out of their agreed-upon sums. Almost invariably, the phishing groups will splinter apart over the drama caused by one of these snaking events, and individual members eventually will then re-form a new phishing group.</p>
<p><strong>Allison Nixon</strong> is the chief research officer for <a href="https://www.unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a>, a cybersecurity firm in New York that has worked on a number of investigations involving these voice phishing groups. Nixon said the constant snaking within the voice phishing circles points to a psychological self-selection phenomenon that is in desperate need of academic study.</p>
<p>&#8220;In short, a person whose moral compass lets them rob old people will also be a bad business partner,&#8221; Nixon said. &#8220;This is another fundamental flaw in this ecosystem and why most groups end in betrayal. This structural problem is great for journalists and the police too. Lots of snitching.&#8221;</p>
<h2>POINTS FOR BRAZENNESS</h2>
<p>Asked about the size of Perm&#8217;s phishing enterprise, Stotle said there were dozens of distinct phishing groups paying to use Perm&#8217;s panel. He said each group was assigned their own subdomain on Perm&#8217;s main &#8220;command and control server,&#8221; which naturally uses the domain name <strong>commandandcontrolserver[.]com</strong>.</p>
<p>A review of that domain&#8217;s history via <strong>DomainTools.com</strong> shows there are at least 57 separate subdomains scattered across commandandcontrolserver[.]com and two other related control domains &#8212; <strong>thebackendserver[.]com</strong> and <strong>lookoutsucks[.]com</strong>. That latter domain was created and deployed shortly after Lookout published its blog post on Crypto Chameleon.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://urlscan.io/search/#page.url%3A%22captcha%3Forigin%3D%22" target="_blank" rel="noopener">dozens of phishing domains that phone home to these control servers</a> are all kept offline when they are not actively being used in phishing attacks. A social engineering training guide shared by Stotle explains this practice minimizes the chances that a phishing domain will get &#8220;redpaged,&#8221; a reference to the default red warning pages served by Google Chrome or Firefox whenever someone tries to visit a site that&#8217;s been flagged for phishing or distributing malware.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, while the phishing sites are live their operators typically place a CAPTCHA challenge in front of the main page to prevent security services from scanning and flagging the sites as malicious.</p>
<p>It may seem odd that so many cybercriminal groups operate so openly on instant collaboration networks like Telegram and Discord. After all, this blog is replete with stories about cybercriminals getting caught thanks to personal details they inadvertently leaked or disclosed themselves.</p>
<p>Nixon said the relative openness of these cybercrime communities makes them inherently risky, but it also allows for the rapid formation and recruitment of new potential co-conspirators. Moreover, today&#8217;s English-speaking cybercriminals tend to be <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/10/lamborghini-carjackers-lured-by-243m-cyberheist/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more afraid of getting home invaded or mugged by fellow cyber thieves</a> than they are of being arrested by authorities.</p>
<p>&#8220;The biggest structural threat to the online criminal ecosystem is not the police or researchers, it is fellow criminals,&#8221; Nixon said. &#8220;To protect them from themselves, every criminal forum and marketplace has a reputation system, even though they know it&#8217;s a major liability when the police come. That is why I am not worried as we see criminals migrate to various &#8216;encrypted&#8217; platforms that promise to ignore the police. To protect themselves better against the law, they have to ditch their protections against fellow criminals and that&#8217;s not going to happen.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Army Soldier Arrested in AT&#038;T, Verizon Extortions</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-army-soldier-arrested-in-att-verizon-extortions/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-army-soldier-arrested-in-att-verizon-extortions/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 04:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allison Nixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cameron John Wagenius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Connor Riley Moucka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judische]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiberphant0m]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unit 221B]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Federal authorities have arrested and indicted a 20-year-old U.S. Army soldier on suspicion of being Kiberphant0m, a cybercriminal who has been selling and leaking sensitive customer call records stolen earlier this year from AT&#038;T and Verizon. As first reported by KrebsOnSecurity last month, the accused is a communications specialist who was recently stationed in South Korea.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Federal authorities have arrested and indicted a 20-year-old U.S. Army soldier on suspicion of being <strong>Kiberphant0m</strong>, a cybercriminal who has been selling and leaking sensitive customer call records stolen earlier this year from <strong>AT&amp;T</strong> and <strong>Verizon</strong>. As first reported by KrebsOnSecurity last month, the accused is a communications specialist who was recently stationed in South Korea.</p>
<div id="attachment_69974" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69974" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69974" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie.png" alt="" width="750" height="743" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie.png 779w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie-768x761.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69974" class="wp-caption-text">One of several selfies on the Facebook page of Cameron Wagenius.</p></div>
<p><strong>Cameron John Wagenius</strong> was arrested near the Army base in Fort Hood, Texas on Dec. 20, after being indicted on two criminal counts of unlawful transfer of confidential phone records.</p>
<p>The sparse, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/wagenius-indictment.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">two-page indictment</a> (PDF) doesn&#8217;t reference specific victims or hacking activity, nor does it include any personal details about the accused. But a conversation with Wagenius&#8217; mother &#8212; Minnesota native <strong>Alicia Roen </strong>&#8212; filled in the gaps.</p>
<p>Roen said that prior to her son&#8217;s arrest he&#8217;d acknowledged being associated with <strong>Connor Riley Moucka</strong>, a.k.a. &#8220;<strong>Judische</strong>,&#8221; a prolific cybercriminal from Canada who was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested in late October</a> for stealing data from and extorting dozens of companies that stored data at the cloud service <strong>Snowflake</strong>.</p>
<p>In an interview with KrebsOnSecurity, Judische said he had no interest in selling the data he&#8217;d stolen from Snowflake customers and telecom providers, and that he preferred to outsource that to Kiberphant0m and others. Meanwhile, Kiberphant0m claimed in posts on Telegram that he was responsible for hacking into at least 15 telecommunications firms, including AT&amp;T and Verizon.</p>
<p>On November 26, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published a story</a> that followed a trail of clues left behind by Kiberphantom indicating he was a U.S. Army soldier stationed in South Korea.</p>
<p>Ms. Roen said Cameron worked on radio signals and network communications at an Army base in South Korea for the past two years, returning to the United States periodically. She said Cameron was always good with computers, but that she had no idea he might have been involved in criminal hacking.</p>
<p>&#8220;I never was aware he was into hacking,&#8221; Roen said. &#8220;It was definitely a shock to me when we found this stuff out.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ms. Roen said Cameron joined the Army as soon as he was of age, following in his older brother&#8217;s footsteps.</p>
<p>&#8220;He and his brother when they were like 6 and 7 years old would ask for MREs from other countries,&#8221; she recalled, referring to military-issued &#8220;meals ready to eat&#8221; food rations. &#8220;They both always wanted to be in the Army. I&#8217;m not sure where things went wrong.&#8221;<span id="more-69925"></span></p>
<p>Immediately after news broke of Moucka’s arrest, Kiberphant0m posted on the hacker community <strong>BreachForums</strong> what they claimed were the AT&amp;T call logs for <strong>President-elect</strong> <strong>Donald J. Trump</strong> and for <strong>Vice President Kamala Harris</strong>.</p>
<p>“In the event you do not reach out to us @ATNT all presidential government call logs will be leaked,” Kiberphant0m threatened, signing their post with multiple “#FREEWAIFU” tags. “You don’t think we don’t have plans in the event of an arrest? Think again.”</p>
<div id="attachment_69624" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69624" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69624" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema.png" alt="" width="750" height="239" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema.png 1417w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema-768x245.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema-782x249.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69624" class="wp-caption-text">Kiberphant0m posting what he claimed was a &#8220;data schema&#8221; stolen from the NSA via AT&amp;T.</p></div>
<p>On that same day, Kiberphant0m posted what they claimed was the “data schema” from the <strong>U.S. National Security Agency</strong>.</p>
<p>On Nov. 5, Kiberphant0m offered call logs stolen from Verizon’s push-to-talk (PTT) customers — mainly U.S. government agencies and emergency first responders. On Nov. 9, Kiberphant0m posted a sales thread on BreachForums offering a “SIM-swapping” service targeting Verizon PTT customers. In a SIM-swap, fraudsters use credentials that are phished or stolen from mobile phone company employees to divert a target’s phone calls and text messages to a device they control.</p>
<p>The profile photo on Wagenius&#8217; Facebook page was deleted within hours of my Nov. 26 story identifying Kiberphant0m as a likely U.S. Army soldier. Still, many of his original profile photos remain, including several that show Wagenius in uniform while holding various Army-issued weapons.</p>
<div id="attachment_69972" style="width: 612px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69972" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69972" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/wagenius-fb.png" alt="" width="602" height="842" /><p id="caption-attachment-69972" class="wp-caption-text">Several profile photos visible on the Facebook page of Cameron Wagenius.</p></div>
<p>November&#8217;s story on Kiberphant0m cited his own Telegram messages saying he maintained a large botnet that was used for distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks to knock websites, users and networks offline. In 2023, Kiberphant0m sold remote access credentials for a major U.S. defense contractor.</p>
<p><strong>Allison Nixon,</strong> chief research officer at the New York-based cybersecurity firm <a href="https://www.unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a>, helped track down Kiberphant0m&#8217;s real life identity. Nixon was among several security researchers who faced harassment and specific threats of violence from Judische and his associates.</p>
<p>&#8220;Anonymously extorting the President and VP as a member of the military is a bad idea, but it&#8217;s an even worse idea to harass people who specialize in de-anonymizing cybercriminals,&#8221; Nixon told KrebsOnSecurity. She said the investigation into Kiberphant0m shows that law enforcement is getting better and faster at going after cybercriminals &#8212; especially those who are actually living in the United States.</p>
<p>&#8220;Between when we, and an anonymous colleague, found his opsec mistake on November 10th to his last Telegram activity on December 6, law enforcement set the speed record for the fastest turnaround time for an American federal cyber case that I have witnessed in my career,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>Nixon asked to share a message for all the other Kiberphant0ms out there who think they can&#8217;t be found and arrested.</p>
<p>&#8220;I know that young people involved in cybercrime will read these articles,&#8221; Nixon said. &#8220;You need to stop doing stupid shit and get a lawyer. Law enforcement wants to put all of you in prison for a long time.&#8221;</p>
<p>The indictment against Wagenius was filed in Texas, but the case has been transferred to the U.S. District Court for the Western District of Washington in Seattle.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-army-soldier-arrested-in-att-verizon-extortions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 15th Anniversary, KrebsOnSecurity!</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/happy-15th-anniversary-krebsonsecurity/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/happy-15th-anniversary-krebsonsecurity/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 23:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[KrebsOnSecurity.com turns 15 years old today! Maybe it's indelicate to celebrate the birthday of a cybercrime blog that mostly publishes bad news, but happily many of 2024's most engrossing security stories were about bad things happening to bad guys. It's also an occasion to note that despite my publishing fewer stories than ever this past year, we somehow managed to attract near record levels of readership (thank you!).]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_69961" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69961" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69961" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/15bday.png" alt="" width="749" height="486" /><p id="caption-attachment-69961" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, Dreamansions.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity.com turns 15 years old today! Maybe it&#8217;s indelicate to celebrate the birthday of a cybercrime blog that mostly publishes bad news, but happily many of 2024&#8217;s most engrossing security stories were about bad things happening to bad guys. It&#8217;s also an occasion to note that despite my publishing fewer stories than ever this past year, we somehow managed to attract near record levels of readership (thank you!).</p>
<p>In case you missed any of them, here&#8217;s a recap of 2024&#8217;s most-read stories. In January, KrebsOnSecurity told the story of a Canadian man who was falsely charged with larceny and lost his job after becoming the victim of a <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/01/canadian-man-stuck-in-triangle-of-e-commerce-fraud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">complex e-commerce scam known as triangulation fraud.</a> This can occur when you buy something online — from a seller on <strong>Amazon</strong> or <strong>eBay</strong>, for example — but the seller doesn’t actually own the item for sale. Instead, they purchase the item using stolen payment card data and your shipping address. In this scam, you receive what you ordered, and the only party left to dispute the transaction is the owner of the stolen payment card.</p>
<div id="attachment_32692" style="width: 590px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-32692" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-32692" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/triangulationfraud-580x318.png" alt="" width="580" height="318" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/triangulationfraud-580x318.png 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/triangulationfraud.png 637w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /><p id="caption-attachment-32692" class="wp-caption-text">Triangulation fraud. Image: eBay Enterprise.</p></div>
<p>March featured several investigations into the history of various people-search data broker services. One story exposed how the Belarusian CEO of the privacy and data removal service <strong>OneRep</strong> had actually <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/ceo-of-data-privacy-company-onerep-com-founded-dozens-of-people-search-firms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">founded dozens of people-search services</a>, including many that OneRep was offering to remove people from for a fee. That story quickly <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/mozilla-drops-onerep-after-ceo-admits-to-running-people-search-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prompted Mozilla to terminate its partnership with OneRep</a>, which Mozilla had bundled as a privacy option for Firefox users.</p>
<p>A story digging into the consumer data broker <strong>Radaris</strong> <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/a-close-up-look-at-the-consumer-data-broker-radaris/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found its CEO was a fabricated identity</a>, and that the company&#8217;s founders were Russian brothers in Massachusetts who operated multiple Russian language dating services and affiliate programs, in addition to a dizzying array of people-search websites.</p>
<p>Radaris repeatedly threatened to sue KrebsOnSecurity unless that publication was retracted in full, alleging that it was replete with errors both factual and malicious. Instead, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/06/krebsonsecurity-threatened-with-defamation-lawsuit-over-fake-radaris-ceo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">we doubled down and published all of the supporting evidence</a> that wasn&#8217;t included in the original story, leaving little room for doubt about its conclusions. Fittingly, Radaris now pimps OneRep as a service when consumers request that their personal information be removed from the data broker&#8217;s website.</p>
<p>Easily the longest story this year was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-an-iron-hammer-in-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an investigation into Stark Industries Solutions</a>, a large, mysterious new Internet hosting firm that materialized when Russia invaded Ukraine. That piece revealed how Stark was being used as a global proxy network to conceal the true source of cyberattacks and disinformation campaigns against enemies of Russia.</p>
<div id="attachment_67471" style="width: 756px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-67471" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-67471" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions.png" alt="" width="746" height="463" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions.png 1197w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-768x477.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-782x485.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 746px) 100vw, 746px" /><p id="caption-attachment-67471" class="wp-caption-text">The homepage of Stark Industries Solutions.</p></div>
<p>Much of my summer was spent reporting a story about how advertising and marketing firms have created <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/10/the-global-surveillance-free-for-all-in-mobile-ad-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a global free-for-all where anyone can track the daily movements and associations of hundreds of millions of mobile devices</a>, thanks to the ubiquity of mobile location data that is broadly and cheaply available.<span id="more-69936"></span></p>
<p>Research published in September explored <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the dark nexus between harm groups and cybercrime communities consumed with perpetrating financial fraud</a>. That analysis found an increasing number of young, Western cybercriminals are also members of fast-growing online groups that exist solely to bully, stalk, harass and extort vulnerable teens into physically harming themselves and others.</p>
<p>One focus of that story was a Canadian cybercriminal who used the nickname <strong>Judische. </strong>Identified by the Mandiant as one of the most consequential threat actors of 2024, Judische was responsible for a hacking rampage that exposed private information on hundreds of millions of Americans.  That story withheld Judische&#8217;s real name, but the reporting came in handy in late October when <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 25-year-old Canadian man named Connor Riley Moucka was arrested and charged with 20 criminal counts connected to the Snowflake data extortions</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_69625" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69625" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69625" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance.png" alt="" width="747" height="573" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance.png 1137w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance-768x590.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance-782x600.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69625" class="wp-caption-text">A surveillance photo of Connor Riley Moucka, a.k.a. &#8220;Judische&#8221; and &#8220;Waifu,&#8221; dated Oct 21, 2024, 9 days before Moucka&#8217;s arrest. This image was included in an affidavit filed by an investigator with the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP).</p></div>
<p>In November, KrebsOnSecurity published a profile of Judische&#8217;s accomplice &#8212; a hacker known as <strong>Kiberphant0m</strong> &#8212; detailing how Kiberphant0m had left a trail of clues strongly suggesting that <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">they are or recently were a U.S. Army soldier stationed in South Korea</a>.</p>
<p>My reporting in December was mainly split between two investigations. The first profiled <strong>Cryptomus</strong>, a dodgy cryptocurrency exchange allegedly based in Canada that has become a major payment processor and sanctions evasion platform <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-cryptocurrency-turns-to-cash-in-russian-banks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for dozens of Russian exchanges and cybercrime services online</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-to-lose-a-fortune-with-just-one-bad-click/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How to Lose a Fortune with Just One Bad Click</a> told the sad tales of two cryptocurrency heist victims who were scammed out of six and seven figures after falling for complex social engineering schemes over the phone. In these attacks, the phishers abused at least four different Google services to trick targets into believing they were speaking with a Google representative, and into giving thieves control over their account with a single click. Look for a story here in early 2025 that will explore the internal operations of these ruthless and ephemeral voice phishing gangs.</p>
<p>Before signing off for 2024, allow me to remind readers that the reporting we&#8217;re able to provide here is made possible primarily by the ads you may see at the top of this website. If you currently don&#8217;t see any ads when you load this website, please consider enabling an exception in your ad blocker for KrebsOnSecurity.com. There is zero third-party content on this website, apart from the occasional Youtube video embedded as part of a story. More importantly, all of our ads are static images or GIFs that are vetted by me and served in-house directly.</p>
<p>Fundamentally, my work is supported and improved by <em>your</em> <em>readership</em>, tips, encouragement and, yes, criticism. So thank you for that, and keep it coming, please.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s to a happy, healthy, wealthy and wary 2025. Hope to see you all again in the New Year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/happy-15th-anniversary-krebsonsecurity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>56</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web Hacking Service &#8216;Araneida&#8217; Tied to Turkish IT Firm</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/web-hacking-service-araneida-tied-to-turkish-it-firm/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/web-hacking-service-araneida-tied-to-turkish-it-firm/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 17:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acunetix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altug Sara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altugsara321@gmail.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Araneida Scanner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bilitro Yazilim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domaintools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fin7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Invicti Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Sciberras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neil Roseman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ori0nbusiness@protonmail.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Department of Health and Human Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cybercriminals are selling hundreds of thousands of credential sets stolen with the help of a cracked version of Acunetix, a powerful commercial web app vulnerability scanner, new research finds. The cracked software is being resold as a cloud-based attack tool by at least two different services, one of which KrebsOnSecurity traced to an information technology firm based in Turkey.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cybercriminals are selling hundreds of thousands of credential sets stolen with the help of a cracked version of <strong>Acunetix</strong>, a powerful commercial web app vulnerability scanner, new research finds. The cracked software is being resold as a cloud-based attack tool by at least two different services, one of which KrebsOnSecurity traced to an information technology firm based in Turkey.</p>
<div id="attachment_69895" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69895" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69895" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-scanner.png" alt="" width="749" height="562" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-scanner.png 1126w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-scanner-768x576.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-scanner-782x587.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69895" class="wp-caption-text">Araneida Scanner.</p></div>
<p>Cyber threat analysts at <strong>Silent Push</strong> said they recently received reports from a partner organization that identified an aggressive scanning effort against their website using an Internet address previously associated with a campaign by <a href="https://resources.prodaft.com/fin7-cybercrime-gang" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FIN7</a>, a notorious Russia-based hacking group.</p>
<p>But on closer inspection they discovered the address contained an HTML title of &#8220;<strong>Araneida Customer Panel</strong>,&#8221; and found they could search on that text string to find dozens of unique addresses hosting the same service.</p>
<p>It soon became apparent that Araneida was being resold as a cloud-based service using a cracked version of Acunetix, allowing paying customers to conduct offensive reconnaissance on potential target websites, scrape user data, and find vulnerabilities for exploitation.</p>
<p>Silent Push also learned Araneida bundles its service with a robust proxy offering, so that customer scans appear to come from Internet addresses that are randomly selected from a large pool of available traffic relays.</p>
<p>The makers of Acunetix, Texas-based application security vendor <strong>Invicti Security</strong>, confirmed Silent Push&#8217;s findings, saying someone had figured out how to crack the free trial version of the software so that it runs without a valid license key.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have been playing cat and mouse for a while with these guys,&#8221; said <strong>Matt Sciberras</strong>, chief information security officer at Invicti.</p>
<p>Silent Push said Araneida is being advertised by an eponymous user on multiple cybercrime forums. The service&#8217;s Telegram channel boasts nearly 500 subscribers and explains how to use the tool for malicious purposes.</p>
<p>In a &#8220;Fun Facts&#8221; list posted to the channel in late September, Araneida said their service was used to take over more than 30,000 websites in just six months, and that one customer used it to buy a Porsche with the payment card data (&#8220;dumps&#8221;) they sold.</p>
<div id="attachment_69898" style="width: 668px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69898" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69898" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/araneida-tg.png" alt="" width="658" height="273" /><p id="caption-attachment-69898" class="wp-caption-text">Araneida Scanner&#8217;s Telegram channel bragging about how customers are using the service for cybercrime.</p></div>
<p>“They are constantly bragging with their community about the crimes that are being committed, how it’s making criminals money,” said <strong>Zach Edwards</strong>, a senior threat researcher at Silent Push. “They are also selling bulk data and dumps which appear to have been acquired with this tool or due to vulnerabilities found with the tool.”</p>
<p>Silent Push also found a cracked version of Acunetix was powering at least 20 instances of a similar cloud-based vulnerability testing service catering to Mandarin speakers, but they were unable to find any apparently related sales threads about them on the dark web.</p>
<p>Rumors of a cracked version of Acunetix being used by attackers surfaced <a href="https://x.com/FalconFeedsio/status/1665690661377691649" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in June 2023 on Twitter/X</a>, when researchers <a href="https://x.com/TLP_R3D/status/1665777020767293447" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first posited a connection between observed scanning activity and Araneida</a>.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/china-based-threat-actor-profiles-tlpclear.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an August 2023 report</a> (PDF) from the <strong>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</strong> (HHS), Acunetix (presumably a cracked version) is among several tools used by <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/09/chinese-antivirus-firm-was-part-of-apt41-supply-chain-attack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">APT 41</a>, a prolific Chinese state-sponsored hacking group.<span id="more-69811"></span></p>
<h2>THE TURKISH CONNECTION</h2>
<p>Silent Push notes that the website where Araneida is being sold &#8212; <strong>araneida[.]co</strong> &#8212; first came online in February 2023. But a review of this Araneida nickname on the cybercrime forums shows they have been active in the criminal hacking scene since at least 2018.</p>
<p>A search in the threat intelligence platform <a href="https://www.intel471.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel 471</a> shows a user by the name Araneida promoted the scanner on two cybercrime forums since 2022, including <strong>Breached</strong> and <strong>Nulled</strong>. In 2022, Araneida told fellow Breached members they could be reached on Discord at the username &#8220;<strong>Ornie#9811</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to Intel 471, this same Discord account was advertised in 2019 by a person on the cybercrime forum <strong>Cracked</strong> who used the monikers &#8220;<strong>ORN</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>ori0n</strong>.&#8221; The user &#8220;ori0n&#8221; mentioned in several posts that they could be reached on Telegram at the username &#8220;<strong>@sirorny</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_69912" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69912" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69912" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/orn-araneida.png" alt="" width="749" height="411" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/orn-araneida.png 1002w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/orn-araneida-768x422.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/orn-araneida-782x429.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69912" class="wp-caption-text">Orn advertising Araneida Scanner in Feb. 2023 on the forum Cracked. Image: Ke-la.com.</p></div>
<p>The Sirorny Telegram identity also was referenced as a point of contact for a current user on the cybercrime forum Nulled who is selling website development services, and who references araneida[.]co as one of their projects. That user, &#8220;<strong>Exorn</strong>,&#8221; has posts dating back to August 2018.</p>
<p>In early 2020, Exorn promoted a website called &#8220;<strong>orndorks[.]com</strong>,&#8221; which they described as a service for automating the scanning for web-based vulnerabilities. A passive DNS lookup on this domain at <a href="https://www.domaintools.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DomainTools.com</a> shows that its email records pointed to the address <strong>ori0nbusiness@protonmail.com</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.constella.ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Constella Intelligence</a>, a company that tracks information exposed in data breaches, finds this email address was used to register an account at <strong>Breachforums</strong> in July 2024 under the nickname &#8220;<strong>Ornie</strong>.&#8221; Constella also finds the same email registered at the website netguard[.]codes in 2021 using the password &#8220;<strong>ceza2003</strong>&#8221; [full disclosure: Constella is currently an advertiser on KrebsOnSecurity].</p>
<p>A search on the password ceza2003 in Constella finds roughly a dozen email addresses that used it in an exposed data breach, most of them featuring some variation on the name &#8220;<strong>altugsara</strong>,&#8221; including <strong>altugsara321@gmail.com</strong>. Constella further finds altugsara321@gmail.com was used to create an account at the cybercrime community <strong>RaidForums</strong> under the username &#8220;<strong>ori0n</strong>,&#8221; from an Internet address in Istanbul.</p>
<p>According to DomainTools, altugsara321@gmail.com was used in 2020 to register the domain name <strong>altugsara[.]com</strong>. <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20211125114845/http://altugsara.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Archive.org&#8217;s history for that domain</a> shows that in 2021 it featured a website for a then 18-year-old <strong>Altuğ Şara</strong> from Ankara, Turkey.</p>
<div id="attachment_69893" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69893" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-69893" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/altugsaradotcom.png" alt="" width="749" height="345" /><p id="caption-attachment-69893" class="wp-caption-text">Archive.org&#8217;s recollection of what altugsara dot com looked like in 2021.</p></div>
<p><strong>LinkedIn</strong> finds this same <strong>altugsara[.]com</strong> domain listed in the &#8220;contact info&#8221; section of <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/altu%C4%9F-%C5%9Fara-58957b212/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a profile</a> for an <strong>Altug Sara</strong> from Ankara, who says he has worked the past two years as a senior software developer for a Turkish IT firm called <strong>Bilitro Yazilim</strong>.</p>
<p>Neither Altug Sara nor Bilitro Yazilim responded to requests for comment.</p>
<p>Invicti&#8217;s website states that it has offices in Ankara, but the company&#8217;s CEO said none of their employees recognized either name.</p>
<p>&#8220;We do have a small team in Ankara, but as far as I know we have no connection to the individual other than the fact that they are also in Ankara,&#8221; Invicti CEO <strong>Neil Roseman</strong> told KrebsOnSecurity.</p>
<p>Researchers at Silent Push say despite Araneida using a seemingly endless supply of proxies to mask the true location of its users, it is a fairly &#8220;noisy&#8221; scanner that will kick off a large volume of requests to various API endpoints, and make requests to random URLs associated with different content management systems.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, the cracked version of Acunetix being resold to cybercriminals invokes legacy Acunetix SSL certificates on active control panels, which Silent Push says provides a solid pivot for finding some of this infrastructure, particularly from the Chinese threat actors.</p>
<p>Further reading: <a href="https://www.silentpush.com/blog/araneida-scanner-acunetix" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Silent Push&#8217;s research on Araneida Scanner</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/web-hacking-service-araneida-tied-to-turkish-it-firm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Lose a Fortune with Just One Bad Click</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-to-lose-a-fortune-with-just-one-bad-click/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-to-lose-a-fortune-with-just-one-bad-click/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 13:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[(650) 203-0000]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel from Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gemini AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Assistant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Docs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Forms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Graham Cluely]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Junseth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SwanCoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trezor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Adam Griffin is still in disbelief over how quickly he was robbed of nearly $500,000 in cryptocurrencies. A scammer called using a real Google phone number to warn his Gmail account was being hacked, sent email security alerts directly from google.com, and ultimately seized control over the account by convincing him to click "yes" to a Google prompt on his mobile device.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_69859" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69859" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69859" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/thumb-mobile.png" alt="" width="749" height="441" /><p id="caption-attachment-69859" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock, iHaMoo.</p></div>
<p><strong>Adam Griffin</strong> is still in disbelief over how quickly he was robbed of nearly $500,000 in cryptocurrencies. A scammer called using a real <strong>Google</strong> phone number to warn his Gmail account was being hacked, sent email security alerts directly from google.com, and ultimately seized control over the account by convincing him to click &#8220;yes&#8221; to a Google prompt on his mobile device.</p>
<p>Griffin is a battalion chief firefighter in the Seattle area, and on May 6 he received a call from someone claiming they were from Google support saying his account was being accessed from Germany. A Google search on the phone number calling him &#8212; <strong>(650) 203-0000</strong> &#8212; revealed it was an official number for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Assistant" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Assistant</a>, an AI-based service that can engage in two-way conversations.</p>
<p>At the same time, he received an email that came from a google.com email address, warning his Google account was compromised. The message included a &#8220;Google Support Case ID number&#8221; and information about the Google representative supposedly talking to him on the phone, stating the rep&#8217;s name as &#8220;Ashton&#8221;<strong> </strong>&#8212; the same name given by the caller.</p>
<p>Griffin didn&#8217;t learn this until much later, but the email he received had a real google.com address because it was sent via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Forms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Forms</a>, a service available to all <strong>Google Docs</strong> users that makes it easy to send surveys, quizzes and other communications.</p>
<div id="attachment_69865" style="width: 499px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69865" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69865" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/gsid19472345.png" alt="" width="489" height="833" /><p id="caption-attachment-69865" class="wp-caption-text">A phony security alert Griffin received prior to his bitcoin heist, via Google Forms.</p></div>
<p>According to tripwire.com&#8217;s <strong>Graham Cluely</strong>, phishers will use Google Forms to create a security alert message, and then change the form&#8217;s settings to automatically send a copy of the completed form to any email address entered into the form. The attacker then sends an invitation to complete the form to themselves, not to their intended victim.</p>
<p>&#8220;So, the attacker receives the invitation to fill out the form &#8211; and when they complete it, they enter their intended victim&#8217;s email address into the form, not their own,&#8221; Cluely <a href="https://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/google-forms-used-call-back-phishing-scam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote in a December 2023 post</a>. &#8220;The attackers are taking advantage of the fact that the emails are being sent out directly by Google Forms (from the google.com domain). It&#8217;s an established legitimate domain that helps to make the email look more legitimate and is less likely to be intercepted en route by email-filtering solutions.&#8221;</p>
<p>The fake Google representative was polite, patient, professional and reassuring. Ashton told Griffin he was going to receive a notification that would allow him to regain control of the account from the hackers. Sure enough, a Google prompt instantly appeared on his phone asking, &#8220;Is it you trying to recover your account?&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_69818" style="width: 520px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69818" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-69818" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/griffin-gar.png" alt="" width="510" height="889" /><p id="caption-attachment-69818" class="wp-caption-text">Adam Griffin clicked &#8220;yes,&#8221; to an account recovery notification similar to this one on May 6.</p></div>
<p>Griffin said that after receiving the pop-up prompt from Google on his phone, he felt more at ease that he really was talking to someone at Google. In reality, the thieves caused the alert to appear on his phone merely by stepping through Google&#8217;s account recovery process for Griffin&#8217;s Gmail address.</p>
<p>&#8220;As soon as I clicked yes, I gave them access to my Gmail, which was synched to <strong>Google Photos</strong>,&#8221; Griffin said.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for Griffin, years ago he used Google Photos to store an image of the secret seed phrase that was protecting his cryptocurrency wallet. Armed with that phrase, the phishers could drain all of his funds.</p>
<p>&#8220;From there they were able to transfer approximately $450,000 out of my Exodus wallet,&#8221; Griffin recalled.</p>
<p>Griffin said just minutes after giving away access to his Gmail account he received a call from someone claiming to be with Coinbase, who likewise told him someone in Germany was trying to take over his account.</p>
<p>Griffin said a follow-up investigation revealed the attackers had used his Gmail account to gain access to his Coinbase account from a VPN connection in California, providing the multi-factor code from his Google Authenticator app. Unbeknownst to him at the time, Google Authenticator by default also makes the same codes available in one&#8217;s Google account online.</p>
<p>But when the thieves tried to move $100,000 worth of cryptocurrency out of his account, Coinbase sent an email stating that the account had been locked, and that he would have to submit additional verification documents before he could do anything with it.<span id="more-69474"></span></p>
<h2>GRAND THEFT AUTOMATED</h2>
<p>Just days after Griffin was robbed, a scammer impersonating Google managed to phish 45 bitcoins &#8212; approximately $4,725,000 at today&#8217;s value &#8212; from <strong>Tony</strong>, a 42-year-old professional from northern California. Tony agreed to speak about his harrowing experience on condition that his last name not be used.</p>
<p>Tony got into bitcoin back in 2013 and has been investing in it ever since. On the evening of May 15, 2024, Tony was putting his three- and one-year-old boys to bed when he received a message from Google about an account security issue, followed by a phone call from a &#8220;Daniel Alexander&#8221; at Google who said his account was compromised by hackers.</p>
<p>Tony said he had just signed up for Google&#8217;s <strong>Gemini AI</strong> (an artificial intelligence platform formerly known as &#8220;Bard&#8221;), and mistakenly believed the call was part of that service. Daniel told Tony his account was being accessed by someone in Frankfurt, Germany, and that he could evict the hacker and recover access to the account by clicking &#8220;yes&#8221; to the prompt that Google was going to send to his phone.</p>
<p>The Google prompt arrived seconds later. And to his everlasting regret, Tony clicked the &#8220;Yes, it&#8217;s me&#8221; button.</p>
<p>Then came another call, this one allegedly from security personnel at <strong>Trezor</strong>, a company that makes encrypted hardware devices made to store cryptocurrency seed phrases securely offline. The caller said someone had submitted a request to Trezor to close his account, and they forwarded Tony a message sent from his Gmail account that included his name, Social Security number, date of birth, address, phone number and email address.</p>
<p>Tony said he began to believe then that his Trezor account truly was compromised. The caller convinced him to &#8220;recover&#8221; his account by entering his cryptocurrency seed phrase at a phishing website (<strong>verify-trezor[.]io</strong>) that mimicked the official Trezor website.</p>
<p>&#8220;At this point I go into fight or flight mode,&#8221; Tony recalled. &#8220;I&#8217;ve got my kids crying, my wife is like what the heck is going on? My brain went haywire. I put my seed phrase into a phishing site, and that was it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Almost immediately, all of the funds he was planning to save for retirement and for his children&#8217;s college fund were drained from his account.</p>
<p>&#8220;I made mistakes due to being so busy and not thinking correctly,&#8221; Tony told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;I had gotten so far away from the security protocols in bitcoin as life had changed so much since having kids.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_69821" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69821" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69821" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/tony-text.png" alt="" width="747" height="540" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/tony-text.png 867w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/tony-text-768x555.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/tony-text-782x565.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69821" class="wp-caption-text">Tony shared this text message exchange of him pleading with his tormentors after being robbed of 45 bitcoins.</p></div>
<p>Tony said the theft left him traumatized and angry for months.</p>
<p>&#8220;All I was thinking about was protecting my boys and it ended up costing me everything,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Needless to say I&#8217;m devastated and have had to do serious therapy to get through it.&#8221;</p>
<h2>MISERY LOVES COMPANY</h2>
<p>Tony told KrebsOnSecurity that in the weeks following the theft of his 45 bitcoins, he became so consumed with rage and shame that he was seriously contemplating suicide. Then one day, while scouring the Internet for signs that others may have been phished by Daniel, he encountered Griffin posting on Reddit about the phone number involved in his recent bitcoin theft.</p>
<p>Griffin said the two of them were initially suspicious of each other &#8212; exchanging cautious messages for about a week &#8212; but he decided Tony was telling the truth after contacting the FBI agent that Tony said was working his case. Comparing notes, they discovered the fake Google security alerts they received just prior to their individual bitcoin thefts referenced the same phony &#8220;Google Support Case ID&#8221; number.</p>
<div id="attachment_69819" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69819" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69819" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/tony-gar.png" alt="" width="750" height="618" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/tony-gar.png 828w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/tony-gar-768x633.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/tony-gar-782x644.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69819" class="wp-caption-text">Adam Griffin and Tony said they received the same Google Support Case ID number in advance of their thefts. Both were sent via Google Forms, which sends directly from the google.com domain name.</p></div>
<p>More importantly, Tony recognized the voice of &#8220;Daniel from Google&#8221; when it was featured in an interview by <strong>Junseth</strong>, a podcaster who covers cryptocurrency scams. The same voice that had coaxed Tony out of his considerable cryptocurrency holdings just days earlier also had tried to phish Junseth, who played along for several minutes before revealing he knew it was a scam.</p>
<p>Daniel told Junseth he was a teenager and worked with other scam callers who had all met years ago on the game <strong>Minecraft</strong>, and that he recently enjoyed a run of back-to-back Gmail account compromises that led to crypto theft paydays.</p>
<p>&#8220;No one gets arrested,&#8221; Daniel enthused to Junseth in the May 7 podcast, which quickly went viral on social media. &#8220;It&#8217;s almost like there&#8217;s no consequences. I have small legal side hustles, like businesses and shit that I can funnel everything through. If you were to see me in real life, I look like a regular child going to school with my backpack and shit, you’d never expect this kid is stealing all this shit.&#8221;</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NmsAk3kXdz4?si=aJKlS76K2FyPXfaj" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>Daniel explained that they often use an automated bot that initiates calls to targets warning that their account is experiencing suspicious activity, and that they should press &#8220;1&#8221; to speak with a representative. This process, he explained, essentially self-selects people who are more likely to be susceptible to their social engineering schemes. [It is possible &#8212; but not certain &#8212; that this bot Daniel referenced explains the incoming call to Griffin from Google Assistant that precipitated his bitcoin heist].</p>
<p>Daniel told Junseth he and his co-conspirators had just scored a $1.2 million theft that was still pending on the bitcoin investment platform SwanBitcoin. In response, Junseth <a href="https://x.com/verysmallclaims/status/1787950799202468147" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tagged SwanBitcoin in a post about his podcast on Twitter/X</a>, and the CEO of Swan quickly <a href="https://x.com/coryklippsten/status/1787983800389308465" target="_blank" rel="noopener">replied</a> that they caught the $1.2 million transaction that morning.</p>
<p>Apparently, Daniel didn&#8217;t appreciate having his voice broadcast to the world (or his $1.2 million bitcoin heist disrupted) because according to Junseth someone <a href="https://x.com/verysmallclaims/status/1789831026228830280?s=42&amp;t=XLXvAHsqR5zw7RYKGaM_-g" target="_blank" rel="noopener">submitted a baseless copyright infringement claim</a> about it to Soundcloud, which was hosting the recording.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-69820" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/swann-dickarson.png" alt="" width="592" height="373" /></p>
<p>The complaint alleged the recording included a copyrighted song, but that wasn&#8217;t true: Junseth later posted a raw version of the recording to Telegram, and it clearly had no music in the background. Nevertheless, Soundcloud removed the audio file.</p>
<p>&#8220;All these companies are very afraid of copyright,&#8221; Junseth explained in a May 2024 <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NmsAk3kXdz4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interview with the podcast whatbitcoindid.com</a>, which features some of the highlights from his recorded call with Daniel.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s interesting because copyright infringement really is an act that you&#8217;re claiming against the publisher, but for some reason these companies have taken a very hard line against it, so if you even claim there&#8217;s copyrighted material in it they just take it down and then they leave it to you to prove that you&#8217;re innocent,&#8221; Junseth said. &#8220;In Soundcloud&#8217;s instance, part of declaring your innocence is you have to give them your home address and everything else, and it says right on there, &#8216;this will be provided to the person making the copyright claim.'&#8221;</p>
<h2>AFTERMATH</h2>
<p>When Junseth asked how potential victims could protect themselves, Daniel explained that if the target doesn’t have their Google Authenticator synced to their Google cloud account, the scammers can&#8217;t easily pivot into the victim&#8217;s accounts at cryptocurrency exchanges, as they did with Griffin.</p>
<p>By default, Google Authenticator syncs all one-time codes with a Gmail user&#8217;s account, meaning if someone gains access to your Google account, they can then access all of the one-time codes handed out by your Google Authenticator app.</p>
<p>To change this setting, open Authenticator on your mobile device, select your profile picture, and then choose &#8220;Use without an Account&#8221; from the menu. If you disable this, it&#8217;s a good idea to keep <a href="https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/1187538?hl=en&amp;co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a printed copy of one-time backup codes</a>, and to store those in a secure place.</p>
<p>You may also wish to download Google Authenticator to another mobile device that you control. Otherwise, if you turn off cloud synching and lose that sole mobile device with your Google Authenticator app, it could be difficult or impossible to recover access to your account if you somehow get locked out.</p>
<p>Griffin told KrebsOnSecurity he had no idea it was so easy for thieves to take over his account, and to abuse so many different Google services in the process.</p>
<p>&#8220;I know I definitely made mistakes, but I also know Google could do a lot better job protecting people,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>In response to questions from KrebsOnSecurity, Google said it can confirm that this was a narrow phishing campaign, reaching a &#8220;very small group of people.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re aware of this narrow and targeted attack, and have hardened our defenses to block recovery attempts from this actor,&#8221; the company said in a written statement, which emphasized that the real Google will never call you.</p>
<p>&#8220;While these types of social engineering campaigns are constantly evolving, we are continuously working to harden our systems with new tools and technical innovations, as well as sharing <a href="https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/how-to-spot-scams-and-what-to-do-if-you-encounter-one/#intro" target="_blank" rel="noopener">updated guidance</a> with our users to stay ahead of attackers,&#8221; the statement reads.</p>
<p>Both Griffin and Tony say they continue to receive &#8220;account security&#8221; calls from people pretending to work for Google or one of the cryptocurrency platforms.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s like you get put on some kind of list, and then those lists get recycled over and over,&#8221; Tony said.</p>
<p>Griffin said that for several months after his ordeal, he accepted almost every cryptocurrency scam call that came his way, playing along in the vain hope of somehow tricking the caller into revealing details about who they are in real life. But he stopped after his taunting caused one of the scammers to start threatening him personally.</p>
<p>&#8220;I probably shouldn&#8217;t have, but I recorded two 30-minute conversations with these guys,&#8221; Griffin said, acknowledging that maybe it wasn&#8217;t such a great idea to antagonize cybercriminals who clearly already knew everything about him. &#8220;One guy I talked to about his personal life, and then his friend called me up and said he was going to dox me and do all this other bad stuff. My FBI contact later told me not to talk to these guys anymore.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sound advice. So is hanging up whenever anyone calls you about a security problem with one of your accounts. Even security-conscious people tend to underestimate the complex and shifting threat from phone-based phishing scams, but they do so at their peril.</p>
<p>When in doubt: <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/04/when-in-doubt-hang-up-look-up-call-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hang up, look up, and call back</a>. If your response to these types of calls involves anything other than hanging up, researching the correct phone number, and contacting the entity that claims to be calling, you may be setting yourself up for a costly and humbling learning experience.</p>
<p>Understand that your email credentials <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/06/the-value-of-a-hacked-email-account/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">are more than likely the key to unlocking your entire digital identity</a>. Be sure to use a long, unique passphrase for your email address, and never pick a passphrase that you have ever used anywhere else (not even a variation on an old password).</p>
<p>Finally, it&#8217;s also a good idea to take advantage of the strongest multi-factor authentication methods offered. For Gmail/Google accounts, that includes <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/07/google-security-keys-neutralized-employee-phishing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the use of passkeys or physical security keys</a>, which are heavily phishing resistant. For Google users holding measurable sums of cryptocurrency, the most secure option is Google&#8217;s free <a href="https://landing.google.com/advancedprotection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Advanced Protection</a> program, which includes more extensive account security features but also comes <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/google-advanced-protection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with some serious convenience trade-offs</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-to-lose-a-fortune-with-just-one-bad-click/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>75</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Cryptocurrency Turns to Cash in Russian Banks</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-cryptocurrency-turns-to-cash-in-russian-banks/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-cryptocurrency-turns-to-cash-in-russian-banks/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 21:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia's War on Ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blaven Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chainalysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CloudFlare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptomus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CTV News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FINTRAC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Icon Tech SRO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investigative Journalism Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mezhundarondnaya IBU SRO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter German]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PQ Hosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RCMP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richard Sanders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vira Krychka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WS Management and Advisory Corporation Ltd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xeltox Enterprises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A financial firm registered in Canada has emerged as the payment processor for dozens of Russian cryptocurrency exchanges and websites hawking cybercrime services aimed at Russian-speaking customers, new research finds. Meanwhile, an investigation into the Vancouver street address used by this company shows it is home to dozens of foreign currency dealers, money transfer businesses, and cryptocurrency exchanges -- none of which are physically located there.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A financial firm registered in Canada has emerged as the payment processor for dozens of Russian cryptocurrency exchanges and websites hawking cybercrime services aimed at Russian-speaking customers, new research finds. Meanwhile, an investigation into the Vancouver street address used by this company shows it is home to dozens of foreign currency dealers, money transfer businesses, and cryptocurrency exchanges &#8212; none of which are physically located there.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-69766" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/happycanada.png" alt="" width="650" height="397" /></p>
<p><strong>Richard Sanders</strong> is a blockchain analyst and investigator who advises the law enforcement and intelligence community. Sanders spent most of 2023 in Ukraine, traveling with Ukrainian soldiers while mapping the shifting landscape of Russian crypto exchanges that are laundering money for narcotics networks operating in the region.</p>
<p>More recently, Sanders has focused on identifying how dozens of popular cybercrime services are getting paid by their customers, and how they are converting cryptocurrency revenues into cash. For the past several months, he&#8217;s been signing up for various cybercrime services, and then tracking where their customer funds go from there.</p>
<p>The 122 services targeted in Sanders&#8217; research include some of the more prominent businesses advertising on the cybercrime forums today, such as:</p>
<p>-abuse-friendly or &#8220;bulletproof&#8221; hosting providers like anonvm[.]wtf, and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/05/stark-industries-solutions-an-iron-hammer-in-the-cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PQHosting</a>;<br />
-sites selling aged email, financial, or social media accounts, such as verif[.]work and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/06/service-rents-email-addresses-for-account-signups/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kopeechka[.]store</a>;<br />
-anonymity or &#8220;proxy&#8221; providers like crazyrdp[.]com and rdp[.]monster;<br />
-anonymous SMS services, including anonsim[.]net and smsboss[.]pro.</p>
<div id="attachment_69768" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69768" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69768" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/verif-work.png" alt="" width="748" height="462" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/verif-work.png 1253w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/verif-work-768x474.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/verif-work-782x483.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69768" class="wp-caption-text">The site Verif dot work, which processes payments through Cryptomus, sells financial accounts, including debit and credit cards.</p></div>
<p>Sanders said he first encountered some of these services while investigating Kremlin-funded disinformation efforts in Ukraine, as they are all useful in assembling large-scale, anonymous social media campaigns.</p>
<p>According to Sanders, all 122 of the services he tested are processing transactions through a company called <strong>Cryptomus</strong>, which says it is a cryptocurrency payments platform based in Vancouver, British Columbia. Cryptomus&#8217; website says its parent firm &#8212; <strong>Xeltox Enterprises Ltd. </strong>(formerly certa-pay[.]com) &#8212; is registered as a money service business (MSB) with the <strong>Financial Transactions and Reports Analysis Centre of Canada</strong> (FINTRAC).</p>
<p>Sanders said the payment data he gathered also shows that at least 56 cryptocurrency exchanges are currently using Cryptomus to process transactions, including financial entities with names like <strong>casher[.]su</strong>, <strong>grumbot[.]com</strong>, <strong>flymoney[.]biz, obama[.]ru</strong> and <strong>swop[.]is</strong>.</p>
<p>These platforms are built for Russian speakers, and they each advertise the ability to anonymously swap one form of cryptocurrency for another. They also allow the exchange of cryptocurrency for cash in accounts at some of Russia&#8217;s largest banks &#8212; <em>nearly all of which are currently sanctioned by the United States and other western nations</em>.</p>
<div id="attachment_69745" style="width: 761px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/flymoney.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69745" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-69745" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/flymoney.png" alt="" width="751" height="430" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/flymoney.png 1399w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/flymoney-768x440.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/flymoney-782x448.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 751px) 100vw, 751px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-69745" class="wp-caption-text">A machine-translated version of Flymoney, one of dozens of cryptocurrency exchanges apparently nested at Cryptomus.</p></div>
<p>An analysis of their technology infrastructure shows that all of these exchanges use Russian email providers, and most are directly hosted in Russia or by Russia-backed ISPs with infrastructure in Europe (e.g. Selectel, Netwarm UK, Beget, Timeweb and DDoS-Guard). The analysis also showed nearly all 56 exchanges used services from <strong>Cloudflare</strong>, a global content delivery network based in San Francisco.</p>
<p>&#8220;Purportedly, the purpose of these platforms is for companies to accept cryptocurrency payments in exchange for goods or services,&#8221; Sanders told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;Unfortunately, it is next to impossible to find any goods for sale with websites using Cryptomus, and the services appear to fall into one or two different categories: Facilitating transactions with sanctioned Russian banks, and platforms providing the infrastructure and means for cyber attacks.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cryptomus did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p>
<h2>PHANTOM ADDRESSES?</h2>
<p>The Cryptomus website and its FINTRAC listing say the company&#8217;s registered address is <strong>Suite 170, 422 Richards St. in Vancouver, BC.</strong> This address was the subject of <a href="https://theijf.org/msb-cluster-investigation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an investigation published in July</a> by <strong>CTV National News </strong>and the <strong>Investigative Journalism Foundation (IJF)</strong>, which documented dozens of cases across Canada where multiple MSBs are incorporated at the same address, often without the knowledge or consent of the location&#8217;s actual occupant.</p>
<div id="attachment_69744" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69744" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69744" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ijf-ctv.png" alt="" width="749" height="496" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ijf-ctv.png 1020w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ijf-ctv-768x509.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ijf-ctv-782x518.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69744" class="wp-caption-text">This building at 422 Richards St. in downtown Vancouver is the registered address for 90 money services businesses, including 10 that have had their registrations revoked. Image: theijf.org/msb-cluster-investigation.</p></div>
<p>Their inquiry found 422 Richards St. was listed as the registered address for at least 76 foreign currency dealers, eight MSBs, and six cryptocurrency exchanges. At that address is a three-story building that used to be a bank and now houses a massage therapy clinic and a co-working space. But they found none of the MSBs or currency dealers were paying for services at that co-working space.</p>
<p>The reporters found another collection of 97 MSBs clustered at an address for a commercial office suite in Ontario, even though there was no evidence these companies had ever arranged for any business services at that address.</p>
<p><strong>Peter German</strong>, a former deputy commissioner for the <strong>Royal Canadian Mounted Police</strong> who authored two reports on money laundering in British Columbia, told the publications it goes against the spirit of Canada’s registration requirements for such businesses, which are considered high-risk for money laundering and terrorist financing.</p>
<p>“If you’re able to have 70 in one building, that’s just an abuse of the whole system,” German said.</p>
<p>Ten MSBs registered to 422 Richard St. had their registrations revoked. One company at 422 Richards St. whose registration was revoked this year had a director with a listed address in Russia, the publications reported. &#8220;Others appear to be directed by people who are also directors of companies in Cyprus and other high-risk jurisdictions for money laundering,&#8221; they wrote.</p>
<p>A review of <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fintrac-msbs.csv" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FINTRAC&#8217;s registry</a> (.CSV) shows many of the MSBs at 422 Richards St. are international money transfer or remittance services to countries like Malaysia, India and Nigeria. Some act as currency exchanges, while others appear to sell merchant accounts and online payment services. Still, KrebsOnSecurity could find no obvious connections between the 56 Russian cryptocurrency exchanges identified by Sanders and the dozens of payment companies that FINTRAC says share an address with the Cryptomus parent firm Xeltox Enterprises.<span id="more-69725"></span></p>
<h2>SANCTIONS EVASION</h2>
<p>In August 2023, <strong>Binance</strong> and some of the largest cryptocurrency exchanges responded to sanctions against Russia by <a href="https://www.wsj.com/finance/binance-cryptocurrency-russia-sanctions-ddb948c3?mod=e2tw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cutting off many Russian banks</a> and restricting Russian customers to transactions in Rubles only. Sanders said prior to that change, most of the exchanges currently served by Cryptomus were handling customer funds with their own self-custodial cryptocurrency wallets.</p>
<p>By September 2023, Sanders said he found the exchanges he was tracking had all nested themselves like Matryoshka dolls at Cryptomus, which adds a layer of obfuscation to all transactions by generating a new cryptocurrency wallet for each order.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-69800" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/matrydolls.png" alt="" width="638" height="306" /></p>
<p>&#8220;They all simply moved to Cryptomus,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Cryptomus generates new wallets for each order, rendering ongoing attribution to require transactions with high fees each time.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Exchanges like Binance and OKX removing Sberbank and other sanctioned banks and offboarding Russian users did not remove the ability of Russians to transact in and out of cryptocurrency easily,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;In fact, it’s become easier, because the instant-swap exchanges do not even have Know Your Customer rules. The U.S. sanctions resulted in the majority of Russian instant exchanges switching from their self-custodial wallets to platforms, especially Cryptomus.&#8221;</p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin in August signed a new law legalizing cryptocurrency mining and allowing the use of cryptocurrency for international payments. The Russian government&#8217;s embrace of cryptocurrency was a remarkable pivot: Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-26/russia-close-to-starting-trials-of-crypto-payments-exchanges" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notes</a> that as recently as January 2022, just weeks before Russia&#8217;s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, the central bank proposed a blanket ban on the use and creation of cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>In a report on Russia&#8217;s cryptocurrency ambitions published in September, blockchain analysis firm <strong>Chainalysis</strong> said Russia’s move to integrate crypto into its financial system may improve its ability to bypass the U.S.-led financial system and to engage in non-dollar denominated trade.</p>
<p>&#8220;Although it can be hard to quantify the true impact of certain sanctions actions, the fact that Russian officials have singled out the effect of sanctions on Moscow’s ability to process cross-border trade suggests that the impact felt is great enough to incite urgency to legitimize and invest in alternative payment channels it once decried,&#8221; Chainalysis <a href="https://www.chainalysis.com/blog/russias-cryptocurrency-legislated-sanctions-evasion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">assessed</a>.</p>
<p>Asked about its view of activity on Cryptomus, Chainanlysis said Cryptomus has been used by criminals of all stripes for laundering money and/or the purchase of goods and services.</p>
<p>&#8220;We see threat actors engaged in ransomware, narcotics, darknet markets, fraud, cybercrime, sanctioned entities and jurisdictions, and hacktivism making deposits to Cryptomus for purchases but also laundering the services using Cryptomos payment API,&#8221; the company said in a statement.</p>
<h2>SHELL GAMES</h2>
<p>It is unclear if Cryptomus and/or Xeltox Enterprises have any presence in Canada at all. A search in the United Kingdom&#8217;s Companies House registry for Xeltox&#8217;s former name &#8212; Certa Payments Ltd. &#8212; shows <a href="https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/officers/i3FM6G1i2Mptkatjb4YtUXkWL4Y/appointments" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an entity by that name</a> incorporated at a mail drop in London in December 2023.</p>
<p>The sole shareholder and director of that company is listed as a 25-year-old Ukrainian woman in the Czech Republic named <strong>Vira Krychka</strong>. Ms. Krychka was recently appointed the director of <a href="https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/search/officers?q=vera%20krychka" target="_blank" rel="noopener">several other new U.K. firms</a>, including an entity created in February 2024 called <a href="https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/company/15493736/persons-with-significant-control" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Globopay UAB Ltd</a>, and another called <strong>WS Management and Advisory Corporation Ltd. </strong>Ms. Krychka did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p><a href="https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/officers/E_cO2EzffYsXeXBK5-WF6P5_cLY/appointments" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WS Management and Advisory Corporation</a> bills itself as the regulatory body that exclusively oversees licenses of cryptocurrencies in the jurisdiction of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_Sahara" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Western Sahara</a>, a disputed territory in northwest Africa. Its website says the company assists applicants with bank setup and formation, online gaming licenses, and the creation and licensing of foreign exchange brokers. One of Certa Payments&#8217; former websites &#8212; certa[.]website &#8212; also shared a server with 12 other domains, including rasd-state[.]ws, a website for the Central Reserve Authority of the Western Sahara.</p>
<div id="attachment_69802" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69802" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69802" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/crasadr-com.png" alt="" width="748" height="423" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/crasadr-com.png 1490w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/crasadr-com-768x435.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/crasadr-com-782x442.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69802" class="wp-caption-text">The website crasadr dot com, the official website of the Central Reserve Authority of Western Sahara.</p></div>
<p><a href="https://rejstrik-firem.kurzy.cz/osoba/3569774/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This business registry</a> from the Czech Republic indicates Ms. Krychka works as a director at an advertising and marketing firm called <strong>Icon Tech SRO</strong>, which was previously named <strong>Blaven Technologies</strong> (Blaven&#8217;s website says it is an online payment service provider).</p>
<p>In August 2024, Icon Tech changed its name again to <strong>Mezhundarondnaya IBU SRO</strong>, which describes itself as an &#8220;experienced company in IT consulting&#8221; that is based in Armenia. The same registry says Ms. Krychka is somehow also a director at a Turkish investment venture. So much business acumen at such a young age!</p>
<p>For now, Canada remains an attractive location for cryptocurrency businesses to set up shop, at least on paper. The IJF and CTV News found that as of February 2024, there were just over 3,000 actively registered MSBs in Canada, 1,247 of which were located at the same building as at least one other MSB.</p>
<p>&#8220;That analysis does not include the roughly 2,700 MSBs whose registrations have lapsed, been revoked or otherwise stopped,&#8221; they observed. &#8220;If they are included, then a staggering 2,061 out of 5,705 total MSBs share a building with at least one other MSB.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/how-cryptocurrency-turns-to-cash-in-russian-banks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patch Tuesday, December 2024 Edition</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/patch-tuesday-december-2024-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/patch-tuesday-december-2024-edition/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 01:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-49112]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-49138]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fortra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Immersive Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LDAP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lightweight Directory Access Protocol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Patch Tuesday December 2024]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rob Reeves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tenable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyler Reguly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows Common Log File System (CLFS) driver]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today released updates to plug at least 70 security holes in Windows and Windows software, including one vulnerability that is already being exploited in active attacks. The zero-day seeing exploitation involves CVE-2024-49138, a security weakness in the Windows Common… <span class="read-more"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/patch-tuesday-december-2024-edition/">Read More &#187;</a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today released updates to plug at least 70 security holes in <strong>Windows</strong> and Windows software, including one vulnerability that is already being exploited in active attacks.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter  wp-image-56287" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png" alt="" width="749" height="527" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png 841w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-768x541.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-782x550.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>The zero-day seeing exploitation involves <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-49138" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-49138</a>, a security weakness in the <strong>Windows Common Log File System</strong> (CLFS) driver &#8212; used by applications to write transaction logs &#8212; that could let an authenticated attacker gain &#8220;system&#8221; level privileges on a vulnerable Windows device.</p>
<p>The security firm <strong>Rapid7</strong> notes there have been a series of zero-day elevation of privilege flaws in CLFS over the past few years.</p>
<p>&#8220;Ransomware authors who have abused previous CLFS vulnerabilities will be only too pleased to get their hands on a fresh one,&#8221; wrote <strong>Adam Barnett</strong>, lead software engineer at Rapid7. &#8220;Expect more CLFS zero-day vulnerabilities to emerge in the future, at least until Microsoft performs a full replacement of the aging CLFS codebase instead of offering spot fixes for specific flaws.&#8221;</p>
<p>Elevation of privilege vulnerabilities accounted for 29% of the 1,009 security bugs Microsoft has patched so far in 2024, according to a year-end tally by <strong>Tenable</strong>; nearly 40 percent of those bugs were weaknesses that could let attackers run malicious code on the vulnerable device.<span id="more-69721"></span></p>
<p><strong>Rob Reeves</strong>, principal security engineer at <strong>Immersive Labs</strong>, called special attention to <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-49112" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-49112</a>, a remote code execution flaw in the <strong>Lightweight Directory Access Protocol</strong> (LDAP) service <em>on every version of Windows since Windows 7. </em>CVE-2024-49112 has been assigned a CVSS (badness) score of 9.8 out of 10.</p>
<p>&#8220;LDAP is most commonly seen on servers that are Domain Controllers inside a Windows network and LDAP must be exposed to other servers and clients within an enterprise environment for the domain to function,&#8221; Reeves said. &#8220;Microsoft hasn’t released specific information about the vulnerability at present, but has indicated that the attack complexity is low and authentication is not required.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Tyler Reguly</strong> at the security firm <strong>Fortra</strong> had a slightly different 2024 patch tally for Microsoft, at 1,088 vulnerabilities, which he said was surprisingly similar to the 1,063 vulnerabilities resolved in 2023 and the 1,119 vulnerabilities resolved in 2022.</p>
<p>&#8220;If nothing else, we can say that Microsoft is consistent,&#8221; Reguly said. &#8220;While it would be nice to see the number of vulnerabilities each year decreasing, at least consistency lets us know what to expect.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a Windows end user and your system is not set up to automatically install updates, please take a minute this week to run Windows Update, preferably after backing up your system and/or important data.</p>
<p>System admins should keep an eye on <a href="https://www.askwoody.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AskWoody.com</a>, which usually has the details if any of the Patch Tuesday fixes are causing problems. In the meantime, if you run into any problems applying this month&#8217;s fixes, please drop a note about in the comments below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/patch-tuesday-december-2024-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 264/264 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2025-01-25 14:22:51 by W3 Total Cache
-->