<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/?ref=blog.netmanageit.com" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. Offered $10M for Hacker Just Arrested by Russia</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-offered-10m-for-hacker-just-arrested-by-russia/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-offered-10m-for-hacker-just-arrested-by-russia/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aleksandr Ermakov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boriselcin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daryna Antoniuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel 471]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mikhail Lenin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mikhail Matveev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mikhail Shefel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rescator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shtazi-IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sugarlocker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wazawaka]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In January 2022, KrebsOnSecurity identified a Russian man named Mikhail Matveev as "Wazawaka," a cybercriminal who was deeply involved in the formation and operation of multiple ransomware groups. The U.S. government indicted Matveev as a top ransomware purveyor a year later, offering $10 million for information leading to his arrest. Last week, the Russian government reportedly arrested Matveev and charged him with creating malware used to extort companies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In January 2022, KrebsOnSecurity identified a Russian man named <strong>Mikhail Matveev</strong> as &#8220;<strong>Wazawaka</strong>,&#8221; a cybercriminal who was deeply involved in the formation and operation of multiple ransomware groups. The U.S. government indicted Matveev as a top ransomware purveyor a year later, offering $10 million for information leading to his arrest. Last week, the Russian government reportedly arrested Matveev and charged him with creating malware used to extort companies.</p>
<div id="attachment_63686" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-63686" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-63686" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/fbiwanted-matveev.png" alt="" width="748" height="734" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/fbiwanted-matveev.png 804w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/fbiwanted-matveev-768x754.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/fbiwanted-matveev-782x767.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-63686" class="wp-caption-text">An FBI wanted poster for Matveev.</p></div>
<p>Matveev, a.k.a. &#8220;Wazawaka&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Boriselcin</strong>&#8221; worked with at least three different ransomware gangs that extorted hundreds of millions of dollars from companies, schools, hospitals and government agencies, U.S. prosecutors allege.</p>
<p>Russia&#8217;s interior ministry last week issued <a href="https://t.me/mvd39/5931" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a statement</a> saying a 32-year-old hacker had been charged with violating domestic laws against the creation and use of malicious software. The announcement didn&#8217;t name the accused, but the Russian state news agency <em>RIA Novosti</em> <a href="https://ria.ru/20241129/sud-1986456557.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cited</a> anonymous sources saying the man detained is Matveev.</p>
<p>Matveev did not respond to requests for comment. <strong>Daryna Antoniuk</strong> at <em>TheRecord</em> <a href="https://therecord.media/wazawaka-mikhail-matveev-reportedly-arrested-russia" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that a security researcher said on Sunday they had contacted Wazawaka, who confirmed being charged and said he&#8217;d paid two fines, had his cryptocurrency confiscated, and is currently out on bail pending trial.</p>
<p>Matveev&#8217;s hacker identities were remarkably open and talkative on numerous cybercrime forums. Shortly after <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/01/who-is-the-network-access-broker-wazawaka/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">being identified as Wazawaka by KrebsOnSecurity in 2022</a>, Matveev <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/02/wazawaka-goes-waka-waka/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published multiple selfie videos on Twitter/X</a> where he acknowledged using the Wazawaka moniker and mentioned several security researchers by name (including this author). More recently, Matveev&#8217;s X profile (@ransomboris) <a href="https://x.com/LucasKatashi/status/1716815224874140121" target="_blank" rel="noopener">posted</a> a picture of a t-shirt that features the U.S. government&#8217;s &#8220;Wanted&#8221; poster for him.</p>
<div id="attachment_69704" style="width: 597px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69704" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-69704" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/matveev-wanted-tshirt.png" alt="" width="587" height="815" /><p id="caption-attachment-69704" class="wp-caption-text">An image tweeted by Matveev showing the Justice Department&#8217;s wanted poster for him on a t-shirt. image: x.com/vxunderground</p></div>
<p>The golden rule of cybercrime in Russia has always been that as long as you never hack, extort or steal from Russian citizens or companies, you have little to fear of arrest. Wazawaka claimed he zealously adhered to this rule as a personal and professional mantra.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don&#8217;t shit where you live, travel local, and don&#8217;t go abroad,&#8221; Wazawaka wrote in January 2021 on the Russian-language cybercrime forum Exploit. &#8220;Mother Russia will help you. Love your country, and you will always get away with everything.&#8221;<span id="more-69698"></span></p>
<p>Still, Wazawaka may not have always stuck to that rule. At several points throughout his career, Wazawaka claimed he made good money stealing accounts from drug dealers on darknet narcotics bazaars.</p>
<p>Cyber intelligence firm <a href="https://www.intel471.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel 471</a> said Matveev&#8217;s arrest raises more questions than answers, and that Russia&#8217;s motivation here likely goes beyond what&#8217;s happening on the surface.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s possible this is a shakedown by Kaliningrad authorities of a local internet thug who has tens of millions of dollars in cryptocurrency,&#8221; Intel 471 wrote in an analysis published Dec. 2. &#8220;The country’s ingrained, institutional corruption dictates that if dues aren’t paid, trouble will come knocking. But it’s usually a problem money can fix.</p>
<p>Intel 471 says while Russia’s court system is opaque, Matveev will likely be open about the proceedings, particularly if he pays a toll and is granted passage to continue his destructive actions.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unfortunately, none of this would mark meaningful progress against ransomware,&#8221; they concluded.</p>
<p>Although Russia traditionally hasn&#8217;t put a lot of effort into going after cybercriminals within its borders, it has brought a series of charges against alleged ransomware actors this year. In January, four men tied to the REvil ransomware group were sentenced to lengthy prison terms. The men were among <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/01/at-request-of-u-s-russia-rounds-up-14-revil-ransomware-affiliates/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">14 suspected REvil members rounded up by Russia</a> in the weeks before Russia invaded Ukraine in 2022.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Russian authorities arrested at least two men for allegedly operating the short-lived <strong>Sugarlocker</strong> ransomware program in 2021. <strong>Aleksandr Ermakov</strong> and <strong>Mikhail Shefel</strong> (now legally <strong>Mikhail Lenin</strong>) <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/01/who-is-alleged-medibank-hacker-aleksandr-ermakov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ran a security consulting business called <strong>Shtazi-IT</strong></a>. Shortly before his arrest, Ermakov became the first ever cybercriminal sanctioned by Australia, which alleged he stole and leaked data on nearly 10 million customers of the Australian health giant Medibank.</p>
<p>In December 2023, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/12/ten-years-later-new-clues-in-the-target-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">identified Lenin as &#8220;<strong>Rescator</strong>,&#8221;</a> the nickname used by the cybercriminal responsible for selling more than 100 million payment cards stolen from customers of Target and Home Depot in 2013 and 2014. Last month, Shefel <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/an-interview-with-the-target-home-depot-hacker/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">admitted in an interview with KrebsOnSecurity</a> that he was Rescator, and claimed his arrest in the Sugarlocker case was payback for reporting the son of his former boss to the police.</p>
<p>Ermakov was sentenced to two years probation. But on the same day my interview with Lenin was published here, a Moscow court declared him insane, and ordered him to undergo compulsory medical treatment, The Record&#8217;s Antoniuk notes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-offered-10m-for-hacker-just-arrested-by-russia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Phishers Love New TLDs Like .shop, .top and .xyz</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/why-phishers-love-new-tlds-like-shop-top-and-xyz/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/why-phishers-love-new-tlds-like-shop-top-and-xyz/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 13:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[@chenlun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[and Mobile Anti-Abuse Working Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anti-Phishing Working Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coalition Against Unsolicited Commercial Email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICANN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interisle Consulting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Levine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new gTLDs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Postal Service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Phishing attacks increased nearly 40 percent in the year ending August 2024, with much of that growth concentrated at a small number of new generic top-level domains (gTLDs) -- such as .shop, .top, .xyz -- that attract scammers with rock-bottom prices and no meaningful registration requirements, new research finds. Meanwhile, the nonprofit entity that oversees the domain name industry is moving forward with plans to introduce a slew of new gTLDs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Phishing attacks increased nearly 40 percent in the year ending August 2024, with much of that growth concentrated at a small number of new generic top-level domains (gTLDs) &#8212; such as <strong>.shop</strong>, <strong>.top</strong>, <strong>.xyz</strong> &#8212; that attract scammers with rock-bottom prices and no meaningful registration requirements, new research finds. Meanwhile, the nonprofit entity that oversees the domain name industry is moving forward with plans to introduce a slew of new gTLDs.</p>
<div id="attachment_68142" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68142" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-68142" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/phishtrap.png" alt="" width="748" height="457" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/phishtrap.png 776w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/phishtrap-768x469.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-68142" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock.</p></div>
<p>A <a href="https://interisle.net/insights/cybercrimesupplychain2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener">study</a> on phishing data released by <strong>Interisle Consulting</strong> finds that new gTLDs introduced in the last few years command just 11 percent of the market for new domains, but accounted for roughly 37 percent of cybercrime domains reported between September 2023 and August 2024.</p>
<p>Interisle was sponsored by several anti-spam organizations, including the <strong>Anti-Phishing Working Group</strong> (APWG), the <strong>Coalition Against Unsolicited Commercial Email</strong> (CAUCE), and the <strong>Messaging, Malware, and Mobile Anti-Abuse Working Group</strong> (M3AAWG).</p>
<p>The study finds that while <strong>.com</strong> and <strong>.net</strong> domains made up approximately half of all domains registered in the past year (more than all of the other TLDs combined) they accounted for just over 40 percent of all cybercrime domains. Interisle says an almost equal share &#8212; 37 percent &#8212; of cybercrime domains were registered through new gTLDs.</p>
<p>Spammers and scammers gravitate toward domains in the new gTLDs because these registrars tend to offer cheap or free registration with little to no account or identity verification requirements. For example, among the gTLDs with the highest cybercrime domain scores in this year&#8217;s study, nine offered registration fees for less than $1, and nearly two dozen offered fees of less than $2.00. By comparison, the cheapest price identified for a .com domain was $5.91.</p>
<p>Currently, there are around 2,500 registrars authorized to sell domains by the <strong>Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers</strong> (ICANN), the California nonprofit that oversees the domain industry.</p>
<div id="attachment_69689" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69689" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69689" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/interisle-top-xyz.png" alt="" width="749" height="503" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/interisle-top-xyz.png 862w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/interisle-top-xyz-768x516.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/interisle-top-xyz-782x525.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69689" class="wp-caption-text">The top 5 new gTLDs, ranked by cybercrime domains reported. Image: Interisle Cybercrime Supply Chain 2014.</p></div>
<p>Incredibly, despite years of these reports showing phishers heavily abusing new gTLDs, ICANN is shuffling forward on a plan to introduce even more of them. ICANN&#8217;s proposed <a href="https://newgtldprogram.icann.org/en/application-rounds/round2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">next round envisions</a> accepting applications for new gTLDs in 2026.</p>
<p><strong>John Levine </strong>is author of the book &#8220;The Internet for Dummies&#8221; and president of CAUCE. Levine said adding more TLDs without a much stricter registration policy will likely further expand an already plentiful greenfield for cybercriminals.</p>
<p>&#8220;The problem is that ICANN can&#8217;t make up their mind whether they are the neutral nonprofit regulator or just the domain speculator trade association,&#8221; Levine told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;But they act a lot more like the latter.&#8221;<span id="more-69531"></span></p>
<p>Levine said the vast majority of new gTLDs have a few thousand domains &#8212; a far cry from the number of registrations they would need just to cover the up-front costs of operating a new gTLD (~$180,000-$300,000). New gTLD registrars can quickly attract customers by selling domains cheaply to customers who buy domains in bulk, but that tends to be a losing strategy.</p>
<p>&#8220;Selling to criminals and spammers turns out to be lousy business,&#8221; Levine said. &#8220;You can charge whatever you want on the first year, but you have to charge list price on domain renewals. And criminals and spammers never renew. So if it sounds like the economics makes no sense it&#8217;s because the economics makes no sense.&#8221;</p>
<p>In virtually all previous spam reports, Interisle found the top brands referenced in phishing attacks were the largest technology companies, including Apple, Facebook, Google and PayPal. But this past year, Interisle found the <strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong> was by far the most-phished entity, with more than four times the number of phishing domains as the second most-frequent target (Apple).</p>
<p>At least some of that increase is likely from a prolific cybercriminal using the nickname <strong>Chenlun</strong>, who has been <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/10/phishers-spoof-usps-12-other-natl-postal-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">selling phishing kits targeting domestic postal services</a> in the United States and at least a dozen other countries.</p>
<p>Interisle says an increasing number of phishers are eschewing domain registrations altogether, and instead taking advantage of subdomain providers like <strong>blogspot.com</strong>, <strong>pages.dev</strong>, and <strong>weebly.com</strong>. The report notes that cyberattacks hosted at subdomain provider services can be tough to mitigate, because only the subdomain provider can disable malicious accounts or take down malicious web pages.</p>
<p>&#8220;Any action upstream, such as blocking the second-level domain, would have an impact across the provider&#8217;s whole customer base,&#8221; the report observes.</p>
<p>Interisle tracked more than 1.18 million instances of subdomains used for phishing in the past year (a 114 percent increase), and found more than half of those were subdomains at blogspot.com and other services operated by Google.</p>
<p>&#8220;Many of these services allow the creation of large numbers of accounts at one time, which is highly exploited by criminals,&#8221; the report concludes. &#8220;Subdomain providers should limit the number of subdomains (user accounts) a customer can create at one time and suspend automated, high-volume automated account sign-ups – especially using free services.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dec. 4, 10:21 a.m. ET: Corrected link to report.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/why-phishers-love-new-tlds-like-shop-top-and-xyz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hacker in Snowflake Extortions May Be a U.S. Soldier</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DDoS-for-Hire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boxfan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buttholio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Connor Riley Moucka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyb3rph4nt0m]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Erin Binns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judische]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiberphant0m]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Naver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Proman557]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reverseshell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shi-Bot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snowflake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telekomterrorist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vars_Secc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waifu]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two men have been arrested for allegedly stealing data from and extorting dozens of companies that used the cloud data storage company Snowflake, but a third suspect -- a prolific hacker known as Kiberphant0m -- remains at large and continues to publicly extort victims. However, this person's identity may not remain a secret for long: A careful review of Kiberphant0m's daily chats across multiple cybercrime personas suggests they are a U.S. Army soldier who is or was recently stationed in South Korea.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two men have been arrested for allegedly stealing data from and extorting dozens of companies that used the cloud data storage company <strong>Snowflake</strong>, but a third suspect &#8212; a prolific hacker known as <strong>Kiberphant0m </strong>&#8212; remains at large and continues to publicly extort victims. However, this person&#8217;s identity may not remain a secret for long: A careful review of Kiberphant0m&#8217;s daily chats across multiple cybercrime personas suggests they are a U.S. Army soldier who is or was recently stationed in South Korea.</p>
<p>Kiberphant0m&#8217;s identities on cybercrime forums and on Telegram and Discord chat channels have been selling data stolen from customers of the cloud data storage company Snowflake. At the end of 2023, malicious hackers discovered that many companies had uploaded huge volumes of sensitive customer data to Snowflake accounts that were protected with nothing more than a username and password (no multi-factor authentication required).</p>
<p>After scouring darknet markets for stolen Snowflake account credentials, the hackers began raiding the data storage repositories for some of the world’s largest corporations. Among those was <strong>AT&amp;T</strong>, which <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/07/hackers-steal-phone-sms-records-for-nearly-all-att-customers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disclosed in July</a> that cybercriminals had stolen personal information, phone and text message records for roughly 110 million people.  <strong>Wired.com</strong> <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/atandt-paid-hacker-300000-to-delete-stolen-call-records/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported in July</a> that AT&amp;T paid a hacker $370,000 to delete stolen phone records.</p>
<p>On October 30, Canadian authorities <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested</a> <strong>Alexander Moucka, </strong>a.k.a.<strong> Connor Riley Moucka </strong>of Kitchener, Ontario, on a provisional arrest warrant from the United States, which has since indicted him on 20 criminal counts connected to the Snowflake breaches. Another suspect in the Snowflake hacks, <strong>John Erin Binns</strong>, is an American who is currently incarcerated in Turkey.</p>
<div id="attachment_69625" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69625" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69625" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance.png" alt="" width="749" height="575" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance.png 1137w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance-768x590.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/moucka-surveillance-782x600.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69625" class="wp-caption-text">A surveillance photo of Connor Riley Moucka, a.k.a. &#8220;Judische&#8221; and &#8220;Waifu,&#8221; dated Oct 21, 2024, 9 days before Moucka&#8217;s arrest. This image was included in an affidavit filed by an investigator with the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP).</p></div>
<p>Investigators say Moucka, who went by the handles <strong>Judische</strong> and <strong>Waifu</strong>, had tasked Kiberphant0m with selling data stolen from Snowflake customers who refused to pay a ransom to have their information deleted. Immediately after news broke of Moucka&#8217;s arrest, Kiberphant0m was clearly furious, and posted on the hacker community <strong>BreachForums</strong> what they claimed were the AT&amp;T call logs for <strong>President-elect</strong> <strong>Donald J. Trump</strong> and for <strong>Vice President Kamala Harris</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;In the event you do not reach out to us @ATNT all presidential government call logs will be leaked,&#8221; Kiberphant0m threatened, signing their post with multiple &#8220;#FREEWAIFU&#8221; tags. &#8220;You don&#8217;t think we don&#8217;t have plans in the event of an arrest? Think again.&#8221;</p>
<p>On the same day, Kiberphant0m posted what they claimed was the &#8220;data schema&#8221; from the <strong>U.S. National Security Agency</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;This was obtained from the ATNT Snowflake hack which is why ATNT paid an extortion,&#8221; Kiberphant0m wrote in a thread on BreachForums. &#8220;Why would ATNT pay Waifu for the data when they wouldn&#8217;t even pay an extortion for over 20M+ SSNs?&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_69624" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69624" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-69624" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema.png" alt="" width="750" height="239" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema.png 1417w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema-768x245.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphant0m-nsa-schema-782x249.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-69624" class="wp-caption-text">Kiberphant0m posting what he claimed was a &#8220;data schema&#8221; stolen from the NSA via AT&amp;T.</p></div>
<p>Also on Nov. 5, Kiberphant0m offered call logs stolen from Verizon&#8217;s push-to-talk (PTT) customers &#8212; mainly U.S. government agencies and emergency first responders. On Nov. 9, Kiberphant0m posted a sales thread on BreachForums offering a &#8220;SIM-swapping&#8221; service targeting Verizon PTT customers. In a SIM-swap, fraudsters use credentials that are phished or stolen from mobile phone company employees to divert a target&#8217;s phone calls and text messages to a device they control.</p>
<h2>MEET &#8216;BUTTHOLIO&#8217;</h2>
<p>Kiberphant0m joined BreachForums in January 2024, but their public utterances on Discord and Telegram channels date back to at least early 2022. On their first post to BreachForums, Kiberphant0m said they could be reached at the Telegram handle <strong>@cyb3rph4nt0m</strong>.</p>
<p>A review of @cyb3rph4nt0m shows this user has posted more than 4,200 messages since January 2024. Many of these messages were attempts to recruit people who could be hired to deploy a piece of malware that enslaved host machines in an Internet of Things (IoT) botnet.</p>
<p>On BreachForums, Kiberphant0m has sold the source code to &#8220;<strong>Shi-Bot</strong>,&#8221; a custom Linux DDoS botnet based on <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/tag/mirai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Mirai malware</a>. Kiberphant0m had few sales threads on BreachForums prior to the Snowflake attacks becoming public in May, and many of those involved databases stolen from companies in South Korea.</p>
<p>On June 5, 2024, a Telegram user by the name &#8220;<strong>Buttholio</strong>&#8221; joined the fraud-focused Telegram channel &#8220;<strong>Comgirl</strong>&#8221; and claimed to be Kiberphant0m. Buttholio made the claim after being taunted as a nobody by another denizen of Comgirl, referring to their @cyb3rph4nt0m account on Telegram and the Kiberphant0m user on cybercrime forums.</p>
<p>&#8220;Type &#8216;kiberphant0m&#8217; on google with the quotes,&#8221; Buttholio told another user. &#8220;I&#8217;ll wait. Go ahead. Over 50 articles. 15+ telecoms breached. I got the IMSI number to every single person that&#8217;s ever registered in Verizon, Tmobile, ATNT and Verifone.&#8221;</p>
<p>On Sept. 17, 2023, Buttholio posted in a Discord chat room dedicated to players of the video game <strong>Escape from Tarkov</strong>. &#8220;Come to Korea, servers there is pretty much no extract camper or cheater,&#8221; Buttholio advised.</p>
<p>In another message that same day in the gaming Discord, Buttholio told others they bought the game in the United States, but that they were playing it in Asia.</p>
<p>&#8220;USA is where the game was purchased from, server location is actual in game servers u play on. I am a u.s. soldier so i bought it in the states but got on rotation so i have to use asian servers,&#8221; they shared.<span id="more-69605"></span></p>
<h2>&#8216;REVERSESHELL&#8217;</h2>
<p>The account @Kiberphant0m was assigned the Telegram ID number 6953392511. A review of this ID at the cyber intelligence platform <a href="https://www.flashpoint.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Flashpoint</a> shows that on January 4, 2024 Kibertphant0m posted to the Telegram channel &#8220;Dstat,&#8221; which is populated by cybercriminals involved in launching distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks and selling DDoS-for-hire services [Full disclosure: Flashpoint is currently an advertiser on this website].</p>
<p>Immediately after Kiberphant0m logged on to the Dstat channel, another user wrote &#8220;hi buttholio,&#8221; to which Kiberphant0m replied with an affirmative greeting &#8220;wsg,&#8221; or &#8220;what&#8217;s good.&#8221; On Nov. 1, <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ddos-site-dstatcc-seized-and-two-suspects-arrested-in-germany/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dstat&#8217;s website dstat[.]cc was seized</a> as part of &#8220;Operation PowerOFF,&#8221; an international law enforcement action against DDoS services.</p>
<p>Flashpoint&#8217;s data shows that @kiberphant0m told a fellow member of Dstat on April 10, 2024 that their alternate Telegram username was &#8220;<strong>@reverseshell</strong>,&#8221; and did the same two weeks later in the Telegram chat The Jacuzzi. The Telegram ID for this account is <strong>5408575119</strong>.</p>
<p>Way back on Nov. 15, 2022, @reverseshell told a fellow member of a Telegram channel called Cecilio Chat that they were a soldier in the U.S. Army. This user also shared the following image of someone pictured waist-down in military fatigues, with a camouflaged backpack at their feet:</p>
<div id="attachment_69628" style="width: 665px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69628" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-69628 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/reverseshell-fatigues.png" alt="" width="655" height="663" /><p id="caption-attachment-69628" class="wp-caption-text">Kiberphant0m&#8217;s apparent alias ReverseShell posted this image on a Telegram channel Cecilio Chat, on Nov. 15, 2022. Image: Flashpoint.</p></div>
<p>In September 2022, Reverseshell was embroiled in an argument with another member who had threatened to launch a DDoS attack against Reverseshell&#8217;s Internet address. After the promised attack materialized, Reverseshell responded, &#8220;Yall just hit military base contracted wifi.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a chat from October 2022, Reverseshell was bragging about the speed of the servers they were using, and in reply to another member&#8217;s question said that they were accessing the Internet via South Korea Telecom.</p>
<p>Telegram chat logs archived by Flashpoint show that on Aug. 23, 2022, Reverseshell bragged they&#8217;d been using automated tools to find valid logins for Internet servers that they resold to others.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ve hit US gov servers with default creds,&#8221; Reverseshell wrote, referring to systems with easy-to-guess usernames and/or passwords. &#8220;Telecom control servers, machinery shops, Russian ISP servers, etc. I sold a few big companies for like $2-3k a piece. You can sell the access when you get a big SSH into corporation.&#8221;</p>
<p>On July 29, 2023, Reverseshell posted a screenshot of a login page for a major U.S. defense contractor, claiming they had an aerospace company&#8217;s credentials to sell.</p>
<h2>PROMAN AND VARS_SECC</h2>
<p>Flashpoint finds the Telegram ID 5408575119 has used several aliases since 2022, including Reverseshell and <strong>Proman557</strong>.</p>
<p>A search on the username Proman557 at the cyber intelligence platform <a href="https://www.intel471.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel 471</a> shows that a hacker by the name &#8220;<strong>Proman554</strong>&#8221; registered on Hackforums in September 2022, and in messages to other users Proman554 said they can be reached at the Telegram account Buttholio.</p>
<p>Intel 471 also finds the Proman557 moniker is one of many used by a person on the Russian-language hacking forum <strong>Exploit</strong> in 2022 who sold a variety of Linux-based botnet malware.</p>
<p>Proman557 was eventually banned &#8212; allegedly for scamming a fellow member out of $350 &#8212; and the Exploit moderator warned forum users that Proman557 had previously registered under several other nicknames, including an account called &#8220;<strong>Vars_Secc</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Vars_Secc&#8217;s thousands of comments on Telegram over two years show this user divided their time between online gaming, maintaining a DDoS botnet, and promoting the sale or renting of their botnets to other users.</p>
<p>&#8220;I use ddos for many things not just to be a skid,&#8221; Vars_Secc pronounced. &#8220;Why do you think I haven’t sold my net?&#8221; They then proceeded to list the most useful qualities of their botnet:</p>
<blockquote><p>-I use it to hit off servers that ban me or piss me off<br />
-I used to ddos certain games to get my items back since the data reverts to when u joined<br />
-I use it for server side desync RCE vulnerabilities<br />
-I use it to sometimes ransom<br />
-I use it when bored as a source of entertainment</p></blockquote>
<p>Flashpoint shows that in June 2023, Vars_Secc responded to taunting from a fellow member in the Telegram channel SecHub who had threatened to reveal their personal details to the federal government for a reward.</p>
<p>&#8220;Man I’ve been doing this shit for 4 years,&#8221; Vars_Secc replied nonchalantly. &#8220;I highly doubt the government is going to pay millions of dollars for data on some random dude operating a pointless ddos botnet and finding a few vulnerabilities here and there.&#8221;</p>
<p>For several months in 2023, Vars_Secc also was an active member of the Russian-language crime forum <strong>XSS</strong>, where they sold access to a U.S. government server for $2,000. However, Vars_Secc would be banned from XSS after attempting to sell access to the Russian telecommunications giant <strong>Rostelecom</strong>. [In this, Vars_Secc violated the Number One Rule for operating on a Russia-based crime forum: Never offer to hack or sell data stolen from Russian entities or citizens].</p>
<p>On June 20, 2023, Vars_Secc posted a sales thread on the cybercrime forum <strong>Ramp 2.0</strong> titled, &#8220;Selling US Gov Financial Access.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Server within the network, possible to pivot,&#8221; Vars_Secc&#8217;s sparse sales post read. &#8220;Has 3-5 subroutes connected to it. Price $1,250. Telegram: Vars_Secc.&#8221;</p>
<p>Vars_Secc also used Ramp in June 2023 to sell access to a &#8220;Vietnam government Internet Network Information Center.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Selling access server allocated within the network,&#8221; Vars_Secc wrote. &#8220;Has some data on it. $500.&#8221;</p>
<h2>BUG BOUNTIES</h2>
<p>The Vars_Secc identity claimed on Telegram in May 2023 that they made money by submitting reports about software flaws to <strong>HackerOne</strong>, a company that helps technology firms field reports about security vulnerabilities in their products and services. Specifically, Vars_Secc said they had earned financial rewards or &#8220;bug bounties&#8221; from <strong>reddit.com</strong>, the <strong>U.S.</strong> <strong>Department of Defense</strong>, and <strong>Coinbase</strong>, among 30 others.</p>
<p>&#8220;I make money off bug bounties, it&#8217;s quite simple,&#8221; Vars_Secc said when asked what they do for a living. &#8220;That&#8217;s why I have over 30 bug bounty reports on HackerOne.&#8221;</p>
<p>A month before that, Vars_Secc said they&#8217;d found a vulnerability in reddit.com.</p>
<p>&#8220;I poisoned Reddit&#8217;s cache,&#8221; they explained. &#8220;I&#8217;m going to exploit it further, then report it to reddit.&#8221;</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity sought comment from HackerOne, which said it would investigate the claims. This story will be updated if they respond.</p>
<p>The Vars_Secc telegram handle also has claimed ownership of the BreachForums member &#8220;<strong>Boxfan</strong>,&#8221; and Intel 471 shows Boxfan&#8217;s early posts on the forum had the Vars_Secc Telegram account in their signature. In their most recent post to BreachForums in January 2024, Boxfan disclosed a security vulnerability they found in <strong>Naver</strong>, the most popular search engine in South Korea (according to statista.com). Boxfan&#8217;s comments suggest they have strong negative feelings about South Korean culture.</p>
<p>&#8220;Have fun exploiting this vulnerability,&#8221; Boxfan wrote on BreachForums, after pasting a long string of computer code intended to demonstrate the flaw. &#8220;Fuck you South Korea and your discriminatory views. Nobody likes ur shit kpop you evil fucks. Whoever can dump this DB [database] congrats. I don&#8217;t feel like doing it so I&#8217;ll post it to the forum.&#8221;</p>
<p>The many identities tied to Kiberphant0m strongly suggest they are or until recently were a U.S. Army soldier stationed in South Korea. Kiberphant0m&#8217;s alter egos never mentioned their military rank, regiment, or specialization.</p>
<p>However, it is likely that Kiberphant0m&#8217;s facility with computers and networking was noticed by the Army. According to the U.S. Army&#8217;s website, the bulk of its forces in South Korea reside within the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eighth_Army_(United_States)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eighth Army</a>, which has a dedicated cyber operations unit focused on defending against cyber threats.</p>
<p>On April 1, 2023, Vars_Secc posted to a public Telegram chat channel a screenshot of the National Security Agency&#8217;s website. The image indicated the visitor had just applied for some type of job at the NSA.</p>
<div id="attachment_69656" style="width: 720px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69656" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-69656" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiber-nsa-app.png" alt="" width="710" height="511" /><p id="caption-attachment-69656" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot posted by Vars_Secc on Telegram on April 1, 2023, suggesting they just applied for a job at the National Security Agency.</p></div>
<p>The NSA has not yet responded to requests for comment.</p>
<p>Reached via Telegram, Kiberphant0m acknowledged that KrebsOnSecurity managed to unearth their old handles.</p>
<p>&#8220;I see you found the IP behind it no way,&#8221; Kiberphant0m <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiber-tg-replies.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">replied</a>. &#8220;I see you managed to find my old aliases LOL.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kiberphant0m denied being in the U.S. Army or ever being in South Korea, and said all of that was a lengthy ruse designed to create a fictitious persona. &#8220;Epic opsec troll,&#8221; they claimed.</p>
<p>Asked if they were at all concerned about getting busted, Kiberphant0m called that an impossibility.</p>
<p>&#8220;I literally can&#8217;t get caught,&#8221; Kiberphant0m said, declining an invitation to explain why. &#8220;I don&#8217;t even live in the USA Mr. Krebs.&#8221;</p>
<p>Below is a mind map that hopefully helps illustrate some of the connections between and among Kiberphant0m&#8217;s apparent alter egos.</p>
<div id="attachment_69662" style="width: 1592px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphantom-mm.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69662" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-69662 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphantom-mm.png" alt="" width="1582" height="841" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphantom-mm.png 1582w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphantom-mm-768x408.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphantom-mm-1536x817.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/kiberphantom-mm-782x416.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 1582px) 100vw, 1582px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-69662" class="wp-caption-text">A mind map of the connections between and among the identities apparently used by Kiberphant0m. Click to enlarge.</p></div>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity would like to extend a special note of thanks to the New York City based security intelligence firm <a href="https://www.unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a> for their assistance in helping to piece together key elements of Kiberphant0m&#8217;s different identities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feds Charge Five Men in &#8216;Scattered Spider&#8217; Roundup</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/feds-charge-five-men-in-scattered-spider-roundup/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/feds-charge-five-men-in-scattered-spider-roundup/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 20:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SIM Swapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ahmed Hossam Eldin Elbadawy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evans Onyeaka Osiebo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joel Martin Evans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joeleoli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kingbob]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lastpass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Namecheap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah Michael Urban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ogusers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oktapus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scattered Spider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sosa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tylerb]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Federal prosecutors in Los Angeles this week unsealed criminal charges against five men alleged to be members of a hacking group responsible for dozens of cyber intrusions at major U.S. technology companies between 2021 and 2023, including LastPass, MailChimp, Okta, T-Mobile and Twilio.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Federal prosecutors in Los Angeles this week unsealed criminal charges against five men alleged to be members of a hacking group responsible for dozens of cyber intrusions at major U.S. technology companies between 2021 and 2023, including <strong>LastPass</strong>, <strong>MailChimp</strong>, <strong>Okta</strong>, <strong>T-Mobile</strong> and <strong>Twilio</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_61104" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-61104" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-61104" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amitaico.png" alt="" width="749" height="441" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amitaico.png 1427w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amitaico-768x452.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/amitaico-782x460.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-61104" class="wp-caption-text">A visual depiction of the attacks by the SMS phishing group known as Scattered Spider, and Oktapus. Image: Amitai Cohen twitter.com/amitaico.</p></div>
<p>The five men, aged 20 to 25, are allegedly members of a hacking conspiracy dubbed &#8220;<strong>Scattered Spider</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Oktapus</strong>,&#8221; which specialized in SMS-based phishing attacks that tricked employees at tech firms into entering their credentials and one-time passcodes at phishing websites.</p>
<p>The targeted SMS scams asked employees to click a link and log in at a website that mimicked their employer’s Okta authentication page. Some SMS phishing messages told employees their VPN credentials were expiring and needed to be changed; other phishing messages advised employees about changes to their upcoming work schedule.</p>
<p>These attacks leveraged newly-registered domains that often included the name of the targeted company, such as <a href="https://urlscan.io/result/ca9d3120-7c5f-4502-8faf-09a94274ba71/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twilio-help[.]com</a> and <a href="https://urlscan.io/result/d17edad8-ef65-4d25-a0eb-39b7cc4ab593/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ouryahoo-okta[.]com</a>. The phishing websites were normally kept online for just one or two hours at a time, meaning they were often yanked offline before they could be flagged by anti-phishing and security services.</p>
<p>The phishing kits used for these campaigns featured a hidden Telegram instant message bot that forwarded any submitted credentials in real-time. The bot allowed the attackers to use the phished username, password and one-time code to log in as that employee at the real employer website.</p>
<p>In August 2022, multiple security firms gained access to the server that was receiving data from that Telegram bot, which on several occasions leaked the Telegram ID and handle of its developer, who used the nickname &#8220;<strong>Joeleoli</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_69574" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/joeleoli-tg.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69574" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-69574" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/joeleoli-tg.png" alt="" width="748" height="173" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/joeleoli-tg.png 1287w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/joeleoli-tg-768x177.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/joeleoli-tg-782x180.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-69574" class="wp-caption-text">The Telegram username &#8220;Joeleoli&#8221; can be seen sandwiched between data submitted by people who knew it was a phish, and data phished from actual victims. Click to enlarge.</p></div>
<p>That Joeleoli moniker registered on the cybercrime forum <strong>OGusers</strong> in 2018 with the email address <strong>joelebruh@gmail.com</strong>, which also was used to register accounts at several websites for a Joel Evans from North Carolina. Indeed, prosecutors say Joeleoli&#8217;s real name is <strong>Joel Martin Evans</strong>, and he is a 25-year-old from Jacksonville, North Carolina.<span id="more-69568"></span></p>
<p>One of Scattered Spider’s first big victims in its 2022 SMS phishing spree was <strong>Twilio</strong>, a company that provides services for making and receiving text messages and phone calls. The group then used their access to Twilio to attack at least 163 of its customers. According to prosecutors, the group mainly sought to steal cryptocurrency from victim companies and their employees.</p>
<p>&#8220;The defendants allegedly preyed on unsuspecting victims in this phishing scheme and used their personal information as a gateway to steal millions in their cryptocurrency accounts,” <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/pr/5-defendants-charged-federally-running-scheme-targeted-victim-companies-phishing-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> <strong>Akil Davis</strong>, the assistant director in charge of the FBI’s Los Angeles field office.</p>
<p>Many of the hacking group&#8217;s phishing domains were registered through the registrar <strong>NameCheap</strong>, and FBI investigators said records obtained from NameCheap showed the person who managed those phishing websites did so from an Internet address in Scotland. The feds then obtained records from Virgin Media, which showed the address was leased for several months to <strong>Tyler Buchanan</strong>, a 22-year-old from Dundee, Scotland.</p>
<div id="attachment_61078" style="width: 654px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-61078" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-61078 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/twiliophish.png" alt="" width="644" height="471" /><p id="caption-attachment-61078" class="wp-caption-text">A Scattered Spider phishing lure sent to Twilio employees.</p></div>
<p>As <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/06/alleged-boss-of-scattered-spider-hacking-group-arrested/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first reported here in June</a>, Buchanan was arrested in Spain as he tried to board a flight bound for Italy. The Spanish police told local media that Buchanan, who allegedly went by the alias &#8220;<strong>Tylerb</strong>,&#8221; at one time possessed Bitcoins worth $27 million.</p>
<p>The government says much of Tylerb&#8217;s cryptocurrency wealth was the result of successful <strong>SIM-swapping</strong> attacks, wherein crooks transfer the target’s phone number to a device they control and intercept any text messages or phone calls sent to the victim — including one-time passcodes for authentication, or password reset links sent via SMS.</p>
<p>According to several SIM-swapping channels on Telegram where Tylerb was known to frequent, rival SIM-swappers hired thugs to invade his home in February 2023. Those accounts state that the intruders assaulted Tylerb’s mother in the home invasion, and that they threatened to burn him with a blowtorch if he didn’t give up the keys to his cryptocurrency wallets. Tylerb was reputed to have fled the United Kingdom after that assault.</p>
<div id="attachment_67783" style="width: 721px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-67783" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-67783" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/tylerb.png" alt="" width="711" height="293" /><p id="caption-attachment-67783" class="wp-caption-text">A still frame from a video released by the Spanish national police, showing Tyler Buchanan being taken into custody at the airport.</p></div>
<p>Prosecutors allege Tylerb worked closely on SIM-swapping attacks with <strong>Noah Michael Urban</strong>, another alleged Scattered Spider member from Palm Coast, Fla. who went by the handles &#8220;<strong>Sosa</strong>,&#8221; &#8220;<strong>Elijah</strong>,&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Kingbob</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sosa was known to be a top member of the broader cybercriminal community online known as “<strong>The Com</strong>,” wherein hackers boast loudly about high-profile exploits and hacks that almost invariably begin with social engineering — tricking people over the phone, email or SMS into giving away credentials that allow remote access to corporate networks.</p>
<p>In January 2024, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/01/fla-man-charged-in-sim-swapping-spree-is-key-suspect-in-hacker-groups-oktapus-scattered-spider/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">broke the news</a> that Urban had been arrested in Florida in connection with multiple SIM-swapping attacks. That story noted that Sosa&#8217;s alter ego Kingbob routinely targeted people in the recording industry to steal and share &#8220;grails,&#8221; a slang term used to describe unreleased music recordings from popular artists.</p>
<p>FBI investigators identified a fourth alleged member of the conspiracy &#8211; <strong>Ahmed Hossam Eldin Elbadawy</strong>, 23, of College Station, Texas &#8212; after he used a portion of cryptocurrency funds stolen from a victim company to pay for an account used to register phishing domains.</p>
<p>The indictment unsealed Wednesday alleges Elbadawy controlled a number of cryptocurrency accounts used to receive stolen funds, along with another Texas man &#8212; <strong>Evans Onyeaka Osiebo</strong>, 20, of Dallas.</p>
<p>Members of Scattered Spider are reputed to have been involved in <a href="https://archive.ph/MuU4s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a September 2023 ransomware attack</a> against the <strong>MGM Resorts</strong> hotel chain that quickly brought multiple MGM casinos to a standstill. In September 2024, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that a 17-year-old from the United Kingdom was arrested last year by U.K. police as part of an FBI investigation into the MGM hack.</p>
<p>Evans, Elbadawy, Osiebo and Urban were all charged with one count of conspiracy to commit wire fraud, one count of conspiracy, and one count of aggravated identity theft. Buchanan, who is named as an indicted co-conspirator, was charged with conspiracy to commit wire fraud, conspiracy, wire fraud, and aggravated identity theft.</p>
<p>A Justice Department <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/pr/5-defendants-charged-federally-running-scheme-targeted-victim-companies-phishing-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">press release</a> states that if convicted, each defendant would face a statutory maximum sentence of 20 years in federal prison for conspiracy to commit wire fraud, up to five years in federal prison for the conspiracy count, and a mandatory two-year consecutive prison sentence for aggravated identity theft. Buchanan would face up to 20 years in prison for the wire fraud count as well.</p>
<p>Further reading:</p>
<p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/USA-v-Buchanan-COMPLAINT-Redacted.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The redacted complaint against Buchanan</a> (PDF)</p>
<p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/USA-v-Elbadawy-et-al-INDICTMENT.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Charges against Urban and the other defendants</a> (PDF).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/feds-charge-five-men-in-scattered-spider-roundup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fintech Giant Finastra Investigating Data Breach</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/fintech-giant-finastra-investigating-data-breach/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/fintech-giant-finastra-investigating-data-breach/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 01:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abyss0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BreachForums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finastra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ke-la.com]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The financial technology firm Finastra is investigating the alleged large-scale theft of information from its internal file transfer platform, KrebsOnSecurity has learned. Finastra, which provides software and services to 45 of the world's top 50 banks, notified customers of a potential breach after a cybercriminal began selling more than 400 gigabytes of data purportedly stolen from the company. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The financial technology firm <strong>Finastra</strong> is investigating the alleged large-scale theft of information from its internal file transfer platform, KrebsOnSecurity has learned. Finastra, which provides software and services to 45 of the world&#8217;s top 50 banks, notified customers of the security incident after a cybercriminal began selling more than 400 gigabytes of data purportedly stolen from the company.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-50961" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/finastra.png" alt="" width="747" height="453" /></p>
<p>London-based Finastra has offices in 42 countries and reported $1.9 billion in revenues last year. The company employs more than 7,000 people and serves approximately 8,100 financial institutions around the world. A major part of Finastra&#8217;s day-to-day business involves processing huge volumes of digital files containing instructions for wire and bank transfers on behalf of its clients.</p>
<p>On November 8, 2024, Finastra notified financial institution customers that on Nov. 7 its security team detected suspicious activity on Finastra&#8217;s internally hosted file transfer platform. Finastra also told customers that someone had begun selling large volumes of files allegedly stolen from its systems.</p>
<p>&#8220;On November 8, a threat actor communicated on the dark web claiming to have data exfiltrated from this platform,&#8221; reads <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-notice.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Finastra&#8217;s disclosure</a>, a copy of which was shared by a source at one of the customer firms.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is no direct impact on customer operations, our customers&#8217; systems, or Finastra&#8217;s ability to serve our customers currently,&#8221; the notice continued. &#8220;We have implemented an alternative secure file sharing platform to ensure continuity, and investigations are ongoing.&#8221;</p>
<p>But its notice to customers does indicate the intruder managed to extract or &#8220;exfiltrate&#8221; an unspecified volume of customer data.</p>
<p>&#8220;The threat actor did not deploy malware or tamper with any customer files within the environment,&#8221; the notice reads. &#8220;Furthermore, no files other than the exfiltrated files were viewed or accessed. We remain focused on determining the scope and nature of the data contained within the exfiltrated files.&#8221;<span id="more-69538"></span></p>
<p>In a written statement in response to questions about the incident, Finastra said it has been &#8220;actively and transparently responding to our customers’ questions and keeping them informed about what we do and do not yet know about the data that was posted.&#8221; The company also shared an updated communication to its clients, which said while it was still investigating the root cause, &#8220;initial evidence points to credentials that were compromised.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Additionally, we have been sharing Indicators of Compromise (IOCs) and our CISO has been speaking directly with our customers’ security teams to provide updates on the investigation and our eDiscovery process,&#8221; the statement continues. Here is the rest of what they shared:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;In terms of eDiscovery, we are analyzing the data to determine what specific customers were affected, while simultaneously assessing and communicating which of our products are not dependent on the specific version of the SFTP platform that was compromised. The impacted SFTP platform is not used by all customers and is not the default platform used by Finastra or its customers to exchange data files associated with a broad suite of our products, so we are working as quickly as possible to rule out affected customers. However, as you can imagine, this is a time-intensive process because we have many large customers that leverage different Finastra products in different parts of their business. We are prioritizing accuracy and transparency in our communications.</p>
<p>Importantly, for any customers who are deemed to be affected, we will be reaching out and working with them directly.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>On Nov. 8, a cybercriminal using the nickname &#8220;<strong>abyss0</strong>&#8221; posted on the English-language cybercrime community <strong>BreachForums</strong> that they&#8217;d stolen files belonging to some of Finastra&#8217;s largest banking clients. The data auction did not specify a starting or &#8220;buy it now&#8221; price, but said interested buyers should reach out to them on Telegram.</p>
<div id="attachment_69542" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-sales-nov8.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69542" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-69542" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-sales-nov8.png" alt="" width="750" height="489" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-sales-nov8.png 1052w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-sales-nov8-768x500.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-sales-nov8-782x509.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-69542" class="wp-caption-text">abyss0&#8217;s Nov. 7 sales thread on BreachForums included many screenshots showing the file directory listings for various Finastra customers. Image: Ke-la.com.</p></div>
<p>According to screenshots collected by the cyber intelligence platform <a href="https://www.ke-la.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ke-la.com</a>, abyss0 first attempted to sell the data allegedly stolen from Finastra on October 31, but that earlier sales thread did not name the victim company. However, it did reference many of the same banks called out as Finastra customers in the Nov. 8 post on BreachForums.</p>
<div id="attachment_69540" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-bf-oct2024.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69540" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-69540" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-bf-oct2024.png" alt="" width="748" height="422" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-bf-oct2024.png 1057w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-bf-oct2024-768x433.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/finastra-bf-oct2024-782x441.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-69540" class="wp-caption-text">The original October 31 post from abyss0, where they advertise the sale of data from several large banks that are customers of a large financial software company. Image: Ke-la.com.</p></div>
<p>The October sales thread also included a starting price: $20,000. By Nov. 3, that price had been reduced to $10,000. A review of abyss0&#8217;s posts to BreachForums reveals this user has offered to sell databases stolen in several dozen other breaches advertised over the past six months.</p>
<p>The apparent timeline of this breach suggests abyss0 gained access to Finastra&#8217;s file sharing system at least a week before the company says it first detected suspicious activity, and that the Nov. 7 activity cited by Finastra may have been the intruder returning to exfiltrate more data.</p>
<p>Maybe abyss0 found a buyer who paid for their early retirement. We may never know, because this person has effectively vanished. The Telegram account that abyss0 listed in their sales thread appears to have been suspended or deleted. Likewise, abyss0&#8217;s account on BreachForums no longer exists, and all of their sales threads have since disappeared.</p>
<p>It seems improbable that both Telegram and BreachForums would have given this user the boot at the same time. The simplest explanation is that something spooked abyss0 enough for them to abandon a number of pending sales opportunities, in addition to a well-manicured cybercrime persona.</p>
<p>In March 2020, Finastra <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/03/security-breach-disrupts-fintech-firm-finastra/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">suffered a ransomware attack</a> that sidelined a number of the company&#8217;s core businesses for days. According to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-04-08/how-finastra-survived-a-ransomware-attack-without-paying-ransom" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reporting from Bloomberg</a>, Finastra was able to recover from that incident without paying a ransom.</p>
<p><em>This is a developing story. Updates will be noted with timestamps. If you have any additional information about this incident, please reach out to krebsonsecurity @ gmail.com or at protonmail.com.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/fintech-giant-finastra-investigating-data-breach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Interview With the Target &#038; Home Depot Hacker</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/an-interview-with-the-target-home-depot-hacker/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/an-interview-with-the-target-home-depot-hacker/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 04:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pharma Wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aleksandr Ermakov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chronopay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dmitri Golubov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Helkern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Depot breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hydra Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MikeMike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mikhail Lenin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mikhail Shefel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pavel vrublevsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter Vrublevsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sprut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sugar ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[target breach]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In December 2023, KrebsOnSecurity revealed the real-life identity of Rescator, the nickname used by a Russian cybercriminal who sold more than 100 million payment cards stolen from Target and Home Depot between 2013 and 2014. Moscow resident Mikhail Shefel, who confirmed using the Rescator identity in a recent interview, also admitted reaching out because he is broke and seeking publicity for several new money making schemes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In December 2023, KrebsOnSecurity revealed the real-life identity of <strong>Rescator</strong>, the nickname used by a Russian cybercriminal who sold more than 100 million payment cards stolen from <strong>Target</strong> and <strong>Home Depot</strong> between 2013 and 2014. Moscow resident <strong>Mikhail Shefel</strong>, who confirmed using the Rescator identity in a recent interview, also admitted reaching out because he is broke and seeking publicity for several new money making schemes.</p>
<div id="attachment_67207" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-67207" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-67207" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/shefel-fb1.png" alt="" width="750" height="572" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/shefel-fb1.png 942w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/shefel-fb1-768x585.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/shefel-fb1-782x596.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-67207" class="wp-caption-text">Mikhail &#8220;Mike&#8221; Shefel&#8217;s former Facebook profile. Shefel has since legally changed his last name to Lenin.</p></div>
<p>Mr. Shefel, who recently changed his legal surname to <strong>Lenin</strong>, was the star of last year&#8217;s story, <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/12/ten-years-later-new-clues-in-the-target-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ten Years Later, New Clues in the Target Breach</a>. That investigation detailed how the 38-year-old Shefel adopted the nickname Rescator while working as vice president of payments at <strong>ChronoPay</strong>, a Russian financial company that paid spammers to advertise fake antivirus scams, male enhancement drugs and knockoff pharmaceuticals.</p>
<p>Mr. Shefel did not respond to requests for comment in advance of that December 2023 profile. Nor did he respond to reporting here in January 2024 that he ran an IT company with a 34-year-old Russian man named <strong>Aleksandr Ermakov</strong>, who was sanctioned by authorities in Australia, the U.K. and U.S. for <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/01/who-is-alleged-medibank-hacker-aleksandr-ermakov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stealing data on nearly 10 million customers of the Australian health insurance giant Medibank</a>.</p>
<p>But not long after KrebsOnSecurity reported in April that Shefel/Rescator also was behind <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/04/who-stole-3-6m-tax-records-from-south-carolina/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the theft of Social Security and tax information</a> from a majority of South Carolina residents in 2012, Mr. Shefel began contacting this author with the pretense of setting the record straight on his alleged criminal hacking activities.</p>
<p>In a series of live video chats and text messages, Mr. Shefel confirmed he indeed went by the Rescator identity for several years, and that he did operate a slew of websites between 2013 and 2015 that sold payment card data stolen from Target, Home Depot and a number of other nationwide retail chains.</p>
<p>Shefel claims the true mastermind behind the Target and other retail breaches was <a href="https://www.wired.com/2007/01/tracking-the-russian-scammers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Dmitri Golubov</strong></a>, an infamous Ukrainian hacker known as the co-founder of Carderplanet, among the earliest Russian-language cybercrime forums focused on payment card fraud. Mr. Golubov could not be reached for comment, and Shefel says he no longer has the laptop containing evidence to support that claim.</p>
<p>Shefel asserts he and his team were responsible for developing the card-stealing malware that Golubov&#8217;s hackers installed on Target and Home Depot payment terminals, and that at the time he was technical director of a long-running Russian cybercrime community called <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/12/cards-stolen-in-target-breach-flood-underground-markets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lampeduza</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;My nickname was MikeMike, and I worked with Dmitri Golubov and made technologies for him,&#8221; Shefel said. &#8220;I&#8217;m also godfather of his second son.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_69494" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69494" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69494" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/script-cp.png" alt="" width="750" height="733" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/script-cp.png 780w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/script-cp-768x750.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69494" class="wp-caption-text">Dmitri Golubov, circa 2005. Image: U.S. Postal Investigative Service.</p></div>
<p>A week after breaking the story about the 2013 data breach at Target, KrebsOnSecurity published <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/12/whos-selling-credit-cards-from-target/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Who&#8217;s Selling Cards from Target?</a>, which identified a Ukrainian man who went by the nickname <strong>Helkern</strong> as Rescator&#8217;s original identity. But Shefel claims Helkern was subordinate to Golubov, and that he was responsible for introducing the two men more than a decade ago.</p>
<p>&#8220;Helkern was my friend, I [set up a] meeting with Golubov and him in 2013,&#8221; Shefel said. &#8220;That was in Odessa, Ukraine. I was often in that city, and [it&#8217;s where] I met my second wife.&#8221;</p>
<p>Shefel claims he made several hundred thousand dollars selling cards stolen by Golubov&#8217;s Ukraine-based hacking crew, but that not long after Russia annexed Crimea in 2014 Golubov cut him out of the business and replaced Shefel&#8217;s malware coding team with programmers in Ukraine.<span id="more-69482"></span></p>
<p>Golubov was arrested in Ukraine in 2005 as part of a joint investigation with multiple U.S. federal law enforcement agencies, but his political connections in the country ensured his case went nowhere. Golubov later earned immunity from prosecution by becoming an elected politician and <a href="https://www.spiegel.de/netzwelt/web/dimitri-iwanowitsch-golubow-gesuchter-hacker-als-darth-vader-a-903751.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">founding the Internet Party of Ukraine</a>, which called for free internet for all, the creation of country-wide &#8220;hacker schools&#8221; and the &#8220;computerization of the entire economy.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mr. Shefel says he stopped selling stolen payment cards after being pushed out of the business, and invested his earnings in a now-defunct Russian search engine called <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20170630180838/http://tf.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">tf[.]org</a>. He also apparently ran <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9sr3VIXwKMI" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a business called click2dad[.]net</a> that paid people to click on ads for Russian government employment opportunities.</p>
<p>When those enterprises fizzled out, Shefel reverted to selling malware coding services for hire under the nickname &#8220;<strong>Getsend</strong>&#8220;; this claim checks out, as Getsend for many years advertised the same Telegram handle that Shefel used in our recent chats and video calls.</p>
<p>Shefel acknowledged that his outreach was motivated by a desire to publicize several new business ventures. None of those will be mentioned here because Shefel is already using my December 2023 profile of him to advertise what appears to be a pyramid scheme, and to remind others within the Russian hacker community of his skills and accomplishments.</p>
<p>Shefel says he is now flat broke, and that he currently has little to show for a storied hacking career. The Moscow native said he recently heard from his ex-wife, who had read last year&#8217;s story about him and was suddenly wondering where he&#8217;d hidden all of his earnings.</p>
<p>More urgently, Shefel needs money to stay out of prison. In February, he and Ermakov were arrested on charges of operating a short-lived ransomware affiliate program in 2021 called <strong>Sugar</strong> (a.k.a. Sugar Locker), which targeted single computers and end-users instead of corporations. Shefel is due to face those charges in a Moscow court on Friday, Nov. 15, 2024. Ermakov was recently found guilty and given two years probation.</p>
<p>Shefel claims his Sugar ransomware affiliate program was a bust, and never generated any profits. Russia is known for not prosecuting criminal hackers within its borders who scrupulously avoid attacking Russian businesses and consumers. When asked why he now faces prosecution over Sugar, Shefel said he&#8217;s certain the investigation was instigated by  <strong>Pyotr &#8220;Peter&#8221; Vrublevsky</strong> &#8212; the son of his former boss at ChronoPay.</p>
<p>ChronoPay founder and CEO <strong>Pavel Vrublevsky</strong> was the key subject of my 2014 book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Spam-Nation-Organized-Cybercrime-Epidemic-ebook/dp/B00L5QGBL0" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Spam Nation</em></a>, which described his role as head of one of Russia&#8217;s most notorious criminal spam operations.</p>
<p>Vrublevsky Sr. recently declared bankruptcy, and is currently in prison on fraud charges. Russian authorities allege Vrublevsky operated several fraudulent SMS-based payment schemes. They also accused Vrublevsky of facilitating money laundering for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydra_Market" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hydra</a>, the largest Russian darknet market at the time. Hydra trafficked in illegal drugs and financial services, including cryptocurrency tumbling for money laundering, exchange services between cryptocurrency and Russian rubles, and the sale of falsified documents and hacking services.</p>
<p>However, in 2022 KrebsOnSecurity reported on <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/03/spam-nation-villain-vrublevsky-charged-with-fraud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a more likely reason for Vrublevsky&#8217;s latest criminal charges</a>: He&#8217;d been extensively documenting the nicknames, real names and criminal exploits of Russian hackers who worked with the protection of corrupt officials in the Russian Federal Security Service (FSB), and operating a Telegram channel that threatened to expose alleged nefarious dealings by Russian financial executives.</p>
<p>Shefel believes Vrublevsky&#8217;s son Peter paid corrupt cops to levy criminal charges against him after reporting the youth to Moscow police, allegedly for walking around in public with a loaded firearm. Shefel says the Russian authorities told the younger Vrublevsky that he had lodged the firearms complaint.</p>
<p>In July 2024, the Russian news outlet <em>Izvestia</em> published <a href="https://iz.ru/1731854/antonina-matveeva-maksim-solopov-stanislav-kuchushev/reklamnaia-doza-kto-stoit-za-pr-aktciiami-lidera-narkotorgovli-v-rossii" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a lengthy investigation into Peter Vrublevsky</a>, alleging that the younger son took up his father&#8217;s mantle and was responsible for advertising <strong>Sprut</strong>, a Russian-language narcotics bazaar that sprang to life after the Hydra darknet market was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/actions-target-russian-govt-botnet-hydra-dark-market/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shut down by international law enforcement agencies in 2022</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_69493" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69493" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69493" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/sprut-moscow.png" alt="" width="750" height="431" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/sprut-moscow.png 1035w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/sprut-moscow-768x442.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/sprut-moscow-782x450.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69493" class="wp-caption-text">Izvestia reports that Peter Vrublevsky was the advertising mastermind behind this 3D ad campaign and others promoting the Russian online narcotics bazaar Sprut.</p></div>
<p>Izvestia reports that Peter Vrublevsky is currently living in Switzerland, where he reportedly fled in 2022 after being &#8220;arrested in absentia&#8221; in Russia on charges of running a violent group that could be hired via Telegram to conduct a range of physical attacks in real life, including firebombings and muggings.</p>
<p>Shefel claims his former partner Golubov was involved in the development and dissemination of early ransomware strains, including <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/11/cryptolocker-crew-ratchets-up-the-ransom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cryptolocker</a>, and that Golubov remains active in the cybercrime community.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Mr. Shefel portrays himself as someone who is barely scraping by with the few odd coding jobs that come his way each month. Incredibly, the day after our initial interview via Telegram, Shefel proposed going into business together.</p>
<p>By way of example, he suggested maybe a company centered around recovering lost passwords for cryptocurrency accounts, or perhaps a series of online retail stores that sold cheap Chinese goods at a steep markup in the United States.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hi, how are you?&#8221; he inquired. &#8220;Maybe we can open business?&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/an-interview-with-the-target-home-depot-hacker/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Patch Tuesday, November 2024 Edition</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/microsoft-patch-tuesday-november-2024-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/microsoft-patch-tuesday-november-2024-edition/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 21:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security Tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-43451]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-43602]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-49019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-49039]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-49040]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google TAG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Patch Tuesday November 2024]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satnam Narang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tenable]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today released updates to plug at least 89 security holes in its Windows operating systems and other software. November's patch batch includes fixes for two zero-day vulnerabilities that are already being exploited by attackers, as well as two other flaws that were publicly disclosed prior to today.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today released updates to plug at least 89 security holes in its <strong>Windows</strong> operating systems and other software. November&#8217;s patch batch includes fixes for two zero-day vulnerabilities that are already being exploited by attackers, as well as two other flaws that were publicly disclosed prior to today.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-56287" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png" alt="" width="749" height="527" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png 841w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-768x541.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-782x550.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>The zero-day flaw tracked as <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-49039" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-49039</a> is a bug in the <strong>Windows Task Scheduler</strong> that allows an attacker to increase their privileges on a Windows machine. Microsoft credits Google&#8217;s <strong>Threat Analysis Group</strong> with reporting the flaw.</p>
<p>The second bug fixed this month that is already seeing in-the-wild exploitation is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-43451" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-43451</a>, a spoofing flaw that could reveal <a href="https://www.ired.team/offensive-security/initial-access/netntlmv2-hash-stealing-using-outlook" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Net-NTLMv2 hashes</a>, which are used for authentication in Windows environments.</p>
<p><strong>Satnam Narang</strong>, senior staff research engineer at <strong>Tenable</strong>, says the danger with stolen NTLM hashes is that they enable so-called &#8220;pass-the-hash&#8221; attacks, which let an attacker masquerade as a legitimate user without ever having to log in or know the user&#8217;s password. Narang notes that CVE-2024-43451 is the third NTLM zero-day so far this year.</p>
<p>&#8220;Attackers continue to be adamant about discovering and exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities that can disclose NTLMv2 hashes, as they can be used to authenticate to systems and potentially move laterally within a network to access other systems,&#8221; Narang said.<span id="more-69463"></span></p>
<p>The two other publicly disclosed weaknesses Microsoft patched this month are <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-49019" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-49019</a>, an elevation of privilege flaw in <strong>Active Directory Certificate Services</strong> (AD CS); and <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-49040" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-49040</a>, a spoofing vulnerability in <strong>Microsoft Exchange Server</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Ben McCarthy</strong>, lead cybersecurity engineer at <strong>Immersive Labs</strong>, called special attention to <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-43639" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-43639</a>, a remote code execution vulnerability in <strong>Windows Kerberos</strong>, the authentication protocol that is heavily used in Windows domain networks.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is one of the most threatening CVEs from this patch release,&#8221; McCarthy said. &#8220;Windows domains are used in the majority of enterprise networks, and by taking advantage of a cryptographic protocol vulnerability, an attacker can perform privileged acts on a remote machine within the network, potentially giving them eventual access to the domain controller, which is the goal for many attackers when attacking a domain.&#8221;</p>
<p>McCarthy also pointed to <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/en-US/advisory/CVE-2024-43498" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2024-43498</a>, a remote code execution flaw in <strong>.NET</strong> and <strong>Visual Studio</strong> that could be used to install malware. This bug has earned a CVSS severity rating of 9.8 (10 is the worst).</p>
<p>Finally, at least 29 of the updates released today tackle memory-related security issues involving <strong>SQL server</strong>, each of which earned a threat score of 8.8. Any one of these bugs could be used to install malware if an authenticated user connects to a malicious or hacked SQL database server.</p>
<p>For a more detailed breakdown of today&#8217;s patches from Microsoft, check out the <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/diary/Microsoft%20November%202024%20Patch%20Tuesday/31438" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SANS Internet Storm Center’s list</a>. For administrators in charge of managing larger Windows environments, it pays to keep an eye on <a href="https://www.askwoody.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Askwoody.com</a>, which frequently points out when specific Microsoft updates are creating problems for a number of users.</p>
<p>As always, if you experience any problems applying any of these updates, consider dropping a note about it in the comments; chances are excellent that someone else reading here has experienced the same issue, and maybe even has found a solution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/microsoft-patch-tuesday-november-2024-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FBI: Spike in Hacked Police Emails, Fake Subpoenas</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/fbi-spike-in-hacked-police-emails-fake-subpoenas/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/fbi-spike-in-hacked-police-emails-fake-subpoenas/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 19:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emergency data request]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fake EDR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kodex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Donahue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pwnstar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) is urging police departments and governments worldwide to beef up security around their email systems, citing a recent increase in cybercriminal services that use hacked police email accounts to send unauthorized subpoenas and customer data requests to U.S.-based technology companies.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>Federal Bureau of Investigation</strong> (FBI) is urging police departments and governments worldwide to beef up security around their email systems, citing a recent increase in cybercriminal services that use hacked police email accounts to send unauthorized subpoenas and customer data requests to U.S.-based technology companies.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter  wp-image-59128" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/legalrequest.png" alt="" width="750" height="623" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/legalrequest.png 864w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/legalrequest-768x638.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/legalrequest-782x650.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/CSA/2024/241104.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an alert</a> (PDF) published this week, the FBI said it has seen an uptick in postings on criminal forums regarding the process of emergency data requests (EDRs) and the sale of email credentials stolen from police departments and government agencies.</p>
<p>&#8220;Cybercriminals are likely gaining access to compromised US and foreign government email addresses and using them to conduct fraudulent emergency data requests to US based companies, exposing the personal information of customers to further use for criminal purposes,&#8221; the FBI warned.</p>
<p>In the United States, when federal, state or local law enforcement agencies wish to obtain information about an account at a technology provider &#8212; such as the account&#8217;s email address, or what Internet addresses a specific cell phone account has used in the past &#8212; they must submit an official court-ordered warrant or subpoena.</p>
<p>Virtually all major technology companies serving large numbers of users online have departments that routinely review and process such requests, which are typically granted (eventually, and at least in part) as long as the proper documents are provided and the request appears to come from an email address connected to an actual police department domain name.</p>
<p>In some cases, a cybercriminal will offer to forge a court-approved subpoena and send that through a hacked police or government email account. But increasingly, thieves are relying on fake EDRs, which allow investigators to attest that people will be bodily harmed or killed unless a request for account data is granted expeditiously.</p>
<p>The trouble is, these EDRs largely bypass any official review and do not require the requester to supply any court-approved documents. Also, it is difficult for a company that receives one of these EDRs to immediately determine whether it is legitimate.</p>
<p>In this scenario, the receiving company finds itself caught between two unsavory outcomes: Failing to immediately comply with an EDR — and potentially having someone’s blood on their hands — or possibly leaking a customer record to the wrong person.</p>
<p>Perhaps unsurprisingly, compliance with such requests tends to be extremely high. For example, in its most recent <a href="https://www.verizon.com/about/sites/default/files/US-Transparency-Report-2H-2023.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">transparency report</a> (PDF) <strong>Verizon</strong> said it received more than 127,000 law enforcement demands for customer data in the second half of 2023 &#8212; including more than 36,000 EDRs &#8212; and that the company provided records in response to approximately 90 percent of requests.</p>
<p>One English-speaking cybercriminal who goes by the nicknames &#8220;<strong>Pwnstar</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>Pwnipotent</strong>&#8221; has been selling fake EDR services on both Russian-language and English cybercrime forums. Their prices range from $1,000 to $3,000 per successful request, and they claim to control &#8220;gov emails from over 25 countries,&#8221; including Argentina, Bangladesh, Brazil, Bolivia, Dominican Republic, Hungary, India, Kenya, Jordan, Lebanon, Laos, Malaysia, Mexico, Morocco, Nigeria, Oman, Pakistan, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, Philippines, Tunisia, Turkey, United Arab Emirates (UAE), and Vietnam.</p>
<p>&#8220;I cannot 100% guarantee every order will go through,&#8221; Pwnstar explained. &#8220;This is social engineering at the highest level and there will be failed attempts at times. Don&#8217;t be discouraged. You can use escrow and I give full refund back if EDR doesn&#8217;t go through and you don&#8217;t receive your information.&#8221;<span id="more-69445"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_69453" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69453" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69453" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/pwnstar.png" alt="" width="750" height="644" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/pwnstar.png 1001w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/pwnstar-768x660.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/pwnstar-782x672.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69453" class="wp-caption-text">An ad from Pwnstar for fake EDR services.</p></div>
<p>A review of EDR vendors across many cybercrime forums shows that some fake EDR vendors sell the ability to send phony police requests to specific social media platforms, including forged court-approved documents. Others simply sell access to hacked government or police email accounts, and leave it up to the buyer to forge any needed documents.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you get account, it&#8217;s yours, your account, your liability,&#8221; reads an ad in October on <strong>BreachForums</strong>. &#8220;Unlimited Emergency Data Requests. Once Paid, the Logins are completely Yours. Reset as you please. You would need to Forge Documents to Successfully Emergency Data Request.&#8221;</p>
<p>Still other fake EDR service vendors claim to sell hacked or fraudulently created accounts on <strong>Kodex</strong>, a startup that aims to help tech companies do a better job screening out phony law enforcement data requests. Kodex is <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/04/fighting-fake-edrs-with-credit-ratings-for-police/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">trying to tackle the problem of fake EDRs</a> by working directly with the data providers to pool information about police or government officials submitting these requests, with an eye toward making it easier for everyone to spot an unauthorized EDR.</p>
<p>If police or government officials wish to request records regarding Coinbase customers, for example, they must first register an account on Kodexglobal.com. Kodex&#8217;s systems then assign that requestor a score or credit rating, wherein officials who have a long history of sending valid legal requests will have a higher rating than someone sending an EDR for the first time.</p>
<p>It is not uncommon to see fake EDR vendors claim the ability to send data requests through Kodex, with some even sharing redacted screenshots of police accounts at Kodex.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Donahue</strong> is the former FBI agent who founded Kodex in 2021. Donahue said just because someone can use a legitimate police department or government email to create a Kodex account doesn&#8217;t mean that user will be able to send anything. Donahue said even if one customer gets a fake request, Kodex is able to prevent the same thing from happening to another.</p>
<p>Kodex told KrebsOnSecurity that over the past 12 months it has processed a total of 1,597 EDRs, and that 485 of those requests (~30 percent) failed a second-level verification. Kodex reports it has suspended nearly 4,000 law enforcement users in the past year, including:</p>
<p>-1,521 from the Asia-Pacific region;<br />
-1,290 requests from Europe, the Middle East and Asia;<br />
-460 from police departments and agencies in the United States;<br />
-385 from entities in Latin America, and;<br />
-285 from Brazil.</p>
<p>Donahue said 60 technology companies are now routing all law enforcement data requests through Kodex, including an increasing number of financial institutions and cryptocurrency platforms. He said one concern shared by recent prospective customers is that crooks are seeking to use phony law enforcement requests to freeze and in some cases seize funds in specific accounts.</p>
<p>&#8220;What&#8217;s being conflated [with EDRs] is anything that doesn&#8217;t involve a formal judge&#8217;s signature or legal process,&#8221; Donahue said. &#8220;That can include control over data, like an account freeze or preservation request.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a hypothetical example, a scammer uses a hacked government email account to request that a service provider place a hold on a specific bank or crypto account that is allegedly subject to a garnishment order, or party to crime that is globally sanctioned, such as terrorist financing or child exploitation.</p>
<p>A few days or weeks later, the same impersonator returns with a request to seize funds in the account, or to divert the funds to a custodial wallet supposedly controlled by government investigators.</p>
<p>&#8220;In terms of overall social engineering attacks, the more you have a relationship with someone the more they&#8217;re going to trust you,&#8221; Donahue said. &#8220;If you send them a freeze order, that&#8217;s a way to establish trust, because [the first time] they&#8217;re not asking for information. They&#8217;re just saying, &#8216;Hey can you do me a favor?&#8217; And that makes the [recipient] feel valued.&#8221;</p>
<p>Echoing the FBI&#8217;s warning, Donahue said far too many police departments in the United States and other countries have poor account security hygiene, and often do not enforce basic account security precautions &#8212; such as requiring phishing-resistant multifactor authentication.</p>
<p>How are cybercriminals typically gaining access to police and government email accounts? Donahue said it&#8217;s still mostly email-based phishing, and credentials that are stolen by opportunistic malware infections and sold on the dark web. But as bad as things are internationally, he said, many law enforcement entities in the United States still have much room for improvement in account security.</p>
<p>&#8220;Unfortunately, a lot of this is phishing or malware campaigns,&#8221; Donahue said. &#8220;A lot of global police agencies don&#8217;t have stringent cybersecurity hygiene, but even U.S. dot-gov emails get hacked. Over the last nine months, I&#8217;ve reached out to CISA (the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency) over a dozen times about .gov email addresses that were compromised and that CISA was unaware of.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/fbi-spike-in-hacked-police-emails-fake-subpoenas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canadian Man Arrested in Snowflake Data Extortions</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 17:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SIM Swapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advance Auto Parts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexander Antonin Moucka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atomwaffen Division]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Austin Larsen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bharat Sanchar Nigam Ltd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Connor Riley Moucka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IntelSecrets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IRDev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Erin Binns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judische]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiberphant0m]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leak Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending Tree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mandiant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RapeLash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satori]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snowflake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ticketmaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UNC5537]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Verizon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waifu]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=67735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A 26-year-old man in Ontario, Canada has been arrested for allegedly stealing data from and extorting more than 160 companies that used the cloud data service Snowflake.

On October 30, Canadian authorities arrested Alexander Moucka, a.k.a. Connor Riley Moucka of Kitchener, Ontario, on a provisional arrest warrant from the United States. Bloomberg first reported Moucka's alleged ties to the Snowflake hacks on Monday.

At the end of 2023, malicious hackers learned that many large companies had uploaded huge volumes of sensitive customer data to Snowflake accounts that were protected with little more than a username and password (no multi-factor authentication required). After scouring darknet markets for stolen Snowflake account credentials, the hackers began raiding the data storage repositories used by some of the world’s largest corporations.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 25-year-old man in Ontario, Canada has been arrested for allegedly stealing data from and extorting more than 160 companies that used the cloud data service <strong>Snowflake</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_69434" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69434" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-69434" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/snowflaking.png" alt="" width="748" height="432" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/snowflaking.png 983w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/snowflaking-768x443.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/snowflaking-782x451.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69434" class="wp-caption-text">Image: https://www.pomerium.com/blog/the-real-lessons-from-the-snowflake-breach</p></div>
<p>On October 30, Canadian authorities arrested <strong>Alexander Moucka, </strong>a.k.a.<strong> Connor Riley Moucka </strong>of Kitchener, Ontario, on a provisional arrest warrant from the United States. Bloomberg first <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-05/hacker-said-to-be-behind-breach-of-snowflake-customers-arrested?embedded-checkout=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> Moucka&#8217;s alleged ties to the Snowflake hacks on Monday.</p>
<p>At the end of 2023, malicious hackers learned that many large companies had uploaded huge volumes of sensitive customer data to Snowflake accounts that were protected with little more than a username and password (no multi-factor authentication required). After scouring darknet markets for stolen Snowflake account credentials, the hackers began raiding the data storage repositories used by some of the world’s largest corporations.</p>
<p>Among those was <strong>AT&amp;T</strong>, which <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/07/hackers-steal-phone-sms-records-for-nearly-all-att-customers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">disclosed in July</a> that cybercriminals had stolen personal information and phone and text message records for roughly 110 million people — nearly all of its customers. <strong>Wired.com</strong> <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/atandt-paid-hacker-300000-to-delete-stolen-call-records/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported in July</a> that AT&amp;T paid a hacker $370,000 to delete stolen phone records.</p>
<p>A report on the extortion attacks from the incident response firm <strong>Mandiant</strong> notes that Snowflake victim companies were privately approached by the hackers, who demanded a ransom in exchange for a promise not to sell or leak the stolen data. All told, more than 160 Snowflake customers were relieved of data, including <strong>TicketMaster</strong>, <strong>Lending Tree</strong>, <strong>Advance Auto Parts</strong> and <strong>Neiman Marcus</strong>.</p>
<p>Moucka is alleged to have used the hacker handles <strong>Judische</strong> and <strong>Waifu</strong>, among many others. These monikers correspond to a prolific cybercriminal whose exploits were the subject of <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a recent story published here</a> about the overlap between Western, English-speaking cybercriminals and extremist groups that harass and extort minors into harming themselves or others.</p>
<p>On May 2, 2024, Judische claimed on the fraud-focused Telegram channel <strong>Star Chat</strong> that they had hacked <strong>Santander Bank</strong>, one of the first known Snowflake victims. Judische would repeat that claim in Star Chat on May 13 — the day before Santander publicly disclosed a data breach — and would periodically blurt out the names of other Snowflake victims before their data even went up for sale on the cybercrime forums.</p>
<p>404 Media <a href="https://www.404media.co/alleged-snowflake-hacker-appears-in-court-says-prison-in-lockdown/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that at a court hearing in Ontario this morning, Moucka called in from a prison phone and said he was seeking legal aid to hire an attorney.</p>
<h2>TELECOM DOMINOES</h2>
<p>Mandiant has attributed the Snowflake compromises to a group it calls “<strong>UNC5537</strong>,” with members based in North America and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/08/t-mobile-investigating-claims-of-massive-data-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Turkey</a>. Sources close to the investigation tell KrebsOnSecurity the UNC5537 member in Turkey is <strong>John Erin Binns</strong>, an elusive American man indicted by the <strong>U.S. Department of Justice</strong> (DOJ) for <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/08/t-mobile-investigating-claims-of-massive-data-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2021 breach at T-Mobile</a> that exposed the personal information of at least 76.6 million customers.</p>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: The Justice Department has <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unsealed an indictment</a> (PDF) against Moucka and Binns, charging them with one count of conspiracy; 10 counts of wire fraud; four counts of computer fraud and abuse; two counts of extortion in relation to computer fraud; and two counts aggravated identity theft.</p>
<p>In a statement on Moucka&#8217;s arrest, Mandiant said UNC5537 aka Alexander ‘Connor’ Moucka has proven to be one of the most consequential threat actors of 2024.</p>
<p>&#8220;In April 2024, UNC5537 launched a campaign, systematically compromising misconfigured SaaS instances across over a hundred organizations,&#8221; wrote <strong>Austin Larsen</strong>, Mandiant&#8217;s senior threat analyst. &#8220;The operation, which left organizations reeling from significant data loss and extortion attempts, highlighted the alarming scale of harm an individual can cause using off-the-shelf tools.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sources involved in the investigation said UNC5537 has focused on hacking into telecommunications companies around the world. Those sources told KrebsOnSecurity that Binns and Judische are suspected of <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/technology/bsnl-suffers-second-data-breach-in-six-months/articleshow/111264707.cms?from=mdr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stealing data from India&#8217;s largest state-run telecommunications firm</a> <strong>Bharat Sanchar Nigam Ltd</strong> (BNSL), and that the duo even bragged about being able to intercept or divert phone calls and text messages for a large portion of the population of India.</p>
<p>Judische appears to have outsourced the sale of databases from victim companies who refuse to pay, delegating some of that work to a cybercriminal who uses the nickname <strong>Kiberphant0m</strong> on multiple forums. In late May 2024, Kiberphant0m began advertising the sale of hundreds of gigabytes of data stolen from BSNL.</p>
<p>&#8220;Information is worth several million dollars but I&#8217;m selling for pretty cheap,&#8221; Kiberphant0m wrote of the BSNL data in a post on the English-language cybercrime community <strong>Breach Forums</strong>. &#8220;Negotiate a deal in Telegram.&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-69334" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/kiberphant0m-bf.png" alt="" width="750" height="310" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/kiberphant0m-bf.png 1115w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/kiberphant0m-bf-768x317.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/kiberphant0m-bf-782x323.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>Also in May 2024, Kiberphant0m took to the Russian-language hacking forum <strong>XSS</strong> to sell more than 250 gigabytes of data stolen from an unnamed mobile telecom provider in Asia, including a database of all active customers and software allowing the sending of text messages to all customers.</p>
<p>On September 3, 2024, Kiberphant0m posted a sales thread on XSS titled &#8220;Selling American Telecom Access (100B+ Revenue).&#8221; Kiberphant0m&#8217;s asking price of $200,000 was apparently too high because they reposted the sales thread on Breach Forums a month later, with a headline that more clearly explained the data was stolen from <strong>Verizon</strong>&#8216;s &#8220;push-to-talk&#8221; (PTT) customers &#8212; primarily U.S. government agencies and first responders.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.404media.co/hackers-advertise-stolen-verizon-push-to-talk-call-logs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">404Media reported recently</a> that the breach does not appear to impact the main consumer Verizon network. Rather, the hackers broke into a third party provider and stole data on Verizon&#8217;s PTT systems, which are a separate product marketed towards public sector agencies, enterprises, and small businesses to communicate internally.</p>
<h2>INTERVIEW WITH JUDISCHE</h2>
<p>Investigators say Moucka shared a home in Kitchener with other tenants, but not his family. His mother was born in Chechnya, and he speaks Russian in addition to French and English. Moucka&#8217;s father died of a drug overdose at age 26, when the defendant was roughly five years old.</p>
<p>A person claiming to be Judische began communicating with this author more than three months ago on Signal after KrebsOnSecurity started asking around about hacker nicknames previously used by Judische over the years.</p>
<p>Judische admitted to stealing and ransoming data from Snowflake customers, but he said he&#8217;s not interested in selling the information, and that others have done this with some of the data sets he stole.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m not really someone that sells data unless it&#8217;s crypto [databases] or credit cards because they&#8217;re the only thing I can find buyers for that actually have money for the data,&#8221; Judische told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;The rest is just ransom.&#8221;</p>
<p>Judische has sent this reporter dozens of unsolicited and often profane messages from several different Signal accounts, all of which claimed to be an anonymous tipster sharing different identifying details for Judische. This appears to have been an elaborate effort by Judische to &#8220;detrace&#8221; his movements online and muddy the waters about his identity.</p>
<p>Judische frequently claimed he had unparalleled &#8220;<strong>opsec</strong>&#8221; or <strong>operational security</strong>, a term that refers to the ability to compartmentalize and obfuscate one&#8217;s tracks online. In an effort to show he was one step ahead of investigators, Judische shared information indicating someone had given him a Mandiant researcher&#8217;s assessment of who and where they thought he was. Mandiant says those were discussion points shared with select reporters in advance of the researcher&#8217;s recent talk at the <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/press/announcing-labscon-2024-the-ultimate-cybersecurity-research-conference/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LabsCon security conference</a>.</p>
<p>But in a conversation with KrebsOnSecurity on October 26, Judische acknowledged it was likely that the authorities were closing in on him, and said he would seriously answer certain questions about his personal life.</p>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;re coming after me for sure,&#8221; he said.<span id="more-67735"></span></p>
<p>In several previous conversations, Judische referenced suffering from an unspecified personality disorder, and when pressed said he has a condition called &#8220;schizotypal personality disorder&#8221; (STPD).</p>
<p>According to the <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/23061-schizotypal-personality-disorder#:~:text=Schizotypal%20personality%20disorder%20(STPD)%20is,to%20form%20and%20maintain%20relationships." target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cleveland Clinic</a>, schizotypal personality disorder is marked by a consistent pattern of intense discomfort with relationships and social interactions: &#8220;People with STPD have unusual thoughts, speech and behaviors, which usually hinder their ability to form and maintain relationships.&#8221;</p>
<p>Judische said he was prescribed medication for his psychological issues, but that he doesn&#8217;t take his meds. Which might explain why he never leaves his home.</p>
<p>&#8220;I never go outside,&#8221; Judische allowed. &#8220;I&#8217;ve never had a friend or true relationship not online nor in person. I see people as vehicles to achieve my ends no matter how friendly I may seem on the surface, which you can see by how fast I discard people who are loyal or [that] I&#8217;ve known a long time.&#8221;</p>
<p>Judische later admitted he doesn&#8217;t have an official STPD diagnosis from a physician, but said he knows that he exhibits all the signs of someone with this condition.</p>
<p>&#8220;I can&#8217;t actually get diagnosed with that either,&#8221; Judische shared. &#8220;Most countries put you on lists and restrict you from certain things if you have it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked whether he has always lived at his current residence, Judische replied that he had to leave his hometown for his own safety.</p>
<p>&#8220;I can&#8217;t live safely where I&#8217;m from without getting robbed or arrested,&#8221; he said, without offering more details.</p>
<p>A source familiar with the investigation said Moucka previously lived in Quebec, which he allegedly fled after being charged with harassing others on the social network <strong>Discord</strong>.</p>
<p>Judische claims to have made at least $4 million in his Snowflake extortions. Judische said he and others frequently targeted business process outsourcing (BPO) companies, staffing firms that handle customer service for a wide range of organizations. They also went after managed service providers (MSPs) that oversee IT support and security for multiple companies, he claimed.</p>
<p>&#8220;Snowflake isn&#8217;t even the biggest BPO/MSP multi-company dataset on our networks, but what&#8217;s been exfiltrated from them is well over 100TB,&#8221; Judische bragged. &#8220;Only ones that don&#8217;t pay get disclosed (unless they disclose it themselves). A lot of them don&#8217;t even do their SEC filing and just pay us to fuck off.&#8221;</p>
<h2>INTEL SECRETS</h2>
<p>The other half of UNC5537 &#8212; 24-year-old John Erin Binns &#8212; was arrested in Turkey in late May 2024, and currently resides in a Turkish prison. However, it is unclear if Binns faces any immediate threat of extradition to the United States, where he is currently wanted on criminal hacking charges tied to the 2021 breach at T-Mobile.</p>
<p>A person familiar with the investigation said Binns&#8217;s application for Turkish citizenship was inexplicably approved after his incarceration, leading to speculation that Binns may have bought his way out of a sticky legal situation.</p>
<p>Under the Turkish constitution, a Turkish citizen cannot be extradited to a foreign state. Turkey has been <a href="https://www.fdd.org/analysis/2023/07/20/turkey-is-granting-citizenship-to-international-criminals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">criticized for its &#8220;golden passport&#8221; program</a>, which provides citizenship and sanctuary for anyone willing to pay several hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<div id="attachment_68097" style="width: 568px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68097" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-68097" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/binnspassport.png" alt="" width="558" height="399" /><p id="caption-attachment-68097" class="wp-caption-text">This is an image of a passport that Binns shared in one of many unsolicited emails to KrebsOnSecurity since 2021. Binns never explained why he sent this in Feb. 2023.</p></div>
<p>Binns&#8217;s alleged hacker alter egos &#8212; &#8220;<strong>IRDev</strong>&#8221; and &#8220;<strong>IntelSecrets</strong>&#8221; &#8212; were at once feared and revered on several cybercrime-focused Telegram communities, because he was known to possess a powerful weapon: A massive botnet. From reviewing the Telegram channels Binns frequented, we can see that others in those communities &#8212; including Judische &#8212; heavily relied on Binns and his botnet for a variety of cybercriminal purposes.</p>
<p>The IntelSecrets nickname corresponds to an individual who has claimed responsibility for modifying the source code for the<a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/?s=mirai" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Mirai “Internet of Things” botnet</a> to create a variant known as “<strong>Satori</strong>,” and supplying it to others who used it for criminal gain and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/09/satori-iot-botnet-operator-pleads-guilty/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">were later caught and prosecuted</a>.</p>
<p>Since 2020, Binns has filed a flood of lawsuits naming various federal law enforcement officers and agencies — including the <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/18719615/13/1/binns-v-federal-bureau-of-investigation/#text" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FBI</a>, the <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/17348542/binns-v-central-intelligence-agency/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CIA</a>, and the <a href="https://www.socom.mil/FOIA/FOIA%20Logs/FOIA%20Log%20FY%202020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">U.S. Special Operations Command</a> (PDF), demanding that the government turn over information collected about him and seeking restitution for his alleged kidnapping at the hands of the CIA.</p>
<p>Binns claims he was kidnapped in Turkey and subjected to various forms of psychological and physical torture. According to Binns, the <strong>U.S. Central Intelligence Agency</strong> (CIA) falsely told their counterparts in Turkey that he was a supporter or member of the Islamic State (ISIS), a claim he says led to his detention and torture by the Turkish authorities.</p>
<p>However, in a 2020 lawsuit he filed against the CIA, Binns himself acknowledged having visited a previously ISIS-controlled area of Syria prior to moving to Turkey in 2017.</p>
<div id="attachment_68107" style="width: 748px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-68107" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-68107" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/binnscialawsuit.png" alt="" width="738" height="741" /><p id="caption-attachment-68107" class="wp-caption-text">A segment of a lawsuit Binns filed in 2020 against the CIA, in which he alleges U.S. put him on a terror watch list after he traveled to Syria in 2017.</p></div>
<p>Sources familiar with the investigation told KrebsOnSecurity that Binns was so paranoid about possible surveillance on him by American and Turkish intelligence agencies that his erratic behavior and online communications actually brought about the very government snooping that he feared.</p>
<p>In several online chats in late 2023 on Discord, IRDev lamented being lured into a law enforcement sting operation after trying to buy a rocket launcher online. A person close to the investigation confirmed that at the beginning of 2023, IRDev began making earnest inquiries about how to purchase a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FIM-92_Stinger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stinger</a>, an American-made portable weapon that operates as an infrared surface-to-air missile.</p>
<p>Sources told KrebsOnSecurity Binns&#8217; repeated efforts to purchase the projectile earned him multiple visits from the Turkish authorities, who were justifiably curious why he kept seeking to acquire such a powerful weapon.</p>
<h2>WAIFU</h2>
<p>A careful study of Judische&#8217;s postings on Telegram and Discord since 2019 shows this user is more widely known under the nickname &#8220;<strong>Waifu</strong>,&#8221; a moniker that corresponds to one of the more accomplished &#8220;SIM swappers&#8221; in the English-language cybercrime community over the years.</p>
<p><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/?s=sim+swapping" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SIM swapping</a> involves phishing, tricking or bribing mobile phone company employees for credentials needed to redirect a target&#8217;s mobile phone number to a device the attackers control &#8212; allowing thieves to intercept incoming text messages and phone calls.</p>
<p>Several SIM-swapping channels on Telegram maintain a frequently updated leaderboard of the 100 richest SIM-swappers, as well as the hacker handles associated with specific cybercrime groups (Waifu is ranked #24). That list has long included Waifu on a roster of hackers for a group that called itself &#8220;<strong>Beige</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>The term &#8220;Beige Group&#8221; came up in reporting on two stories published here in 2020. The first was in <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/08/voice-phishers-targeting-corporate-vpns/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an August 2020 piece called Voice Phishers Targeting Corporate VPNs</a>, which warned that the COVID-19 epidemic had brought a wave of targeted voice phishing attacks that tried to trick work-at-home employees into providing access to their employers&#8217; networks. Frequent targets of the Beige group included employees at numerous top U.S. banks, ISPs, and mobile phone providers.</p>
<p>The second time Beige Group was mentioned by sources was in reporting on <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/11/godaddy-employees-used-in-attacks-on-multiple-cryptocurrency-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a breach at the domain registrar GoDaddy</a>. In November 2020, intruders thought to be associated with the Beige Group tricked a GoDaddy employee into installing malicious software, and with that access they were able to redirect the web and email traffic for multiple cryptocurrency trading platforms. Other frequent targets of the Beige group included employees at numerous top U.S. banks, ISPs, and mobile phone providers.</p>
<p>Judische&#8217;s various Telegram identities have long claimed involvement in the 2020 GoDaddy breach, and he didn&#8217;t deny his alleged role when asked directly. Judische said he prefers voice phishing or &#8220;vishing&#8221; attacks that result in the target installing data-stealing malware, as opposed to tricking the user into entering their username, password and one-time code.</p>
<p>&#8220;Most of my ops involve malware [because] credential access burns too fast,&#8221; Judische explained.</p>
<h2>CRACKDOWN ON HARM GROUPS?</h2>
<p>The Telegram channels that the Judische/Waifu accounts frequented over the years show this user divided their time between posting in channels dedicated to financial cybercrime, and harassing and stalking others in harm communities like <strong>Leak Society</strong> and <strong>Court</strong>.</p>
<p>Both of these Telegram communities are known for victimizing children through coordinated online campaigns of extortion, doxing, swatting and harassment. People affiliated with harm groups like Court and Leak Society will often recruit new members by lurking on gaming platforms, social media sites and mobile applications that are popular with young people, including <strong>Discord</strong>, <strong>Minecraft</strong>, <strong>Roblox</strong>, <strong>Steam</strong>, <strong>Telegram</strong>, and <strong>Twitch</strong>.</p>
<p>“This type of offence usually starts with a direct message through gaming platforms and can move to more private chatrooms on other virtual platforms, typically one with video enabled features, where the conversation quickly becomes sexualized or violent,” warns a <a href="https://www.rcmp-grc.gc.ca/en/news/2024/rcmp-reminds-canadians-violent-online-groups-targeting-youth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent alert</a> from the <strong>Royal Canadian Mounted Police</strong> (RCMP) about the rise of sextortion groups on social media channels.</p>
<p>“One of the tactics being used by these actors is sextortion, however, they are not using it to extract money or for sexual gratification,” the RCMP continued. “Instead they use it to further manipulate and control victims to produce more harmful and violent content as part of their ideological objectives and radicalization pathway.”</p>
<p>Some of the largest such known groups include those that go by the names <strong>764</strong>, <strong>CVLT</strong>, <strong>Kaskar</strong>, <strong>7997</strong>, <strong>8884</strong>, <strong>2992</strong>, <strong>6996</strong>, <strong>555</strong>, <strong>Slit Town</strong>, <strong>545</strong>, <strong>404</strong>, <strong>NMK</strong>, <strong>303</strong>, and <strong>H3ll</strong>.</p>
<p>On the various cybercrime-oriented channels Judische frequented, he often lied about his or others&#8217; involvement in various breaches. But Judische also at times shared nuggets of truth about his past, particularly when discussing the early history and membership of specific Telegram- and Discord-based cybercrime and harm groups.</p>
<p>Judische claimed in multiple chats, including on Leak Society and Court, that they were an early member of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atomwaffen_Division" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atomwaffen Division</a> (AWD), a white supremacy group whose members are suspected of having committed multiple murders in the U.S. since 2017.</p>
<p>In 2019, KrebsOnSecurity exposed how a loose-knit group of neo-Nazis, some of whom were affiliated with AWD, had <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/07/neo-nazi-swatters-target-dozens-of-journalists/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">doxed and/or swatted nearly three dozen journalists at a range of media publications</a>. Swatting involves communicating a false police report of a bomb threat or hostage situation and tricking authorities into sending a heavily armed police response to a targeted address.</p>
<p>Judsiche also told a fellow denizen of Court that years ago he was active in an older harm community called &#8220;<strong>RapeLash</strong>,&#8221; a truly vile Discord server known for attracting Atomwaffen members. A 2018 retrospective on RapeLash posted to the now defunct neo-Nazi forum <strong>Fascist Forge</strong> explains that RapeLash was awash in gory, violent images and child pornography.</p>
<p>A Fascist Forge member named &#8220;Huddy&#8221; recalled that RapeLash was the third incarnation of an extremist community also known as &#8220;FashWave,&#8221; short for Fascist Wave.</p>
<p>&#8220;I have no real knowledge of what happened with the intermediary phase known as &#8216;FashWave 2.0,&#8217; but FashWave 3.0 houses multiple known Satanists and other degenerates connected with AWD, one of which got arrested on possession of child pornography charges, last I heard,&#8221; Huddy shared.</p>
<p>In June 2024, a Mandiant employee <a href="https://archive.ph/dI52m#selection-1721.0-1721.339" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told Bloomberg</a> that UNC5537 members have made death threats against cybersecurity experts investigating the hackers, and that in one case the group used artificial intelligence to create fake nude photos of a researcher to harass them.</p>
<p><strong>Allison Nixon</strong> is chief research officer with the New York-based cybersecurity firm <a href="https://unit221b.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Unit 221B</a>. Nixon is among several researchers who have faced harassment and specific threats of physical violence from Judische.</p>
<p>Nixon said Judische is likely to argue in court that his self-described psychological disorder(s) should somehow excuse his long career in cybercrime and in harming others.</p>
<p>&#8220;They ran a misinformation campaign in a sloppy attempt to cover up the hacking campaign,&#8221; Nixon said of Judische. &#8220;Coverups are an acknowledgment of guilt, which will undermine a mental illness defense in court. We expect that violent hackers from the [cybercrime community] will experience increasingly harsh sentences as the crackdown continues.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>5:34 p.m. ET:</strong> Updated story to include a clarification from Mandiant. Corrected Moucka&#8217;s age.</p>
<p><strong>Nov. 21, 2024:</strong> Included link to a criminal indictment against Moucka and Binns.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Booking.com Phishers May Leave You With Reservations</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/booking-com-phishers-may-leave-you-with-reservations/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/booking-com-phishers-may-leave-you-with-reservations/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 21:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[booking.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secureworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spear phishing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=69374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A number of cybercriminal innovations are making it easier for scammers to cash in on your upcoming travel plans. This story examines a recent spear-phishing campaign that ensued when a California hotel had its booking.com credentials stolen. We'll also explore an array of cybercrime services aimed at phishers who target hotels that rely on the world's most visited travel website.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A number of cybercriminal innovations are making it easier for scammers to cash in on your upcoming travel plans. This story examines a recent spear-phishing campaign that ensued when a California hotel had its <strong>booking.com</strong> credentials stolen. We&#8217;ll also explore an array of cybercrime services aimed at phishers who target hotels that rely on the world&#8217;s most visited travel website.</p>
<p>According to the market share website <strong>statista.com</strong>, booking.com is by far the Internet&#8217;s busiest travel service, with nearly 550 million visits in September. KrebsOnSecurity last week heard from a reader whose close friend received a targeted phishing message within the Booking mobile app just minutes after making a reservation at a California hotel.</p>
<p>The missive bore the name of the hotel and referenced details from their reservation, claiming that booking.com&#8217;s anti-fraud system required additional information about the customer before the reservation could be finalized.</p>
<div id="attachment_69390" style="width: 425px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69390" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-69390" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bookingcomphish.png" alt="" width="415" height="725" /><p id="caption-attachment-69390" class="wp-caption-text">The phishing message our reader&#8217;s friend received after making a reservation at booking.com in late October.</p></div>
<p>In an email to KrebsOnSecurity, booking.com confirmed one of its partners had suffered a security incident that allowed unauthorized access to customer booking information.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our security teams are currently investigating the incident you mentioned and can confirm that it was indeed a phishing attack targeting one of our accommodation partners, which unfortunately is not a new situation and quite common across industries,&#8221; booking.com replied. &#8220;Importantly, we want to clarify that there has been no compromise of Booking.com&#8217;s internal systems.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_69387" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69387" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69387" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bookingdotcomphishingsite.png" alt="" width="749" height="458" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bookingdotcomphishingsite.png 1558w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bookingdotcomphishingsite-768x470.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bookingdotcomphishingsite-1536x940.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bookingdotcomphishingsite-782x478.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69387" class="wp-caption-text">The phony booking.com website generated by visiting the link in the text message.</p></div>
<p>Booking.com said it now <a href="https://partner.booking.com/en-gb/help/legal-security/security/securing-your-account" target="_blank" rel="noopener">requires 2FA</a>, which forces partners to provide a one-time passcode from a mobile authentication app (Pulse) in addition to a username and password.</p>
<p>&#8220;2FA is required and enforced, including for partners to access payment details from customers securely,&#8221; a booking.com spokesperson wrote. &#8220;That&#8217;s why the cybercriminals follow-up with messages to try and get customers to make payments outside of our platform.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;That said, the phishing attacks stem from partners&#8217; machines being compromised with malware, which has enabled them to also gain access to the partners&#8217; accounts and to send the messages that your reader has flagged,&#8221; they continued.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s unclear, however, if the company&#8217;s 2FA requirement is enforced for all or just newer partners. Booking.com did not respond to questions about that, and its current <a href="https://www.booking.com/trust-and-safety/partners.en-gb.html#tns_partners_account_safe" target="_blank" rel="noopener">account security advice</a> urges customers to enable 2FA.</p>
<div id="attachment_69410" style="width: 631px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69410" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69410" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/whybooking.png" alt="" width="621" height="171" /><p id="caption-attachment-69410" class="wp-caption-text">A scan of social media networks showed this is not an uncommon scam.</p></div>
<p>In November 2023, the security firm <strong>SecureWorks</strong> <a href="https://www.secureworks.com/blog/vidar-infostealer-steals-booking-com-credentials-in-fraud-scam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">detailed</a> how scammers targeted booking.com hospitality partners with data-stealing malware. SecureWorks said these attacks had been going on since at least March 2023.</p>
<p>&#8220;The hotel did not enable multi-factor authentication (MFA) on its Booking.com access, so logging into the account with the stolen credentials was easy,&#8221; SecureWorks said of the booking.com partner it investigated.</p>
<p>In June 2024, booking.com <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8003dd8jzeo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told the BBC</a> that phishing attacks targeting travelers had increased 900 percent, and that thieves taking advantage of new artificial intelligence (AI) tools were the primary driver of this trend.</p>
<p>Booking.com told the BCC the company had started using AI to fight AI-based phishing attacks. Booking.com&#8217;s statement said their investments in that arena &#8220;blocked 85 million fraudulent reservations over more than 1.5 million phishing attempts in 2023.&#8221;</p>
<p><span id="more-69374"></span></p>
<p>The domain name in the phony booking.com website sent to our reader&#8217;s friend &#8212; <strong>guestssecureverification[.]com</strong> &#8212; was registered to the email address <strong>ilotirabec207@gmail.com</strong>. According to <a href="https://www.domaintools.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DomainTools.com</a>, this email address was used to register more than 700 other phishing domains in the past month alone.</p>
<p>Many of the 700+ domains appear to target hospitality companies, including platforms like booking.com and <strong>Airbnb</strong>. Others seem crafted to phish users of <strong>Shopify</strong>, <strong>Steam</strong>, and a variety of financial platforms. A full, defanged list of domains is available <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1k8c2d2XZLXIG9tFUaU6MGRK-puAKxoCuWuzB8GSqkAM/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>A cursory review of recent posts across dozens of cybercrime forums monitored by the security firm <a href="https://www.intel471.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Intel 471</a> shows there is a great demand for compromised booking.com accounts belonging to hotels and other partners.</p>
<p>One post last month on the Russian-language hacking forum <strong>BHF</strong> offered up to $5,000 for each hotel account. This seller claims to help people monetize hacked booking.com partners, apparently by using the stolen credentials to set up fraudulent listings.</p>
<p>A service advertised on the English-language crime community <strong>BreachForums</strong> in October courts phishers who may need help with certain aspects of their phishing campaigns targeting booking.com partners. Those include more than two million hotel email addresses, and services designed to help phishers organize large volumes of phished records. Customers can interact with the service via an automated Telegram bot.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-69394" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/airbnb-bf.png" alt="" width="747" height="588" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/airbnb-bf.png 952w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/airbnb-bf-768x605.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/airbnb-bf-782x616.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /></p>
<p>Some cybercriminals appear to have used compromised booking.com accounts to power their own travel agencies catering to fellow scammers, with up to 50 percent discounts on hotel reservations through booking.com. Others are selling ready-to-use &#8220;config&#8221; files designed to make it simple to conduct automated login attempts against booking.com administrator accounts.</p>
<p>SecureWorks found the phishers targeting booking.com partner hotels used malware to steal credentials. But today&#8217;s thieves can just as easily just visit crime bazaars online and purchase stolen credentials to cloud services that do not enforce 2FA for all accounts.</p>
<p>That is <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/snowflake-breach-advanced-auto-parts-lendingtree/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">exactly what transpired</a> over the past year with many customers of the cloud data storage giant <strong>Snowflake</strong>. In late 2023, cybercriminals figured out that while tons of companies had stashed enormous amounts of customer data at Snowflake, many of those customer accounts were not protected by 2FA.</p>
<p>Snowflake responded by making 2FA mandatory for all new customers. But that change came only after thieves used stolen credentials to siphon data from 160 companies &#8212; including <strong>AT&amp;T</strong>, <strong>Lending Tree</strong> and <strong>TicketMaster</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/booking-com-phishers-may-leave-you-with-reservations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 243/243 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2024-12-10 09:35:03 by W3 Total Cache
-->