<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Krebs on Security</title>
	<atom:link href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com</link>
	<description>In-depth security news and investigation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 03:02:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Feds Link $150M Cyberheist to 2022 LastPass Hacks</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/feds-link-150m-cyberheist-to-2022-lastpass-hacks/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/feds-link-150m-cyberheist-to-2022-lastpass-hacks/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 01:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Larsen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fbi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Karim Toubba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lastpass breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nick Bax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taylor Monahan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Secret Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZachXBT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70634</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In September 2023, KrebsOnSecurity published findings from security researchers who concluded that a series of six-figure cyberheists across dozens of victims resulted from thieves cracking master passwords stolen from the password manager service LastPass in 2022. In a court filing this week, U.S. federal agents investigating a spectacular $150 million cryptocurrency heist said they had reached the same conclusion.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In September 2023, KrebsOnSecurity published findings from security researchers who concluded that a series of six-figure cyberheists across dozens of victims resulted from thieves cracking master passwords stolen from the password manager service <strong>LastPass</strong> in 2022. In a court filing this week, U.S. federal agents investigating a spectacular $150 million cryptocurrency heist said they had reached the same conclusion.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-31264" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lastpass-580x132.png" alt="" width="580" height="132" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lastpass-580x132.png 580w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lastpass.png 808w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /></p>
<p>On March 6, federal prosecutors in northern California said they seized approximately $24 million worth of cryptocurrencies that were clawed back following a $150 million cyberheist on Jan. 30, 2024. The complaint refers to the person robbed only as &#8220;Victim-1,&#8221; but according to blockchain security researcher <strong>ZachXBT</strong> the theft was perpetrated against <strong>Chris Larsen</strong>, the co-founder of the cryptocurrency platform <strong>Ripple</strong>.</p>
<p>ZachXBT was the <a href="https://x.com/zachxbt/status/1752694489905528943" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first to report on the heist</a>, of which approximately $24 million was frozen by the feds before it could be withdrawn. This week&#8217;s action by the government merely allows investigators to officially seize the frozen funds.</p>
<p>But there is an important conclusion in this seizure document: It basically says the <strong>U.S. Secret Service</strong> and the <strong>FBI</strong> agree with the findings of <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2023/09/experts-fear-crooks-are-cracking-keys-stolen-in-lastpass-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the LastPass breach story published here in September 2023</a>. That piece quoted security researchers who said they were witnessing six-figure crypto heists several times each month that they believed all appeared to be the result of crooks cracking master passwords for the password vaults stolen from LastPass in 2022.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Federal Bureau of Investigation has been investigating these data breaches, and law enforcement agents investigating the instant case have spoken with FBI agents about their investigation,&#8221; reads the seizure complaint, which was written by a U.S. Secret Service agent. &#8220;From those conversations, law enforcement agents in this case learned that the stolen data and passwords that were stored in several victims’ online password manager accounts were used to illegally, and without authorization, access the victims’ electronic accounts and steal information, cryptocurrency, and other data.&#8221;</p>
<p>The document continues:</p>
<p>&#8220;Based on this investigation, law enforcement had probable cause to believe the same attackers behind the above-described commercial online password manager attack used a stolen password held in Victim 1’s online password manager account and, without authorization, accessed his cryptocurrency wallet/account.&#8221;</p>
<p>Working with dozens of victims, security researchers <strong>Nick Bax</strong> and <strong>Taylor Monahan</strong> found that none of the six-figure cyberheist victims appeared to have suffered the sorts of attacks that typically preface a high-dollar crypto theft, such as the compromise of one’s email and/or mobile phone accounts, or SIM-swapping attacks.</p>
<p>They discovered the victims all had something else in common: Each had at one point stored their cryptocurrency seed phrase &#8212; the secret code that lets anyone gain access to your cryptocurrency holdings &#8212; in the &#8220;Secure Notes&#8221; area of their LastPass account prior to the 2022 breaches at the company.</p>
<p>Bax and Monahan found another common theme with these robberies: They all followed a similar pattern of cashing out, rapidly moving stolen funds to a dizzying number of drop accounts scattered across various cryptocurrency exchanges.</p>
<p>According to the government, a similar level of complexity was present in the $150 million heist against the Ripple co-founder last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;The scale of a theft and rapid dissipation of funds would have required the efforts of multiple malicious actors, and was consistent with the online password manager breaches and attack on other victims whose cryptocurrency was stolen,&#8221; the government wrote. &#8220;For these reasons, law enforcement agents believe the cryptocurrency stolen from Victim 1 was committed by the same attackers who conducted the attack on the online password manager, and cryptocurrency thefts from other similarly situated victims.&#8221;</p>
<p>Reached for comment, LastPass said it has seen no definitive proof &#8212; from federal investigators or others &#8212; that the cyberheists in question were linked to the LastPass breaches.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since we initially disclosed this incident back in 2022, LastPass has worked in close cooperation with multiple representatives from law enforcement,&#8221; LastPass said in a written statement. &#8220;To date, our law enforcement partners have not made us aware of any conclusive evidence that connects any crypto thefts to our incident. In the meantime, we have been investing heavily in enhancing our security measures and will continue to do so.&#8221;<span id="more-70634"></span></p>
<p>On August 25, 2022, <strong>LastPass CEO Karim Toubba</strong> told users the company had detected unusual activity in its software development environment, and that the intruders stole some source code and proprietary LastPass technical information. On Sept. 15, 2022, LastPass said an investigation into the August breach determined the attacker did not access any customer data or password vaults.</p>
<p>But on Nov. 30, 2022, LastPass notified customers about another, far more serious security incident that the company said leveraged data stolen in the August breach. LastPass disclosed that criminal hackers had compromised encrypted copies of some password vaults, as well as other personal information.</p>
<p>Experts say the breach would have given thieves &#8220;offline&#8221; access to encrypted password vaults, theoretically allowing them all the time in the world to try to crack some of the weaker master passwords using powerful systems that can attempt millions of password guesses per second.</p>
<p>Researchers found that many of the cyberheist victims had chosen master passwords with relatively low complexity, and were among LastPass&#8217;s oldest customers. That&#8217;s because legacy LastPass users were more likely to have master passwords that were protected with far fewer &#8220;iterations,&#8221; which refers to the number of times your password is run through the company&#8217;s encryption routines. In general, the more iterations, the longer it takes an offline attacker to crack your master password.</p>
<p>Over the years, LastPass forced new users to pick longer and more complex master passwords, and they increased the number of iterations on multiple occasions by several orders of magnitude. But researchers found strong indications that LastPass never succeeded in upgrading many of its older customers to the newer password requirements and protections.</p>
<p>Asked about LastPass&#8217;s continuing denials, Bax said that after the initial warning in our 2023 story, he naively hoped people would migrate their funds to new cryptocurrency wallets.</p>
<p>&#8220;While some did, the continued thefts underscore how much more needs to be done,&#8221; Bax told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;It&#8217;s validating to see the Secret Service and FBI corroborate our findings, but I’d much rather see fewer of these hacks in the first place. ZachXBT and <a href="https://x.com/_SEAL_Org/status/1868805837311074576" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SEAL 911 reported yet another wave of thefts</a> as recently as December, showing the threat is still very real.&#8221;</p>
<p>Monahan said LastPass still hasn’t alerted their customers that their secrets—especially those stored in “Secure Notes”—may be at risk.</p>
<p>&#8220;Its been two and a half years since LastPass was first breached [and] hundreds of millions of dollars has been stolen from individuals and companies around the globe,&#8221; Monahan said. &#8220;They could have encouraged users to rotate their credentials. They could’ve prevented millions and millions of dollars from being stolen by these threat actors. But  instead they chose to deny that their customers were are risk and blame the victims instead.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/feds-link-150m-cyberheist-to-2022-lastpass-hacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who is the DOGE and X Technician Branden Spikes?</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/who-is-the-doge-and-x-technician-branden-spikes/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/who-is-the-doge-and-x-technician-branden-spikes/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branden Spikes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California Russian Association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Congress of Russian Americans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Constellation of Humanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberinc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Government Efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diana Fishman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald J. Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inc.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ivan Y. Podvalov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jacqueline Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maye Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natalia Haldeman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natalia Spikes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radaris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reeve Haldeman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian American Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Heritage Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Orthodox Church Outside of Russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott Haldeman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SpaceX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spikes Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Digital Service]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At 49, Branden Spikes isn't just one of the oldest technologists who has been involved in Elon Musk's Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE). As the current director of information technology at X/Twitter and an early hire at PayPal, Zip2, Tesla and SpaceX, Spikes is also among Musk's most loyal employees. Here's a closer look at this trusted Musk lieutenant, whose Russian ex-wife was once married to Elon's cousin.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At 49, <strong>Branden Spikes</strong> isn&#8217;t just one of the oldest technologists who has been involved in Elon Musk&#8217;s <strong>Department of Government Efficiency</strong> (DOGE). As the current director of information technology at <strong>X/Twitter</strong> and an early hire at <strong>PayPal</strong>, <strong>Zip2</strong>,<strong> Tesla</strong> and <strong>SpaceX</strong>, Spikes is also among Musk&#8217;s most loyal employees. Here&#8217;s a closer look at this trusted Musk lieutenant, whose Russian ex-wife was once married to Elon&#8217;s cousin.</p>
<div id="attachment_70586" style="width: 601px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70586" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70586" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/x-spikes.png" alt="" width="591" height="533" /><p id="caption-attachment-70586" class="wp-caption-text">The profile of Branden Spikes on X.</p></div>
<p>When President Trump took office again in January, he put the world&#8217;s richest man &#8212; Elon Musk &#8212; in charge of the <strong>U.S. Digital Service</strong>, and renamed the organization as DOGE. The group is reportedly staffed by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/02/27/us/politics/doge-staff-list.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">at least 50 technologists</a>, many of whom have ties to Musk&#8217;s companies.</p>
<p>DOGE has been enabling the president&#8217;s ongoing mass layoffs and firings of federal workers, largely by seizing control over computer systems and government data for a multitude of federal agencies, including the Social Security Administration, the Department of Homeland Security, the Office of Personnel Management, and the Treasury Department.</p>
<p>It is difficult to find another person connected to DOGE who has stronger ties to Musk than Branden Spikes. A native of California, Spikes initially teamed up with Musk in 1997 as a lead systems engineer for the software company Zip2, the first major venture for Musk. In 1999, Spikes was hired as director of IT at PayPal, and in 2002 he became just the fourth person hired at SpaceX.</p>
<p>In 2012, Spikes launched <strong>Spikes Security</strong>, a software product that sought to create a compartmentalized or &#8220;sandboxed&#8221; web browser that could insulate the user from malware attacks. A review of spikes.com in the Wayback Machine shows that as far back as 1998, Musk could be seen joining Spikes for team matches in the online games Quake and Quake II. In 2016, Spikes Security was merged with another security suite called Aurionpro, with the combined company renamed Cyberinc.</p>
<div id="attachment_70608" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70608" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70608" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spikesquake.png" alt="" width="748" height="682" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spikesquake.png 879w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spikesquake-768x700.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spikesquake-782x713.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70608" class="wp-caption-text">A snapshot of spikes.com from 1998 shows Elon Musk&#8217;s profile in Spike&#8217;s clan for the games Quake and Quake II.</p></div>
<p>Spikes&#8217;s <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/brandenspikes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LinkedIn profile</a> says he was appointed head of IT at X in February 2025. And although his name shows up on none of the lists of DOGE employees circulated by various media outlets, multiple sources told KrebsOnSecurity that Spikes was working with DOGE and operates within Musk&#8217;s inner circle of trust.</p>
<p>In a conversation with KrebsOnSecurity, Spikes said he is dedicated to his country and to saving it from what he sees as certain ruin.</p>
<p>&#8220;Myself, I was raised by a southern conservative family in California and I strongly believe in America and her future,&#8221; Spikes said. &#8220;This is why I volunteered for two months in DC recently to help DOGE save us from certain bankruptcy.&#8221;</p>
<p>Spikes told KrebsOnSecurity that he recently decided to head back home and focus on his job as director of IT at X.</p>
<p>&#8220;I loved it, but ultimately I did not want to leave my hometown and family back in California,&#8221; Spikes said of his tenure at DOGE. &#8220;After a couple of months it became clear that to continue helping I would need to move to DC and commit a lot more time, so I politely bowed out.&#8221;</p>
<p>Prior to founding Spikes Security, Branden Spikes was married to a native Russian woman named <strong>Natalia</strong> whom he&#8217;d met at a destination wedding in South America in 2003.</p>
<p>Branden and Natalia&#8217;s names are both on the registration records for the domain name <strong>orangetearoom[.]com</strong>. This domain, which DomainTools.com says was originally registered by Branden in 2009, is the home of a tax-exempt charity in Los Angeles called the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20141221061648/http://www.russiancalifornia.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>California Russian Association</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Here is a photo from a 2011 event organized by the California Russian Association, showing Branden and Natalia at one of its &#8220;White Nights&#8221; charity fundraisers:</p>
<div id="attachment_70585" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70585" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70585" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spikes-heritage.png" alt="" width="749" height="564" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spikes-heritage.png 777w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spikes-heritage-768x578.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70585" class="wp-caption-text">Branden and Natalia Spikes, on left, in 2011. The man on the far right is Ivan Y. Podvalov, a board member of the Kremlin-aligned Congress of Russian Americans (CRA). The man in the center is Feodor Yakimoff, director of operations at the Transib Global Sourcing Group, and chairman of the Russian Imperial Charity Balls, which works in concert with the Russian Heritage Foundation.</p></div>
<p>In 2011, the Spikes couple got divorced, and Natalia changed her last name to Haldeman. That is not her maiden name, which appears to be &#8220;Libina.&#8221; Rather, Natalia acquired the surname Haldeman in 1998, when she married Elon Musk&#8217;s cousin.</p>
<p><strong>Reeve Haldeman</strong> is the son of <strong>Scott Haldeman</strong>, who is the brother of Elon Musk&#8217;s mother, <strong>Maye Musk</strong>. Divorce records show Reeve and Natalia <a href="https://unicourt.com/case/ca-ora2-haldeman-v-haldeman-609208" target="_blank" rel="noopener">officially terminated</a> their marriage in 2007. Reeve Haldeman did not respond to a request for comment.<span id="more-70579"></span></p>
<p>A review of other domain names connected to Natalia Haldeman&#8217;s email address show she has registered more than a dozen domains over the years that are tied to the California Russian Association, and an apparently related entity called the <strong>Russian Heritage Foundation, Inc.</strong>:</p>
<p>russianamericans.org<br />
russianamericanstoday.com<br />
russianamericanstoday.org<br />
russiancalifornia.org<br />
russianheritagefoundation.com<br />
russianheritagefoundation.org<br />
russianwhitenights.com<br />
russianwhitenights.org<br />
theforafoundation.org<br />
thegoldentearoom.com<br />
therussianheritagefoundation.org<br />
tsarinahome.com</p>
<p>Ms. Haldeman did not respond to requests for comment. Her name and contact information appears in the registration records for these domains dating back to 2010, and <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/organizations/452775704 California Russian Foundation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a document</a> published by <em>ProPublica</em> show that by 2016 Natalia Haldeman was appointed CEO of the California Russian Foundation.</p>
<p>The domain name that bears both Branden&#8217;s and Natalia&#8217;s names &#8212; orangetearoom.com &#8212; features photos of Ms. Haldeman at fundraising events for the Russian foundation through 2014. Additional photos of her and many of the same people can be seen through 2023 at another domain she registered in 2010 &#8212; <strong>russianheritagefoundation.com</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_70630" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70630" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70630" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/haldeman-mayemusk-1.png" alt="" width="750" height="429" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/haldeman-mayemusk-1.png 1258w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/haldeman-mayemusk-1-768x439.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/haldeman-mayemusk-1-782x447.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70630" class="wp-caption-text">A photo from Natalia Haldeman&#8217;s Facebook page shows her mother (left) pictured with Maye Musk, Elon Musk&#8217;s mother, in 2022.</p></div>
<p>The photo of Branden and Natalia above is from one such event in 2011 (tied to russianwhitenights.org, another Haldeman domain). The person on the right in that image &#8212; <strong>Ivan Y. Podvalov</strong> &#8212; appears in many fundraising event photos published by the foundation over the past decade. Podvalov is a board member of the <strong>Congress of Russian Americans</strong> (CRA), a nonprofit group that is known for vehemently opposing U.S. financial and legal sanctions against Russia.</p>
<p>Writing for <em>The Insider</em> in 2022, journalist <strong>Diana Fishman</strong> described how the CRA has engaged in outright political lobbying, noting that the organization in June 2014 sent a letter to President Obama and the secretary of the United Nations, calling for an end to the &#8220;large-scale US intervention in Ukraine and the campaign to isolate Russia.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The US military contingents must be withdrawn immediately from the Eastern European region, and NATO&#8217;s enlargement efforts and provocative actions against Russia must cease,” the message read.</p>
<p>The Insider said the CRA director sent another two letters, this time to President Donald Trump, in 2017 and 2018.</p>
<p>&#8220;One was a request not to sign a law expanding sanctions against Russia,&#8221; Fishman <a href="https://theins.ru/en/politics/256825" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>. &#8220;The other regretted the expulsion of 60 Russian diplomats from the United States and urged not to jump to conclusions on Moscow&#8217;s involvement in the poisoning of Sergei Skripal.&#8221;</p>
<p>The nonprofit tracking website CauseIQ.com <a href="https://www.causeiq.com/organizations/russian-heritage-foundation,831537424/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that The Russian Heritage Foundation, Inc. is now known as <strong>Constellation of Humanity</strong>.</p>
<p>The Russian Heritage Foundation and the California Russian Association both promote the interests of <a href="https://cepa.org/article/an-unorthodox-russian-vision-of-heaven-and-hell/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Russian Orthodox Church</a>. <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20141119232054/http://www.russiancalifornia.org/russian-orthodox-church-orange-county/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This page</a> indexed by Archive.org from russiancalifornia.org shows The California Russian Foundation organized a community effort to establish an Orthodox church in Orange County, Calif.</p>
<p>A press release from the <strong>Russian Orthodox Church Outside of Russia</strong> (ROCOR) shows that in 2021 the Russian Heritage Foundation <a href="https://www.rocorstudies.org/2021/03/09/russian-heritage-foundation-supports-our-work/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">donated money</a> to organize a conference for the Russian Orthodox Church in Serbia.</p>
<p>A review of the &#8220;<a href="https://orangetearoom.com/index.php/network/about-us" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Partners</a>&#8221; listed on the Spikes&#8217; jointly registered domain &#8212; orangetearoom.com &#8212; shows the organization worked with a marketing company called <strong>Russian American Media</strong>. <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/a-close-up-look-at-the-consumer-data-broker-radaris/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reporting by KrebsOnSecurity last year</a> showed that Russian American Media also partners with the problematic people-search service <strong>Radaris</strong>, which was formed by two native Russian brothers in Massachusetts who have built a fleet of consumer data brokers and Russian affiliate programs.</p>
<p>When asked about his ex-wife&#8217;s history, Spikes said she has a good heart and bears no ill-will toward anyone.</p>
<p>&#8220;I attended several of Natalia&#8217;s social events over the years we were together and can assure you that she&#8217;s got the best intentions with those,&#8221; Spikes told KrebsOnSecurity. &#8220;There&#8217;s no funny business going on. It is just a way for those friendly immigrants to find resources amongst each other to help get settled in and chase the American dream. I mean, they&#8217;re not unlike the immigrants from other countries who come to America and try to find each other and help each other find others who speak the language and share in the building of their businesses here in America.&#8221;</p>
<p>Spikes said his own family roots go back deeply into American history, sharing that his 6th great grandfather was Alexander Hamilton on his mom&#8217;s side, and Jessie James on his dad&#8217;s side.</p>
<p>&#8220;My family roots are about as American as you can get,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I&#8217;ve also been entrusted with building and safeguarding Elon&#8217;s companies since 1999 and have a keen eye (as you do) for bad actors, so have enough perspective to tell you that Natalia has no bad blood and that she loves America.&#8221;</p>
<p>Of course, this perspective comes from someone who has the utmost regard for the interests of the &#8220;special government employee&#8221; Mr. Musk, who has been bragging about tossing entire federal agencies into the &#8220;wood chipper,&#8221; and who recently <a href="https://apnews.com/article/musk-chainsaw-trump-doge-6568e9e0cfc42ad6cdcfd58a409eb312" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wielded an actual chainsaw</a> on stage while referring to it as the &#8220;chainsaw for bureaucracy.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Elon&#8217;s intentions are good and you can trust him,&#8221; Spikes assured.</p>
<p>A special note of thanks for research assistance goes to <strong>Jacqueline Sweet</strong>, an independent investigative journalist whose work has been published in The Guardian, Rolling Stone, POLITICO and The Intercept.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/03/who-is-the-doge-and-x-technician-branden-spikes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notorious Malware, Spam Host &#8220;Prospero&#8221; Moves to Kaspersky Lab</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/notorious-malware-spam-host-prospero-moves-to-kaspersky-lab/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/notorious-malware-spam-host-prospero-moves-to-kaspersky-lab/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 20:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alfa Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BEARHOST]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GootLoader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interisle Consulting Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intrinsec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaspersky Lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kentik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prospero OOO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Securehost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent Push]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SocGholish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spamhaus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zach Edwards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the most notorious providers of abuse-friendly "bulletproof" web hosting for cybercriminals has started routing its operations through networks run by the Russian antivirus and security firm Kaspersky Lab, KrebsOnSecurity has learned.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most notorious providers of abuse-friendly &#8220;bulletproof&#8221; web hosting for cybercriminals has started routing its operations through networks run by the Russian antivirus and security firm <strong>Kaspersky Lab</strong>, KrebsOnSecurity has learned.</p>
<p>Security experts say the Russia-based service provider <strong>Prospero OOO </strong>(the triple O is the Russian version of &#8220;LLC&#8221;) has long been a persistent source of malicious software, botnet controllers, and <a href="https://urlscan.io/search/#page.asn%3Aas200593" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a torrent of phishing websites</a>. Last year, the French security firm <strong>Intrinsec</strong> <a href="https://www.intrinsec.com/prospero-proton66-tracing-uncovering-the-links-between-bulletproof-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">detailed</a> Prospero&#8217;s connections to bulletproof services advertised on Russian cybercrime forums under the names <strong>Securehost</strong> and <strong>BEARHOST</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_70550" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70550" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70550" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bearhost.png" alt="" width="749" height="492" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bearhost.png 902w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bearhost-768x504.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bearhost-782x513.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70550" class="wp-caption-text">The bulletproof hosting provider BEARHOST. This screenshot has been machine-translated from Russian. Image: Ke-la.com.</p></div>
<p>Bulletproof hosts are so named when they earn or cultivate a reputation for ignoring legal demands and abuse complaints. And BEARHOST has been cultivating its reputation since at least 2019.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you need a server for a botnet, for malware, brute, scan, phishing, fakes and any other tasks, please contact us,&#8221; BEARHOST&#8217;s ad on one forum advises. &#8220;We completely ignore all abuses without exception, including SPAMHAUS and other organizations.&#8221;</p>
<p>Intrinsec found Prospero has courted some of Russia&#8217;s nastiest cybercrime groups, hosting control servers for multiple ransomware gangs over the past two years. Intrinsec said its analysis showed Prospero frequently hosts malware operations such as <a href="https://www.reliaquest.com/blog/new-python-socgholish-infection-chain/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SocGholish</a> and <a href="https://redcanary.com/threat-detection-report/threats/gootloader/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GootLoader</a>, which are spread primarily via fake browser updates on hacked websites and often lay the groundwork for more serious cyber intrusions &#8212; including ransomware.</p>
<div id="attachment_70548" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70548" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70548" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/fakeupdates.png" alt="" width="749" height="361" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/fakeupdates.png 1121w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/fakeupdates-768x371.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/fakeupdates-782x377.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70548" class="wp-caption-text">A fake browser update page pushing mobile malware. Image: Intrinsec.</p></div>
<p>BEARHOST prides itself on the ability to evade blocking by <a href="https://www.spamhaus.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Spamhaus</a>, an organization that many Internet service providers around the world rely on to help identify and block sources of malware and spam. Earlier this week, Spamhaus said it <a href="https://www.cidr-report.org/cgi-bin/as-report?as=AS200593" target="_blank" rel="noopener">noticed</a> that Prospero was suddenly connecting to the Internet by routing through networks operated by Kaspersky Lab in Moscow.</p>
<p><strong>Update, March 1, 9:43 a.m. ET:</strong> In a written statement, Kaspersky said it is aware of the public claim about the company allegedly providing services to a &#8220;bulletproof&#8221; web hosting provider. Here is their full statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Kaspersky denies these claims as the company does not work and has never worked with the service provider in question. The routing through networks operated by Kaspersky doesn&#8217;t by default mean provision of the company&#8217;s services, as Kaspersky&#8217;s automatic system (AS) path might appear as a technical prefix in the network of telecom providers the company works with and provides its DDoS services.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Kaspersky pays great attention to conducting business ethically and ensuring that its solutions are used for their original purpose of providing cybersecurity protection. The company is currently investigating the situation to inform the company whose network could have served as a transit for a &#8220;bulletproof&#8221; web hosting provider so that the former takes the necessary measures.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Kaspersky began selling antivirus and security software in the United States in 2005, and the company&#8217;s malware researchers have earned accolades from the security community for many important discoveries over the years. But in September 2017, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) barred U.S. federal agencies from using Kaspersky software, mandating its removal within 90 days.<span id="more-70525"></span></p>
<p>Cybersecurity reporter <strong>Kim Zetter</strong> notes that DHS didn&#8217;t cite any specific justification for its ban in 2017, but media reports quoting anonymous government officials referenced two incidents. Zetter wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>According to one story, an NSA contractor developing offensive hacking tools for the spy agency had Kaspersky software installed on his home computer where he was developing the tools, and the software detected the source code as malicious code and extracted it from his computer, as antivirus software is designed to do. A second story claimed that Israeli spies caught Russian government hackers using Kaspersky software to search customer systems for files containing U.S. secrets.</p>
<p>Kaspersky denied that anyone used its software to search for secret information on customer machines and said that the tools on the NSA worker&#8217;s machine were detected in the same way that all antivirus software detects files it deems suspicious and then quarantines or extracts them for analysis. Once Kaspersky discovered that the code its antivirus software detected on the NSA worker&#8217;s machine were not malicious programs but source code in development by the U.S. government for its hacking operations, CEO Eugene Kaspersky says he ordered workers to delete the code.</p></blockquote>
<p>Last year, the U.S. Commerce Department <a href="https://www.zetter-zeroday.com/kaspersky-lab-closing-u-s-division-laying-off-workers-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">banned the sale of Kaspersky software in the U.S.</a> effective July 20, 2024. U.S. officials argued the ban was needed because Russian law requires domestic companies to cooperate in all official investigations, and thus the Russian government could force Kaspersky to secretly gather intelligence on its behalf.</p>
<p>Phishing data gathered last year by the <strong>Interisle Consulting Group</strong> ranked hosting networks by their size and concentration of spambot hosts, and <a href="https://www.cybercrimeinfocenter.org/spam-activity-in-hosting-networks-december-february-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found</a> Prospero had a higher spam score than any other provider by far.</p>
<div id="attachment_70549" style="width: 758px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70549" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70549" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/cidr-as200593.png" alt="" width="748" height="483" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/cidr-as200593.png 896w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/cidr-as200593-768x495.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/cidr-as200593-782x504.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70549" class="wp-caption-text">AS209030, owned by Kaspersky Lab, is providing connectivity to the bulletproof host Prospero (AS200593). Image: cidr-report.org.</p></div>
<p>It remains unclear why Kaspersky is providing transit to Prospero. <strong>Doug Madory</strong>, director of Internet analysis at <strong>Kentik</strong>, said routing records show the relationship between Prospero and Kaspersky started at the beginning of December 2024.</p>
<p>Madory said Kaspersky&#8217;s network appears to be <a href="https://www.cidr-report.org/cgi-bin/as-report?as=AS209030&amp;v=4&amp;view=2.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hosting several financial institutions</a>, including Russia&#8217;s largest &#8212; <strong>Alfa-Bank</strong>. Kaspersky sells services to help protect customers from distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks, and Madory said it could be that Prospero is simply purchasing that protection from Kaspersky.</p>
<p>But if that is the case, it doesn&#8217;t make the situation any better, said <strong>Zach Edwards</strong>, a senior threat researcher at the security firm <strong>Silent Push</strong>.</p>
<p>&#8220;In some ways, providing DDoS protection to a well-known bulletproof hosting provider may be even worse than just allowing them to connect to the rest of the Internet over your infrastructure,&#8221; Edwards said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/notorious-malware-spam-host-prospero-moves-to-kaspersky-lab/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Soldier Charged in AT&#038;T Hack Searched &#8220;Can Hacking Be Treason&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/u-s-soldier-charged-in-att-hack-searched-can-hacking-be-treason/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/u-s-soldier-charged-in-att-hack-searched-can-hacking-be-treason/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 03:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breadcrumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cameron John Wagenius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Connor Riley Moucka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Erin Binns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiberphant0m]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70530</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A U.S. Army soldier who pleaded guilty last week to leaking phone records for high-ranking U.S. government officials searched online for non-extradition countries and for an answer to the question "can hacking be treason?" prosecutors in the case said Wednesday. The government disclosed the details in a court motion to keep the defendant in custody until he is discharged from the military.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A U.S. Army soldier who pleaded guilty last week to leaking phone records for high-ranking U.S. government officials searched online for non-extradition countries and for an answer to the question &#8220;can hacking be treason?&#8221; prosecutors in the case said Wednesday. The government disclosed the details in a court motion to keep the defendant in custody until he is discharged from the military.</p>
<div id="attachment_69974" style="width: 757px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-69974" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-69974" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie.png" alt="" width="747" height="740" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie.png 779w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/camwagenius-selfie-768x761.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /><p id="caption-attachment-69974" class="wp-caption-text">One of several selfies on the Facebook page of Cameron Wagenius.</p></div>
<p><strong>Cameron John Wagenius</strong>, 21, was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/12/u-s-army-soldier-arrested-in-att-verizon-extortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested</a> near the Army base in Fort Cavazos, Texas on Dec. 20, and charged with two criminal counts of unlawful transfer of confidential phone records. Wagenius was a communications specialist at a U.S. Army base in South Korea, who secretly went by the nickname <strong>Kiberphant0m</strong> and was part of a trio of criminal hackers that extorted dozens of companies last year over stolen data.</p>
<p>At the end of 2023, malicious hackers learned that many companies had uploaded sensitive customer records to accounts at the cloud data storage service <strong>Snowflake</strong> that were protected with little more than a username and password (no multi-factor authentication needed). After scouring darknet markets for stolen Snowflake account credentials, the hackers began raiding the data storage repositories used by some of the world&#8217;s largest corporations.</p>
<p>Among those was <strong>AT&amp;T</strong>, which disclosed in July that cybercriminals had stolen personal information and phone and text message records for roughly 110 million people — nearly all of its customers. AT&amp;T <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/atandt-paid-hacker-300000-to-delete-stolen-call-records/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reportedly</a> paid a hacker $370,000 to delete stolen phone records. More than 160 other Snowflake customers were relieved of data, including TicketMaster, Lending Tree, Advance Auto Parts and Neiman Marcus.</p>
<p>In several posts to an English-language cybercrime forum in November, Kiberphant0m leaked some of the phone records and threatened to leak them all unless paid a ransom. Prosecutors said that in addition to his public posts on the forum, Wagenius had engaged in multiple direct attempts to extort &#8220;Victim-1,&#8221; which appears to be a reference to AT&amp;T. The government states that Kiberphant0m privately demanded $500,000 from Victim-1, threatening to release all of the stolen phone records unless he was paid.</p>
<p>On Feb. 19, Wagenius <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.343000/gov.uscourts.wawd.343000.27.0.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pleaded guilty</a> to two counts of unlawfully transferring confidential phone records, but he did so without the benefit of a plea agreement. In entering the plea, Wagenius&#8217;s attorneys had asked the court to allow him to stay with his father pending his sentencing.</p>
<p>But in <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.343000/gov.uscourts.wawd.343000.30.0.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a response filed today</a> (PDF), prosecutors in Seattle said Wagenius was a flight risk, partly because prior to his arrest he was searching online for how to defect to countries that do not extradite to the United States. According to the government, while Kiberphant0m was extorting AT&amp;T, Wagenius&#8217;s searches included:</p>
<p>-&#8220;where can i defect the u.s government military which country will not hand me over&#8221;<br />
-&#8220;U.S. military personnel defecting to Russia&#8221;<br />
-&#8220;Embassy of Russia – Washington, D.C.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;As discussed in the government’s sealed filing, the government has uncovered evidence suggesting that the charged conduct was only a small part of Wagenius’ malicious activity,&#8221; the government memo states. &#8220;On top of this, for more than two weeks in November 2024, Wagenius communicated with an email address he believed belonged to Country-1’s military intelligence service in an attempt to sell stolen information. Days after he apparently finished communicating with Country-1’s military intelligence service, Wagenius Googled, &#8216;can hacking be treason.'&#8221;<span id="more-70530"></span></p>
<p>Prosecutors told the court investigators also found a screenshot on Wagenius&#8217; laptop that suggested he had over 17,000 files that included passports, driver’s licenses, and other identity cards belonging to victims of a breach, and that in one of his online accounts, the government also found a fake identification document that contained his picture.</p>
<p>&#8220;Wagenius should also be detained because he presents a serious risk of flight, has the means and intent to flee, and is aware that he will likely face additional charges,&#8221; the Seattle prosecutors asserted.</p>
<p>The court filing says Wagenius is presently in the process of being separated from the Army, but the government has not received confirmation that his discharge has been finalized.</p>
<p>&#8220;The government’s understanding is that, until his discharge from the Army is finalized (which is expected to happen in early March), he may only be released directly to the Army,&#8221; reads a footnote in the memo. &#8220;Until that process is completed, Wagenius’ proposed release to his father should be rejected for this additional reason.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wagenius&#8217;s interest in defecting to another country in order to escape prosecution mirrors that of his alleged co-conspirator, <strong>John Erin Binns</strong>, an 25-year-old elusive American man indicted by the Justice Department for <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/08/t-mobile-investigating-claims-of-massive-data-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a 2021 breach at T-Mobile</a> that exposed the personal information of at least 76.6 million customers.</p>
<p>Binns has since been charged with the Snowflake hack and subsequent extortion activity. He is currently in custody in a Turkish prison. Sources close to the investigation told KrebsOnSecurity that prior to his arrest by Turkish police, Binns visited the Russian embassy in Turkey to inquire about Russian citizenship.</p>
<p>In late November 2024, Canadian authorities <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/canadian-man-arrested-in-snowflake-data-extortions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrested a third alleged member of the extortion conspiracy</a>, 25-year-old <strong>Connor Riley Moucka</strong> of Kitchener, Ontario. The U.S. government has indicted Moucka and Binns, charging them with one count of conspiracy; 10 counts of wire fraud; four counts of computer fraud and abuse; two counts of extortion in relation to computer fraud; and two counts aggravated identity theft.</p>
<p>Less than a month before Wagenius&#8217;s arrest, KrebsOnSecurity published <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a deep dive</a> into Kiberphant0m&#8217;s various Telegram and Discord identities over the years, revealing how the owner of the accounts told others they were in the Army and stationed in South Korea.</p>
<p>The maximum penalty Wagenius could face at sentencing includes up to ten years in prison for each count, and fines not to exceed $250,000.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/u-s-soldier-charged-in-att-hack-searched-can-hacking-be-treason/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump 2.0 Brings Cuts to Cyber, Consumer Protections</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/trump-2-0-brings-cuts-to-cyber-consumer-protections/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/trump-2-0-brings-cuts-to-cyber-consumer-protections/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 23:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia's War on Ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bruce Schneier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bybit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christopher Stanley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conservative Political Action Conference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumer Financial Protection Bureau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Davi Ottenheimer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Government Efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Homeland Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edward Coristine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gavin Kliger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Global Investigative Journalism Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hunter Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internal Revenue Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jacob Silverman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jacob Williams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katie Arrington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KleptoCapture Task Force]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leland Dudek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lizardstresser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michelle King]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natalya Martynova]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Institute of Standards and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Treasury Employees Union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Office of Management and Budget]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Office of Personnel Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project 2025]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rep. Andy Ogles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean Cairncross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Security Administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starlink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Treasury Department]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Agency for International Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Foreign Corrupt Practices Act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Valery Martynov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volodymyr Zelensky]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One month into his second term, President Trump's actions to shrink the government through mass layoffs, firings and withholding funds allocated by Congress have thrown federal cybersecurity and consumer protection programs into disarray. At the same time, agencies are battling an ongoing effort by the world's richest man to wrest control over their networks and data.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One month into his second term, President Trump&#8217;s actions to shrink the government through mass layoffs, firings and withholding funds allocated by Congress have thrown federal cybersecurity and consumer protection programs into disarray. At the same time, agencies are battling an ongoing effort by the world&#8217;s richest man to wrest control over their networks and data.</p>
<div id="attachment_70185" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70185" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70185" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/whitehousenight.png" alt="" width="750" height="495" /><p id="caption-attachment-70185" class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock. Greg Meland.</p></div>
<p>The Trump administration has fired at least 130 employees at the federal government&#8217;s foremost cybersecurity body &#8212; the <strong>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</strong> (CISA). Those dismissals <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/02/07/trump-guts-cyber-workers-00203087" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reportedly</a> included CISA staff dedicated to securing U.S. elections, and fighting misinformation and foreign influence operations.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, technologists with Elon Musk&#8217;s <strong>Department of Government Efficiency</strong> (DOGE) <a href="https://www.nextgov.com/cybersecurity/2025/02/doge-employee-edward-coristine-lands-cisa-dhs-email/403126/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arrived at CISA</a> and gained access to the agency&#8217;s email and networked files. Those DOGE staffers include <strong>Edward &#8220;Big Balls&#8221; Coristine</strong>, a <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/teen-on-musks-doge-team-graduated-from-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">19-year-old former denizen of the &#8220;Com,&#8221;</a> an archipelago of Discord and Telegram chat channels that function as a kind of distributed <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/09/the-dark-nexus-between-harm-groups-and-the-com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cybercriminal social network</a>.</p>
<p>The investigative journalist <strong>Jacob Silverman</strong> <a href="https://www.jacobsilverman.com/p/prominent-doge-staffer-is-grandson" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that Coristine is the grandson of <strong>Valery Martynov</strong>, a KGB double agent who spied for the United States. Silverman recounted how Martynov&#8217;s wife <strong>Natalya Martynova</strong> moved to the United States with her two children after her husband&#8217;s death.</p>
<p>&#8220;Her son became a Virginia police officer who sometimes posts comments on blogs about his historically famous father,&#8221; Silverman wrote. &#8220;Her daughter became a financial professional who married Charles Coristine, the proprietor of LesserEvil, a snack company. Among their children is a 19-year-old young man named Edward Coristine, who currently wields an unknown amount of power and authority over the inner-workings of our federal government.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another member of DOGE is <strong>Christopher Stanley</strong>, formerly senior director for security engineering at X and principal security engineer at Musk&#8217;s <strong>SpaceX</strong>. Stanley, 33, had a brush with celebrity on Twitter in 2015 when he leaked the user database for the DDoS-for-hire service <strong>LizardStresser</strong>, and soon faced threats of physical violence against his family.</p>
<p>My <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2015/01/another-lizard-arrested-lizard-lair-hacked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2015 story on that leak</a> did not name Stanley, but he exposed himself as the source by posting a video about it on his Youtube channel. A review of domain names registered by Stanley shows he went by the nickname &#8220;enKrypt,&#8221; and was the former owner of a pirated software and hacking forum called <strong>error33[.]net</strong>, as well as <strong>theC0re</strong>, a video game cheating community.</p>
<h2>&#8220;A NATIONAL CYBERATTACK&#8221;</h2>
<p>DOGE has been steadily gaining sensitive network access to federal agencies that hold a staggering amount of personal and financial information on Americans, including the <strong>Social Security Administration </strong>(SSA), the <strong>Department of Homeland Security</strong>, the <strong>Office of Personnel Management</strong> (OPM), and the <strong>Treasury Department</strong>.</p>
<p>Most recently, DOGE has sought broad access to systems at the <strong>Internal Revenue Service</strong> that contain the personal tax information on millions of Americans, including how much individuals earn and owe, property information, and even details related to child custody agreements. The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/21/us/politics/irs-doge-gavin-kliger.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported Friday</a> that the IRS had reached an agreement whereby a single DOGE employee &#8212; 25-year-old <strong>Gavin Kliger </strong>&#8212; will be allowed to see only anonymized taxpayer information.</p>
<p>The rapidity with which DOGE has rifled through one federal database after another in the name of unearthing &#8220;massive fraud&#8221; by government agencies has alarmed many security experts, who warned that DOGE&#8217;s actions bypassed essential safeguards and security measures.</p>
<p>&#8220;The most alarming aspect isn’t just the access being granted,&#8221; <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2025/02/doge-as-a-national.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> <strong>Bruce Schneier</strong> and <strong>Davi Ottenheimer</strong>, referring to DOGE as a national cyberattack. &#8220;It&#8217;s the systematic dismantling of security measures that would detect and prevent misuse—including standard incident response protocols, auditing, and change-tracking mechanisms—by removing the career officials in charge of those security measures and replacing them with inexperienced operators.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Jacob Williams</strong> is a former hacker with the <strong>U.S. National Security Agency</strong> who now works as managing director of the cybersecurity firm <strong>Hunter Labs</strong>. Williams kicked a virtual hornet&#8217;s nest last week when he posted on LinkedIn that the network incursions by DOGE were &#8220;a bigger threat to U.S. federal government information systems than China.&#8221;</p>
<p>Williams said while he doesn&#8217;t believe anyone at DOGE would intentionally harm the integrity and availability of these systems, it&#8217;s widely reported (and not denied) that DOGE introduced code changes into multiple federal IT systems. These code changes, he maintained, are not following the normal process for vetting and review given to federal government IT systems.</p>
<p>&#8220;For those thinking &#8216;I&#8217;m glad they aren’t following the normal federal government IT processes, those are too burdensome&#8217; I get where you’re coming from,&#8221; Williams <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/red-tape-security-controls-jacob-williams-adwqe/?trackingId=l8be8vjAEQRKTRSklk%2BZrA%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>. &#8220;But another name for &#8216;red tape&#8217; are &#8216;controls.&#8217; If you&#8217;re comfortable bypassing controls for the advancement of your agenda, I have questions – mostly about whether you do this in your day job too. Please tag your employer letting them know your position when you comment that controls aren’t important (doubly so if you work in cybersecurity). All satire aside, if you&#8217;re comfortable abandoning controls for expediency, I implore you to decide where the line is that you won&#8217;t cross in that regard.&#8221;</p>
<p>The DOGE website&#8217;s &#8220;wall of receipts&#8221; boasts that Musk and his team have saved the federal government more than $55 billion through staff reductions, lease cancellations and terminated contracts. But a team of reporters at <strong>The New York Times</strong> found the math that could back up those checks is marred with accounting errors, incorrect assumptions, outdated data and other mistakes.</p>
<p>For example, DOGE claimed it saved $8 billion in one contract, when the total amount was actually $8 million, The Times found.</p>
<p>&#8220;Some contracts the group claims credit for were double- or triple-counted,&#8221; reads <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/18/upshot/doge-contracts-musk-trump.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a Times story with six bylines</a>. &#8220;Another initially contained an error that inflated the totals by billions of dollars. While the DOGE team has surely cut some number of billions of dollars, its slapdash accounting adds to a pattern of recklessness by the group, which has recently gained access to sensitive government payment systems.&#8221;</p>
<p>So far, the DOGE website does not inspire confidence: We learned last week that the doge.gov administrators somehow left their database wide open, allowing someone to publish messages that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/02/doges-gov-site-lampooned-as-coders-quickly-realize-it-can-be-edited-by-anyone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ridiculed the site&#8217;s insecurity</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_70474" style="width: 762px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70474" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70474" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/doge-experts.png" alt="" width="752" height="478" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/doge-experts.png 1371w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/doge-experts-768x488.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/doge-experts-782x497.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 752px) 100vw, 752px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70474" class="wp-caption-text">A screenshot of the DOGE website after it was defaced with the message: &#8220;These &#8216;experts&#8217; left their database open &#8211; roro&#8221;</p></div>
<h2>APPOINTMENTS</h2>
<p>Trump&#8217;s efforts to grab federal agencies by their data has seen him replace career civil servants who refused to allow DOGE access to agency networks. <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/17/politics/social-security-head-steps-down-doge-access/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CNN reports</a> that <strong>Michelle King</strong>, acting commissioner of the Social Security Administration for more than 30 years, was shown the door after she denied DOGE access to sensitive information.</p>
<p>King was replaced by <strong>Leland Dudek</strong>, formerly a senior advisor in the SSA&#8217;s Office of Program Integrity. This week, Dudek posted a now-deleted message on LinkedIn acknowledging he had been placed on administrative leave for cooperating with DOGE.</p>
<p>&#8220;I confess,&#8221; Dudek wrote. &#8220;I bullied agency executives, shared executive contact information, and circumvented the chain of command to connect DOGE with the people who get stuff done. I confess. I asked where the fat was and is in our contracts so we can make the right tough choices.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70473" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70473" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70473" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/dudek-li.png" alt="" width="750" height="627" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/dudek-li.png 853w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/dudek-li-768x642.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/dudek-li-782x654.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70473" class="wp-caption-text">Dudek&#8217;s message on LinkedIn.</p></div>
<p>According to Wired, the <strong>National Institute of Standards and Technology</strong> (NIST) was also bracing this week for roughly 500 staffers to be fired, which could have serious impacts on NIST’s cybersecurity standards and software vulnerability tracking work.</p>
<p>&#8220;And cuts last week at the US Digital Service included the cybersecurity lead for the central Veterans Affairs portal, VA.gov, potentially leaving VA systems and data more vulnerable without someone in his role,&#8221; Wired&#8217;s Andy Greenberg and Lily Hay Newman <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/1-4-billion-stolen-from-bybit-in-biggest-crypto-theft-ever/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>.</p>
<p>NextGov <a href="https://www.nextgov.com/defense/2025/02/katie-arrington-announces-she-dods-new-ciso/403091/?oref=ng-homepage-river" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that Trump named the Department of Defense&#8217;s new chief information security officer: <strong>Katie Arrington</strong>, a former South Carolina state lawmaker who helped steer Pentagon cybersecurity contracting policy before being put on leave amid accusations that she disclosed classified data from a military intelligence agency.</p>
<p>NextGov notes that the <strong>National Security Agency</strong> suspended her clearance in 2021, although the exact reasons that led to the suspension and her subsequent leave were classified. Arrington argued that the suspension was a politically motivated effort to silence her.</p>
<p>Trump also appointed the former chief operating officer of the <strong>Republican National Committee</strong> as the new head of the Office of National Cyber Director. <strong>Sean Cairncross</strong>, who has no formal experience in technology or security, will be responsible for coordinating national cybersecurity policy, advising the president on cyber threats, and ensuring a unified federal response to emerging cyber-risks, Politico <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/02/11/sean-cairncross-cyber-director-nomination-00203759" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a>.</p>
<p><strong>DarkReading</strong> <a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/president-trump-nominate-former-rnc-official-national-cyber-director" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that Cairncross would share responsibility for advising the president on cyber matters, along with the director of cyber at the White House National Security Council (NSC) — a group that advises the president on all matters security related, and not just cyber.</p>
<h2>CONSUMER PROTECTION?</h2>
<p>The president also ordered staffers at the <strong>Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</strong> (CFPB) to stop most work. Created by Congress in 2011 to be a clearinghouse of consumer complaints, the CFPB has sued some of the nation&#8217;s largest financial institutions for violating consumer protection laws.</p>
<p>The CFPB says its actions have put nearly $18 billion back in Americans&#8217; pockets in the form of monetary compensation or canceled debts, and imposed $4 billion in civil money penalties against violators. The CFPB&#8217;s homepage has featured a &#8220;404: Page not found&#8221; error for weeks now.</p>
<p>Trump has appointed <strong>Russell Vought</strong>, the architect of the conservative policy playbook <strong>Project 2025</strong>, to be the CFPB&#8217;s acting director. Vought has publicly favored abolishing the agency, as has Elon Musk, whose efforts to remake X into a payments platform would otherwise be regulated by the CFPB.</p>
<p>The New York Times recently published a useful graphic showing all of the government staffing changes, including the firing of several top officials, affecting agencies with federal investigations into or regulatory battles with Musk&#8217;s companies. Democrats on the House Judiciary Committee also have released <a href="https://democrats-judiciary.house.gov/uploadedfiles/2025.02.13_fact_sheet_re_musk_investigations.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a comprehensive account (PDF)</a> of Musk&#8217;s various conflicts of interest.</p>
<div id="attachment_70476" style="width: 740px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70476" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70476" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/newyorktimes-musk-conflicts.png" alt="" width="730" height="653" /><p id="caption-attachment-70476" class="wp-caption-text">Image: nytimes.com</p></div>
<p>As the Times notes, Musk and his companies have repeatedly failed to comply with federal reporting protocols aimed at protecting state secrets, and these failures have prompted at least three federal reviews. Those include an inquiry launched last year by the Defense Department&#8217;s Office of Inspector General. Four days after taking office, Trump fired the DoD inspector general along with 17 other inspectors general.</p>
<p>The Trump administration also shifted the enforcement priorities of the <strong>U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission</strong> (SEC) away from prosecuting misconduct in the cryptocurrency sector, reassigning lawyers and <a href="https://www.sec.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2025-42" target="_blank" rel="noopener">renaming the unit</a> to focus more on &#8220;cyber and emerging technologies.&#8221;</p>
<p>Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-securities-regulator-drop-lawsuit-against-coinbase-exchange-says-2025-02-21/#:~:text=Feb%2021%20(Reuters)%20%2D%20Coinbase,platform%20and%20the%20broader%20sector." target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that the former SEC chair <strong>Gary Gensler</strong> made fighting misconduct in a sector he termed the &#8220;wild west&#8221; a priority for the agency, targeting not only cryptocurrency fraudsters but also the large firms that facilitate trading such as <strong>Coinbase</strong>.</p>
<p>On Friday, Coinbase said the SEC planned to withdraw its lawsuit against the crypto exchange. Also on Friday, the cryptocurrency exchange <strong>Bybit</strong> <a href="https://therecord.media/hackers-drained-bybit-crypto-exchange-hack" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced on X</a> that a cybersecurity breach led to the theft of more than $1.4 billion worth of cryptocurrencies &#8212; making it the largest crypto heist ever.<span id="more-70399"></span></p>
<h2>ORGANIZED CRIME AND CORRUPTION</h2>
<p>On Feb. 10, Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/pausing-foreign-corrupt-practices-act-enforcement-to-further-american-economic-and-national-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ordered</a> executive branch agencies to stop enforcing the <strong>U.S. Foreign Corrupt Practices Act</strong>, which froze foreign bribery investigations, and even allows for &#8220;remedial actions&#8221; of past enforcement actions deemed &#8220;inappropriate.&#8221;</p>
<p>Trump&#8217;s action also disbanded the <strong>Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative</strong> and <strong>KleptoCapture Task Force</strong> &#8212; units which proved their value in corruption cases and in seizing the assets of sanctioned Russian oligarchs &#8212; and diverted resources away from investigating white-collar crime.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s according to the independent <strong>Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project</strong> (OCCRP), an investigative journalism outlet that until very recently was funded in part by the <strong>U.S. Agency for International Development</strong> (USAID).</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.occrp.org/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OCCRP</a> lost nearly a third of its funding and was forced to lay off 43 reporters and staff after Trump moved to shutter USAID and freeze its spending. NBC News <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/usaid-reduce-foreign-service-officers-trump-cuts-federal-government-rcna191122" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> the Trump administration plans to gut the agency and leave fewer than 300 staffers on the job out of the current 8,000 direct hires and contractors.</p>
<p>The <strong>Global Investigative Journalism Network</strong> <a href="https://gijn.org/stories/usaid-crisis-funding-future-independent-media/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> this week that the sudden hold on USAID foreign assistance funding has frozen an estimated $268 million in agreed grants for independent media and the free flow of information in more than 30 countries &#8212; including several under repressive regimes.</p>
<p>Elon Musk has called USAID &#8220;a criminal organization&#8221; without evidence, and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/doge/elon-musk-boosted-false-usaid-conspiracy-theories-global-aid-rcna190646" target="_blank" rel="noopener">promoted fringe theories</a> on his social media platform X that the agency operated without oversight and was rife with fraud. Just months before the election, USAID&#8217;s Office of Inspector General <a href="https://oig.usaid.gov/node/6814" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> an investigation into USAID&#8217;s oversight of Starlink satellite terminals provided to the government of Ukraine.</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity this week heard from a trusted source that all outgoing email from USAID now carries a notation of &#8220;<a href="https://fam.state.gov/fam/12fam/12fam0540.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sensitive but unclassified</a>,&#8221; a designation that experts say could make it more difficult for journalists and others to obtain USAID email records under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). On Feb. 20, Fedscoop <a href="https://fedscoop.com/usaid-emails-sensitive-but-unclassified-foia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> also hearing the same thing from multiple sources, noting that the added message cannot be seen by senders until after the email is sent.</p>
<h2>FIVE BULLETS</h2>
<p>On Feb. 18, Trump issued <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/ensuring-accountability-for-all-agencies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an executive order</a> declaring that only the U.S. attorney general and the president can provide authoritative interpretations of the law for the executive branch, and that this authority extends to independent agencies operating under the executive branch.</p>
<p>Trump is arguing that Article II, Clause 1 of the Constitution vests this power with the president. However, jurist.org <a href="https://www.jurist.org/news/2025/02/trump-signs-order-declaring-only-president-and-ag-can-interpret-us-law-for-executive-branch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that Article II does not expressly state the president or any other person in the executive branch has the power to interpret laws.</p>
<p>&#8220;The article states that the president is required to &#8216;take care that the laws be faithfully executed,'&#8221; Juris noted. &#8220;Jurisdiction to interpret laws and determine constitutionality belongs to the judicial branch under Article III. The framers of the Constitution designed the separation of duties to prevent any single branch of government from becoming too powerful.&#8221;</p>
<p>The executive order requires all agencies to submit to &#8220;performance standards and management objectives&#8221; to be established by the White House Office of Management and Budget, and to report periodically to the president.</p>
<p>Those performance metrics are already being requested: Employees at multiple federal agencies on Saturday reported receiving an email from the <strong>Office of Personnel Management</strong> ordering them to reply with a set of bullet points justifying their work for the past week.</p>
<p>&#8220;Please reply to this email with approx. 5 bullets of what you accomplished last week and cc your manager,&#8221; the notice read. &#8220;Please do not send any classified information, links, or attachments. Deadline is this Monday at 11:59 p.m. EST.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_70477" style="width: 490px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/agencyusers.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70477" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70477 size-full" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/agencyusers.png" alt="" width="480" height="783" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-70477" class="wp-caption-text">An email sent by the OPM to more than two million federal employees late in the afternoon EST on Saturday, Feb. 22.</p></div>
<p>In a social media post Saturday, Musk said the directive came at the behest of President Trump, and that failure to respond would be taken as a resignation. Meanwhile, Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-02-23/doj-heads-tell-staff-not-to-reply-to-musk-demand-for-job-details" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> the <strong>Department of Justice</strong> has been urging employees to hold off replying out of concern doing so could trigger ethics violations. The <strong>National Treasury Employees Union</strong> also is <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/nteu-advisory.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">advising its employees not to respond</a>.</p>
<p>A legal battle over Trump&#8217;s latest executive order is bound to join <a href="https://www.courtwatch.news/p/lawsuits-related-to-trump-admin-executive-orders" target="_blank" rel="noopener">more than 70 other lawsuits</a> currently underway to halt the administration&#8217;s efforts to massively reduce the size of the federal workforce through layoffs, firings and attrition.</p>
<h2>KING TRUMP?</h2>
<p>On Feb. 15, the president posted on social media, &#8220;He who saves his Country does not violate any Law,&#8221; citing a quote often attributed to the French dictator Napoleon Bonaparte. Four days later, Trump referred to himself as &#8220;the king&#8221; on social media, while the White House nonchalantly posted an illustration of him wearing a crown.</p>
<p>Trump has been <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/02/20/trump-third-term-king-unconstitutional/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">publicly musing about running for an unconstitutional third-term in office</a>, a statement that some of his supporters dismiss as Trump just trying to rile his liberal critics. However, just days after Trump began his second term, <strong>Rep. Andy Ogles</strong> (R-Tenn.) <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/01/23/trump-third-term-amendment-constitution-ogles.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">introduced a bill</a> to amend the Constitution so that Trump &#8212; and any other future president &#8212; can be elected to serve a third term.</p>
<p>This week at the <strong>Conservative Political Action Conference</strong> (CPAC), Rep. Ogles reportedly led a group of Trump supporters calling itself the &#8220;Third Term Project,&#8221; which is trying to gain support for the bill from GOP lawmakers. The event featured images of Trump depicted as Caesar.</p>
<div id="attachment_70475" style="width: 618px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70475" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70475" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thirdtermproject.png" alt="" width="608" height="733" /><p id="caption-attachment-70475" class="wp-caption-text">A banner at the CPAC conference this week in support of The Third Term Project, a group of conservatives trying to gain support for a bill to amend the Constitution and allow Trump to run for a third term.</p></div>
<p>Russia continues to be among the world&#8217;s top exporters of cybercrime, narcotics, money laundering, human trafficking, disinformation, war and death, and yet the Trump administration has suddenly broken with the Western world in normalizing relations with Moscow.</p>
<p>This week President Trump stunned U.S. allies by repeating Kremlin talking points that Ukraine is somehow responsible for Russia&#8217;s invasion, and that <strong>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky</strong> is a &#8220;dictator.&#8221; The president repeated these lies even as his administration is demanding that Zelensky give the United States half of his country&#8217;s mineral wealth in exchange for a promise that Russia will cease its territorial aggression there.</p>
<p>President Trump&#8217;s servility toward <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thisisadictator.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an actual dictator</a> &#8212; <strong>Russian President Vladimir Putin</strong> &#8212; does not bode well for efforts to improve the cybersecurity of U.S. federal IT networks, or the private sector systems on which the government is largely reliant. In addition, this administration&#8217;s baffling moves to alienate, antagonize and sideline our closest allies could make it more difficult for the United States to secure their ongoing cooperation in cybercrime investigations.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also startling how closely DOGE&#8217;s approach so far hews to tactics typically employed by ransomware gangs: A group of 20-somethings with names like &#8220;Big Balls&#8221; shows up on a weekend and gains access to your servers, deletes data, locks out key staff, takes your website down, and prevents you from serving customers.</p>
<p>When the federal executive starts imitating ransomware playbooks against its own agencies while Congress largely gazes on in either bewilderment or amusement, we&#8217;re in four-alarm fire territory. At least in theory, one can negotiate with ransomware purveyors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/trump-2-0-brings-cuts-to-cyber-consumer-protections/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>104</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Phished Data Turns into Apple &#038; Google Wallets</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 18:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[All About Skimmers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Fraud 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andy Chandler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSIS Security Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford Merrill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghost tap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grant Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iMessage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M3AAWG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RCS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SecAlliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ThreatFabric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ZNFC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carding -- the underground business of stealing, selling and swiping stolen payment card data -- has long been the dominion of Russia-based hackers. Happily, the broad deployment of more secure chip-based payment cards in the United States has weakened the carding market. But a flurry of innovation from cybercrime groups in China is breathing new life into the carding industry, by turning phished card data into mobile wallets that can be used online and at main street stores.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Carding &#8212; the underground business of stealing, selling and swiping stolen payment card data &#8212; has long been the dominion of Russia-based hackers. Happily, the broad deployment of more secure chip-based payment cards in the United States has weakened the carding market. But a flurry of innovation from cybercrime groups in China is breathing new life into the carding industry, by turning phished card data into mobile wallets that can be used online and at main street stores.</p>
<div id="attachment_70443" style="width: 490px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70443" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70443" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/tollpassphishing.png" alt="" width="480" height="630" /><p id="caption-attachment-70443" class="wp-caption-text">An image from one Chinese phishing group&#8217;s Telegram channel shows various toll road phish kits available.</p></div>
<p>If you own a mobile phone, the chances are excellent that at some point in the past two years it has received at least one phishing message that spoofs the <strong>U.S. Postal Service</strong> to supposedly collect some outstanding delivery fee, or an SMS that pretends to be a local toll road operator warning of a delinquent toll fee.</p>
<p>These messages are being sent through sophisticated phishing kits sold by several cybercriminals based in mainland China. And they are not traditional SMS phishing or &#8220;<strong>smishing</strong>&#8221; messages, as they bypass the mobile networks entirely. Rather, the missives are sent through the <strong>Apple iMessage</strong> service and through <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rich_Communication_Services" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RCS</a>, the functionally equivalent technology on <strong>Google</strong> phones.</p>
<p>People who enter their payment card data at one of these sites will be told their financial institution needs to verify the small transaction by sending a one-time passcode to the customer&#8217;s mobile device. In reality, that code will be sent by the victim&#8217;s financial institution to verify that the user indeed wishes to link their card information to a mobile wallet.</p>
<p>If the victim then provides that one-time code, the phishers will link the card data to a new mobile wallet from Apple or Google, loading the wallet onto a mobile phone that the scammers control.</p>
<h2>CARDING REINVENTED</h2>
<p><strong>Ford Merrill</strong> works in security research at <a href="https://www.secalliance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SecAlliance</a>, a <a href="https://www.csis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CSIS Security Group</a> company. Merrill has been studying the evolution of several China-based smishing gangs, and found that most of them feature helpful and informative video tutorials in their sales accounts on Telegram. Those videos show the thieves are loading multiple stolen digital wallets on a single mobile device, and then selling those phones in bulk for hundreds of dollars apiece.</p>
<p>&#8220;Who says carding is dead?,&#8221; said Merrill, who presented about his findings at the <a href="https://www.m3aawg.org/upcoming-meetings" target="_blank" rel="noopener">M3AAWG</a> security conference in Lisbon earlier today. &#8220;This is the best mag stripe cloning device ever. This threat actor is saying you need to buy at least 10 phones, and they&#8217;ll air ship them to you.&#8221;</p>
<p>One promotional video shows stacks of milk crates stuffed full of phones for sale. A closer inspection reveals that each phone is affixed with a handwritten notation that typically references the date its mobile wallets were added, the number of wallets on the device, and the initials of the seller.</p>
<div id="attachment_70436" style="width: 759px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70436" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-70436" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png" alt="" width="749" height="567" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones.png 1160w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-768x581.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phishingphones-782x591.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70436" class="wp-caption-text">An image from the Telegram channel for a popular Chinese smishing kit vendor shows 10 mobile phones for sale, each loaded with 4-6 digital wallets from different UK financial institutions.</p></div>
<p>Merrill said one common way criminal groups in China are cashing out with these stolen mobile wallets involves setting up fake e-commerce businesses on <strong>Stripe</strong> or <strong>Zelle</strong> and running transactions through those entities &#8212; often for amounts totaling between $100 and $500.</p>
<p>Merrill said that when these phishing groups first began operating in earnest two years ago, they would wait between 60 to 90 days before selling the phones or using them for fraud. But these days that waiting period is more like just seven to ten days, he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;When they first installed this, the actors were very patient,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Nowadays, they only wait like 10 days before [the wallets] are hit hard and fast.&#8221;<span id="more-70276"></span></p>
<h2>GHOST TAP</h2>
<p>Criminals also can cash out mobile wallets by obtaining real point-of-sale terminals and using tap-to-pay on phone after phone. But they also offer a more cutting-edge mobile fraud technology: Merrill found that at least one of the Chinese phishing groups sells an Android app called &#8220;<strong>ZNFC</strong>&#8221; that can relay a valid NFC transaction to anywhere in the world. The user simply waves their phone at a local payment terminal that accepts Apple or Google pay, and the app relays an NFC transaction over the Internet from a phone in China.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ekqZjPAxB4c?si=hYLqGPIBrNthAg9_" width="750" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>&#8220;The software can work from anywhere in the world,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;These guys provide the software for $500 a month, and it can relay both NFC enabled tap-to-pay as well as any digital wallet. The even have 24-hour support.&#8221;</p>
<p>The rise of so-called &#8220;ghost tap&#8221; mobile software was <a href="https://www.threatfabric.com/blogs/ghost-tap-new-cash-out-tactic-with-nfc-relay" target="_blank" rel="noopener">first documented in November 2024</a> by security experts at <strong>ThreatFabric</strong>. <strong>Andy Chandler</strong>, the company&#8217;s chief commercial officer, said their researchers have since identified a number of criminal groups from different regions of the world latching on to this scheme.</p>
<p>Chandler said those include organized crime gangs in Europe that are using similar mobile wallet and NFC attacks to take money out of ATMs made to work with smartphones.</p>
<p>&#8220;No one is talking about it, but we&#8217;re now seeing ten different methodologies using the same modus operandi, and none of them are doing it the same,&#8221; Chandler said. &#8220;This is much bigger than the banks are prepared to say.&#8221;</p>
<p>A November 2024 story in the Singapore daily <em>The Straits Times</em> <a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/scam-syndicates-sending-foreigners-into-singapore-to-cheat-retailers-like-apple-store-and-best-denki" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> authorities there arrested three foreign men who were recruited in their home countries via social messaging platforms, and given ghost tap apps with which to purchase expensive items from retailers, including mobile phones, jewelry, and gold bars.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since Nov 4, at least 10 victims who had fallen for e-commerce scams have reported unauthorised transactions totaling more than $100,000 on their credit cards for purchases such as electronic products, like iPhones and chargers, and jewelry in Singapore,&#8221; <em>The Straits Times</em> wrote, noting that in another case with a similar modus operandi, the police arrested a Malaysian man and woman on Nov 8.</p>
<div id="attachment_70459" style="width: 863px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70459" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70459" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thestraitstimes.png" alt="" width="853" height="567" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thestraitstimes.png 853w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thestraitstimes-768x510.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/thestraitstimes-782x520.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 853px) 100vw, 853px" /><p id="caption-attachment-70459" class="wp-caption-text">Three individuals charged with using ghost tap software at an electronics store in Singapore. Image: The Straits Times.</p></div>
<h2>ADVANCED PHISHING TECHNIQUES</h2>
<p>According to Merrill, the phishing pages that spoof the USPS and various toll road operators are powered by several innovations designed to maximize the extraction of victim data.</p>
<p>For example, a would-be smishing victim might enter their personal and financial information, but then decide the whole thing is scam before actually submitting the data. In this case, anything typed into the data fields of the phishing page will be captured in real time, regardless of whether the visitor actually clicks the &#8220;submit&#8221; button.</p>
<p>Merrill said people who submit payment card data to these phishing sites often are then told their card can&#8217;t be processed, and urged to use a different card. This technique, he said, sometimes allows the phishers to steal more than one mobile wallet per victim.</p>
<p>Many phishing websites expose victim data by storing the stolen information directly on the phishing domain. But Merrill said these Chinese phishing kits will forward all victim data to a back-end database operated by the phishing kit vendors. That way, even when the smishing sites get taken down for fraud, the stolen data is still safe and secure.</p>
<p>Another important innovation is the use of mass-created Apple and Google user accounts through which these phishers send their spam messages. One of the Chinese phishing groups posted images on their Telegram sales channels showing how these robot Apple and Google accounts are loaded onto Apple and Google phones, and arranged snugly next to each other in an expansive, multi-tiered rack that sits directly in front of the phishing service operator.</p>
<div id="attachment_70435" style="width: 528px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70435" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70435" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phonesashtray.png" alt="" width="518" height="688" /><p id="caption-attachment-70435" class="wp-caption-text">The ashtray says: You&#8217;ve been phishing all night.</p></div>
<p>In other words, the smishing websites are powered by real human operators as long as new messages are being sent. Merrill said the criminals appear to send only a few dozen messages at a time, likely because completing the scam takes manual work by the human operators in China. After all, most one-time codes used for mobile wallet provisioning are generally only good for a few minutes before they expire.</p>
<p>Notably, none of the phishing sites spoofing the toll operators or postal services will load in a regular Web browser; they will only render if they detect that a visitor is coming from a mobile device.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the reasons they want you to be on a mobile device is they want you to be on the same device that is going to receive the one-time code,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;They also want to minimize the chances you will leave. And if they want to get that mobile tokenization and grab your one-time code, they need a live operator.&#8221;</p>
<p>Merrill found the Chinese phishing kits feature another innovation that makes it simple for customers to turn stolen card details into a mobile wallet: They programmatically take the card data supplied by the phishing victim and convert it into a digital image of a real payment card that matches that victim&#8217;s financial institution. That way, attempting to enroll a stolen card into Apple Pay, for example, becomes as easy as scanning the fabricated card image with an iPhone.</p>
<div id="attachment_70439" style="width: 407px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70439" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70439" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/phish-cabelas.png" alt="" width="397" height="488" /><p id="caption-attachment-70439" class="wp-caption-text">An ad from a Chinese SMS phishing group&#8217;s Telegram channel showing how the service converts stolen card data into an image of the stolen card.</p></div>
<p>&#8220;The phone isn&#8217;t smart enough to know whether it&#8217;s a real card or just an image,&#8221; Merrill said. &#8220;So it scans the card into Apple Pay, which says okay we need to verify that you&#8217;re the owner of the card by sending a one-time code.&#8221;</p>
<h2>PROFITS</h2>
<p>How profitable are these mobile phishing kits? The best guess so far comes from data gathered by other security researchers who&#8217;ve been tracking these advanced Chinese phishing vendors.</p>
<p>In August 2023, the security firm Resecurity <a href="https://www.resecurity.com/blog/article/smishing-triad-targeted-usps-and-us-citizens-for-data-theft" target="_blank" rel="noopener">discovered a vulnerability</a> in one popular Chinese phish kit vendor&#8217;s platform that exposed the personal and financial data of phishing victims. Resecurity dubbed the group the <strong>Smishing Triad</strong>, and found the gang had harvested 108,044 payment cards across 31 phishing domains (3,485 cards per domain).</p>
<p>In August 2024, security researcher <strong>Grant Smith</strong> gave <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gLOv67LlIQs&amp;list=PL9fPq3eQfaaB2scbXRczwvjVH0ckX4bwt&amp;index=14" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a presentation</a> at the DEFCON security conference about tracking down the Smishing Triad after scammers spoofing the U.S. Postal Service <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/usps-scam-text-smishing-triad/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">duped his wife</a>. By identifying a different vulnerability in the gang&#8217;s phishing kit, Smith said he was able to see that people entered 438,669 unique credit cards in 1,133 phishing domains (387 cards per domain).</p>
<p>Based on his research, Merrill said it&#8217;s reasonable to expect between $100 and $500 in losses on each card that is turned into a mobile wallet. Merrill said they observed nearly 33,000 unique domains tied to these Chinese smishing groups during the year between the publication of Resecurity&#8217;s research and Smith&#8217;s DEFCON talk.</p>
<p>Using a median number of 1,935 cards per domain and a conservative loss of $250 per card, that comes out to about $15 billion in fraudulent charges over a year.</p>
<p>Merrill was reluctant to say whether he&#8217;d identified additional security vulnerabilities in any of the phishing kits sold by the Chinese groups, noting that the phishers quickly fixed the vulnerabilities that were detailed publicly by Resecurity and Smith.</p>
<h2>FIGHTING BACK</h2>
<p>Adoption of touchless payments took off in the United States after the Coronavirus pandemic emerged, and many financial institutions in the United States were eager to make it simple for customers to link payment cards to mobile wallets. Thus, the authentication requirement for doing so defaulted to sending the customer a one-time code via SMS.</p>
<p>Experts say the continued reliance on one-time codes for onboarding mobile wallets has fostered this new wave of carding. KrebsOnSecurity interviewed a security executive from a large European financial institution who spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not authorized to speak to the press.</p>
<p>That expert said the lag between the phishing of victim card data and its eventual use for fraud has left many financial institutions struggling to correlate the causes of their losses.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s part of why the industry as a whole has been caught by surprise,&#8221; the expert said. &#8220;A lot of people are asking, how this is possible now that we&#8217;ve tokenized a plaintext process. We&#8217;ve never seen the volume of sending and people responding that we&#8217;re seeing with these phishers.&#8221;</p>
<p>To improve the security of digital wallet provisioning, some banks in Europe and Asia require customers to log in to the bank&#8217;s mobile app before they can link a digital wallet to their device.</p>
<p>Addressing the ghost tap threat may require updates to contactless payment terminals, to better identify NFC transactions that are being relayed from another device. But experts say it&#8217;s unrealistic to expect retailers will be eager to replace existing payment terminals before their expected lifespans expire.</p>
<p>And of course Apple and Google have an increased role to play as well, given that their accounts are being created en masse and used to blast out these smishing messages. Both companies could easily tell which of their devices suddenly have 7-10 different mobile wallets added from 7-10 different people around the world. They could also recommend that financial institutions use more secure authentication methods for mobile wallet provisioning.</p>
<p>Neither Apple nor Google responded to requests for comment on this story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/how-phished-data-turns-into-apple-google-wallets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nearly a Year Later, Mozilla is Still Promoting OneRep</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/nearly-a-year-later-mozilla-is-still-promoting-onerep/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/nearly-a-year-later-mozilla-is-still-promoting-onerep/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dimitiri Shelest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozilla Monitor Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuwber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OneRep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radaris]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In mid-March 2024, KrebsOnSecurity revealed that the founder of the personal data removal service Onerep also founded dozens of people-search companies. Shortly after that investigation was published, Mozilla said it would stop bundling Onerep with the Firefox browser and wind down its partnership. But nearly a year later, Mozilla is still promoting it to Firefox users.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In mid-March 2024, KrebsOnSecurity revealed that the founder of the personal data removal service <strong>Onerep</strong> also founded dozens of people-search companies. Shortly after that investigation was published, <strong>Mozilla</strong> said it would stop bundling Onerep with the <strong>Firefox</strong> browser and wind down its partnership with the company. But nearly a year later, Mozilla is still promoting it to Firefox users.</p>
<p>Mozilla offers Onerep to Firefox users on a subscription basis as part of <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/about/legal/terms/subscription-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mozilla Monitor Plus</a>. Launched in 2018 under the name <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firefox_Monitor" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Firefox Monitor</a>, Mozilla Monitor also checks data from the website <a href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Have I Been Pwned?</a> to let users know when their email addresses or password are leaked in data breaches.</p>
<p>The ink on that partnership agreement had barely dried before KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/ceo-of-data-privacy-company-onerep-com-founded-dozens-of-people-search-firms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published a story</a> showing that Onerep’s Belarusian CEO and founder <strong>Dimitiri Shelest</strong> launched dozens of people-search services since 2010, including a still-active data broker called <strong>Nuwber</strong> that sells background reports on people. This seemed to contradict Onerep&#8217;s stated motto, &#8220;We believe that no one should compromise personal online security and get a profit from it.”</p>
<p>Shelest released <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Dimitri-Shelest-Letter-_-Comment-on-Krebs-article-3.20.24-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a lengthy statement</a> (PDF) wherein he acknowledged maintaining an ownership stake in <strong>Nuwber</strong>, a consumer data broker he founded in 2015 — around the same time he started Onerep.</p>
<div id="attachment_66783" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-66783" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-66783" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/onerep-shellest.png" alt="" width="750" height="439" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/onerep-shellest.png 1275w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/onerep-shellest-768x450.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/onerep-shellest-782x458.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /><p id="caption-attachment-66783" class="wp-caption-text">Onerep.com CEO and founder Dimitri Shelest, as pictured on the &#8220;about&#8221; page of onerep.com.</p></div>
<p>Shelest maintained that Nuwber has “zero cross-over or information-sharing with Onerep,” and said any other old domains that may be found and associated with his name are no longer being operated by him.</p>
<p>“I get it,” Shelest wrote. “My affiliation with a people search business may look odd from the outside. In truth, if I hadn’t taken that initial path with a deep dive into how people search sites work, Onerep wouldn’t have the best tech and team in the space. Still, I now appreciate that we did not make this more clear in the past and I’m aiming to do better in the future.”</p>
<p>When asked to comment on the findings, Mozilla said then that although customer data was never at risk, the outside financial interests and activities of Onerep&#8217;s CEO did not align with their values.</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re working now to solidify a transition plan that will provide customers with a seamless experience and will continue to put their interests first,&#8221; Mozilla <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/mozilla-drops-onerep-after-ceo-admits-to-running-people-search-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a>.</p>
<p>In October 2024, Mozilla published a statement saying the search for a different provider was taking longer than anticipated.</p>
<p>&#8220;While we continue to evaluate vendors, finding a technically excellent and values-aligned partner takes time,&#8221; Mozilla <a href="https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/securing-new-partner-monitor-plus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a>. &#8220;While we continue this search, Onerep will remain the backend provider, ensuring that we can maintain uninterrupted services while we continue evaluating new potential partners that align more closely with Mozilla’s values and user expectations. We are conducting thorough diligence to find the right vendor.&#8221;</p>
<p>Asked for an update, Mozilla said the search for a replacement partner continues.</p>
<p>&#8220;The work’s ongoing but we haven’t found the right alternative yet,&#8221; Mozilla said in an emailed statement. &#8220;Our customers’ data remains safe, and since the product provides a lot of value to our subscribers, we’ll continue to offer it during this process.”</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a win-win for Mozilla that they&#8217;ve received accolades for their principled response while continuing to partner with Onerep almost a year later. But if it takes so long to find a suitable replacement, what does that say about the personal data removal industry itself?<span id="more-70392"></span></p>
<p>Onerep appears to be working in partnership with another problematic people-search service: <strong>Radaris</strong>, which has a history of ignoring opt-out requests or failing to honor them. A week before breaking the story about Onerep, KrebsOnSecurity <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/03/a-close-up-look-at-the-consumer-data-broker-radaris/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published research</a> showing the co-founders of Radaris were two native Russian brothers who&#8217;d built a vast network of affiliate marketing programs and consumer data broker services.</p>
<p>Lawyers for the Radaris co-founders threatened to sue KrebsOnSecurity unless that story was retracted in full, claiming the founders were in fact Ukrainian and that our reporting had defamed the brothers by associating them with the actions of Radaris. Instead, we published <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/06/krebsonsecurity-threatened-with-defamation-lawsuit-over-fake-radaris-ceo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a follow-up investigation</a> which showed that not only did the brothers from Russia create Radaris, for many years they issued press releases quoting a fictitious CEO seeking money from investors.</p>
<p>Several readers have shared emails they received from Radaris after attempting to remove their personal data, and those messages show Radaris has been promoting Onerep.</p>
<div id="attachment_70413" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70413" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70413" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email.png" alt="" width="750" height="316" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email.png 1402w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email-768x324.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/onerep-radaris-email-782x330.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-70413" class="wp-caption-text">An email from Radaris promoting Onerep.</p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/nearly-a-year-later-mozilla-is-still-promoting-onerep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Microsoft Patch Tuesday, February 2025 Edition</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/microsoft-patch-tuesday-february-2025-edition/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/microsoft-patch-tuesday-february-2025-edition/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 04:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time to Patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Barnett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adobe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2024-38193]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21377]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21391]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CVE-2025-21418]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Chrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft 365 Copilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft Patch Tuesday February 2025]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rapid7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sans internet storm center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satnam Narang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tenable]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft today issued security updates to fix at least 56 vulnerabilities in its Windows operating systems and supported software, including two zero-day flaws that are being actively exploited.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Microsoft</strong> today issued security updates to fix at least 56 vulnerabilities in its Windows operating systems and supported software, including two zero-day flaws that are being actively exploited.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter  wp-image-56287" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png" alt="" width="749" height="527" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate.png 841w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-768x541.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-782x550.png 782w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/windupate-100x70.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /></p>
<p>All supported Windows operating systems will receive an update this month for a buffer overflow vulnerability that carries the catchy name <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-21418" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21418</a>. This patch should be a priority for enterprises, as Microsoft says it is being exploited, has low attack complexity, and no requirements for user interaction.</p>
<p><strong>Tenable</strong> senior staff research engineer <strong>Satnam Narang</strong> noted that since 2022, there have been nine elevation of privilege vulnerabilities in this same Windows component &#8212; three each year &#8212; including one in 2024 that was exploited in the wild as a zero day (CVE-2024-38193).</p>
<p>&#8220;CVE-2024-38193 was exploited by the North Korean APT group known as Lazarus Group to implant a new version of the FudModule rootkit in order to maintain persistence and stealth on compromised systems,&#8221; Narang said. &#8220;At this time, it is unclear if CVE-2025-21418 was also exploited by Lazarus Group.&#8221;</p>
<p>The other zero-day, <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-21391" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21391</a>, is an elevation of privilege vulnerability in Windows Storage that could be used to delete files on a targeted system. Microsoft&#8217;s advisory on this bug references something called “CWE-59: Improper Link Resolution Before File Access,&#8221; says no user interaction is required, and that the attack complexity is low.</p>
<p><strong>Adam Barnett</strong>, lead software engineer at <strong>Rapid7</strong>, said although the advisory provides scant detail, and even offers some vague reassurance that &#8216;an attacker would only be able to delete targeted files on a system,&#8217; it would be a mistake to assume that the impact of deleting arbitrary files would be limited to data loss or denial of service.</p>
<p>&#8220;As long ago as 2022, ZDI researchers set out how a motivated attacker could parlay arbitrary file deletion into full SYSTEM access using techniques which also involve creative misuse of symbolic links,&#8221;Barnett wrote.<span id="more-70396"></span></p>
<p>One vulnerability patched today that was publicly disclosed earlier is <a href="https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide/vulnerability/CVE-2025-21377" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2025-21377</a>, another weakness that could allow an attacker to elevate their privileges on a vulnerable Windows system. Specifically, this is yet another Windows flaw that can be used to steal NTLMv2 hashes &#8212; essentially allowing an attacker to authenticate as the targeted user without having to log in.</p>
<p>According to Microsoft, minimal user interaction with a malicious file is needed to exploit CVE-2025-21377, including selecting, inspecting or &#8220;performing an action other than opening or executing the file.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This trademark linguistic ducking and weaving may be Microsoft’s way of saying &#8216;if we told you any more, we’d give the game away,'&#8221; Barnett said. &#8220;Accordingly, Microsoft assesses exploitation as more likely.&#8221;</p>
<p>The <a href="https://isc.sans.edu/diary/Microsoft%20February%202025%20Patch%20Tuesday/31674" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SANS Internet Storm Center</a> has a handy list of all the Microsoft patches released today, indexed by severity. Windows enterprise administrators would do well to keep an eye on <a href="http://www.askwoody.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">askwoody.com</a>, which often has the scoop on any patches causing problems.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s getting harder to buy Windows software that isn&#8217;t also bundled with Microsoft&#8217;s flagship Copilot artificial intelligence (AI) feature. Last month Microsoft started bundling Copilot with <strong>Microsoft Office 365</strong>, which Redmond has since rebranded as &#8220;<strong>Microsoft 365 Copilot</strong>.&#8221; Ostensibly to offset the costs of its substantial AI investments, Microsoft also jacked up prices from 22 percent to 30 percent for upcoming license renewals and new subscribers.</p>
<p>Office-watch.com <a href="https://office-watch.com/2025/microsoft-365-classic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that existing Office 365 users who are paying an annual cloud license do have the option of &#8220;Microsoft 365 Classic,&#8221; an AI-free subscription at a lower price, but that many customers are not offered the option until they attempt to cancel their existing Office subscription.</p>
<p>In other security patch news, <strong>Apple</strong> has shipped iOS 18.3.1, which fixes a <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/122174">zero day</a> vulnerability (CVE-2025-24200) that is showing up in attacks.</p>
<p><strong>Adobe</strong> has issued security updates that fix a total of 45 vulnerabilities across <strong>InDesign</strong>, <strong>Commerce</strong>, <strong>Substance 3D</strong> <strong>Stager</strong>, <strong>InCopy</strong>, <strong>Illustrator</strong>, <strong>Substance 3D Designer</strong> and <strong>Photoshop Elements</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Chris Goettl</strong> at <strong>Ivanti</strong> notes that <strong>Google Chrome</strong> is shipping an update today which will trigger updates for Chromium based browsers including <strong>Microsoft Edge</strong>, so be on the lookout for Chrome and Edge updates as we proceed through the week.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/microsoft-patch-tuesday-february-2025-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teen on Musk&#8217;s DOGE Team Graduated from &#8216;The Com&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/teen-on-musks-doge-team-graduated-from-the-com/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/teen-on-musks-doge-team-graduated-from-the-com/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ne'er-Do-Well News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AS400495]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BackConnect Security LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Curtis Gervais]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DiamondCDN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Director of National Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOGE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dstat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edward Coristine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marshal Webb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neuralink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Packetware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Path Networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla Sexy LLC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tucker Preston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wired reported this week that a 19-year-old working for Elon Musk's so-called Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) was given access to sensitive US government systems even though his past association with cybercrime communities should have precluded him from gaining the necessary security clearances to do so. As today's story explores, the DOGE teen is a former denizen of 'The Com,' an archipelago of Discord and Telegram chat channels that function as a kind of distributed cybercriminal social network for facilitating instant collaboration.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Wired</em> reported this week that a 19-year-old working for <strong>Elon Musk</strong>&#8216;s so-called <strong>Department of Government Efficiency</strong> (DOGE) was given access to sensitive US government systems even though his past association with cybercrime communities should have precluded him from gaining the necessary security clearances to do so. As today&#8217;s story explores, the DOGE teen is a former denizen of &#8216;<strong>The Com</strong>,&#8217; an archipelago of Discord and Telegram chat channels that function as a kind of distributed cybercriminal social network for facilitating instant collaboration.</p>
<p>Since President Trump&#8217;s second inauguration, Musk&#8217;s DOGE team has gained access to a truly staggering amount of personal and sensitive data on American citizens, moving quickly to seize control over databases at the <strong>U.S. Treasury</strong>, the <strong>Office of Personnel Management</strong>, the <strong>Department of Education</strong>, and the <strong>Department of Health and Human Resources</strong>, among others.</p>
<p><em>Wired</em> first <a href="https://archive.ph/HCCA4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported on Feb. 2</a> that one of the technologists on Musk&#8217;s crew is a 19-year-old high school graduate named <strong>Edward Coristine</strong>, who reportedly goes by the nickname &#8220;Big Balls&#8221; online. One of the companies Coristine founded, <strong>Tesla.Sexy LLC</strong>, was set up in 2021, when he would have been around 16 years old.</p>
<p>&#8220;Tesla.Sexy LLC controls dozens of web domains, including at least two Russian-registered domains,&#8221; <em>Wired</em> reported. &#8220;One of those domains, which is still active, offers a service called Helfie, which is an AI bot for Discord servers targeting the Russian market. While the operation of a Russian website would not violate US sanctions preventing Americans doing business with Russian companies, it could potentially be a factor in a security clearance review.&#8221;</p>
<p>Mr. Coristine has not responded to requests for comment. In <a href="https://archive.ph/VAD48" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a follow-up story</a> this week, <em>Wired</em> found that someone using a Telegram handle tied to Coristine solicited a DDoS-for-hire service in 2022, and that he worked for a short time at a company that specializes in protecting customers from DDoS attacks.</p>
<div id="attachment_70369" style="width: 647px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70369" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70369" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/coristine.png" alt="" width="637" height="636" /><p id="caption-attachment-70369" class="wp-caption-text">A profile photo from Coristine&#8217;s WhatsApp account.</p></div>
<p>Internet routing records <a href="https://bgp.he.net/net/23.133.104.0/24#_whois" target="_blank" rel="noopener">show</a> that Coristine runs an Internet service provider called <strong>Packetware</strong> (AS400495). Also known as &#8220;<strong>DiamondCDN</strong>,&#8221; Packetware <a href="https://bgp.he.net/net/23.133.104.0/24#_dnsrecords" target="_blank" rel="noopener">currently hosts</a> tesla[.]sexy and diamondcdn[.]com, among other domains.</p>
<p>DiamondCDN was advertised and claimed by someone who used the nickname &#8220;<strong>Rivage</strong>&#8221; on several Com-based Discord channels over the years. A review of chat logs from some of those channels show other members frequently referred to Rivage as &#8220;Edward.&#8221;</p>
<p>From late 2020 to late 2024, Rivage&#8217;s conversations would show up in multiple Com chat servers that are closely monitored by security companies. In November 2022, Rivage could be seen requesting recommendations for a reliable and powerful DDoS-for-hire service.</p>
<p>Rivage made that request in the cybercrime channel &#8220;<strong>Dstat</strong>,&#8221; a core Com hub where users could buy and sell attack services. <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/ddos-site-dstatcc-seized-and-two-suspects-arrested-in-germany/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dstat’s website dstat[.]cc was seized</a> in 2024 as part of “Operation PowerOFF,” an international law enforcement action against DDoS services.</p>
<p>Coristine&#8217;s LinkedIn profile said that in 2022 he worked at an anti-DDoS company called <strong>Path Networks</strong>, which <em>Wired</em> generously described as a &#8220;network monitoring firm known for hiring reformed blackhat hackers.&#8221; <em>Wired</em> wrote:</p>
<p>&#8220;At Path Network, Coristine worked as a systems engineer from April to June of 2022, according to his now-deleted LinkedIn résumé. Path has at times listed as employees <strong>Eric Taylor</strong>, also known as Cosmo the God, a well-known former cybercriminal and member of the hacker group UGNazis, as well as Matthew Flannery, an Australian convicted hacker whom police allege was a member of the hacker group LulzSec. It’s unclear whether Coristine worked at Path concurrently with those hackers, and WIRED found no evidence that either Coristine or other Path employees engaged in illegal activity while at the company.&#8221;</p>
<p>The founder of Path is a young man named <strong>Marshal Webb</strong>. I wrote about Webb back in 2016, in a story about a DDoS defense company he co-founded called <strong>BackConnect Security LLC</strong>. On September 20, 2016, KrebsOnSecurity published data showing that the company <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/ddos-mitigation-firm-has-history-of-hijacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">had a history of hijacking Internet address space that belonged to others</a>.</p>
<p>Less than 24 hours after that story ran, KrebsOnSecurity.com was <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/krebsonsecurity-hit-with-record-ddos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hit with the biggest DDoS attack the Internet had ever seen at the time</a>. That sustained attack <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/09/the-democratization-of-censorship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kept this site offline for nearly 4 days</a>.</p>
<p>The other founder of BackConnect Security LLC was <strong>Tucker Preston</strong>, a Georgia man who <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2020/01/ddos-mitigation-firm-founder-admits-to-ddos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pleaded guilty in 2020</a> to paying a DDoS-for-hire service to launch attacks against others.</p>
<p>The aforementioned Path employee Eric Taylor <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/02/men-who-sent-swat-team-heroin-to-my-home-sentenced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pleaded guilty in 2017</a> to charges including <a href="http://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/03/the-world-has-no-room-for-cowards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an attack on our home in 2013</a>. Taylor was among several men involved in making a false report to my local police department about a supposed hostage situation at our residence in Virginia. In response, a heavily-armed police force surrounded my home and put me in handcuffs at gunpoint before the police realized it was all a dangerous hoax known as &#8220;swatting.&#8221;</p>
<p>CosmoTheGod rocketed to Internet infamy in 2013 when he and a number of other hackers <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2013/03/credit-reports-sold-for-cheap-in-the-underweb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">set up the Web site exposed[dot]su</a>, which “doxed” dozens of public officials and celebrities by publishing the address, Social Security numbers and other personal information on the former First Lady Michelle Obama, the then-director of the FBI and the U.S. attorney general, among others. The group also swatted many of the people they doxed.</p>
<p><em>Wired</em> noted that Coristine only worked at Path for a few months in 2022, but the story didn&#8217;t mention why his tenure was so short. A screenshot shared on the website <a href="https://www.pathtruths.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pathtruths.com</a> includes a snippet of conversations in June 2022 between Path employees discussing Coristine&#8217;s firing.</p>
<p>According to that record, Path founder Marshal Webb dismissed Coristine for leaking internal documents to a competitor. Not long after Coristine&#8217;s termination, someone leaked an abundance of internal Path documents and conversations. Among other things, those chats revealed that one of Path&#8217;s technicians was a Canadian man named <strong>Curtis Gervais</strong> who was convicted in 2017 of <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2017/09/canadian-man-gets-9-months-detention-for-serial-swattings-bomb-threats/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">perpetrating dozens of swatting attacks and fake bomb threats</a> &#8212; including at least two attempts against our home in 2014.</p>
<div id="attachment_70370" style="width: 595px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70370" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-70370" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/pathchat.png" alt="" width="585" height="808" /><p id="caption-attachment-70370" class="wp-caption-text">A snippet of text from an internal Path chat room, wherein members discuss the reason for Coristine&#8217;s termination: Allegedly, leaking internal company information. Source: Pathtruths.com.</p></div>
<p><span id="more-70358"></span></p>
<p>On May 11, 2024, Rivage posted on a Discord channel for a DDoS protection service that is chiefly marketed to members of The Com. Rivage expressed frustration with his time spent on Com-based communities, suggesting that its profitability had been oversold.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a lot of money to be made in the com,&#8221; Rivage lamented. &#8220;I&#8217;m not buying Heztner [servers] to set up some com VPN.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rivage largely stopped posting messages on Com channels after that. <em>Wired</em> reports that Coristine subsequently spent three months last summer working at <strong>Neuralink</strong>, Elon Musk&#8217;s brain implant startup.</p>
<p>The trouble with all this is that even if someone sincerely intends to exit The Com after years of consorting with cybercriminals, they are often still subject to personal attacks, harassment and hacking long after they have left the scene.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s because a huge part of Com culture involves harassing, swatting and hacking other members of the community. These internecine attacks are often for financial gain, but just as frequently they are perpetrated by cybercrime groups to exact retribution from or assert dominance over rival gangs.</p>
<p>Experts say it is extremely difficult for former members of violent street gangs to gain a security clearance needed to view sensitive or classified information held by the U.S. government. That&#8217;s because ex-gang members are highly susceptible to extortion and coercion from current members of the same gang, and that alone presents an unacceptable security risk for intelligence agencies.</p>
<p>And make no mistake: The Com is the English-language cybercriminal hacking equivalent of a violent street gang. KrebsOnSecurity has published numerous stories detailing how feuds within the community <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2022/09/violence-as-a-service-brickings-firebombings-shootings-for-hire/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">periodically spill over into real-world violence</a>.</p>
<p>When Coristine&#8217;s name surfaced in <em>Wired</em>&#8216;s report this week, members of The Com immediately took notice. In the following segment from a February 5, 2025 chat in a Com-affiliated hosting provider, members criticized Rivage&#8217;s skills, and discussed harassing his family and notifying authorities about incriminating accusations that may or may not be true.</p>
<blockquote><p>2025-02-05 16:29:44 UTC vperked#0 they got this nigga on indiatimes man<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:46 UTC alexaloo#0 Their cropping is worse than AI could have done<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:48 UTC hebeatsme#0 bro who is that<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:53 UTC hebeatsme#0 yalla re talking about<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:56 UTC xewdy#0 edward<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:56 UTC .yarrb#0 rivagew<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:57 UTC vperked#0 Rivarge<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:57 UTC xewdy#0 diamondcdm<br />
2025-02-05 16:29:59 UTC vperked#0 i cant spell it<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:00 UTC hebeatsme#0 rivage<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:08 UTC .yarrb#0 yes<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:14 UTC hebeatsme#0 i have him added<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:20 UTC hebeatsme#0 hes on discord still<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:47 UTC .yarrb#0 hes focused on stroking zaddy elon<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:47 UTC vperked#0 https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Coristine<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:50 UTC vperked#0 no fucking way<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:53 UTC vperked#0 they even made a wiki for him<br />
2025-02-05 16:30:55 UTC vperked#0 LOOOL<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:05 UTC hebeatsme#0 no way<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:08 UTC hebeatsme#0 hes not a good dev either<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:14 UTC hebeatsme#0 like????<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:22 UTC hebeatsme#0 has to be fake<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:24 UTC xewdy#0 and theyre saying ts<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:29 UTC xewdy#0 like ok bro<br />
2025-02-05 16:31:51 UTC .yarrb#0 now i wanna know what all the other devs are like&#8230;<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:00 UTC vperked#0 &#8220;`Coristine used the moniker &#8220;bigballs&#8221; on LinkedIn and @Edwardbigballer on Twitter, according to The Daily Dot.[&#8220;`<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:05 UTC vperked#0 LOL<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:06 UTC hebeatsme#0 lmfaooo<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:07 UTC vperked#0 bro<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:10 UTC hebeatsme#0 bro<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:17 UTC hebeatsme#0 has to be fake right<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:22 UTC .yarrb#0 does it mention Rivage?<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:23 UTC xewdy#0 He previously worked for NeuraLink, a brain computer interface company led by Elon Musk<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:26 UTC xewdy#0 bro what<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:27 UTC alexaloo#0 I think your current occupation gives you a good insight of what probably goes on<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:29 UTC hebeatsme#0 bullshit man<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:33 UTC xewdy#0 this nigga got hella secrets<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:37 UTC hebeatsme#0 rivage couldnt print hello world<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:42 UTC hebeatsme#0 if his life was on the line<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:50 UTC xewdy#0 nigga worked for neuralink<br />
2025-02-05 16:32:54 UTC hebeatsme#0 bullshit<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:06 UTC Nashville Dispatch ##0000 ||@PD Ping||<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:07 UTC hebeatsme#0 must have killed all those test pigs with some bugs<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:24 UTC hebeatsme#0 ur telling me the rivage who failed to start a company<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:28 UTC hebeatsme#0 https://cdn.camp<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:32 UTC hebeatsme#0 who didnt pay for servers<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:34 UTC hebeatsme#0 ?<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:42 UTC hebeatsme#0 was too cheap<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:44 UTC vperked#0 yes<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:50 UTC hebeatsme#0 like??<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:53 UTC hebeatsme#0 it aint adding up<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:56 UTC alexaloo#0 He just needed to find his calling idiot.<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:58 UTC alexaloo#0 He found it.<br />
2025-02-05 16:33:59 UTC hebeatsme#0 bro<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:01 UTC alexaloo#0 Cope in a river dude<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:04 UTC hebeatsme#0 he cant make good money right<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:08 UTC hebeatsme#0 doge is about efficiency<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:11 UTC hebeatsme#0 he should make $1/he<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:15 UTC hebeatsme#0 $1/hr<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:25 UTC hebeatsme#0 and be whipped for better code<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:26 UTC vperked#0 prolly makes more than us<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:35 UTC vperked#0 with his dad too<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:52 UTC hebeatsme#0 time to report him for fraud<br />
2025-02-05 16:34:54 UTC hebeatsme#0 to donald trump<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:04 UTC hebeatsme#0 rivage participated in sim swap hacks in 2018<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:08 UTC hebeatsme#0 put that on his wiki<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:10 UTC hebeatsme#0 thanks<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:15 UTC hebeatsme#0 and in 2021<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:17 UTC hebeatsme#0 thanks<br />
2025-02-05 16:35:19 UTC chainofcommand#0 i dont think they&#8217;ll care tbh</p></blockquote>
<p>Given the speed with which Musk&#8217;s DOGE team was allowed access to such critical government databases, it strains credulity that Coristine could have been properly cleared beforehand. After all, he&#8217;d recently been dismissed from a job <em>for allegedly leaking internal company information to outsiders</em>.</p>
<p>According to the national security adjudication <a href="https://www.dni.gov/files/NCSC/documents/Regulations/SEAD-4-Adjudicative-Guidelines-U.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">guidelines</a> (PDF) released by the <strong>Director of National Intelligence</strong> (DNI), eligibility determinations take into account a person&#8217;s stability, trustworthiness, reliability, discretion, character, honesty, judgment, and ability to protect classified information.</p>
<p>The DNI policy further states that &#8220;eligibility for covered individuals shall be granted only when facts and circumstances indicate that eligibility is clearly consistent with the national security interests of the United States, and any doubt shall be resolved in favor of national security.&#8221;</p>
<p>On Thursday, 25-year-old DOGE staff member <strong>Marko Elez</strong> resigned after being linked to a deleted social media account that advocated racism and eugenics. Elez resigned after <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/doge-staffer-resigns-over-racist-posts-d9f11a93" target="_blank" rel="noopener">asked</a> the White House about his connection to the account.</p>
<p>&#8220;Just for the record, I was racist before it was cool,” the account posted in July. &#8220;You could not pay me to marry outside of my ethnicity,” the account wrote on X in September. &#8220;Normalize Indian hate,&#8221; the account wrote the same month, in reference to a post noting the prevalence of people from India in Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>Elez&#8217;s resignation came a day after the Department of Justice agreed to limit the number of DOGE employees who have access to federal payment systems. The DOJ said access would be limited to two people, Elez and <strong>Tom Krause</strong>, the CEO of a company called Cloud Software Group.</p>
<p>Earlier today, Musk <a href="https://thehill.com/business/5133430-elon-musk-doge-staffer-racist-posts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said he planned to rehire Elez</a> after <strong>President Trump</strong> and <strong>Vice President JD Vance</strong> reportedly endorsed the idea. Speaking at The White House today, Trump said he wasn&#8217;t concerned about the security of personal information and other data accessed by DOGE, adding that he was &#8220;very proud of the job that this group of young people&#8221; are doing.</p>
<p>A White House official <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/staffer-with-elon-musks-doge-amplified-white-supremacists-online-2025-02-07/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">told</a> <em>Reuters</em> on Wednesday that Musk and his engineers have appropriate security clearances and are operating in &#8220;full compliance with federal law, appropriate security clearances, and as employees of the relevant agencies, not as outside advisors or entities.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>NPR</em> <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/02/07/nx-s1-5288988/doge-elon-musk-staff-trump" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> Trump added that his administration&#8217;s cost-cutting efforts would soon turn to the Education Department and the Pentagon, &#8220;where he suggested without evidence that there could be &#8216;trillions&#8217; of dollars in wasted spending within the $6.75 trillion the federal government spent in fiscal year 2024.&#8221;</p>
<p>GOP leaders in the Republican-controlled House and Senate have largely shrugged about Musk&#8217;s ongoing efforts to seize control over federal databases, dismantle agencies mandated by Congress, freeze federal spending on a range of already-appropriated government programs, and threaten workers with layoffs.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, multiple parties have sued to stop DOGE&#8217;s activities. ABC News <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/judge-decide-block-doge-accessing-sensitive-labor-department/story?id=118575362" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> a federal judge was to rule today on whether DOGE should be blocked from accessing Department of Labor records, following a lawsuit alleging Musk&#8217;s team sought to illegally access highly sensitive data, including medical information, from the federal government.</p>
<p>At least 13 state attorneys general say they plan to file a lawsuit to stop DOGE from accessing federal payment systems containing Americans&#8217; sensitive personal information, <a href="https://www.mychamplainvalley.com/news/local-news/vermont-joins-lawsuit-over-doge-access-to-government-payment-system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> <em>The Associated Press</em>.</p>
<p>Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-treasury-temporarily-agrees-limit-doge-access-amid-privacy-lawsuit-2025-02-06/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported Thursday</a> that the U.S. Treasury Department had agreed not to give Musk&#8217;s team access to its payment systems while a judge is hearing arguments in a lawsuit by employee unions and retirees alleging Musk illegally searched those records.</p>
<p><em>Ars Technica</em> <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/02/lawsuit-tries-to-block-doges-access-to-student-loan-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that The Department of Education (DoE) was sued Friday by a California student association demanding an &#8220;immediate stop&#8221; to DOGE&#8217;s &#8220;unlawfully&#8221; digging through student loan data to potentially dismantle the DoE.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/teen-on-musks-doge-team-graduated-from-the-com/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>170</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experts Flag Security, Privacy Risks in DeepSeek AI App</title>
		<link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/experts-flag-security-privacy-risks-in-deepseek-ai-app/</link>
					<comments>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/experts-flag-security-privacy-risks-in-deepseek-ai-app/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[BrianKrebs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 21:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Little Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest Warnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Coming Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Hoog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app transport security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ByteDance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepseek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deepseek AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NowSecure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volcengine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://krebsonsecurity.com/?p=70323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New mobile apps from the Chinese artificial intelligence (AI) company DeepSeek have remained among the top three "free" downloads for Apple and Google devices since their debut on Jan. 25, 2025. But experts caution that many of DeepSeek's design choices -- such as using hard-coded encryption keys, and sending unencrypted user and device data to Chinese companies -- introduce a number of glaring security and privacy risks.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New mobile apps from the Chinese artificial intelligence (AI) company <strong>DeepSeek</strong> have remained among the top three &#8220;free&#8221; downloads for Apple and Google devices since their debut on Jan. 25, 2025. But experts caution that many of DeepSeek&#8217;s design choices &#8212; such as using hard-coded encryption keys, and sending unencrypted user and device data to Chinese companies &#8212; introduce a number of glaring security and privacy risks.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-70327" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek.png" alt="" width="747" height="417" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek.png 854w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-768x428.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-782x436.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 747px) 100vw, 747px" /></p>
<p>Public interest in the DeepSeek AI chat apps swelled following widespread <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/27/business/us-stock-market-deepseek-ai-sp500-nvidia.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">media</a> reports that the upstart Chinese AI firm had managed to match the abilities of cutting-edge chatbots while using a fraction of the specialized computer chips that leading AI companies rely on. As of this writing, DeepSeek is the third most-downloaded &#8220;free&#8221; app on the Apple store, and #1 on Google Play.</p>
<p>DeepSeek&#8217;s rapid rise caught the attention of the mobile security firm <strong>NowSecure</strong>, a Chicago-based company that helps clients screen mobile apps for security and privacy threats. In <a href="https://www.nowsecure.com/blog/2025/02/06/nowsecure-uncovers-multiple-security-and-privacy-flaws-in-deepseek-ios-mobile-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a teardown</a> of the DeepSeek app published today, NowSecure urged organizations to remove the DeepSeek iOS mobile app from their environments, citing security concerns.</p>
<p>NowSecure founder <strong>Andrew Hoog</strong> said they haven&#8217;t yet concluded an in-depth analysis of the DeepSeek app for <strong>Android</strong> devices, but that there is little reason to believe its basic design would be functionally much different.</p>
<p>Hoog told KrebsOnSecurity there were a number of qualities about the DeepSeek iOS app that suggest the presence of deep-seated security and privacy risks. For starters, he said, the app collects an awful lot of data about the user&#8217;s device.</p>
<p>&#8220;They are doing some very interesting things that are on the edge of advanced device fingerprinting,&#8221; Hoog said, noting that one property of the app tracks the device&#8217;s name &#8212; which for many iOS devices defaults to the customer&#8217;s name followed by the type of iOS device.</p>
<p>The device information shared, combined with the user&#8217;s Internet address and <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/10/the-global-surveillance-free-for-all-in-mobile-ad-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">data gathered from mobile advertising companies</a>, could be used to deanonymize users of the DeepSeek iOS app, NowSecure warned. The report notes that DeepSeek communicates with <strong>Volcengine</strong>, a cloud platform developed by <strong>ByteDance</strong> (the makers of <strong>TikTok</strong>), although NowSecure said it wasn&#8217;t clear if the data is just leveraging ByteDance&#8217;s digital transformation cloud service or if the declared information share extends further between the two companies.</p>
<div id="attachment_70342" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-70342" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-70342" src="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic.png" alt="" width="750" height="327" srcset="https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic.png 1634w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic-768x335.png 768w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic-1536x669.png 1536w, https://krebsonsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/deepseek-graphic-782x341.png 782w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-70342" class="wp-caption-text">Image: NowSecure.</p></div>
<p>Perhaps more concerning, NowSecure said the iOS app transmits device information &#8220;in the clear,&#8221; without any encryption to encapsulate the data. This means the data being handled by the app could be intercepted, read, and even modified by anyone who has access to any of the networks that carry the app&#8217;s traffic.</p>
<p>&#8220;The DeepSeek iOS app globally disables App Transport Security (ATS) which is an iOS platform level protection that prevents sensitive data from being sent over unencrypted channels,&#8221; the report observed. &#8220;Since this protection is disabled, the app can (and does) send unencrypted data over the internet.&#8221;<span id="more-70323"></span></p>
<p>Hoog said the app does selectively encrypt portions of the responses coming from DeepSeek servers. But they also found it uses an insecure and now deprecated encryption algorithm called 3DES (aka <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triple_DES" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Triple DES</a>), and that the developers had hard-coded the encryption key. That means the cryptographic key needed to decipher those data fields can be extracted from the app itself.</p>
<p>There were other, less alarming security and privacy issues highlighted in the report, but Hoog said he&#8217;s confident there are additional, unseen security concerns lurking within the app&#8217;s code.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we see people exhibit really simplistic coding errors, as you dig deeper there are usually a lot more issues,&#8221; Hoog said. &#8220;There is virtually no priority around security or privacy. Whether cultural, or mandated by China, or a witting choice, taken together they point to significant lapse in security and privacy controls, and that puts companies at risk.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apparently, plenty of others share this view. <em>Axios</em> <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/01/30/house-congress-bans-deepseek-ai" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> on January 30 that U.S. congressional offices are being warned not to use the app.</p>
<p>&#8220;[T]hreat actors are already exploiting DeepSeek to deliver malicious software and infect devices,&#8221; read the notice from the chief administrative officer for the House of Representatives. &#8220;To mitigate these risks, the House has taken security measures to restrict DeepSeek’s functionality on all House-issued devices.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>TechCrunch</em> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/03/deepseek-the-countries-and-agencies-that-have-banned-the-ai-companys-tech/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reports</a> that Italy and Taiwan have already moved to ban DeepSeek over security concerns. <em>Bloomberg</em> <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-30/pentagon-workers-used-deepseek-s-chatbot-for-days-before-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writes</a> that <strong>The Pentagon</strong> has blocked access to DeepSeek. <em>CNBC</em> <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/01/31/nasa-becomes-latest-federal-agency-to-block-chinas-deepseek.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> <strong>NASA</strong> also banned employees from using the service, as did the <strong>U.S. Navy</strong>.</p>
<p>Beyond security concerns tied to the DeepSeek iOS app, there are indications the Chinese AI company may be playing fast and loose with the data that it collects from and about users. On January 29, researchers at <strong>Wiz</strong> <a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/wiz-research-uncovers-exposed-deepseek-database-leak" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> they discovered a publicly accessible database linked to DeepSeek that exposed &#8220;a significant volume of chat history, backend data and sensitive information, including log streams, API secrets, and operational details.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;More critically, the exposure allowed for full database control and potential privilege escalation within the DeepSeek environment, without any authentication or defense mechanism to the outside world,&#8221; Wiz wrote. [Full disclosure: Wiz is currently an advertiser on this website.]</p>
<p>KrebsOnSecurity sought comment on the report from DeepSeek and from Apple. This story will be updated with any substantive replies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/02/experts-flag-security-privacy-risks-in-deepseek-ai-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 280/280 objects using memcached
Page Caching using memcached (User agent is rejected) 
Database Caching using memcached

Served from: krebsonsecurity.com @ 2025-03-08 17:00:05 by W3 Total Cache
-->