<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>SentinelLabs - We are hunters, reversers, exploit developers, and tinkerers shedding light on the world of malware, exploits, APTs, and cybercrime across all platforms.</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/</link>
	<description>Next Generation Endpoint Security</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 07:06:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; Follow the Money: Uncovering the Incorporation and the CCP’s Ownership of Chinese Firms Investing in the USA</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-follow-the-money-uncovering-the-incorporation-and-the-ccps-ownership-of-chinese-firms-investing-in-the-usa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=113321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chinese foreign direct investment should trigger American national security concerns, but much of it doesn’t. Elly Rostoum reveals why.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="letter-spacing: 0px;">Chinese foreign direct investment should trigger American national security concerns, but much of it doesn’t. In this ‘behind closed doors’ talk at LABScon 24, Elly Rostoum reveals why and what can be done to improve our understanding of the influence of Chinese FDI.</span></p>
<p>Chinese foreign direct investment (FDI) enabled the technology revolution in China and set China as a strategic competitor to the United States. It opened new global markets, redrew trade routes, tapped into intellectual property, allowed for opportunities in industrial espionage, reshaped supply chains, and allowed for technological breakthroughs in genomics, quantum computing, artificial intelligence, and other critical and emerging technologies that are quite simply re-imagining the world.</p>
<p>But who exactly owns the Chinese firms undertaking this FDI?</p>
<p>The research presented by <a href="https://www.labscon.io/speakers/elly-rostoum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elly Rostoum</a> in this LABScon 2024 keynote address tracks the incorporation structures and ownership of the 672 Chinese firms undertaking FDI globally.</p>
<p>Taking the audience on a journey from how Chinese FDI triggers &#8211; and sometimes fails to trigger &#8211;  American national security concerns to the complex ownership structure of Chinese businesses operating within the U.S., Elly Rostoum reveals how the Chinese government has been able to evade American national security reviews by instrumentalizing investment through 3rd &amp; 4th+ level subsidiaries, private equity, and holding companies.</p>
<p>While much policy and attention has been focused on the investments of Chinese state-owned enterprises, Elly Rostoum argues that the real threat is “within” and buried in the details: seemingly “American” businesses that are ultimately owned by Chinese investment companies.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/glyHKbaS4Fs" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Author</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.ellyrostoum.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elly Rostoum</a> is a former U.S. Intelligence Analyst and National Security Council staffer at the White House. She is the Managing Director of the Alperovitch Institute for Cybersecurity Studies at Johns Hopkins University, where she teaches courses on national security vulnerabilities of critical and emerging technologies, intelligence, public policy, strategic studies, and energy markets; with a regional expertise covering China and the Middle East.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLabs.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/elly-rostoum-ftr.jpg" length="478489" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; The Real AI Race: Disinformation in the Taiwanese Election</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-the-real-ai-race-disinformation-in-the-taiwanese-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[LABScon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=111725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Martin Wendiggensen reveals how disinformation shaped Taiwan’s election, and how AI-powered research uncovered hidden influences on voter behavior. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AI disinformation, deep fakes, armies of lying bots, and automated deception is the biggest threat to our elections, or so we’ve been told. But looking at Taiwan’s 2024 election, none of these nightmare scenarios materialized. The deafening silence of effective AI disinformation from China, America’s most advanced opponent, was surprising. Even more so given the focus on the election at the highest levels of the Chinese government.</p>
<p>In this highly-engaging talk, Martin Wendiggensen details how he set out to study the election and collected tens of thousands of hours of footage from YouTube and television as well as hundreds of thousands of news articles, blog posts, and social media content. This collection was then analyzed with a multi-modal AI pipeline. The results indicated that the small amount of AI-content received no engagement and had no impact.</p>
<p>Instead, Taiwanese billionaires earning most of their money in China mounted a concerted effort to buy or set up local news outlets in Taiwan in the run-up to the election. Conducting a large-scale analysis of these outlets’ output uncovered interesting results. Their viewership, numbering in the millions, presented slanted narratives aligned with the Beijing-friendly KMT and a new emergent third party. While losing the presidential election, these two parties managed to wrest control of Taiwan’s parliament and are set to have a major impact on the country’s foreign and domestic policies.</p>
<p>This presentation guides the audience through Chinese and local disinformation efforts in the Taiwanese election, highlighting the main lessons that can be drawn from them to safeguard future elections. Along the way, Martin explains the research methodology and toolbox that leverages open-source AI to fight disinformation.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d1nlYJW44nc" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Author</h2>
<p>Martin Wendiggensen is a PhD candidate and lecturer at the Alperovitch Institute, focusing on Great Power Competition in Cyberspace, especially competition around AI and state-sponsored information operations. He has conducted research at NATO as well as the University of Mannheim, and applied his knowledge in Artificial Intelligence at his own small startup, which won contracts to monitor electoral environments. Currently, he is conducting research on AI-generated content using Advanced Research Computing at Johns Hopkins SAIS.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLabs.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/martin_w_labscon24_soc.jpg" length="572656" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; The Ransomware Trust Paradox</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[LABScon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=110935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Max Smeets explores how ransomware groups leverage public reporting and why we must disrupt the trust dynamic between threat actors and victims.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In his Keynote talk at LABScon 24, Max Smeets explores how ransomware operators build a unique relationship between themselves and their victims. In contrast to most other threat actors, ransomware operators rely on and leverage public visibility into their activities. Unlike APTs and other threat actors that prize stealth, ransomware gangs seek to publicize their attacks in order to convince future victims that they are trustworthy enough to deliver on their promises &#8211; providing a decryptor and deleting stolen data &#8211; if paid.</p>
<p>In &#8216;The Ransomware Trust Paradox&#8217;, Max observes that this notion of trust is not only a prerequisite for ransomware gangs&#8217; profitability but also relies on media and security vendor reporting. Detailing the mechanisms by which ransomware operators establish trust, build brand awareness, and foster a reputation for reliability, this talk is essential viewing for anyone reporting on crimeware activities.</p>
<p>Max calls for the establishment of a reporting code of ethics for threat intelligence and the media, and a shift in policy to undermine the trust dynamics between threat actors and their victims.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ktlz7Xfp-CE&amp;t=4s" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Author</h2>
<p>Max Smeets is the author of Ransom War: How Cyber Crime Became a Threat to National Security and No Shortcuts: Why States Struggle to Develop a Military Cyber Force. Max is Co-director of <a href="https://virtual-routes.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Virtual Routes</a> and Senior Researcher at ETH Zurich.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world&#8217;s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne&#8217;s research arm, SentinelLabs.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Max_Smeets_ftr.jpg" length="561135" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; Let Them Eat Cake: “Secure by Upgrade” Software is a National Security Threat</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[LABScon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=111195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kymberlee Price reveals the technical chaos facing SMBs as they struggle with solutions aimed at bigger fish in the face of expanding crimeware.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ransomware is doing more to change the security landscape than the last 20 years of Secure Development Lifecycle, DevSecOps, Zero Days, Breaches, or any corporate memo. Pair this with predatory pricing models from software vendors that sell security features as add-on products in premium or enterprise tier licenses, and you’ve got a perfect storm that hits small and medium sized businesses (SMBs) the hardest.</p>
<p>In this hard-hitting talk, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kymberleeprice/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Kymberlee Price</a> reveals the technical chaos facing the US’s largest employment sector: SMBs. With restricted budgets, a lack of expertise, no access to consumer reports by which to clearly compare products, and a SaaS industry that makes basic security features like SSO a premium add-on, many businesses remain easy pickings for threat actors in a rapidly expanding crimeware landscape.</p>
<p>Why should we care about this, is it really a national threat, and what can a bunch of security engineers do about it?</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cmsBUq1vcxc" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Author</h2>
<p>Kymberlee Price is a dynamic engineering leader and public speaker known for developing high-performing multidisciplinary teams responsible for the security and integrity of software products, services, and infrastructure. A recognized expert in the information security industry, she has extensive experience in product security incident response and investigations, coordinated vulnerability disclosure and bug bounties, Secure Development Lifecycle (SDL), and Open Source Security strategy. Kymberlee speaks regularly at conferences around the world and is currently on the content review board for Black Hat USA and LocoMocoSec.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLabs.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Kymberlee-ftr.jpg" length="621118" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Operation Digital Eye &#124; Chinese APT Compromises Critical Digital Infrastructure via Visual Studio Code Tunnels</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/operation-digital-eye-chinese-apt-compromises-critical-digital-infrastructure-via-visual-studio-code-tunnels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleksandar Milenkoski &amp; Luigi Martire (Tinexta Cyber)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 10:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=109526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Threat actors abused Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Azure infrastructure to target large business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">From late June to mid-July 2024, a suspected China-nexus threat actor targeted large business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe, an activity cluster that we dubbed ‘Operation Digital Eye’.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The intrusions could have enabled the adversaries to establish strategic footholds and compromise downstream entities. SentinelLabs and Tinexta Cyber detected and interrupted the activities in their initial phases.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The threat actors used a lateral movement capability indicative of the presence of a shared vendor or digital quartermaster maintaining and provisioning tooling within the Chinese APT ecosystem.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The threat actors abused Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Azure infrastructure for C2 purposes, attempting to evade detection by making malicious activities appear legitimate.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Our visibility suggests that the abuse of Visual Studio Code for C2 purposes had been relatively rare in the wild prior to this campaign. Operation Digital Eye marks the first instance of a suspected Chinese APT group using this technique that we have directly observed.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Tinexta Cyber and SentinelLabs have been tracking threat activities targeting business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe. Based on the malware, infrastructure, techniques used, victimology, and the timing of the activities, we assess that it is highly likely these attacks were conducted by a China-nexus threat actor with cyberespionage motivations.</p>
<p>The relationships between European countries and China are complex, characterized by cooperation, competition, and underlying tensions in areas such as trade, investment, and technology. Suspected China-linked cyberespionage groups <a href="https://cert.europa.eu/static/files/TLP-CLEAR-JointPublication-23-01.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">frequently</a> <a href="https://cert.europa.eu/publications/threat-intelligence/cb24-08/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">target</a> public and private organizations across Europe to gather strategic intelligence, gain competitive advantages, and advance geopolitical, economic, and technological interests.</p>
<p>The attack campaign, which we have dubbed Operation Digital Eye, took place from late June to mid-July 2024, lasting approximately three weeks. The targeted organizations provide solutions for managing data, infrastructure, and cybersecurity for clients across various industries, making them prime targets for cyberespionage actors.</p>
<p>A sustained presence within these organizations would provide the Operation Digital Eye actors with a strategic foothold, creating opportunities for intrusions across the digital supply chain and enabling them to exert control over critical IT processes within the downstream compromised entities. The attacks were detected and disrupted during their initial phases.</p>
<p>The exact group behind Operation Digital Eye remains unclear due to the extensive <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/chinese-entanglement-dll-hijacking-in-the-asian-gambling-sector/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sharing</a> of malware, operational playbooks, and infrastructure management processes within the Chinese threat landscape. The threat actors used a pass-the-hash capability, likely originating from the same source as closed-source custom Mimikatz modifications observed exclusively in suspected Chinese cyberespionage activities, such as <a href="https://www.cybereason.com/blog/research/operation-soft-cell-a-worldwide-campaign-against-telecommunications-providers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Operation Soft Cell</a> and <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/operation-tainted-love-chinese-apts-target-telcos-in-new-attacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Operation Tainted Love</a>. The malware and tooling used in these campaigns have been <a href="https://github.com/yt0ng/cracking_softcell/blob/main/Cracking_SOFTCLL_TLP_WHITE.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">linked </a>to several distinct Chinese APT groups. We collectively refer to these custom Mimikatz modifications as mimCN.</p>
<p>The long-term evolution and versioning of mimCN samples, along with notable features such as instructions left for a separate team of operators, suggest the involvement of a shared vendor or digital quartermaster responsible for the active maintenance and provisioning of tooling. This function within the Chinese APT ecosystem, corroborated by the <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/unmasking-i-soon-the-leak-that-revealed-chinas-cyber-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I-Soon leak</a>, likely plays a key role in facilitating China-nexus cyberespionage operations.</p>
<p>The abuse of <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Visual Studio Code</a> <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/remote/tunnels" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Remote Tunnels</a> for C2 purposes is central to this campaign. Originally designed to enable remote development, this technology provides full endpoint access, including command execution and filesystem manipulation. Additionally, Visual Studio Code tunneling involves executables signed by Microsoft and Microsoft Azure network infrastructure, both of which are often not closely monitored and are typically allowed by application controls and firewall rules. As a result, this technique may be challenging to detect and could evade security defenses. Combined with the full endpoint access it provides, this makes Visual Studio Code tunneling an attractive and powerful capability for threat actors to exploit.</p>
<p>Tinexta Cyber and SentinelLabs have notified Microsoft about the abuse of Visual Studio Code and Azure infrastructure in connection with Operation Digital Eye.</p>
<h2>Infection Vector and Attack Progression</h2>
<p>The attackers used SQL (Structured Query Language) injection as an initial access vector to infiltrate Internet-facing web and database servers. <code>User-Agent</code> request headers in the web traffic logs we retrieved indicate that the attackers used the <a href="https://sqlmap.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sqlmap</a> tool to automate the detection and exploitation of SQL injection vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>To establish an initial foothold and maintain persistent access, the threat actors deployed a PHP-based webshell. Relatively simple in design and implementation, the webshell uses the <a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/function.assert.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">assert</a> function to execute attacker-provided PHP code. Its implementation does not resemble any other webshells we are familiar with. We track this webshell under the name PHPsert.</p>
<p>To disguise the files implementing PHPsert and attempt to evade detection based on filesystem activity, the attackers used custom names tailored to the infiltrated environments, making the filenames appear legitimate. This included using the local language and terms that aligned with the technological context of the targeted organizations.</p>
<p>After establishing an initial foothold, the threat actors conducted reconnaissance using a variety of third-party tools and built-in Windows utilities, such as <a href="https://joeware.net/freetools/tools/getuserinfo/index.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GetUserInfo</a> and <code>ping</code>. They also deployed the <code>local.exe</code> tool, which is part of the Microsoft Windows NT Resource Kit and allows for viewing user group memberships.</p>
<p>To steal credentials, the attackers used the <code>CreateDump</code> tool to <a href="https://lolbas-project.github.io/lolbas/OtherMSBinaries/Createdump/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">extract</a> memory allocated to the Local Security Authority Subsystem Service (LSASS) process and exfiltrate credentials. <code>CreateDump</code> is part of the Microsoft .NET Framework distribution. The threat actors also retrieved credentials from the Security Account Manager (SAM) database, which they extracted from the Windows Registry using the <code>reg save</code> <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/administration/windows-commands/reg-save" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">command</a>.</p>
<p>The threat actors frequently named the files they deployed using the pattern <code>do.*</code>. Examples include <code>do.log</code> (output from <code>ping</code> commands), <code>do.exe</code> (the <code>CreateDump</code> tool), and <code>do.bat</code> (a script that executes and deletes the <code>CreateDump</code> executable).</p>
<p>From the initially compromised endpoints, the attackers moved laterally across the internal network, primarily using RDP (Remote Desktop Protocol) connections and pass-the-hash techniques. For the pass-the-hash attacks, they used a custom modified version of Mimikatz, implemented in an executable named <code>bK2o.exe</code>.</p>
<p>In addition to the PHPsert webshell, the threat actors used two methods for remote command execution: SSH access, enabled by deploying <code>authorized_keys</code> files containing public keys for authentication, and Visual Studio Code Remote Tunnels.</p>
<p>Visual Studio Code Remote Tunnels, based on Microsoft’s <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/developer/dev-tunnels/overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dev tunnel</a> technology, enable developers to access and work on remote systems. This access includes the command terminal and file system, allowing activities such as command execution and file editing. The Operation Digital Eye actors abused this functionality to maintain persistent backdoor access to compromised systems.</p>
<p>In an attempt to evade detection based on filesystem activity, the threat actors used <code>%SystemRoot%\Temp</code> and <code>%ProgramData%\Visual Studio Code</code> as their primary working directories for storing tools and data. <code>%SystemRoot%\Temp</code> is a directory where Windows stores temporary files and is often monitored with less scrutiny. <code>%ProgramData%\Visual Studio Code</code> was intended to appear as a legitimate directory associated with Visual Studio Code.</p>
<p>The intrusions were detected and interrupted before the attackers could proceed to further phases, such as exfiltrating data.</p>
<h2>Abuse of Visual Studio Code</h2>
<p>The threat actors deployed a portable Visual Studio Code executable named <code>code.exe</code>, which is digitally signed by Microsoft, and used the <a href="https://github.com/winsw/winsw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">winsw</a> tool to run it as a Windows service. The <code>winsw</code> configuration file we retrieved indicates that the attackers created a service named <code>Visual Studio Code Service</code>, which executes <code>code.exe</code> with the <code>tunnel</code> command-line parameter at every system startup.</p>
<p>The configuration file reveals a pragmatic approach by the threat actors, who likely modified a <a href="https://github.com/winsw/winsw/blob/v3/samples/complete.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">publicly available</a> <code>winsw</code> configuration. This is suggested by the use of the <code>myapp</code> service identifier and the <code>%BASE%\logs</code> directory for storing <code>winsw</code> log files, both of which appear in the public configuration file as well as in the one we retrieved.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109546" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109546" style="width: 852px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye13.jpg" alt="winsw configuration file" width="852" height="396" class="size-full wp-image-109546" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye13.jpg 852w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye13-300x139.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye13-768x357.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 852px) 100vw, 852px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109546" class="wp-caption-text">winsw configuration file</figcaption></figure>
<p>The <code>tunnel</code> parameter instructs Visual Studio Code to create a dev tunnel and act as a server to which remote users can connect. After <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/developer/dev-tunnels/security" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">authenticating</a> to the tunnel with a Microsoft or GitHub account, remote users can access the endpoint running the Visual Studio Code server, either through the Visual Studio Code desktop application or the browser-based version, <a href="https://vscode.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">vscode.dev</a>.</p>
<p>After creating the dev tunnels, the threat actors authenticated using GitHub accounts and accessed the compromised endpoints through the browser-based version of Visual Studio Code. We have no knowledge of whether the threat actors used self-registered or compromised GitHub accounts to authenticate to the tunnels.</p>
<h2>Network Infrastructure</h2>
<p>The Operation Digital Eye actors used infrastructure located exclusively within Europe, sourced from the provider M247 and the Cloud platform Microsoft Azure. This was likely part of a deliberate strategy. Since the targeted organizations are based and operate within Europe, the attackers may have aimed to minimize suspicion by aligning their infrastructure&#8217;s location with that of their targets. Additionally, Cloud infrastructure commonly used in legitimate IT workflows, such as Microsoft Azure, is often not closely monitored and is frequently allowed through firewall restrictions. By leveraging public Cloud infrastructure for malicious purposes, the attackers made the traffic appear legitimate, which can be challenging to detect and may evade security defenses.</p>
<p>In the initial phases of the attacks, the threat actors used the server with IP address <code>146.70.161[.]78</code> to establish initial access by detecting and exploiting SQL injection vulnerabilities, and the server with IP address <code>185.76.78[.]117</code> to operate the PHPsert webshell. Both IP addresses are allocated to the infrastructure provider M247 and are located in Poland and Italy, respectively.</p>
<p>In the later phases of the attacks, the threat actors used the server with IP address <code>4.232.170[.]137</code> for C2 purposes when remotely accessing compromised endpoints via the SSH protocol. This server is part of Microsoft&#8217;s Azure infrastructure in the <code>Italy North</code> <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/virtual-machines/regions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">datacenter region</a> (<a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=56519" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure IP range</a>: <code>4.232.128[.]0/18</code>, <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/virtual-network/service-tags-overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">service tag</a>: <code>AzureCloud.italynorth</code>). We currently have no information on whether the threat actors used self-registered or compromised Azure credentials to access and manage the Azure resources and services.</p>
<p>The abuse of Visual Studio Code tunneling for C2 purposes also relies on Microsoft Azure infrastructure. Creating and hosting a dev tunnel requires connecting to a Microsoft Azure server with a domain of <code>*.[clusterID].devtunnels.ms</code>, where <code>[clusterID]</code> corresponds to the Azure region of the endpoint running the Visual Studio Code server, <a href="https://global.rel.tunnels.api.visualstudio.com/api/v1/clusters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">such as</a> <code>euw</code> for <code>West Europe</code>. In Operation Digital Eye, the creation of dev tunnels involved establishing connections to the server with the domain <code>[REDACTED].euw.devtunnels[.]ms</code>, which resolved to the IP address <code>20.103.221[.]187</code>. This server is part of Microsoft&#8217;s Azure infrastructure in the <code>West Europe</code> datacenter region (Azure IP range: <code>20.103.0[.]0/16</code>, service tag: <code>AzureCloud.westeurope</code>).</p>
<h2>The PHPsert Webshell</h2>
<p>PHPsert executes attacker-provided PHP code using the <a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/function.assert.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">assert</a> function, which, in PHP versions prior to 8.0.0, interprets and runs parameter strings as PHP code. To hinder static analysis and evade detection, the webshell uses various code obfuscation techniques, including XOR encoding, hexadecimal character representation, string concatenation, and randomized variable names.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109540" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109540" style="width: 664px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye3.jpg" alt="PHPsert implementation" width="664" height="434" class="size-full wp-image-109540" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye3.jpg 664w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye3-300x196.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 664px) 100vw, 664px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109540" class="wp-caption-text">PHPsert implementation</figcaption></figure>
<p>The PHPsert webshell operates as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">PHPsert instantiates a class with a single regular method, which XOR-decodes and concatenates hexadecimal characters to generate the string <code>assert</code>. The class&#8217;s destructor (the magic method <code>__destruct</code>) uses this string to invoke the <code>assert</code> function, passing attacker-provided PHP code as a parameter.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The webshell retrieves the attacker-provided PHP code from an HTTP POST request parameter, for example, <code>momomomo</code>. If the <code>id</code> parameter is present in the request URL, PHPsert decodes the Base64-encoded value of the POST parameter. If the <code>id</code> parameter is absent, the webshell uses the raw value of the parameter.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Finally, when PHPsert finishes executing, the class&#8217;s destructor is invoked, which in turn calls the <code>assert</code> function to execute the attacker-provided PHP code.</li>
</ul>
<p>We identified multiple PHPsert variants, which have been submitted to malware sharing platforms since May 2023, from various locations including Japan, Singapore, Peru, Taiwan, Iran, Korea, and the Philippines. These variants show only minor differences in their implementation, such as varying variable names and POST request parameters like <code>mr6</code>, <code>brute</code>, and <code>qq</code>. Our analysis suggests that PHPsert is deployed not only as a standalone PHP file but is also integrated into various types of web content, including web text editors and content management systems.</p>
<p>One of the PHPsert variants contains commented-out code snippets and comments in simplified Chinese that describe nearby code. These comments and snippets are not present in the PHPsert versions observed in Operation Digital Eye, nor in any of the webshell’s other variants. Below are the code comments, all of which are machine-translated from simplified Chinese:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><code>结果是"assert"</code>, which translates to <code>The result is "assert"</code>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><code>验证 $this->rg 是否安全</code>, which translates to <code>Verify that $this->rg is safe</code>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><code>验证和清理用户输入</code>, which translates to <code>Validating and sanitizing user input</code>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye14.jpg" alt="" width="382" height="196" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-109545" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye14.jpg 382w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye14-300x154.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 382px) 100vw, 382px" /><br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye2.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="119" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-109541" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye2.jpg 580w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye2-300x62.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /><br />
<figure id="attachment_109548" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109548" style="width: 671px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye11.jpg" alt="PHPsert code snippets with comments in Chinese" width="671" height="45" class="size-full wp-image-109548" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye11.jpg 671w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye11-300x20.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 671px) 100vw, 671px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109548" class="wp-caption-text">PHPsert code snippets with comments in Chinese</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>The presence of these comments, along with the indicators of removed code across PHPsert variants, suggests the potential involvement of Chinese-speaking developers who may have been simplifying the webshell&#8217;s execution logic.</p>
<h2>Pass-the-Hash Capability</h2>
<p>The <code>bK2o.exe</code> executable (a custom modified version of Mimikatz used in Operation Digital Eye for pass-the-hash attacks) enables the execution of processes within a user&#8217;s security context by leveraging a compromised NTLM password hash, bypassing the need for the user’s actual password. To achieve this, <code>bK2o.exe</code> overwrites memory of the LSASS process. The tool supports the following command-line parameters:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><code>/c</code>: The process to execute; defaults to <code>cmd.exe</code> if not provided.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><code>/u</code>: The user’s username.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><code>/d</code>: The user’s domain.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><code>/h</code>: The NTLM password hash.</li>
</ul>
<p><code>bK2o.exe</code> implements a pass-the-hash technique by overwriting LSASS memory in a manner similar to Mimikatz, with its implementation partially overlapping with Mimikatz functions such as <code>kuhl_m_sekurlsa_pth_luid</code> and <code>kuhl_m_sekurlsa_msv_enum_cred_callback_pth</code>. In summary, <code>bK2o.exe</code> performs the following:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/api/winbase/nf-winbase-createprocesswithlogonw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Creates</a> a suspended process in a new logon session, specifying the attacker-provided process, username, domain, and an empty password.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Based on the session’s locally unique identifier (LUID), locates and extracts from the LSASS process memory an encrypted credential data blob containing the user’s NTLM hash and the encryption keys required to decrypt the blob.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Decrypts the data blob, overwrites the user’s NTLM hash with the attacker-provided hash, and re-encrypts the data blob.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Resumes the suspended process.</li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_109535" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109535" style="width: 749px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye8.jpg" alt="bK2o.exe creates a new process and retrieves the logon session’s LUID" width="749" height="527" class="size-full wp-image-109535" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye8.jpg 749w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye8-300x211.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 749px) 100vw, 749px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109535" class="wp-caption-text">bK2o.exe creates a new process and retrieves the logon session’s LUID</figcaption></figure>
<p>To navigate LSASS memory, <code>bK2o.exe</code> uses code signatures, represented as byte sequences in hexadecimal format. These sequences correspond to known LSASS instructions, which serve as navigation points within the memory.</p>
<p>To hinder static analysis and evade detection, <code>bK2o.exe</code> obfuscates code signatures and strings by constructing them dynamically on the stack at runtime, instead of storing them as static data.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109542" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109542" style="width: 382px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye17.jpg" alt="bK2o.exe constructs the string lsasrv.dll on the stack" width="382" height="181" class="size-full wp-image-109542" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye17.jpg 382w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye17-300x142.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 382px) 100vw, 382px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109542" class="wp-caption-text">bK2o.exe constructs the string lsasrv.dll on the stack</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_109538" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109538" style="width: 314px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye5.jpg" alt="bK2o.exe constructs the code signature 33 ff 41 89 37 4c 8b f3 [...] on the stack" width="314" height="121" class="size-full wp-image-109538" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye5.jpg 314w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye5-300x116.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109538" class="wp-caption-text">bK2o.exe constructs the code signature 33 ff 41 89 37 4c 8b f3 [&#8230;] on the stack</figcaption></figure>
<h2>From Operation Digital Eye to Tainted Love and Soft Cell</h2>
<p>We identified two additional samples uploaded to malware sharing platforms that construct code signatures on the stack, which we refer to as <code><code>wsx1.exe</code></code> and <code>wsx1.exe</code>. Like <code>bK2o.exe</code>, both <code>wsx.exe</code> and <code>wsx1.exe</code> are custom modified versions of Mimikatz and implement pass-the-hash functionality.</p>
<p>Substantial code segments in <code>wsx.exe</code> and <code>wsx1.exe</code>, which implement the construction of code signatures on the stack, overlap with those in <code>bK2o.exe</code>, including identical <code>mov</code> instruction operand sizes and values. This suggests that <code>wsx.exe</code>, <code>wsx1.exe</code>, and <code>bK2o.exe</code> are highly likely derived from the same source.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_109549" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109549" style="width: 442px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye10.jpg" alt="Code segment in bK2o.exe" width="442" height="542" class="size-full wp-image-109549" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye10.jpg 442w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye10-245x300.jpg 245w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 442px) 100vw, 442px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109549" class="wp-caption-text">Code segment in bK2o.exe</figcaption></figure><br />
<figure id="attachment_109550" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109550" style="width: 473px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye1.jpg" alt="Code segment in wsx1.exe" width="473" height="562" class="size-full wp-image-109550" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye1.jpg 473w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye1-252x300.jpg 252w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 473px) 100vw, 473px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109550" class="wp-caption-text">Code segment in wsx1.exe</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>In turn, we observed overlaps between <code>wsx.exe</code>, <code>wsx1.exe</code>, and mim221 components. mim221 is a versioned and well-maintained credential theft tool, also a custom modified version of Mimikatz, which SentinelLabs observed in <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/operation-tainted-love-chinese-apts-target-telcos-in-new-attacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Operation Tainted Love</a> — a campaign targeting telecommunication providers in the Middle East in 2023.</p>
<p>We attributed Operation Tainted Love to a suspected Chinese cyberespionage group within the nexus of Granite Typhoon (formerly known as Gallium) and APT41, while acknowledging the possibility of tool sharing among Chinese state-sponsored threat actors and the potential involvement of a shared vendor or digital quartermaster. We assess that mim221 represents an evolution of tooling <a href="https://www.cybereason.com/blog/research/deadringer-exposing-chinese-threat-actors-targeting-major-telcos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">associated</a> with <a href="https://www.cybereason.com/blog/research/operation-soft-cell-a-worldwide-campaign-against-telecommunications-providers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Operation Soft Cell</a>, such as <a href="https://www.virustotal.com/gui/file/65ea5f7750f44d98f1077397b906b2611781579a2ae6def44a4de5b41265a9b9/details" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">simplify_32.exe</a>. Operation Soft Cell, which targeted telecommunication providers in 2017 and 2018, has been <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/microsoft-warns-of-gallium-threat-group-attacking-global-telcos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">linked</a> to Granite Typhoon, and possible <a href="https://github.com/yt0ng/cracking_softcell/blob/main/Cracking_SOFTCLL_TLP_WHITE.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">connections</a> between the Soft Cell actors and APT41 have also been suggested.</p>
<p>mim221 has a multi-component architecture, with a single executable staging three components — <code>pc.dll</code>, <code>AddSecurityPackage64.dll</code>, and <code>getHashFlsa64.dll</code> — using techniques such as decryption, injection, and reflective image loading. These components share several overlaps with <code>bK2o.exe</code>, <code>wsx.exe</code>, and <code>wsx1.exe</code>.</p>
<p>To hinder static analysis, some mim221 components also obfuscate strings by constructing them on the stack at runtime. Additionally, the mim221 components <code>AddSecurityPackage64.dll</code> and <code>getHashFlsa64.dll</code> implement error logging similar to that of <code>wsx.exe</code> and <code>wsx1.exe</code>, including identical custom error messages, a consistent output format, and the same English-language errors.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_109534" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109534" style="width: 311px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye9.jpg" alt="Error messages in mim221" width="311" height="110" class="size-full wp-image-109534" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye9.jpg 311w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye9-300x106.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 311px) 100vw, 311px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109534" class="wp-caption-text">Error messages in mim221</figcaption></figure><br />
<figure id="attachment_109544" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109544" style="width: 331px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye15.jpg" alt="Error messages in wsx.exe and wsx1.exe" width="331" height="109" class="size-full wp-image-109544" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye15.jpg 331w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye15-300x99.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 331px) 100vw, 331px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109544" class="wp-caption-text">Error messages in wsx.exe and wsx1.exe</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>In addition, RTTI (Run-Time Type Information) information stored in <code>wsx.exe</code>, <code>wsx1.exe</code>, and the mim221 component <code>getHashFlsa64.dll</code> reveals that classes with the same names are declared across these executables. We have not observed these class names in open-source or publicly available tooling.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109537" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109537" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye6.jpg" alt="Class names (those present in more than one executable are highlighted in bold)" width="1999" height="1621" class="size-full wp-image-109537" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye6.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye6-300x243.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye6-1024x830.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye6-768x623.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye6-1536x1246.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109537" class="wp-caption-text">Class names (those present in more than one executable are highlighted in bold)</figcaption></figure>
<h2>mimCN | A Collection of China-Nexus APT Tools</h2>
<p>Due to the previously discussed overlaps between <code>bK2o.exe</code> (used in Operation Digital Eye), <code>wsx.exe</code>, <code>wsx1.exe</code>, mim221 components (used in Operation Tainted Love), and <code>simplify_32.exe</code> (used in Operation Soft Cell), we collectively refer to this collection of tools as mimCN.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109543" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109543" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye16.jpg" alt="The mimCN samples bK2o.exe, wsx.exe, wsx1.exe, and mim221" width="1999" height="895" class="size-full wp-image-109543" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye16.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye16-300x134.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye16-1024x458.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye16-768x344.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye16-1536x688.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109543" class="wp-caption-text">The mimCN samples bK2o.exe, wsx.exe, wsx1.exe, and mim221</figcaption></figure>
<p>We include in the mimCN tool collection not only the previously mentioned tools but also any other custom modifications of Mimikatz that have overlaps with other mimCN executables, suggesting they may originate from the same source. Such overlaps include shared code-signing certificates and the use of unique custom error messages or obfuscation techniques.</p>
<p>To date, we have observed mimCN tools exclusively in the context of suspected Chinese APT activities. Although the compilation timestamps of the mimCN samples observed in these intrusions could have been manipulated, the proximity of the timestamps to when the activities occurred suggests that they are likely authentic.</p>
<div style="font-size:0.8em">
<div style="overflow-x:auto;">
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 120px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 20.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>Operation</strong></td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>mimCN sample</strong></td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>Compilation timestamp (UTC)</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 20.0%; height: 24px;">Digital Eye</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">bK2o.exe</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">Thu May 30 08:47:56 2024</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 20.0%; height: 24px;">Tainted Love</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">mim221 (pc.exe)</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">Thu Jun 09 08:02:12 2022</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 20.0%; height: 24px;">Tainted Love</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">mim221 (AddSecurityPackage64.dll)</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">Thu Jun 09 08:01:46 2022</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 20.0%; height: 24px;">Tainted Love</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">mim221 (pc.dll)</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">Tue Jun 07 16:55:05 2022</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 20.0%; height: 24px;">Tainted Love</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">mim221 (getHashFlsa64.dll)</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">Fri May 27 20:56:26 2022</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 20.0%; height: 24px;">Soft Cell</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">simplify_32.exe</td>
<td style="width: 40.0%; height: 24px;">Tue Nov 20 03:54:21 2018</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<figure id="attachment_109547" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109547" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye12.jpg" alt="Use of mimCN samples" width="1999" height="668" class="size-full wp-image-109547" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye12.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye12-300x100.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye12-1024x342.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye12-768x257.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye12-1536x513.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109547" class="wp-caption-text">Use of mimCN samples</figcaption></figure>
<p>Further, unique usage instructions found in some mimCN samples, such as <code>[ERROR]Please input command. eg, /cmd:xxx</code>  and <code>[ERROR]Please input ip. eg, /ip:xx.XXX.xx.x or /ip:xxx.com</code>, suggest the involvement of a dedicated development team that is leaving instructions for a separate group of operators. Combined with the presence of overlapping mimCN samples across various intrusions attributed to China-nexus APT groups and distributed over years, this suggests that mimCN is likely the product of an entity responsible for maintaining and provisioning tools to multiple clusters within the Chinese APT ecosystem.</p>
<h2>Attribution Analysis</h2>
<p>We assess that Operation Digital Eye was highly likely conducted by a China-nexus cluster with cyberespionage motivations. The specific group responsible remains unclear due to the extensive sharing of malware, operational playbooks, and infrastructure management processes among Chinese APT clusters. Our assessment is based on a collective consideration of multiple indicators, including the malware, infrastructure, and techniques used, victimology, and the timing of the activities.</p>
<h3>Malware</h3>
<p>A variant of the PHPsert webshell contains code comments in simplified Chinese. This suggests the potential involvement of Chinese-speaking developers. Further, the custom Mimikatz modification <code>bK2o.exe</code> used in Operation Digital Eye is part of the mimCN collection and shares implementation overlaps with other custom Mimikatz modifications, suggesting a common origin. These tools have been observed exclusively in the context of suspected Chinese APT activities, such as <a href="https://www.cybereason.com/blog/research/operation-soft-cell-a-worldwide-campaign-against-telecommunications-providers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Operation Soft Cell</a> and <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/operation-tainted-love-chinese-apts-target-telcos-in-new-attacks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Operation Tainted Love</a>. Malware and tooling used in these operations have been associated with the suspected Chinese APT groups Granite Typhoon and APT41, and <a href="https://github.com/yt0ng/cracking_softcell/blob/main/Cracking_SOFTCLL_TLP_WHITE.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">possible connections</a> to other China-nexus groups, such as APT10 and Lucky Mouse have also been suggested.</p>
<p>The mimCN tool collection suggests the presence of a shared vendor or digital quartermaster responsible for the sustained development and provisioning of tools to groups within the Chinese APT ecosystem. This function is <a href="https://go.recordedfuture.com/hubfs/reports/cta-2023-1107.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">suspected</a> to play a significant role in the Chinese threat landscape. The <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/unmasking-i-soon-the-leak-that-revealed-chinas-cyber-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I-Soon leak</a>, which offers rare insight into China’s cyberespionage activities, provides supporting evidence for the existence of digital quartermasters within this landscape.</p>
<h3>Infrastructure</h3>
<p>While not exclusive to Chinese APT groups, the use of M247 infrastructure, as seen in Operation Digital Eye, has been common among them in recent years. One example is the <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/sandman-apt-china-based-adversaries-embrace-lua/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">M247 infrastructure attributed</a> to the suspected Chinese cluster STORM-0866 (also known as Red Dev 40), with which the <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/sandman-apt-a-mystery-group-targeting-telcos-with-a-luajit-toolkit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sandman APT group</a> is associated.</p>
<p>Additionally, the use of Cloud services and resources located in geographic proximity to the targeted organizations in Operation Digital Eye suggests a carefully planned and targeted infrastructure management approach. In this context, we suspect the potential involvement of third-party entities tasked with administering and provisioning infrastructure, a practice that has become <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/china-nexus-espionage-orb-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">increasingly common</a> in the Chinese APT ecosystem in recent years.</p>
<h3>Abuse of Visual Studio Code</h3>
<p>Our visibility into threat actor activities suggests that the abuse of Visual Studio Code tunneling for C2 purposes was relatively rare in the wild before Operation Digital Eye.</p>
<p>Previous <a href="https://venturebeat.com/security/crowdstrike-2024-report-exposes-north-koreas-covert-workforce-in-u-s-tech-firms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">research</a> indicates that, starting in 2023, a suspected North Korean group has used Visual Studio Remote Tunnels to maintain persistence in compromised networks. Additionally, in October 2024, Cyble released a <a href="https://cyble.com/blog/silent-intrusion-unraveling-the-sophisticated-attack-leveraging-vs-code-for-unauthorized-access/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">report</a> documenting unattributed activity in which threat actors distributed a <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/who-needs-macros-threat-actors-pivot-to-abusing-explorer-and-other-lolbins-via-windows-shortcuts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Windows Shortcut</a> (LNK) file to deploy Visual Studio Code and activate its tunneling feature to establish remote access.</p>
<p>As of this writing, the only publicly disclosed use of this technique around the time of Operation Digital Eye has been attributed to a suspected Chinese APT group. In September 2024, Unit 42 published a <a href="https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/stately-taurus-abuses-vscode-southeast-asian-espionage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">report</a> on a campaign targeting government entities in Southeast Asia, in which threat actors used Visual Studio Code as a backdoor. The campaign was attributed to Stately Taurus (also known as Mustang Panda). The exact timeline of the campaign is unclear, with mid-August 2024 being the only reference point explicitly mentioned in the Unit 42 report. Based on this, we suspect that Operation Digital Eye occurred prior to this activity.</p>
<p>We did not observe any overlaps in TTPs between Operation Digital Eye and the activity reported by Unit 42, except for the abuse of Visual Studio Code. We recognize the possibility that distinct Chinese APT clusters may share operational playbooks that include leveraging Visual Studio Code for C2 purposes.</p>
<h3>Temporal Analysis</h3>
<p>Our analysis of timestamps marking the dates and times of operator activity in the targeted organizations showed that all activities occurred on workdays (Monday to Friday). Additionally, converting the timestamps from their original time zones, Coordinated Universal Time (UTC) and Central European Summer Time (CEST, UTC+2), to China Standard Time (CST, UTC+8) revealed that the operators were primarily active during typical working hours in China, mostly between 9 a.m. and 9 p.m. CST.</p>
<p>This suggests a potentially state-sanctioned operation. The &#8216;996&#8217; work schedule (9 a.m. to 9 p.m. CST, six days a week) has been common in China’s technology sector, but it was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinese-authorities-say-overtime-996-policy-is-illegal-2021-08-27/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ruled illegal</a> by the Supreme People&#8217;s Court in 2021. As a result, state employees are almost certainly restricted to weekday work, typically between 9 a.m. and 9 p.m., aligning closely with our observations from the timestamp analysis.</p>
<p>The figure below shows the total number of connections established by the threat actors to Visual Studio Code tunnels throughout Operation Digital Eye, broken down by hour of the day. The data is presented in both the original time zone (CEST) and in China Standard Time (CST, CEST+6). We observed minimal to no activity between 10 p.m. and 9 a.m. CST, as well as between 11 a.m. and 1 p.m. CST, which aligns with the typical daily working hours in China, including the midday lunch break.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109536" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109536" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye7.jpg" alt="Number of established connections to Visual Studio Code tunnels" width="1999" height="704" class="size-full wp-image-109536" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye7.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye7-300x106.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye7-1024x361.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye7-768x270.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op_Digital_Eye7-1536x541.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109536" class="wp-caption-text">Number of established connections to Visual Studio Code tunnels</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Conclusions</h2>
<p>Operation Digital Eye highlights the persistent threat posed by Chinese cyberespionage groups to European entities, with these threat actors continuing to focus on high-value targets. The campaign underscores the strategic nature of this threat, as breaching organizations that provide data, infrastructure, and cybersecurity solutions to other industries gives the attackers a foothold in the digital supply chain, enabling them to extend their reach to downstream entities.</p>
<p>The abuse of Visual Studio Code Remote Tunnels in this campaign illustrates how Chinese APT groups often rely on practical, solution-oriented approaches to evade detection. By leveraging a trusted development tool and infrastructure, the threat actors aimed to disguise their malicious activities as legitimate. The exploitation of widely used technologies, which security teams may not scrutinize closely, presents a growing challenge for organizations. For defenders, this calls for a reevaluation of traditional security approaches and the implementation of robust detection mechanisms to identify such evasive techniques in real time.</p>
<p>Lateral movement capabilities observed in Operation Digital Eye, linked to custom Mimikatz modifications used in previous campaigns, indicate the potential involvement of shared vendors or digital quartermasters and the important function they serve in the Chinese APT ecosystem. These centralized entities provide continuity and adaptability to cyberespionage operations, equipping threat actors with consistently updated tools and evolving tactics as they target new victims.</p>
<h2>Indicators of Compromise</h2>
<div style="font-size:0.8em">
<b>SHA1 Hashes</b></p>
<div style="overflow-x:auto;">
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 120px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>Value</strong></td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>Note</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">0be9dd709d7d68887a92c793881dd4a010796e95</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">The CreateDump tool (do.exe)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">213f06ed5ac9e688816b4bbe73bf507994949964</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">The GetUserInfo tool</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">289f3bfe297923507cf4c26ca500ae01819c6a95</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">The local.exe tool</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">2e2cf8a4a0e7decceb8e22536b13173479da0d13</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">3035d8846d7a9f309f2d24daba6ac33ad99524fc</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">399776991a094e1ee78b2a915bf4491e67c04ec7</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">3a688c844259822c51ceb3aea508303c4a654eb3</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">4d6947a19dd9a420c22fee39fac8b4df95a47569</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">63cea28d927f8e629377399fa08a9cb4fd0c6238</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">6549e50645bb1c02e4972651d335a75cb6d5aa74</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">7941909fd5c1277c6f7baf21e484c9e59ea454ee</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">mimCN (bK2o.exe)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">7cb7bcb9187f8faf47fd77cf1213ab3fe2350a77</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">mimCN (simplify_32.exe)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">82b1cb9b69d5f05bb20852322fb3c2c00bce9134</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">mimCN (wsx.exe)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">83ca53c95705352ff60149b0b17a686956e23172</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">a9d6d0c47728094feb794ad7e25c253737633140</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">Visual Studio Code (code.exe)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">b2811cb4d0afe13d2722093039a72588c348dcfd</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">c0e03fce8f7f51e91da79f773aa870f0897b0ee2</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">cb6726fb3f7952ede04ed22d2c72389255991827</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">d57fa43944676c56e66f4b20ffa3d82048e354fd</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">PHPsert variant</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">e572380ab95c4ab5a87f701d4654d3386911b387</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">do.bat</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">e8a8d8fa7122c1592a314343b45bac2c213bb57d</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">mimCN (wsx1.exe)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p><b>IP Addresses</b></p>
<div style="overflow-x:auto;">
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 120px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 38.0%;   height: 24px;"><strong>Value</strong></td>
<td style="width: 62.0%;   height: 24px;"><strong>Note</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 38.0%;   height: 24px;">146.70.161[.]78</td>
<td style="width: 62.0%;   height: 24px;">Server used for initial access (SQL injection attack)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 38.0%;   height: 24px;">185.76.78[.]117</td>
<td style="width: 62.0%;   height: 24px;">C2 server (PHPsert webshells)</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 38.0%;   height: 24px;">20.103.221[.]187</td>
<td style="width: 62.0%;   height: 24px;">Visual Studio Code dev tunnel</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 38.0%;   height: 24px;">4.232.170[.]137</td>
<td style="width: 62.0%;   height: 24px;">C2 server (SSH access)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p><b>Domains</b></p>
<div style="overflow-x:auto;">
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 120px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 38.0%;   height: 24px;"><strong>Value</strong></td>
<td style="width: 62.0%;   height: 24px;"><strong>Note</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 38.0%;   height: 24px;">[REDACTED].euw.devtunnels[.]ms</td>
<td style="width: 62.0%;   height: 24px;">Visual Studio Code dev tunnel</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Op-Digital-Eye-ftr.jpg" length="524719" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; PKfail: Supply-Chain Failures in Secure Boot Key Management</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 16:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=110004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Binarly’s Alex Matrosov and Fabio Pagani present PKfail, a firmware supply-chain security issue affecting major device vendors and hundreds of device models.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Modern computing heavily relies on establishing and maintaining trust, which begins with trusted foundations and extends through operating systems and applications in a chain-like manner. This ensures that end users can confidently rely on the integrity of the underlying hardware, firmware, and software.</p>
<p>One of the most prevalent mechanisms for enforcing trust in the UEFI firmware ecosystem is Secure Boot, which ensures that only digitally signed and verified software is executed during the system boot process, safeguarding against attacks on “external” firmware components and boot loaders. A key component of Secure Boot is the Platform Key (PK), the root-of-trust key used for managing the cryptographic material that validates external components and bootloaders before execution.</p>
<p>Given its critical role, one would expect all best practices for cryptographic key management to be meticulously followed, but that has not always been the case. </p>
<p>In this talk, Binarly’s Alex Matrosov and Fabio Pagani unveil PKfail, a firmware supply-chain security issue affecting major device vendors and hundreds of device models. PKfail is the result of shipping default test keys included by IBVs in their reference implementation—a problem known since 2016 but clearly forgotten by the firmware industry.</p>
<p>Given these test keys leaked during various data breaches in the past few years, an attacker can leverage PKfail to completely bypass Secure Boot on affected devices. As Alex and Fabio  demonstrate in the presentation, PKfail makes it extremely straightforward to bootkit affected devices and to launch advanced firmware-level threats, such as BlackLotus.</p>
<p>The speakers also offer a retrospective industry-wide analysis on PKfail, based on their extensive dataset of UEFI firmware images, spanning hundreds of product lines marketed over the past decade.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lTA2r_5kNhU" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Authors</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.labscon.io/speakers/alex-matrosov/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Alex Matrosov</a> is CEO and Founder of <a href="https://www.binarly.io/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Binarly Inc</a>. where he builds an AI-powered platform to protect devices against emerging firmware threats. Alex has over two decades of experience with reverse engineering, advanced malware analysis, firmware security, and exploitation techniques.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.labscon.io/speakers/fabio-pagani/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Fabio Pagani</a> is a Vulnerability Research Lead at Binarly, where he works at the intersection of static and dynamic analysis techniques to help secure the UEFI ecosystem. As part of the Binarly REsearch team, he discovered LogoFAIL and helped affected vendors to identify and mitigate this vulnerability.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLabs.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pkfail-ftr.jpg" length="539312" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; A 30-Year Journey from Compilation Student to Decompilation Pioneer</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Decompilers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Malware Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=109618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dr. Cristina Cifuentes, known as the Mother of Decompilation, reflects on three decades of innovation in reverse engineering in her LABScon 2024 keynote.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 1990, Cristina Cifuentes worked on a machine code interpreter for the Modula-2 programming language as part of her Compilers project. That summer, she integrated it into a mixed GPM Modula-2 compiler/interpreter for the 8086 processor. This gave her hands-on experience with assembly language and the process of converting intermediate representations into executable code, laying the groundwork for her later research.</p>
<p>In 1994, she submitted a PhD thesis entitled <i>Reverse Compilation Techniques</i>. The work involved analyzing 80286 DOS binaries, studying assembly language, mapping groups of instructions into graphs, tracing parameters and data flows, and understanding how compilers optimized code. Her groundbreaking research introduced techniques that, while initially a niche academic endeavor, gained significant traction in the 2000s with the rising focus on application security and need to reverse engineer malware</p>
<p>In this keynote, Dr Cifuentes reflects on her pioneering PhD work, the evolution of decompilation technology over the past three decades, its adoption in commercial applications, and its role in developing tools for malware analysis.</p>
<p>Through this retrospective, she connects the foundational research of her early career with its enduring impact on cybersecurity today.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wo3xEa2elp4" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Author</h2>
<p>Dr Cristina Cifuentes is Vice President of Oracle’s Software Assurance organization. Cristina’s passion for tackling the big issues in the field of Program Analysis began with her doctoral work in binary decompilation at the Queensland University of Technology, which led to her being named the Mother of Decompilation for her contributions to this domain.</p>
<p>Before she joined Oracle and Sun Microsystems, Cristina held academic posts at major Australian Universities, co-edited Going Digital, a landmark book on Cybersecurity, and served on the executive committees of ACM SIGPLAN and IEEE Reverse Engineering.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/labscon24-highlights-examining-the-latest-in-cybersecurity-trends-challenges/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2024</a>, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLabs.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Cristina-ftr.jpg" length="595795" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CyberVolk &#124; A Deep Dive into the Hacktivists, Tools and Ransomware Fueling Pro-Russian Cyber Attacks</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim Walter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 10:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hacktivism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=108943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A loose collective of mostly low-skilled actors, CyberVolk absorbs and adapts a wide array of destructive malware for use against political targets.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">CyberVolk/GLORIAMIST is a hacktivist collective originating in India with pro-Russia leanings. Between June and October 2024, CyberVolk claimed responsibility for multiple ransomware attacks.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The main objective of CyberVolk and related groups is to leverage geopolitical issues to launch and justify attacks on public and government entities, primarily in the service of Russian government interests.</li>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLabs has observed a shared codebase used by CyberVolk, AzzaSec and DoubleFace’s ransomware. Additionally, CyberVolk has promoted other ransomware families like HexaLocker and Parano. These groups and the tools they leverage are all closely intertwined.</li>
<li aria-level="1">These hacktivist groups are extremely dynamic and volatile. In-fighting, threats, and inflated political-posturing are common, leading to fragmentation and the rapid re-shaping of the hacktivist threat landscape.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>CyberVolk is a politically motivated hacktivist collective which launched its own RaaS in June 2024. The group uses both DDoS and ransomware attacks in its efforts to undermine and disrupt the operations of those opposed to Russian interests.</p>
<p>The group has become an increasingly prominent player within the cybercrime ecosystem, adopting and repurposing existing commodity malware to advance its causes. Highly-skilled actors within the collective expand and revise such tools, effectively making them more sophisticated as they move through various hands.</p>
<p>The CyberVolk collective is a prime example of how readily threat actors can access and deploy dangerous ransomware builders such as AzzaSec, Diamond, LockBit, Chaos and others. This adaptability makes the group highly dynamic and increasingly challenging to track.</p>
<p>In this post, we provide an overview of a number of ransomware families within the context of CyberVolk’s operations, breaking down the increasingly blurred lines between tools and group affiliations. Understanding the shifting nature of dynamic hacktivist collectives like CyberVolk can help organizations prepare and fortify their defenses.</p>
<h2>The Origins of CyberVolk Ransomware</h2>
<p>CyberVolk is a <a href="https://threatmon.io/blog/cybervolk-ransomware-technical-malware-analysis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pro-India/pro-Russia</a> “hacktivist” group that has been actively targeting entities in multiple countries. In its current form, it emerged during May 2024. Prior to this, the group was known by a few different names, including GLORIAMIST, GLORIAMIST India and Solntsevskaya Bratva. CyberVolk exploits current geopolitical issues, focused on launching and justifying its attacks on public and government entities.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_1-1.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="302" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-109360" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_1-1.jpg 540w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_1-1-300x168.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></p>
<p>While the group claims alliances with other broad groups such as <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/lapsus-data-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LAPSUS$</a>, <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/hacktivism-and-state-sponsored-knock-offs-attributing-deceptive-hack-and-leak-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anonymous</a>, and the <a href="https://threatmon.io/blog/digital-war-in-the-middle-east-cyber-threats-in-israel-iran-conflict/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Moroccan</a> <a href="https://threatmon.io/blog/digital-war-in-the-middle-east-cyber-threats-in-israel-iran-conflict/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dragons</a>, it has also been associated with <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/noname05716-the-pro-russian-hacktivist-group-targeting-nato/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NONAME057(16)</a> and other RU-friendly, DDoS-focused, groups. However, CyberVolk has also <a href="https://www.rapid7.com/blog/post/2024/10/03/ransomware-groups-demystified-cybervolk-ransomware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">embraced ransomware</a> as a tool to further its cause, with self-branded ransomware payloads as well as alliances with associated ransomware families, namely Doubleface, HexaLocker, and the Parano family.</p>
<p>CyberVolk’s branded ransomware is derived from the AzzaSec (<i>aka</i> AzzaSecurity) ransomware code. <a href="https://threatmon.io/blog/darkwebs-new-favorite-azzasec-ransomware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AzzaSec</a> is a pro-Russia, anti-Israel, and anti-Ukraine hacktivist group that emerged in February of 2024. It has claimed alliances with some of the same groups linked to CyberVolk such as <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/noname05716-the-pro-russian-hacktivist-group-targeting-nato/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NONAME057(16)</a>. Initially conducting DDoS and defacement attacks, the group later expanded into extortion and ransomware.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109345" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109345" style="width: 560px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109345" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_30.jpg" alt="June 2024 Release of AzzaSec Ransomware" width="560" height="571" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_30.jpg 560w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_30-294x300.jpg 294w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_30-50x50.jpg 50w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_30-24x24.jpg 24w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109345" class="wp-caption-text">June 2024 Release of AzzaSec Ransomware</figcaption></figure>
<p>In June, the source-code for “AzzaSec Ransom” was leaked and subsequently adopted and adapted by multiple groups aligned with AzzaSec’s mission. Prior to its disbandment in August of 2024, AzzaSec operated under a ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) model and pushed out multiple iterations of its Windows-centric ransomware.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109308" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109308" style="width: 499px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_42.jpg" alt="AzzaSec “disbandment” announcement, August 2024" width="499" height="731" class="size-full wp-image-109308" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_42.jpg 499w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_42-205x300.jpg 205w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 499px) 100vw, 499px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109308" class="wp-caption-text">AzzaSec “disbandment” announcement, August 2024</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Post-AzzaSec | The Rise of CyberVolk’s RaaS Operations</h2>
<p>The CyberVolk-branded RaaS was announced in late June 2024.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109347" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109347" style="width: 755px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_20.jpg" alt="CyberVolk Ransomware Announcement, June 2024" width="755" height="385" class="size-full wp-image-109347" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_20.jpg 755w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_20-300x153.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 755px) 100vw, 755px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109347" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk Ransomware Announcement, June 2024</figcaption></figure>
<p>The CyberVolk-modified ransomware’s development is credited to<code> @ghostdoor_maldev</code> and is based on the earlier AzzaSec Ransomware code. The Windows-specific payloads are written in C++. Upon execution, the payloads drop bitmap images (files with extension <code>.bmp</code>) into <code>%temp%</code> folder, and display them, prior to any encryption occurring. The ransomware will terminate any running processes belonging to either Microsoft Management Console (MMC) or Task Manager.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109302" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109302" style="width: 568px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_8.jpg" alt="CyberVolk Ransomware MMC processes and Task Manager Termination" width="568" height="206" class="size-full wp-image-109302" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_8.jpg 568w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_8-300x109.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 568px) 100vw, 568px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109302" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk Ransomware MMC processes and Task Manager Termination</figcaption></figure>
<p>Early versions of CyberVolk Ransomware used the AES algorithm for file encryption and the SHA512 algorithm for key generation. This was later updated to “ChaCha20-Poly1305 + AES + RSA + Quantum resistant algorithms” according to posts on the group&#8217;s Telegram.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109326" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109326" style="width: 1661px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_26.jpg" alt="CyberVolk wallpaper with countdown timer" width="1661" height="876" class="size-full wp-image-109326" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_26.jpg 1661w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_26-300x158.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_26-1024x540.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_26-768x405.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_26-1536x810.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1661px) 100vw, 1661px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109326" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk wallpaper with countdown timer</figcaption></figure>
<p>The payment screen used by CyberVolk Ransomware displays the decryption timer along with payment details. CyberVolk ransomware supports BTC and USDT payments. Across all the functional samples we analyzed, the timeout value was set to 5 hours, with the ransom amount set to $1000.00 (equivalent in BTC or USDT). A ransom note named <code>CyberVolk_Readme.txt</code> containing the same contact details presented in the wallpaper and payment screens is also dropped to disk. Telegram contact details are provided as well.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109348" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109348" style="width: 746px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/cybervolk28.jpg" alt="CyberVolk ransom note" width="746" height="224" class="size-full wp-image-109348" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/cybervolk28.jpg 746w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/cybervolk28-300x90.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 746px) 100vw, 746px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109348" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk ransom note</figcaption></figure>
<p>The <code>.CyberVolk</code> extension is added to affected files:</p>
<figure id="attachment_109350" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109350" style="width: 621px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_23.jpg" alt="CyberVolk-encrypted files" width="621" height="430" class="size-full wp-image-109350" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_23.jpg 621w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_23-300x208.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 621px) 100vw, 621px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109350" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk-encrypted files</figcaption></figure>
<p>The decryption timer is controlled via a <code>time.dat</code> file written to <code>%appdata%\Roaming</code> directory. The timeout is set to 5 hours in CyberVolk samples analyzed by SentinelOne. This functionality is mirrored in the Invisible Ransom payloads as well, as they are based on the same codebase (AzzaSec Ransom).</p>
<figure id="attachment_109328" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109328" style="width: 708px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_24.jpg" alt="Decryption timer in CyberVolk" width="708" height="233" class="size-full wp-image-109328" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_24.jpg 708w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_24-300x99.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 708px) 100vw, 708px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109328" class="wp-caption-text">Decryption timer in CyberVolk</figcaption></figure>
<p>The <code>time.dat</code> file stores the defined timeout value in seconds. Default builds of Invisible Ransom (or CyberVolk) will write <code>time.dat</code> with a value of <strong>17967</strong> seconds (roughly 5 hours).</p>
<p>CyberVolk has continued to utilize their branded ransomware payloads, more recently in attacks against entities in Japan, and hype up these attacks across their various channels (e.g., Telegram, X, Discord). These campaigns were part of “#OpJP” which extended through October. Victims of “#OpJP” include:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">The Japan Foundation</li>
<li aria-level="1">Japan Oceanographic Data Center (JODC)</li>
<li aria-level="1">The Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Tokyo Global Information System Centre</li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_109351" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109351" style="width: 523px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_43.jpg" alt="CyberVolk and #OpJP (Targeting Japan)" width="523" height="445" class="size-full wp-image-109351" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_43.jpg 523w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_43-300x255.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 523px) 100vw, 523px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109351" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk and #OpJP (Targeting Japan)</figcaption></figure>
<h2>CyberVolk Associates | Invisible/Doubleface Team Ransomware</h2>
<p>Invisible or Doubleface ransomware is associated with “Doubleface Team” (<i>aka</i> Double Alliance). This group emerged in August-September 2024 as a convergence of associates within CyberVolk, Doubleface, and Moroccan Black Cyber Army. CyberVolk began promoting Doubleface on September 22, 2024.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109342" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109342" style="width: 493px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_11.jpg" alt="September 22 DoubleAlliance / CyberVolk posting" width="493" height="404" class="size-full wp-image-109342" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_11.jpg 493w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_11-300x246.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 493px) 100vw, 493px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109342" class="wp-caption-text">September 22 DoubleAlliance / CyberVolk posting</figcaption></figure>
<p>Invisible/Doubleface ransomware payloads function in an identical manner to CyberVolk-branded ransomware samples. This includes duplication of the 5-hour timeout setting and active wallpaper modification used for input of the decryption key and displaying payment details. Both ransomware families are derived from the same AzzaSec Ransomware code base.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109311" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109311" style="width: 1065px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_4.jpg" alt="Invisible/Doubleface ransomware wallpaper" width="1065" height="545" class="size-full wp-image-109311" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_4.jpg 1065w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_4-300x154.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_4-1024x524.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_4-768x393.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1065px) 100vw, 1065px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109311" class="wp-caption-text">Invisible/Doubleface ransomware wallpaper</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Invisible/Doubleface Source</h3>
<p>The source code/builder for Invisible has been leaked publicly and distributed through various channels, mainly Telegram. As stated previously, both Invisible and CyberVolk’s payloads as of this writing are based on the same code, observed in AzzaSec Ransomware.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109336" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109336" style="width: 972px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_17.jpg" alt="Invisible Ransom source files" width="972" height="350" class="size-full wp-image-109336" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_17.jpg 972w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_17-300x108.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_17-768x277.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 972px) 100vw, 972px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109336" class="wp-caption-text">Invisible Ransom source files</figcaption></figure>
<p>The archive contains the full Visual Studio project and source code for building new Invisible Ransom payloads, along with some already compiled samples/stubs.</p>
<p>The file <code>ransom.cpp</code> contains the main logic for the ransomware payload. It contains all the global variables including ransomware note template data, orchestrates all the encryption tasks, and handles any process termination or manipulation. The main <code>ransom.cpp</code> handles calls out to <code>Cryptographic.cpp</code> to process encryption tasks, including the implementation of AES/RSA (via <code>aes.cpp</code> and <code>rsa.cpp</code> respectively).</p>
<p>Similar to earlier AzzaSec ransomware examples, these payloads encrypt files via AES, then manage encryption keys and wrapping via RSA. The current implementation indicates AES-256 for file encryption, and RSA-2048 for wrapping the keys. Each file is encrypted via AES-256 (EncFile function in <code>Cryptographic.cpp</code>) with the AES key then encrypted via RSA-2048.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109313" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109313" style="width: 1398px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_38.jpg" alt="Encrypting files in Invisible Ransom" width="1398" height="916" class="size-full wp-image-109313" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_38.jpg 1398w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_38-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_38-1024x671.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_38-768x503.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1398px) 100vw, 1398px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109313" class="wp-caption-text">Encrypting files in Invisible Ransom</figcaption></figure>
<p>We can also see the implementation of the ransom countdown mechanism in <code>ransom.cpp</code>. As with CyberVolk Ransom, the default timeout period is 5 hours. This is initially set via the <code>timeLeft</code> variable in <code>ransom.cpp</code></p>
<p>The timer writes a <code>time.dat</code> file to <code>%appdata%\Roaming</code> as we saw with CyberVolk. The 5 hour time limit for these samples is read from this path. In theory, this file could be manipulated to alter the timeout.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109331" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109331" style="width: 741px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_21.jpg" alt="Timer code in Invisible Ransom, referencing time.dat" width="741" height="361" class="size-full wp-image-109331" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_21.jpg 741w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_21-300x146.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 741px) 100vw, 741px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109331" class="wp-caption-text">Timer code in Invisible Ransom, referencing time.dat</figcaption></figure>
<p>The <code>ransom.cpp</code> source file also contains the template for the ransom notes, which are written to the same path from which the ransomware is executed as <code>InvisibleReadMe.txt</code>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109387" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109387" style="width: 744px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_7cut.jpg" alt="Invisible Ransom ransom note template in “ransom.cpp”" width="744" height="95" class="size-full wp-image-109387" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_7cut.jpg 744w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_7cut-300x38.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 744px) 100vw, 744px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109387" class="wp-caption-text">Invisible Ransom&#8217;s ransom note template in “ransom.cpp”</figcaption></figure>
<p>The termination of MMC processes and Task Manager is also present in the Invisible Ransom source (as we also see with CyberVolk samples)</p>
<h2>“Lock. Demand. Dominate” | HexaLocker Ransomware</h2>
<p>HexaLocker is a ransomware family that first appeared in July 2024. HexaLocker is closely associated with <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/lapsus-data-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LAPSUS$</a>, reportedly having been originally developed by “ZZART3XX”, a proclaimed former associate of the group. HexaLocker payloads are written in <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/alphagolang-a-step-by-step-go-malware-reversing-methodology-for-ida-pro/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Golang</a>. As of this writing, we have only observed payloads targeting Windows systems.</p>
<p>On July 22, CyberVolk first referenced HexaLocker via one of Holy League’s posts. The Holy League is a loosely affiliated group of 70+ members born out of protest against Spain and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/three-pro-russian-hackers-arrested-spain-over-cyberattacks-2024-07-20/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">associated arrests</a> of members of <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/noname05716-the-pro-russian-hacktivist-group-targeting-nato/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NONAME057(16)</a>. HexaLocker’s posts and branding are all laden with their “Lock. Demand. Dominate” slogan.</p>
<p>In September 2024, HexaLocker launched a new Telegram channel after previous ones had been banned or removed. The updated channel contains details on their ongoing existence along with screenshots of the current HexaLocker panel.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109306" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109306" style="width: 869px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_44.jpg" alt="HexaLocker Telegram message" width="869" height="295" class="size-full wp-image-109306" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_44.jpg 869w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_44-300x102.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_44-768x261.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 869px) 100vw, 869px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109306" class="wp-caption-text">HexaLocker Telegram message</figcaption></figure>
<p>Throughout October 2024, CyberVolk’s communication channels continued to echo messaging from HexaLocker. This includes HexaLocker’s solicitations for help in continuing to progress with HexaLocker. On October 2, 2024, HexaLocker posted an update asking for help but also teasing new features in the pipeline. These include:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Stronger anti-debug/anti-analysis features</li>
<li aria-level="1">Advanced obfuscations (crypting/packing)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Inclusion of EDR/XDR/AV-Killer</li>
<li aria-level="1">Permanent AMSI bypass</li>
<li aria-level="1">Improved process-injection</li>
<li aria-level="1">Remote Thread Hijacking</li>
<li aria-level="1">UAC Bypass improvements</li>
<li aria-level="1">Self-deletion</li>
</ul>
<p>Interesting developments continued with HexaLocker throughout October 2024. On October 4th, the group posted an update with a video demo claiming that an “EDR Killer” and AMSI/WD Bypass features had been added. This was followed on October 6th with an update stating that UAC bypasses had been added to the product.</p>
<p>On October 20, 2024, the actor behind the HexaLocker Telegram channel (ZZART3XX) posted their intention to officially leave and denounce LAPSUS$ as well as any peripheral affiliations. This includes the maintenance of the HexaLocker project and all the relationships and alliances that revolve around it.</p>
<p>In this announcement, the author also indicated that they would be offering HexaLocker source code, including its web panel, along with “LAPSUS$ Ransomware” source for sale.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109320" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109320" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_31.jpg" alt="HexaLocker “shut down” posting via Telegram" width="500" height="487" class="size-full wp-image-109320" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_31.jpg 500w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_31-300x292.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_31-50x50.jpg 50w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_31-24x24.jpg 24w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109320" class="wp-caption-text">HexaLocker “shut down” posting via Telegram</figcaption></figure>
<p>This was followed the next day on October 21 with offers to sell HexaLocker and the panel infrastructure, along with associated “LAPSUS$ Ransomware”. These messages were echoed across HexaLocker, Holy League, and LAPSUS$-aligned channels.</p>
<p>The overt promotion of HexaLocker within CyberVolk channels has ceased since the HexaLocker shutdown announcement.</p>
<h2>Parano Ransomware Within the CyberVolk Collective</h2>
<p>In late October 2024, various identities in the CyberVolk community began promoting the release of Parano Ransomware v1. This appears to be another affiliation for the CyberVolk collective.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109353" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109353" style="width: 617px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_15.jpg" alt="October 2024 Parano Ransomware Announcement by CyberVolk" width="617" height="528" class="size-full wp-image-109353" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_15.jpg 617w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_15-300x257.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 617px) 100vw, 617px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109353" class="wp-caption-text">October 2024 Parano Ransomware Announcement by CyberVolk</figcaption></figure>
<p>According to the announcement, Parano Ransomware comes with a $400.00 USD price tag per single payload/stub. The ransomware features strong anti-analysis and anti-debugging features, and uses a combination of AES-128 and RSA-4096 for key management. </p>
<p>The Parano malware family extends beyond ransomware, also including “Parano Checker” and &#8220;Parano Stealer”, a commodity, Python-based, infostealer. The malware attempts to gather and exfiltrate browser data, Discord details, crypto wallet information and keys, along with other related software and system diagnostic details. The data can be exfiltrated via Discord webhook to a channel or location of the attacker&#8217;s choosing.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109355" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109355" style="width: 516px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_35.jpg" alt="Parano Stealer Announcement, October 2024" width="516" height="475" class="size-full wp-image-109355" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_35.jpg 516w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_35-300x276.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 516px) 100vw, 516px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109355" class="wp-caption-text">Parano Stealer Announcement, October 2024</figcaption></figure>
<p>Parano Checker is a reconnaissance and info-gathering tool capable of navigating targets and helping to isolate interesting ingress points or data repositories, or assist with dictionary/brute force attacks on certain interfaces (e.g., CPanel and WordPress login panels).</p>
<p>At the time of writing, we have not observed the executable variations of Parano (<i>aka</i> Paraodeus Ransomware) in the wild. The author has shared a non-malicious Python-based demo of a “ScreenLocker”. As it stands, the nature of the relationship between CyberVolk and the Parano ecosystem is still evolving.</p>
<h2>Beyond Ransomware | CyberVolk Stealers and Webshells</h2>
<p>In addition to ransomware and other disruptive attacks, CyberVolk develops and distributes infostealer malware and webshells. The group announced the new webshell in late October 2024.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109318" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109318" style="width: 469px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_33.jpg" alt="CyberVolk Webshell announcement (Telegram)" width="469" height="552" class="size-full wp-image-109318" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_33.jpg 469w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_33-255x300.jpg 255w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 469px) 100vw, 469px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109318" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk Webshell announcement (Telegram)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The CyberVolk webshell is distributed as a standard PHP file with the actual malicious code base64-encoded inside its body.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109325" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109325" style="width: 981px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="magnify" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_27.jpg" alt="CyberVolk Webshell decoded" width="981" height="545" class="size-full wp-image-109325" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_27.jpg 981w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_27-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_27-768x427.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 981px) 100vw, 981px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109325" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk Webshell decoded</figcaption></figure>
<p>The publicly <a href="https://x.com/FalconFeedsio/status/1838244850669392307/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">released</a> version of the CyberVolk webshell provides multiple functions. The current version of the webshell allows for files to be uploaded, renamed, and downloaded. Further, attackers can traverse directories on the target server and gather environmental details.</p>
<p>“CyberVolk Stealer” is distributed in the form of a Python script and is based on LBX-Grabber, an existing Python information stealer, which is in turn built into <a href="https://www.cyfirma.com/research/blx-stealer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BLX-Stealer</a>. Specifically, CyberVolk is derived from the LBX-Grabber component.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109309" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109309" style="width: 1764px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_41.jpg" alt="CyberVolk Stealer Python Script" width="1764" height="1034" class="size-full wp-image-109309" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_41.jpg 1764w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_41-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_41-1024x600.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_41-768x450.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_41-1536x900.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1764px) 100vw, 1764px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109309" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk Stealer Python Script</figcaption></figure>
<p>CyberVolk Stealer attempts to gather various types of data from the system, then exfiltrates the data via Discord. Version 1 of the stealer was announced in September 2024. Core features include robust gathering of browser, discord, game and crypto wallet data. The stealer targets multiple browsers and numerous wallets.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109304" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109304" style="width: 663px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_6.jpg" alt="CyberVolk Stealer identifying sensitive data" width="663" height="533" class="size-full wp-image-109304" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_6.jpg 663w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_6-300x241.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 663px) 100vw, 663px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109304" class="wp-caption-text">CyberVolk Stealer identifying sensitive data</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Telegram Exit and Weaponized Bans</h2>
<p>In early November 2024, CyberVolk, and numerous affiliated groups, vanished from Telegram as a result of a mass ban of hacktivist groups. The last significant posts to the CyberVolk Telegram channels were on November 3, 2024.</p>
<p>The group subsequently announced, via Twitter/X, that it would only be using the X platform going forward. The Twitter/X account for DoubleFace, <code>@DoubleFace_Team</code>, made a similar announcement around the same time.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109322" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109322" style="width: 1260px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_3.jpg" alt="Telegram ban updates on X" width="1260" height="346" class="size-full wp-image-109322" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_3.jpg 1260w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_3-300x82.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_3-1024x281.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_3-768x211.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1260px) 100vw, 1260px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109322" class="wp-caption-text">Telegram ban updates on X</figcaption></figure>
<p>Telegram channels belonging to CyberVolk and numerous allies appear to have been banned maliciously. We have observed specific actors claiming responsibility for attempting to close and/or extort channels belonging to AzzaSec and DoubleFace amongst others.</p>
<p>In September, some users began threatening to have rival hacktivist group channels including CyberVolk, APTZone, Doubleface, AzzaSec and others banned.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109341" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109341" style="width: 1586px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_12.jpg" alt="September 14, 2024 - “Matteo” targeting CyberVolk/APTZone with bans" width="1586" height="886" class="size-full wp-image-109341" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_12.jpg 1586w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_12-300x168.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_12-1024x572.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_12-768x429.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_12-1536x858.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1586px) 100vw, 1586px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109341" class="wp-caption-text">September 14, 2024 &#8211; “Matteo” targeting CyberVolk/APTZone with bans</figcaption></figure>
<p>On November 16, 2024, RipperSec posted their ‘perspective’ on the banning of multiple hacktivist channels, indicating that some prior members of AzzaSec and Doubleface were attempting to exhort other channels under the threat of a Telegram ban.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109334" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109334" style="width: 675px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_19.jpg" alt="November 13, 2024 RipperSec Telegram Post" width="675" height="294" class="size-full wp-image-109334" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_19.jpg 675w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_19-300x131.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 675px) 100vw, 675px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109334" class="wp-caption-text">November 13, 2024 RipperSec Telegram Post</figcaption></figure>
<p>This was highlighted in another post on November 13, 2024 in the “Hunt3r Kill3rs” Telegram channel. In this post, an actor referring to AzzaSec claimed “they didn’t close nobody’s channels, all the channels got closed by me”. The post went on to advise others receiving extortion threats to ignore them. “I’m the only one that is closing the hacktivist community’s channels and groups”, the actor claimed.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109333" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109333" style="width: 529px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_2.jpg" alt="November 13, 2024 posting in Hunt3r Kill3rs Telegram Channel" width="529" height="324" class="size-full wp-image-109333" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_2.jpg 529w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/CyberVolk_2-300x184.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109333" class="wp-caption-text">November 13, 2024 posting in Hunt3r Kill3rs Telegram Channel</figcaption></figure>
<p>This weaponization of the Telegram <a href="https://securityintelligence.com/articles/what-telegrams-recent-policy-shift-means-for-cyber-crime/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Terms-of-Service</a> is increasing in parallel with threat actor groups moving off Telegram to seek more clandestine and secure communication channels in response to increased <a href="https://apnews.com/article/telegram-pavel-durov-arrest-2c8015c102cce23c23d55c6ca82641c5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">scrutiny</a> and declining trust in the platform after the arrest of Telegram founder Pavel Durov.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The number of ransomware families associated with the CyberVolk hacktivist group highlights the ability of this group to rapidly pivot, building upon existing tools to suit their needs and further their causes. Though primarily composed of lower-skilled threat actors that reach for and use whatever works for them, we continue to see how quickly the group is able to move and adapt.</p>
<p>The reuse of tools like AzzaSec Ransom, Diamond RW, and even more established ones like LockBit and Chaos, demonstrates just how dynamic these affiliations and alliances between hacktivist groups can be. Not only are such groups touting new tools within short time frames only to abandon them and pivot to something else later, the number of hacktivist groups is also growing. Infighting and tensions amongst them are also fuel for the rates of growth and change &#8211; as alliances crumble or shift, the threat environment stays highly volatile and dynamic, making it more difficult for cyber defenders to track their activities consistently.</p>
<p>As groups like CyberVolk leverage openly-available commodity tools with high potential for causing damage, they continue to add more layers of complexity, expanding and revising the tools as they are passed around within the collective. Ransomware operations will only get muddier and increase how much cybersecurity teams will need to monitor in order to stay up to date on the happenings within the cybercrime ecosystem.</p>
<h2>Indicators of Compromise</h2>
<div style="font-size:0.8em">
<p><strong>CyberVolk</strong><br />
0ce59e479ec6eacd3a44ed3de2dc572676e5b2dd<br />
16bf55122bbb6073cc1d77ce23e2a8e6052f9ec1 | Stealer<br />
3bf6a90017bf22083ab735ecf3f8589a3f220e53 | Ransom note<br />
5d8bed459f55a37e2fcb801d04de337a01c5d623 | Ransom note<br />
813c510fb2463ecc6dff7795ef96744ca82544b3 | Webshell<br />
b958fb7241cc9675b8dd967b02df6a6ad92de52d<br />
c70d2350cbac3d0abeb896adcce2fcf243943633 | Webshell<br />
eae366ee4a7c19a87bc5ab9360f4333907a6a387<br />
f5d0c94b2be91342dc01ecf2f89e7e6f21a74b90</p>
<p><strong>AzzaSec</strong><br />
5499da31260a4aa75eea46c1d4aa6559074749a8 | Ransomware (src)</p>
<p><strong>Invisible / Doubleface Team</strong><br />
197d5c9c5cbf53ed3e78d53a008b6ad665fa3e4c<br />
1f325950a7a8e1a2050e954f33d2c3774510bd6e<br />
59e293623e4fb828a29fb982d5ac9a4f993abc3b<br />
d35da3f4e36eebf36a130bc7e0182fc4c35cf551 | Archive</p>
<p><strong>HexaLocker</strong><br />
11288fb54c6f2ed4d8cddfb004c754e5e9c35ad5<br />
4c24fdf504af452fb7245db33bfc1dc4f72c04a8<br />
4f8e1e7bfd484cf312fdc77e8687086f6f6007c<br />
7ba4eb7842730bbc82fc129a3f3d4a239ac436c2<br />
84dacf9da57d9d69c2ca711831895bf185834b8c<br />
904f46ef4c66ccf844bf31d37c11298fb7f65157<br />
93334882ff3c03c42b1179d9db0c165c99145369<br />
a4b7ef2ca1d5fda318505cac6757b5313b47eeac<br />
b6a9c5692b76f2defc1c170bdce0e41d91d706db<br />
be581fc1f430dd6855effd9e54429c5c5fcb9f8c | Ransom note<br />
cd8f934fa7ba7817bb62f0e4b968b3f124355b60</p>
<p><strong>PDBs</strong> </p>
<pre>
C:/Users/zzart/Desktop/HexaLocker RaaS/crypter.go
C:/Users/zzart/Desktop/MalwareDeveloppement/HexaLocker RaaS/decrypt_key.go
C:/Users/zzart/Desktop/MalwareDeveloppement/HexaLocker RaaS/crypterV1.go
</pre>
<p><strong>DNS</strong><br />
darkslategray-baboon-853641[.]hostingersite[.]com</p>
<p><strong>LAPSUS$/HexaLocker</strong><br />
481830db2daf40607748bd9624e970781e7f4408<br />
e1d8993ef4bbc8d2aa331262e5422d91865acc4f</p>
<p><strong>Parano</strong><br />
3ce26f45f5da58ab75b4d1cecc78c3bbe275f708 | Stealer (archive)<br />
4581b30e6f5946a570963cd76dc79beaa8bcf1c3 | ScreenLocker<br />
91abb7fadf847f3810bbe0734e3c31d5dc7bce6d | ScreenLocker<br />
b5d8e690a75f07e7d3e18fcc5b86bfe2362a3300 | ScreenLocker
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/cybervolk_v2-ftr.jpg" length="900294" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DPRK IT Workers &#124; A Network of Active Front Companies and Their Links to China</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Hegel &amp; Dakota Cary]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 10:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPRK]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=109228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SentinelLabs has identified multiple deceptive websites linked to businesses in China fronting for North Korea's fake IT workers scheme.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLabs has identified unique characteristics of multiple websites, now seized by the US Government, associated with the DPRK IT Worker front companies.</li>
<li aria-level="1">We assess with high confidence that DPRK actors seek to impersonate US based software and technology consulting businesses by copying the online brands of legitimate organizations, seeking to use these for financial objectives.</li>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLabs has linked the activity to several active front companies and links these with high confidence to a larger set of organizations being created in China.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Our findings link additional companies, which remain active today, to the DPRK IT Workers scheme.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Background</h2>
<p>North Korea operates a global network of IT workers, both as individuals and under front companies, to evade sanctions and generate revenue for the regime. These workers are highly skilled in areas like software development, mobile applications, blockchain, and cryptocurrency technologies. By posing as professionals from other countries using fake identities and forged credentials, they secure remote jobs and freelance contracts with businesses worldwide.</p>
<p>Our PinnacleOne team has compiled an executive summary of this threat, <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/pinnacleone-execbrief-north-korean-it-worker-threat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">available here</a>.</p>
<p>Front companies, often based in China, Russia, Southeast Asia, and Africa, play a key role in masking the workers’ true origins and managing payments. Notable examples include China-based Yanbian Silverstar Network Technology Co. Ltd., <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-court-authorized-action-disrupt-illicit-revenue-generation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">disrupted in October 2023</a>, and Russia-based Volasys Silver Star, sanctioned by the U.S. Department of the Treasury <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sm481" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in 2018</a>, for their roles in facilitating fraudulent IT operations. These entities helped DPRK workers launder earnings through online payment services and Chinese bank accounts. The payments, often routed through cryptocurrencies or shadow banking systems, ultimately support state programs, including weapons development, circumventing international sanctions.</p>
<p>These schemes present significant risks to employers, including potential legal violations, reputational damage, and insider threats such as intellectual property theft or malware implantation. Addressing these risks requires heightened awareness and stringent vetting processes to limit North Korea’s ability to exploit global tech markets.</p>
<p>This blog explores four newly identified examples of DPRK IT Worker front companies, analyzing their online presence and the methods they use to appear legitimate to unsuspecting targets in recent months. These four companies’ websites were recently subject to law enforcement action and taken offline.</p>
<h2>Independent Lab LLC</h2>
<p>The Independent Lab LLC website, <code>inditechlab[.]com</code> was active since at least February 2024, with indication it was acquired and operated using InterServer hosting since May 2022 (<code>174.138.181[.]198</code>). The domain itself was registered through NameCheap.</p>
<p>The content of the website is in line with what you would expect of a legitimate software development outsourcing business, with no obvious major indicators associated with the DPRK, or even illegitimate in any way. In the case of Independent Lab LLC, the website format and content was copied from Kitrum, a legitimate custom software firm headquartered in the United States. The DPRK actors did not retain the “We Stand with Ukraine” link or menu header.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109246" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109246" style="width: 1412px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109246" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_13.jpg" alt="DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website - Independent Lab LLC" width="1412" height="947" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_13.jpg 1412w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_13-300x201.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_13-1024x687.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_13-768x515.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1412px) 100vw, 1412px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109246" class="wp-caption-text">DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website &#8211; Independent Lab LLChot</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_109244" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109244" style="width: 1391px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109244" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_15.jpg" alt="Legitimate business, source of copied website design used by DPRK" width="1391" height="1034" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_15.jpg 1391w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_15-300x223.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_15-1024x761.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_15-768x571.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1391px) 100vw, 1391px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109244" class="wp-caption-text">Legitimate business, source of copied website design used by DPRK</figcaption></figure>
<p>The content of the website centered around the Contact Us form, enticing visitors to engage in communications, providing no contact details on the website itself.</p>
<h2>Shenyang Tonywang Technology LTD</h2>
<p>The name “Shenyang Tonywang Technology” was used in the formal content of the website; however, the domain itself is <code>tonywangtech[.]com</code>. The website first became active in November 2023, overlapping with previously used InterServer hosting infrastructure (<code>174.138.181[.]198</code>), and was also registered via NameCheap.</p>
<p>Similar to the previous example, Shenyang Tonywang Technology advertises itself as a top software consulting company with bespoke solutions, including DevOps &amp; cloud consulting. In this case, the website format and content was copied from Urolime, a legitimate DevOps consulting company headquartered in the United States.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109237" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109237" style="width: 1506px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109237" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_4.jpg" alt="DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website - Shenyang Tonywang Technology LTD" width="1506" height="925" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_4.jpg 1506w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_4-300x184.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_4-1024x629.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_4-768x472.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1506px) 100vw, 1506px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109237" class="wp-caption-text">DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website &#8211; Shenyang Tonywang Technology LTD</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_109235" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109235" style="width: 1344px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109235" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_6.jpg" alt="Legitimate Urolime business, source of copied website design used by DPRK" width="1344" height="988" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_6.jpg 1344w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_6-300x221.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_6-1024x753.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_6-768x565.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1344px) 100vw, 1344px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109235" class="wp-caption-text">Legitimate Urolime business, source of copied website design used by DPRK</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Tony WKJ LLC</h2>
<p>Tony WKJ LLC IT Services website, <code>wkjllc[.]com</code>, was active since at least May 2024, with indication it was acquired and operated using InterServer hosting (<code>174.138.181[.]198</code>) since May 2022. The domain itself was registered through NameCheap.</p>
<p>Tony WKJ LLC advertises itself as a leading software development company that specializes in Agile IT development. Once again, In this case the website format and content was copied from a legitimate business. Specifically, this website is a copy from  ArohaTech IT Services, a software and web development company headquartered in Noida, India.</p>
<p>However, a comparison to the legitimate website reveals that the DPRK actors have not only placed their own name, and removed original ArohaTech logos, they have also modified the content to clearly attempt to brand Tony WKJ LLC as a US based company.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109234" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109234" style="width: 1392px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109234" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_7.jpg" alt="DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website - Tony WKJ LLC" width="1392" height="1158" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_7.jpg 1392w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_7-300x250.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_7-1024x852.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_7-768x639.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1392px) 100vw, 1392px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109234" class="wp-caption-text">DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website &#8211; Tony WKJ LLC</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_109241" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109241" style="width: 1390px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109241" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_18.jpg" alt="Legitimate business, source of copied website design used by DPRK" width="1390" height="1259" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_18.jpg 1390w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_18-300x272.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_18-1024x927.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_18-768x696.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1390px) 100vw, 1390px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109241" class="wp-caption-text">Legitimate business, source of copied website design used by DPRK</figcaption></figure>
<h2>HopanaTech</h2>
<p>HopanaTech website, <code>hopanatech[.]com</code> is a bit more unique from the others above. The domain itself was first registered in November 2020, and began hosting publicly via Asia Web Services Ltd (<code>180.235.135[.]177</code>) in December 2020. The website has been presented as shown below since at least the end of 2021. The domain was registered through NameCheap.</p>
<p>The website content aligns with the previous examples, including the description of being a custom software development company. The HopanaTech version of the content has been modified significantly; however, it continued to make use of customer reviews and marketing content from legitimate public websites. However, in some cases, content that would have required more than a simple text edit remains unchanged, showing the original sources name, such as the legitimate ITechArt firm&#8217;s website.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109236" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109236" style="width: 1527px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109236" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_5.jpg" alt="DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website - HopanaTech" width="1527" height="1036" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_5.jpg 1527w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_5-300x204.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_5-1024x695.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_5-768x521.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1527px) 100vw, 1527px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109236" class="wp-caption-text">DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website &#8211; HopanaTech</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_109239" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109239" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109239" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_2.jpg" alt="DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website - HopanaTech - Showing content source" width="1999" height="1020" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_2.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_2-300x153.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_2-1024x523.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_2-768x392.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_2-1536x784.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109239" class="wp-caption-text">DPRK IT Worker Front Company Website &#8211; HopanaTech &#8211; Showing content source</figcaption></figure>
<h2>United States Government Response</h2>
<p>Each of the above four companies has been disrupted by US Government agencies, specifically the Department of Justice, Federal Bureau of Investigation, Homeland Security Investigations, Defense Criminal Investigative Service, and the United States Postal Inspection Service.</p>
<p>On October 10th, the US Government seized the four domains belonging to the front companies, each of which now shows the standard takedown alert and links to <a href="https://ofac.treasury.gov/media/923131/download?inline" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the 2022 US Treasury fact sheet</a> on DPRKs IT Worker scheme. The websites rotate between English and Korean language versions.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109233" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109233" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109233" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_8.jpg" alt="Domain Seized Alert - English" width="1999" height="1128" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_8.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_8-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_8-1024x578.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_8-768x433.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_8-1536x867.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109233" class="wp-caption-text">Domain Seized Alert &#8211; English</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_109240" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109240" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109240" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_19.jpg" alt="Domain Seized Alert - Korean" width="1999" height="1124" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_19.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_19-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_19-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_19-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_19-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_19-1600x900.jpg 1600w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109240" class="wp-caption-text">Domain Seized Alert &#8211; Korean</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Expanded Analysis</h2>
<p>Drawing on details from the four companies disrupted by US Government agencies, SentinelLabs was able to find multiple leads to an active network of DPRK IT front companies originating in China.</p>
<h3>The Mysterious A1 Building</h3>
<p>In an early 2024 archived snapshot of Shenyang Tonywang Technology’s website, <code>tonywangtech[.]com</code>, we can see the actor added the following address:</p>
<p><i>No. 1006-25, Building A1, No. 11, Tawan Street, Huanggu District, Shenyang City Liaoning 110036</i></p>
<p><figure id="attachment_109248" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109248" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109248" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_10.jpg" alt="tonywangtech[.]com listed address and contact details" width="1999" height="1022" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_10.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_10-300x153.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_10-1024x524.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_10-768x393.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_10-1536x785.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109248" class="wp-caption-text">tonywangtech[.]com listed address and contact details</figcaption></figure>We identified an additional company with similar traits. First, the address happens to be highly close in proximity – listed next to each other on the same floor of the same building. <i>No. 1006-23, Building A1, No. 11, Tawan Street, Huanggu, Shenyang, Liaoning, China</i></p>
<p>The additional company is Shenyang Huguo Technology Ltd, which uses the domain <code>huguotechltd[.]com</code> in a similar way to the previous four. The website uses copied content and logos from the legitimate Indian software firm TatvaSoft.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109238" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109238" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109238" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_3.jpg" alt="Active DPRK linked company website -Shenyang Huguo Technology Ltd" width="1999" height="1065" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_3.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_3-300x160.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_3-1024x546.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_3-768x409.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_3-1536x818.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109238" class="wp-caption-text">Active DPRK linked company website -Shenyang Huguo Technology Ltd</figcaption></figure>
<p>The <code>huguotechltd[.]com</code> domain was registered in October 2023 via NameCheap. The domain has since been and continues to be hosted at <code>103.15.29[.]44</code>, of Asia Web Services Ltd.</p>
<p>We assess Shenyang Huguo Technology Ltd. is closely associated with the previously four reviewed DPRK IT Worker front companies, and had remained online long enough to have been used to achieve the DPRKs objectives.</p>
<h3>The Tony Wang Link</h3>
<p>HopanaTech’s website, <code>hopanatech[.]com</code>, listed three contacts before it was taken down by law enforcement. The first person, Wang Kejia, is listed with the email address “Tonywkj”.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109245" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109245" style="width: 1058px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_14.jpg" alt="Contacts from the now-seized HopanaTech website" width="1058" height="738" class="size-full wp-image-109245" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_14.jpg 1058w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_14-300x209.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_14-1024x714.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_14-768x536.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1058px) 100vw, 1058px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109245" class="wp-caption-text">Contacts from the now-seized HopanaTech website</figcaption></figure>
<p>The “wkj” is almost certainly the acronym for the preceding Chinese name, Wang Kejia. The <code>Tonywkj@Hopana</code> email address establishes a link between Wang Kejia, a real person who is a resident of the address in New Jersey and the “Tony Wang” identity. The Shenyang Tonywang Technology Company website discussed above was also subject to law enforcement action, and its name bears resemblance to the same Tongwkj listed by Hopana. Furthermore, the Tonywkj email also directly matches the domain of another taken-down DPRK IT Worker site discussed above, Tony WKJ LLC.</p>
<h3>The Tong Yuze Identity</h3>
<p>Law enforcement action established that Hopana Tech and <code>Hopanatech[.]com</code> are DRPK IT Worker Front companies. This analysis expands on the Hopana Tech company corporate registration data inside China.</p>
<p>A corporate records website from the PRC indicates the Beijing Xiwang Technology Company (北京市戏网科技有限公司), previously used the name Beijing Hou Pa Na Technology Company (北京后帕纳科技有限公司), a clear cognate for the English-translated “HopanaTech.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_109232" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109232" style="width: 1838px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109232" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_9.jpg" alt="Corporate record showing Xiwang’s previous use of the Hopana Technology name" width="1838" height="556" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_9.jpg 1838w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_9-300x91.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_9-1024x310.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_9-768x232.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_9-1536x465.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1838px) 100vw, 1838px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109232" class="wp-caption-text">Corporate record showing Xiwang’s previous use of the Hopana Technology name</figcaption></figure>
<p>Furthermore, the above screenshot of HopanaTech’s website, which lists the Tonywkj email address, also lists Tong Yuze (佟雨泽). The same name is used for the corporate registrant of Beijing Xiwang Technology Company.Highlighted text shows that Beijing Xiwang Technology was previously known as Hopana Tech.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109247" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109247" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109247" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_12.jpg" alt="Contacts from the now-seized HopanaTech website" width="1999" height="969" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_12.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_12-300x145.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_12-1024x496.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_12-768x372.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_12-1536x745.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109247" class="wp-caption-text">Contacts from the now-seized HopanaTech website</figcaption></figure>
<p>As if to allay concerns that Beijing Xiwang Technology Company was not a front company, corporate records show the firm only pays unemployment insurance, health insurance, and employee injury liability insurance for one person.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109243" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109243" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109243" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_16.jpg" alt="Corporate records for Bejing Xiwang Technology Company" width="1999" height="449" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_16.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_16-300x67.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_16-1024x230.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_16-768x173.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_16-1536x345.jpg 1536w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_16-221x51.jpg 221w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109243" class="wp-caption-text">Corporate records for Bejing Xiwang Technology Company</figcaption></figure>
<p>Tong Yuze is currently listed as the corporate registrant of 25 companies in China, including many restaurants and catering companies. Owing to increased data protection measures by the PRC, a complete accounting of Tong Yuze’s companies is not possible.</p>
<p>Some companies identified as Tong Yuze’s include:</p>
<ul>
<li>海口宜路畅佟科技贸易有限公司</li>
<li>北京上日清新食品有限公司</li>
<li>京山味诚（北京）餐饮管理有限公司</li>
<li>泽日启程（北京）餐饮管理有限公司</li>
<li>北京哈巴萨科贸有限公司</li>
</ul>
<p>This foray into restaurants does not appear to be a case of mistaken identity. The email provided for Tong Yuze on the registration of Beijing Xiwang Technology Company is <code>tongyuze@jswc[.]com[.]cn</code>. The email domain “JSWC” aligns with the name of some of Tong Yuze’s restaurant companies. In this case, Jing Shan Wei Cheng (京山味诚), matches the acronym of the email domain. This provides reasonable evidence of a legitimate connection between Tong Yuze and the mentioned food service companies.</p>
<p>Given the very real businesses being run by Tong Yuze’s other corporate registrations– seemingly many franchises of Yiwei Yicheng (一味一诚) –it’s possible this individual is serving as a cut-out for the DPRK. We hypothesize that his collection of businesses may serve to provide cover for illegal ones.</p>
<h3>The Haikou Yilu Changtong Technology Trading Company</h3>
<p>One of the companies connected to the Tong Yuze identity and accessible on corporate registration sites is Haikou Yilu Changtong Technology Trading Company (海口宜路畅佟科技贸易有限公司).</p>
<figure id="attachment_109249" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109249" style="width: 1844px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-109249" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_1.jpg" alt="Haikou Yilu Changtong Technology Trading Company corporate registration" width="1844" height="472" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_1.jpg 1844w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_1-300x77.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_1-1024x262.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_1-768x197.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_1-1536x393.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1844px) 100vw, 1844px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109249" class="wp-caption-text">Haikou Yilu Changtong Technology Trading Company corporate registration</figcaption></figure>
<p>Haikou Yilu is distinct from the other Tong Yuze-registered companies for two reasons. First, it is another technology company–not a restaurant. Second, its corporate registration makes use of a telephone number that differs from Tong Yuze’s restaurant businesses but is shared with the Beijing Xiwang Technology Company corporate registration.</p>
<p>To help visualize the connections we described, the graphic below provides a simplified representation of the key relationships and pivots.</p>
<figure id="attachment_109242" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-109242" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="magnify" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK_IT_17.jpg" alt="Visual representation of front company connections" width="1999" height="1047" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-109242" class="wp-caption-text">Visual representation of front company connections</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The DPRK&#8217;s use of the IT Worker scheme underscores the regime&#8217;s adaptability in exploiting global markets to further its financial objectives. By impersonating legitimate U.S.-based software and technology consulting firms, North Korean actors aim to gain trust and access to sensitive contracts, circumventing sanctions and evading detection. These tactics highlight a deliberate and evolving strategy that leverages the global digital economy to fund state activities, including weapons development.</p>
<p>Our research not only exposes the deceptive tactics employed by DPRK IT workers but also connects these efforts to a broader, active network of front companies originating in China. This linkage emphasizes the scale and complexity of North Korea’s financial schemes and the importance of vigilance across industries. Organizations are urged to implement robust vetting processes, including careful scrutiny of potential contractors and suppliers, to mitigate risks and prevent inadvertent support of such illicit operations. By shedding light on these activities, SentinelLabs aims to equip businesses, governments, and the public with the insights needed to stay ahead of these threats and safeguard the integrity of global markets.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DPRK-Front-v3-ftr.jpg" length="503118" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlueNoroff Hidden Risk &#124; Threat Actor Targets Macs with Fake Crypto News and Novel Persistence</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Raffaele Sabato, Phil Stokes &amp; Tom Hegel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 10:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DPRK]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=108328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.</li>
<li aria-level="1">We assess with high confidence that the same actor is responsible for earlier attacks attributed to BlueNoroff and the RustDoor/ThiefBucket and RustBucket campaigns.</li>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLabs observed the use of a novel persistence mechanism abusing the Zsh configuration file <code>zshenv</code>.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The campaign, which we dubbed ‘Hidden Risk’, uses emails propagating fake news about cryptocurrency trends to infect targets via a malicious application disguised as a PDF file.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Cryptocurrency-related businesses have been targets of North Korean-affiliated threat actors for some time now, with multiple campaigns aiming to steal funds and/or insert backdoor malware into targets. In April 2023, <a href="https://www.jamf.com/blog/bluenoroff-apt-targets-macos-rustbucket-malware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">researchers</a> detailed an APT campaign targeting macOS users with multi-stage malware that culminated in a Rust backdoor capable of downloading and executing further malware on infected devices. ‘RustBucket’, as they labeled it, was attributed with strong confidence to the BlueNoroff APT. In May 2023, ESET researchers discovered a second RustBucket variant targeting macOS users, followed by Elastic’s <a href="https://www.elastic.co/security-labs/DPRK-strikes-using-a-new-variant-of-rustbucket" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">discovery</a> in July that year of a third variant that included a LaunchAgent for persistence. In November 2023, Elastic also <a href="https://www.elastic.co/security-labs/elastic-catches-dprk-passing-out-kandykorn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reported</a> on another DPRK campaign targeting blockchain engineers of a crypto exchange platform with KandyKorn malware. Further analysis by SentinelLabs was able to <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/dprk-crypto-theft-macos-rustbucket-droppers-pivot-to-deliver-kandykorn-payloads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">connect</a> the KandyKorn and RustBucket campaigns.</p>
<p>In early September 2024, the FBI began <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/PSA/2024/PSA240903" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">warning</a> that North Korea was conducting “highly tailored, difficult-to-detect social engineering campaigns against employees of decentralized finance (&#8220;DeFi&#8221;), cryptocurrency, and similar businesses to deploy malware and steal company cryptocurrency”. Researchers from <a href="https://www.jamf.com/blog/jamf-threat-labs-observes-targeted-attacks-amid-fbi-warnings/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jamf</a> subsequently followed up on this report a few weeks later detailing an attack attempt that deployed malware masquerading as a Visual Studio updater.</p>
<p>In October 2024, SentinelLabs observed a phishing attempt on a crypto-related industry that delivered a dropper application and a payload bearing many of the hallmarks of these previous attacks. We believe the campaign likely began as early as July 2024 and uses email and PDF lures with fake news headlines or stories about crypto-related topics. We dubbed this campaign ‘Hidden Risk’ and detail its operation and indicators of compromise below, including the use of a novel persistence mechanism abusing the zshenv configuration file.</p>
<h2>Infection Vector</h2>
<p>Initial infection is achieved via phishing email containing a link to a malicious application. The application is disguised as a link to a PDF document relating to a cryptocurrency topic such as “Hidden Risk Behind New Surge of Bitcoin Price”, “Altcoin Season 2.0-The Hidden Gems to Watch” and “New Era for Stablecoins and DeFi, CeFi”.</p>
<p>The emails hijack the name of a real person in an unrelated industry as a sender and purport to be forwarding a message from a well-known crypto social media influencer. In the case of the ‘Hidden Risk’ pdf, the threat actors copied a <a href="https://ijsra.net/sites/default/files/IJSRA-2024-1296.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">genuine research paper</a> entitled ‘Bitcoin ETF: Opportunities and risk’ by an academic associated with the University of Texas and hosted online by the International Journal of Science and Research Archive (IJSRA).</p>
<figure id="attachment_108341" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108341" style="width: 1789px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108341" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_4.jpg" alt="The fake PDF displayed to targets (left) and the original source document hosted online (right)" width="1789" height="614" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_4.jpg 1789w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_4-300x103.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_4-1024x351.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_4-768x264.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_4-1536x527.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1789px) 100vw, 1789px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108341" class="wp-caption-text">The fake PDF displayed to targets (left) and the original source document hosted online (right)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Unlike earlier campaigns attributed to BlueNoroff, the Hidden Risk campaign uses an unsophisticated phishing email that does not engage the recipient with contextually-relevant content, such as reference to personal or work-related information.</p>
<p>Also of note is that the sender domain in our observed incident, <code>kalpadvisory[.]com</code>, has been <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IndianStockMarket/comments/1c3rema/incessant_spam_calls_from_kalp_advisory_and_others/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">noted</a> for spamming among online communities involved in the Indian stock market.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108336" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108336" style="width: 1574px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108336" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_9.jpg" alt="Social media users complain about spam calls from Kalp Advisory" width="1574" height="1024" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_9.jpg 1574w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_9-300x195.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_9-1024x666.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_9-768x500.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_9-1536x999.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1574px) 100vw, 1574px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108336" class="wp-caption-text">Social media users complain about spam calls from Kalp Advisory</figcaption></figure>
<p>The ‘open’ link in the phishing email hides a URL to another domain, <code>delphidigital[.]org</code>. The full URL currently serves a benign form of the Bitcoin ETF document with titles that differ over time. However, at some point, this URL has or does switch to serving the first stage of a malicious application bundle entitled ‘Hidden Risk Behind New Surge of Bitcoin Price.app’ (<code>3f17c5a7d1e7fd138163d8039e614b8a967a56cb</code>).</p>
<figure id="attachment_108345" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108345" style="width: 1674px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108345" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_14.jpg" alt="Application icon for the Stage 1 dropper" width="1674" height="650" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_14.jpg 1674w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_14-300x116.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_14-1024x398.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_14-768x298.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_14-1536x596.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1674px) 100vw, 1674px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108345" class="wp-caption-text">Application icon for the Stage 1 dropper</figcaption></figure>
<h2>First Stage | “Bait and Switch” Dropper Application Replaces PDF</h2>
<p>The first stage is a Mac application written in Swift displaying the same name as the expected PDF, “Hidden Risk Behind New Surge of Bitcoin Price.app”. The application bundle has the bundle identifier <code>Education.LessonOne</code> and contains a universal architecture (i.e., arm64 and x86-64) Mach-O executable named <code>LessonOne</code>.</p>
<p>The application bundle was signed and notarized on 19 October, 2024 with the Apple Developer ID “Avantis Regtech Private Limited (2S8XHJ7948)”. The signature has since been revoked by Apple.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108337" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108337" style="width: 1892px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108337" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_8.jpg" alt="Code signing details for the Hidden Risk Behind New Surge of Bitcoin Price.app" width="1892" height="1004" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_8.jpg 1892w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_8-300x159.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_8-1024x543.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_8-768x408.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_8-1536x815.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1892px) 100vw, 1892px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108337" class="wp-caption-text">Code signing details for the Hidden Risk Behind New Surge of Bitcoin Price.app</figcaption></figure>
<p>On launch, the application downloads the decoy “Hidden Risk” pdf file from a Google Drive share and opens it using the default macOS PDF viewer (typically Preview). Similar TTPs were previously reported by researchers at <a href="https://www.kandji.io/blog/todoswift-disguises-malware-download-behind-bitcoin-pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kandji</a> in August. The PDF is written into a temporary file before being moved to <code>/Users/Shared</code> using NSFileManager’s <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/foundation/nsfilemanager/1414750-moveitematurl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">moveItemAtURL:toURL:error</a> method.</p>
<p>The malware then downloads and executes a malicious x86-64 binary sourced from <code>matuaner[.]com</code> via a URL hard-coded into the Stage 1 binary. Since by default macOS won’t allow an application to download from an insecure HTTP protocol, the application’s <code>Info.plist</code> specifies this domain in the dictionary for its <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/bundleresources/information_property_list/nsapptransportsecurity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NSAppTransportSecurity</a> key and sets the <code>NSExceptionAllowsInsecureHTTPLoads</code> value to “true”.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108348" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108348" style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108348" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_11.jpg" alt="The Stage 1’s Info.plist adds the C2 domain as an exception for Apple’s App Transport Security settings" width="1200" height="646" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_11.jpg 1200w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_11-300x162.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_11-1024x551.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_11-768x413.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108348" class="wp-caption-text">The Stage 1’s <em>Info.plist</em> adds the C2 domain as an exception for Apple’s App Transport Security settings</figcaption></figure>
<p>The <code>Info.plist</code> also indicates that the application was built on a macOS 14.2 Sonoma machine but will run on both Intel and Apple silicon Macs with macOS 12 Monterey or later.</p>
<h2>Second Stage | ‘growth’ x86-64 Mach-O Backdoor</h2>
<p>The malicious binary downloaded by the first stage dropper is a single architecture Mach-O x86-64 executable (<code>7e07765bf8ee2d0b2233039623016d6dfb610a6d</code>), meaning that although the parent dropper will execute on both Intel and Apple silicon machines, the Stage 2 will only run on Intel architecture Macs or Apple silicon devices with the <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/why-your-macos-edr-solution-shouldnt-be-running-under-rosetta-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rosetta emulation framework</a> installed. The binary, written in C++, has the name ‘growth’, weighs in at around 5.1 MB and is not code signed at all (SentinelLabs was able to share the file for researchers <a href="https://www.virustotal.com/gui/file/bd2aa5805b76f272b43a595b3d73e29d0fc4647e15e87950b8f904ea26dcf053/detection" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>).</p>
<p>The executable contains a number of identifiable functions, which we outline below, with the overall objective being to act as a backdoor to execute remote commands.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108347" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108347" style="width: 1638px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108347" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_12.jpg" alt="Some interesting functions in the 'growth' binary" width="1638" height="516" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_12.jpg 1638w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_12-300x95.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_12-1024x323.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_12-768x242.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_12-1536x484.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1638px) 100vw, 1638px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108347" class="wp-caption-text">Some interesting functions in the &#8216;growth&#8217; binary</figcaption></figure>
<p>On execution, the ‘growth’ binary performs the following actions.</p>
<ol>
<li aria-level="1">Calls the <code>sym.install_char__char_</code> function to install persistence. We discuss this in the next section.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Runs several commands to gather environmental information from the host and generate a random UUID of length 16. These commands include <code>sw_vers ProductVersion</code>, <code>sysctl hw.model</code> and <code>sysctl kern.boottime</code>.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Calculates the current date and time and performs <code>ps aux</code> to list running processes.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Sends the string “ci”, the random UUID and the gathered host data to a remote server using the <code>DoPost</code> function and awaits the C2 response.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Uses the <code>ProcessRequest</code> function to parse the response. If the first byte in the response is <b>0x31</b>, it sends the string “cs”, the random UUID and the value <b>-1</b> using <code>DoPost</code> and exits. If the first byte in the response is <b>0x30</b>, it executes the <code>SaveAndExec</code> function, sends the string “cs”, the random UUID and the value <b>0</b> using <code>DoPost</code>. The <code>SaveAndExec</code> function reads the C2 response, parses it, saves it into a random, hidden file at <code>/Users/Shared/.XXXXXX</code>, and executes it.
<p><figure id="attachment_108346" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108346" style="width: 1704px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108346" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_13.jpg" alt="The ProcessRequest function parses the C2 response" width="1704" height="608" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_13.jpg 1704w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_13-300x107.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_13-1024x365.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_13-768x274.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_13-1536x548.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1704px) 100vw, 1704px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108346" class="wp-caption-text">The <em>ProcessRequest</em> function parses the C2 response</figcaption></figure></li>
<li aria-level="1">Sleeps for 60 seconds and starts the flow again from step 3.</li>
</ol>
<p>The <code>DoPost</code> function is used to make the HTTP Post request to the C2 using <code>libcurl</code>. The first argument is the C2 URL, the second argument is the data sent in the body of the POST request, and the third argument is the data pointer passed to the write callback.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108340" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108340" style="width: 1258px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108340" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_5.jpg" alt="The DoPost function constructs and sends the http request" width="1258" height="1035" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_5.jpg 1258w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_5-300x247.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_5-1024x842.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_5-768x632.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1258px) 100vw, 1258px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108340" class="wp-caption-text">The <em>DoPost</em> function constructs and sends the HTTP request</figcaption></figure>
<p>We have previously <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/bluenoroff-how-dprks-macos-rustbucket-seeks-to-evade-analysis-and-detection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">noted</a> that this same User-Agent string, <code>mozilla/4.0 (compatible; msie 8.0; windows nt 5.1; trident/4.0)</code>, appeared in RustBucket malware in 2023. The User-Agent string also uses <code>cur1-agent</code> (using a 1 in place of the l in “curl”) as <a href="https://www.elastic.co/security-labs/DPRK-strikes-using-a-new-variant-of-rustbucket" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reported</a> by Elastic, a fairly unique indicator we have not observed elsewhere.</p>
<p>We also see similarities in the way that earlier malware parsed the response from the C2, essentially comparing one of two values as decision logic between awaiting further response, exiting or reading and writing a remote command to file. The <code>ProcessRequest</code> function used for this purpose was also the name of an <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/dprk-crypto-theft-macos-rustbucket-droppers-pivot-to-deliver-kandykorn-payloads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ObjCShellz</a> payload observed in a previous campaign.</p>
<p>The <code>SaveAndExec</code> function is responsible for executing any commands received from the C2. This function takes two parameters, the payload received and the length of the payload. The function parses the malicious payload and calculates indices related to the presence of the characters “#” and the “:”, receiving data from the C2 in the form <code>0#\0:command</code>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108339" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108339" style="width: 872px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108339" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_6.jpg" alt="SaveAndExec function parses the received script for embedded commands" width="872" height="580" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_6.jpg 872w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_6-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_6-768x511.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 872px) 100vw, 872px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108339" class="wp-caption-text"><em>SaveAndExec</em> function parses the received script for embedded commands</figcaption></figure>
<p>Based on the calculated indices, it creates a random file name of length 6 and writes the received command as a hidden file to <code>/Users/Shared/.%s</code>. It then uses <code>chmod 0x777</code> to set the permissions of the file to world read, write and execute, and finally executes it via <code>popen</code>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108338" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108338" style="width: 1064px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108338" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_7.jpg" alt="The SaveAndExec function changes the file’s permissions and then executes it" width="1064" height="720" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_7.jpg 1064w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_7-300x203.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_7-1024x693.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_7-768x520.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1064px) 100vw, 1064px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108338" class="wp-caption-text">The <em>SaveAndExec</em> function changes the file’s permissions and then executes it</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Persistence via Zshenv</h2>
<p>The backdoor’s operation is functionally similar to previous malware attributed to this threat actor, but what makes it especially interesting is the persistence mechanism, which abuses the Zshenv configuration file.</p>
<p>Zshenv is one of several optional configuration files used by the Zsh shell. At the user level, it sits as a hidden file in the Home directory, <code>~/.zshenv</code>. A system wide version can also be located at <code>/etc/zshenv</code>. If it exists, the file is sourced for all Zsh sessions, including interactive and non-interactive shells, non-login shells and scripts. It is also read before all other Zsh startup files.</p>
<p>Interestingly, previous malware samples used by the same threat actor have referenced <a href="https://www.jamf.com/blog/jamf-threat-labs-observes-targeted-attacks-amid-fbi-warnings/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">zsh_env</a> in their naming convention, but not actually used the mechanism. In an <a href="https://www.jamf.com/blog/jamf-threat-labs-observes-targeted-attacks-amid-fbi-warnings/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">earlier campaign</a>, BlueNoroff used the <code>~/.zshrc</code> config file to achieve persistence. However, this is a less reliable form of persistence since the file is only sourced when a user launches an interactive Terminal session or subsession from an existing console.</p>
<p>Infecting the host with a malicious Zshenv file allows for a more powerful form of persistence. While this technique is not unknown, it is the first time we have observed it used in the wild by malware authors. It has particular value on modern versions of macOS since Apple <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/apples-macos-ventura-7-new-security-changes-to-be-aware-of/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">introduced user notifications</a> for background Login Items as of macOS 13 Ventura. Apple’s notification aims to warn users when a persistence method is installed, particularly oft-abused LaunchAgents and LaunchDaemons. Abusing Zshenv, however, does not trigger such a notification in current versions of macOS.</p>
<p>In the binary, installation of the persistence mechanism is handled by the <code>sym.install_char__char_</code> function. The mechanism checks for a hidden touch file (zero byte) in the <code>/tmp/</code> folder called <code>.zsh_init_success</code>. If the file does not exist, then the &#8216;growth&#8217; binary is called and the touch file is created.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108343" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108343" style="width: 1195px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108343" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_16.jpg" alt="Contents of the malicious ~/.zshenv, executed for every Zsh session" width="1195" height="281" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_16.jpg 1195w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_16-300x71.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_16-1024x241.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_16-768x181.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_16-221x51.jpg 221w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1195px) 100vw, 1195px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108343" class="wp-caption-text">Contents of the malicious <em>~/.zshenv</em>, executed for every Zsh session</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Network Infrastructure</h2>
<p>Analysis of the actor operated and controlled network infrastructure associated with the Hidden Risk campaign further corroborates our confidence in attribution to DPRK’s BlueNoroff threat actor. Additionally, infrastructure analysis provides new insight into an extensive cluster of activity over the last year plus, and provides further links to industry reporting mentioned above, and <a href="https://x.com/500mk500/status/1826552762995187893" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">others in the community</a>.</p>
<p>Over recent months, the actor has built a network of connected infrastructure often themed around their cryptocurrency interests, methods of delivering malware lures, and mimicking legitimate Web3, cryptocurrency, fintech, and investment organizations to appear legitimate. NameCheap is the predominant domain registrar being abused. Virtual server hosting services such as Quickpacket, Routerhosting, Hostwinds, and others are the most commonly used based on our observations.</p>
<p>Various methods of pivoting across network infrastructures and services can be used to connect the Hidden Risk campaign to domains themed around the following organizations, indicating the actors interest in potential targeting and spoofing for targeting on other organizations.</p>
<div style="overflow-x: auto;">
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 120px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 50.0%; height: 24px;">Cryptocurrency Technologies</td>
<td style="width: 50.0%; height: 24px;">Delphi Digital, Solana Labs, Douro Labs, bitsCrunch, Caladan</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 50.0%; height: 24px;">Investment and Capital Entities</td>
<td style="width: 50.0%; height: 24px;">Maelstrom Fund, Selini Capital, Flori Ventures, ARK Invest, Long Journey Ventures</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 50.0%; height: 24px;">Generic IT/Communication</td>
<td style="width: 50.0%; height: 24px;">Virtual Meetings (Zoom, generic), Software Updates (macOS, browsers, generic)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p>When examining the infrastructure of the campaign detailed above in infrastructure analysis tools such as Validin, we can identify clear relations between the initial stage 1 delivery domain (<code>matuaner[.]com</code>) and the IPs <code>45.61.135[.]105</code> and <code>172.86.108[.]47</code>. These two IPs, in combination with an overlapping certificate use, link to a variety of domains that open the door to the larger and longer running history of BlueNoroff activity (green lines), and additional lesser confidence infrastructure to explore further (orange dotted lines).</p>
<figure id="attachment_108344" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108344" style="width: 1220px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="magnify" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_15.jpg" alt="Pivoting from sample delivery to initial set of infrastructure" width="1220" height="1082" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108344" class="wp-caption-text">Pivoting from sample delivery to initial set of infrastructure</figcaption></figure>
<p>Additional valuable pivoting can be achieved by analyzing attributes like DNS TXT records linked to domains that the actor may be using for phishing email delivery. For instance, we’ve observed the actor abusing email marketing automation tools, such as Brevo, where they go so far as to verify domain ownership to <a href="https://help.brevo.com/hc/en-us/articles/12163873383186-Authenticate-your-domain-with-Brevo-Brevo-code-DKIM-record-DMARC-record" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">meet email authentication standards</a>—an effort to bypass spam and phishing detection filters.</p>
<figure id="attachment_108349" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108349" style="width: 1016px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="magnify" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_10.jpg" alt="Pivoting initial infrastructure to wider set, though DNS TXT Records" width="1016" height="1048" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108349" class="wp-caption-text">Pivoting initial infrastructure to wider set, though DNS TXT Records</figcaption></figure>
<p>Beyond direct pivoting based on infrastructure and overlapping response data, we also identified additional domains registered using similar methods that reflect previous organization naming themes across various top level domains (TLDs), though these domains have not yet been linked to any known actor activity. For instance, by analyzing bulk domain search datasets, we found related but non-pivotable domains based on &#8220;Selini Capital,&#8221; such as <code>selinicapital[.]network</code>. This approach has proven effective in uncovering additional BlueNoroff domains linked to the Hidden Risk activity cluster.</p>
<p>Example Regular Expression: <code>/s+e+l+i+n+i+c+a+p+i+t+a+l+\.[a-z0-9-]+/</code></p>
<figure id="attachment_108350" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-108350" style="width: 1861px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-108350" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_1.jpg" alt="Bulk domain scanning, past 180 days, showing registration summary" width="1861" height="1417" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_1.jpg 1861w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_1-300x228.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_1-1024x780.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_1-768x585.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief_1-1536x1170.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1861px) 100vw, 1861px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-108350" class="wp-caption-text">Bulk domain scanning, past 180 days, showing registration summary</figcaption></figure>
<p>The extensive collection of BlueNoroff infrastructure we&#8217;ve gathered over the years, recently expanded through the latest Hidden Risk campaign activity, prevents us from detailing every unique pivoting method as this actor continues to evolve. As with all quality threat intelligence, our goal is to aid defenders while carefully managing the exposure of our tracking techniques to the actor. However, we are sharing a broader set of associated infrastructure in the Indicator of Compromise section below.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Over the last 12 months or so, North Korean cyber actors have engaged in a series of campaigns against crypto-related industries, many of which involved extensive &#8216;grooming&#8217; of targets via social media. We observe that the Hidden Risk campaign diverts from this strategy taking a more traditional and cruder, though not necessarily any less effective, email phishing approach. Despite the bluntness of the initial infection method, other hallmarks of previous DPRK-backed campaigns are evident, both in terms of observed malware artifacts and associated network infrastructure, as discussed extensively throughout this post.</p>
<p>We might speculate that heightened attention on previous DRPK campaigns could have reduced the effectiveness of previous &#8216;social media grooming&#8217; attempts, perhaps as a result of intended targets in DeFi, ETF and other crypto-related industries becoming more wary, but it is equally likely that such state-backed threat actors have sufficient resources to pursue multiple strategies simultaneously.</p>
<p>One factor that is relatively consistent throughout many of these campaigns is that the threat actors are seemingly able to acquire or hijack valid Apple &#8216;identified developer&#8217; accounts at will, have their malware notarized by Apple, and bypass macOS Gatekeeper and other built-in Apple security technologies. In light of this and the general increase in macOS crimeware observed across the security industry, we encourage all macOS users, but particularly those in organizational settings, to harden their security and increase their awareness of potential risks.</p>
<h2>Indicators of Compromise</h2>
<div style="font-size: 0.8em;">
<div style="overflow-x: auto;">
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 120px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 55.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>SHA1</strong></td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>Function</strong></td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>File</strong></td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>Arch</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 55.0%; height: 24px;">05c178891ca1e65af53bbcfdbec573da3f74d176</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Dropper</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Macho</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">arm64</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 55.0%; height: 24px;">3f17c5a7d1e7fd138163d8039e614b8a967a56cb</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Dropper</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">App</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Universal</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 55.0%; height: 24px;">7e07765bf8ee2d0b2233039623016d6dfb610a6d</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Backdoor</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Macho</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">x86_64</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 55.0%; height: 24px;">baf4da6b89b7d7cbf24c9deef5984ef9dfd52e6a</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Dropper</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Macho</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Universal</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 55.0%; height: 24px;">e5d97afa5f1501b3d5ec1a471dc8a3b8e2a84fdb</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Dropper</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">Macho</td>
<td style="width: 15.0%; height: 24px;">x86_64</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p><b>IP Addresses</b><br />
23[.]254.253[.]75<br />
45[.]61.128[.]122<br />
45[.]61.135[.]105<br />
45[.]61.140[.]26<br />
139[.]99.66[.]103<br />
144[.]172.74[.]23<br />
144[.]172.74[.]141<br />
172[.]86.102[.]98<br />
172[.]86.108[.]47<br />
216[.]107.136[.]10</p>
<p><b>Domains</b><br />
analysis.arkinvst[.]com<br />
appleaccess[.]pro<br />
arkinvst[.]com<br />
atajerefoods[.]com<br />
buy2x[.]com<br />
calendly[.]caladan[.]video<br />
cardiagnostic[.]net<br />
cmt[.]ventures<br />
community.edwardcaputo[.]shop<br />
community.kevinaraujo[.]shop<br />
community.selincapital[.]com<br />
community.selincapital[.]com<br />
customer-app[.]xyz<br />
delphidigital[.]org<br />
doc.solanalab[.]org<br />
dourolab[.]xyz<br />
drogueriasanjose[.]net<br />
edwardcaputo[.]shop<br />
email.sellinicapital[.]com<br />
evalaskatours[.]com<br />
happyz[.]one<br />
hwsrv-1225327.hostwindsdns[.]com<br />
info.ankanimatoka[.]com<br />
info.customer-app[.]xyz<br />
kevinaraujo[.]shop<br />
maelstromfund[.]org<br />
maelstroms[.]fund<br />
matuaner[.]com<br />
mbupdate.linkpc[.]net<br />
mc.tvdhoenn[.]net<br />
meet.caladan[.]video<br />
meet.caladangroup[.]xyz<br />
meet.hananetwork[.]video<br />
meet.selinicapital[.]info<br />
meet.selinicapital[.]online<br />
meet.selinicapital[.]xyz<br />
meet.sellinicapital[.]com<br />
meeting.sellinicapital[.]com<br />
meeting.zoom-client[.]com<br />
mg21.1056[.]uk<br />
nodnote.com<br />
online.selinicapital[.]info<br />
online.zoom-client[.]com<br />
panda95sg[.]asia<br />
pixelmonmmo[.]net<br />
presentations[.]life<br />
selincapital[.]com<br />
selinicapital[.]info<br />
selinicapital[.]network<br />
selinicapital[.]online<br />
sellinicapital[.]com<br />
sendmailed[.]com<br />
sendmailer[.]org<br />
shh5.baranftw[.]xyz<br />
tvdhoenn[.]net<br />
verify.selinicapital[.]info<br />
versionupdate.dns[.]army<br />
www.buy2x[.]com<br />
www.delphidigital[.]org<br />
www.frameworks[.]ventures<br />
www.happyz[.]one<br />
www.huspot[.]blog<br />
www.maelstromfund[.]org<br />
www.panda95sg[.]asia<br />
www.prismlab[.]xyz<br />
www.sellinicapital[.]com<br />
www.sendmailed[.]com<br />
www.sendmailer[.]org<br />
www.yoannturp[.]xyz<br />
xu10.1056[.]uk<br />
zoom-client[.]com</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BNThief-feature.jpg" length="376259" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
